<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tmp on</title><link>/tags/tmp/</link><description>Recent content in Tmp on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2009 00:30:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/tmp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[TIP] Ubuntu 1 MB /tmp Partition Problem</title><link>/2009/02/10/tip-ubuntu-1-mb-tmp-partition-problem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2009 00:30:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/02/10/tip-ubuntu-1-mb-tmp-partition-problem/</guid><description>Recently someone asked me about an issue he was facing with his Ubuntu Hardy Heron installation. Many of the applications, that he regularly used, were misbehaving. e.g., he couldn&amp;rsquo;t play flash videos in firefox, downloads were failing, installation of new applications were failing, etc. Everything was giving errors of not enough disk space even though he had quite a few GBs left on his drive. A few of the error messages pointed out that there wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough space in /tmp.</description><content>&lt;p>Recently someone asked me about an issue he was facing with his Ubuntu Hardy Heron installation. Many of the applications, that he regularly used, were misbehaving. e.g., he couldn&amp;rsquo;t play flash videos in firefox, downloads were failing, installation of new applications were failing, etc. Everything was giving errors of not enough disk space even though he had quite a few GBs left on his drive. A few of the error messages pointed out that there wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough space in /tmp. And indeed, he was unable to store anything more than 1 MB inside this particular directory. After a quick look I found out the issue. Ubuntu had created another partition with /tmp being its mount point and its maz size was set to 1 MB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A search told me that this occurs if you happen to run out of disk space on your root partition some time, so Ubuntu automatically limits the size of /tmp to squeeze as much out of the remaining space as it can. Ideally, original behaviour of /tmp should be restored once you recover some space but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen. The solution? Well, it is pretty simple. Just follow these steps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Step 1. Open up /etc/mtab in your favourite editor. e.g. gksudo gedit /etc/mtab&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Step 2. Look for a line that looks something like below example and delete it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>overflow /tmp tmpfs rw,size=1048576,mode=1777 0 0&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Step 3. Save the file and restart your computer. That&amp;rsquo;s it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, this problem might not just be Ubuntu specific though and might happen with other distros as well. So, if you come across such an issue, try out this solution.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>