<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ACT Fibernet on</title><link>/tags/act-fibernet/</link><description>Recent content in ACT Fibernet on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 16:46:24 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/act-fibernet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bypass ISP DNS hijack by changing DNS port on Ubiquiti USG router</title><link>/posts/bypass-isp-dns-hijack-ubiquiti-ubnt-usg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 16:46:24 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/bypass-isp-dns-hijack-ubiquiti-ubnt-usg/</guid><description>The Background We talked earlier about how certain ISPs block websites by using DNS hijack methods and I had recommended using DNSCrypt to bypass it. Well, as part of my home network overhaul, I moved over from the consumer grade (but still decent enough) Asus router over to Ubiquiti stack which, among other things, lead me to use their &amp;ldquo;Unify Security Gateway (USG)&amp;rdquo; as the router. Now, this router is pretty decent and is running Ubiquiti&amp;rsquo;s EdgeOS (derived from Vyatta OS, which in turn is based on linux/debian).</description></item><item><title>ACT Fibernet blocks sites using deep packet inspection</title><link>/posts/act-fibernet-deep-packet-inspection-blocking-sites/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 16:04:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/act-fibernet-deep-packet-inspection-blocking-sites/</guid><description>ISPs in India have been blocking websites since many years. It&amp;rsquo;s often done without much sense to it. The goveernment/telecom bodies and courts sometimes tell the ISPs to block content instead of telling the same to the websites that host the content. Sometimes, the orders are to block certain urls and ISPs are over-enthusiastic in implementing the orders and block complete websites. It&amp;rsquo;s all frustrating but it becomes enraging when you find out that the ISPs are messing with your traffic in a less than ethical way to implement this.</description></item><item><title>Indian ISP ACT Fibernet blocks bit.ly. Does DNS Hijacking</title><link>/posts/indian-isp-act-fibernet-blocks-bit-ly-does-dns-hijacking/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 17:14:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/indian-isp-act-fibernet-blocks-bit-ly-does-dns-hijacking/</guid><description>TLDR;
Indian ISP ACT Fibernet (aka Beam Telecom) hijacks its users&amp;rsquo; DNS requests (even when using public DNS servers like Google or OpenDNS) and blocks websites through this method. This has huge implications beyond website blocking and you can&amp;rsquo;t rely on anything that you are browsing anymore though there are ways available to make yourself safe.
Aside: Indian ISPs are blocking benign/collateral damage sites now like bit.ly for ACT and behance.</description></item></channel></rss>