<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Userfriendly on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/userfriendly/</link><description>Recent content in Userfriendly on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 May 2008 15:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/userfriendly/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Top 5 Comics For The Geeks</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/26/my-top-5-comics-for-the-geeks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2008 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/26/my-top-5-comics-for-the-geeks/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you think that all geeks do is walk around wearing thick glasses, code in unreadable languages and make weird gizmos from parts scrapped out of your junkyard, well you think wrong. We do like to have our share of fun. And what better to begin the day with a nice hot cuppa along with some geeky humour. Folks, here it is, the 5 comic strips that I love the most (in no particular order):&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>If you think that all geeks do is walk around wearing thick glasses, code in unreadable languages and make weird gizmos from parts scrapped out of your junkyard, well you think wrong. We do like to have our share of fun. And what better to begin the day with a nice hot cuppa along with some geeky humour. Folks, here it is, the 5 comic strips that I love the most (in no particular order):&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1. &lt;a href="http://dilbert.com/">Dilbert&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>: Our friendly neighbourhood engineer is in town. Have fun reading through his daily life&amp;rsquo;s traumas. Of course, his tragedies couldn&amp;rsquo;t be as funny without the able support of the likes of Wally, Asok, dogbert, catbert, and yeah the &amp;ldquo;pointy haired manager&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2. &lt;a href="http://xkcd.com/">XKCD&lt;/a>:&lt;/strong> Don&amp;rsquo;t know if this is the abbreviated form of something but the author calls it a webcomic of romance, sarcasm, math, and language. You&amp;rsquo;d be frowning at your monitor screen right now, trying to understand the relation between these things but you know the saying, There is the biggest order behind the biggest chaos (or something, I just made up that saying just now :-) )&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**3. &lt;a href="http://userfriendly.org/">Userfriendly&lt;/a>: **This is a story about a small ISP with your regular, average joe, sys-admins having a fun time at the expense of their unsuspecting management and, of course, about Pitr who has bigger plans for world domination than even google.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**4. &lt;a href="http://www.cad-comic.com/">Ctrl+Alt+Del&lt;/a>: **Your last resort on Windows is now your daily appetite in the form of this little story about (mis)adventures of a group of nerdy friends who just love to get into trouble, all while playing that game of Halo with one hand (and that too tied behind their backs).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>5. &lt;a href="http://www.penny-arcade.com/comic/">Penny Arcade&lt;/a>:&lt;/strong> If you are a gamer, you can&amp;rsquo;t miss this. Even &amp;ldquo;Jack Thomson&amp;rdquo; couldn&amp;rsquo;t, so you know, this one is a keeper ;-).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, go and have a nice time and yeah, don&amp;rsquo;t forget to tell me about what are your favourite tech comics.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>