<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>widgets on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/widgets/</link><description>Recent content in widgets on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 18:42:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/widgets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How To Debug Android Widgets</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/13/how-to-debug-android-widgets/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 18:42:42 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/13/how-to-debug-android-widgets/</guid><description>For most new android app developers (like me), it is a bit puzzling how to debug the android widgets or how to put a breakpoint in an android widget code. For normal applications, it is quite simple as when you press &amp;ldquo;debug&amp;rdquo; on the eclipse toolbar, it launches the emulator (or connects to existing emulator/device), syncs your application and launches its main activity and puts the control in your hands if you have put a breakpoint.</description></item><item><title>My First WordPress Plugin: Please Welcome shantz-wp-qotd</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/10/my-first-wordpress-plugin-please-welcome-shantz-wp-qotd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 11:00:27 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/10/my-first-wordpress-plugin-please-welcome-shantz-wp-qotd/</guid><description>Motivated by Ronald’s ultimate wordpress plugin tutorial at devlounge, I decided that the best way to learn something is to use it in a live project. Armed with my laptop and multiple flasks of coffee, the marathon began on Friday night. My only experience with web-related development so far had been around 8–10 years ago as a kid when, just like everybody else at that time, I was fascinated by HTML and did a “read-through” of HTML 4.</description></item><item><title>Shantz WordPress QOTD</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/10/shantz-wordpress-qotd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 10:22:57 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/10/shantz-wordpress-qotd/</guid><description>Shantz WP QOTD is a plugin to add quotes to your wordpress blog in a few easy clicks. It adds quotes to your posts and your sidebars with a multitude of options for sources and customization.
== Description ==
There are many quotes plugins out there. This one has been started with a view to have the best of features and options, ease of use and multiple sources to get the quotes from.</description></item><item><title>Hack: Wordpress i3theme IE6 sidebar problem solved</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/04/hack-wordpress-i3theme-ie6-sidebar-problem-solved/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2008 14:51:21 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/04/hack-wordpress-i3theme-ie6-sidebar-problem-solved/</guid><description>The awesome i3theme that this blog uses is a treat to the eyes, except to a lot of IE6 users. The issue is that for many people viewing wordpress blogs using this theme, the right sidebar doesn&amp;rsquo;t appear on the right, but **below **the middle column main area.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t know this problem existed as I don&amp;rsquo;t use IE but when a friend mailed to let me know, I started hunting around for the solution.</description></item></channel></rss>