<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Search on</title><link>/tags/search/</link><description>Recent content in Search on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 04:26:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/search/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Use Encrypted Google Search As Default in Chrome</title><link>/2011/05/12/use-encrypted-google-search-as-default-in-chrome/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 04:26:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2011/05/12/use-encrypted-google-search-as-default-in-chrome/</guid><description>Google just launched an encrypted search portal which is a Godsend for people on public networks since there is a lot that can be gleaned from your search queries. For doing your protected searches, however, you have to go to a different portal which I linked to above. Now, the omnibar (the address bar in Google Chrome) also serves as a search box but searches on the normal google portal by default.</description><content>&lt;p>Google just launched an &lt;a href="https://encrypted.google.com/">encrypted search portal&lt;/a> which is a Godsend for people on public networks since there is a lot that can be gleaned from your search queries. For doing your protected searches, however, you have to go to a different portal which I linked to above. Now, the omnibar (the address bar in Google Chrome) also serves as a search box but searches on the normal google portal by default. Here is a simple, few seconds process to switch it over to encrypted search.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the wrench/tool icon at the top of Google Chrome and go to Options.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On the &amp;ldquo;Basics&amp;rdquo; tab, go to the &amp;ldquo;Search&amp;rdquo; item and click on &amp;ldquo;Manage Search Engines&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Go to the very bottom of the new page that opens and you will see three empty boxes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>For the first box (leftmost), give any nickname for the engine. I gave &amp;ldquo;EncryptedGoogle&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>For second box, give a keyword that invokes the new search engine. I gave &amp;ldquo;encrypted.google.com&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>For last box, give the url for the search engine. This should be&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;code>https://encrypted.google.com/search?{google:RLZ}{google:acceptedSuggestion}{google:originalQueryForSuggestion}sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie={inputEncoding}&amp;amp;q=%s&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="7">
&lt;li>Press Enter and the engine will be added to the list. Then hover over the engine row and click on &amp;ldquo;Make as default&amp;rdquo;. And you are done.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Happy safe searching :)&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>