<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>IPhone on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/iphone/</link><description>Recent content in IPhone on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 19:16:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/iphone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Android/iPhone Beware: WP7 Phones have already sold 12 million devices</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/12/04/androidiphone-beware-wp7-phones-have-already-sold-12-million-devices/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 19:16:19 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/12/04/androidiphone-beware-wp7-phones-have-already-sold-12-million-devices/</guid><description>According to TechCrunch, that is. TC has a post on its blog right now (from none other than Michael Arrington) that says Toddlers Pick iPhone Over Windows 7 Phones 10-1. The article says that this is because a toddlers&amp;rsquo; app maker&amp;rsquo;s notes that their app sold 71.5 apps per day on average on the iOS app store, while the number was 7.5 on the WP7 marketplace. Go read the article (it&amp;rsquo;s pretty short) and come back to read the below.</description><content>&lt;p>According to TechCrunch, that is. TC has a post on its blog right now (from none other than Michael Arrington) that says &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2010/12/04/toddlers-pick-iphone-over-windows-7-phones-10-1/">Toddlers Pick iPhone Over Windows 7 Phones 10-1&lt;/a>. The article says that this is because a toddlers&amp;rsquo; app maker&amp;rsquo;s notes that their app sold 71.5 apps per day on average on the iOS app store, while the number was 7.5 on the WP7 marketplace. Go read the article (it&amp;rsquo;s pretty short) and come back to read the below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I posted in the comments there, the &amp;ldquo;article&amp;rdquo; has fail written all over it. Points to note:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Moms make the choice, not toddlers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The sample set is too small&lt;/li>
&lt;li>iPhone has been selling for 3 years and WP7 for like 1 month..so D.U.H&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The iPhone apps also sell on iPod/iPad.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It&amp;rsquo;s not &amp;ldquo;Windows 7 phones&amp;rdquo;, its &amp;ldquo;Windows Phone 7&amp;rdquo; lol. One of the most prominent tech blogs can&amp;rsquo;t even get the name right.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Acc to TechCrunch, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em>Data like this hints at the total run rate for Win7 phones&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo;, so basically WP7 has already sold around 12 million already (Total iOS devices sold till now is around 120mn acc to Jobs). That&amp;rsquo;s mighty impressive for a one month run.. :P&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>On a serious note, I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect this post to be coming from Mike. Or maybe this is like that recent editorial plagiarism scandal where the newspaper editor said that he was tired so he got it written by his juniors.. :P&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>ZDNet Fail. Answer is Stop Tech Blogging</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/11/19/zdnet-fail-answer-is-stop-tech-blogging/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2010 15:45:04 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/11/19/zdnet-fail-answer-is-stop-tech-blogging/</guid><description>Just read this article over at zdnet. What it basically says is condensed in these two points:
Android is a failure for Google because it is open and carriers/OEMs are stripping off google search from it and putting replacements like baidu/Bing. (BTW, half the people say Android is fail because it is not open and the other half say it is fail because it is open. Which one is it, please decide ;) )</description><content>&lt;p>Just read this &lt;a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/android-fail-the-answer-is-a-google-phone/7822">article&lt;/a> over at zdnet. What it basically says is condensed in these two points:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Android is a failure for Google because it is open and carriers/OEMs are stripping off google search from it and putting replacements like baidu/Bing. (BTW, half the people say Android is fail because it is not open and the other half say it is fail because it is open. Which one is it, please decide ;) )&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The solution is a Google Phone with google branding, sold unlocked at full price.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Let me answer 2nd point first. Dana Blankenhorn, thanks for that nice blast from the past advice. Google already did it with Nexus One, like, one year ago duh..&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, on to the first point. Even if lot of people are stripping off Google search, they still have a big share of the mobile search market. They didn&amp;rsquo;t create Android solely to earn from it directly. It was more of a way to ensure that they still have an avenue for mobile revenue which would have otherwise been completely lost (iPhone). Another thing here is that if they didn&amp;rsquo;t keep it open enough for other players, it might have not got such widespread adoption or they might have been killed in US/EU under antitrust laws.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, all I can say to Dana and ZDNet is &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-&amp;gt; kthxbi :P&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>The Real Threat Of Windows Phone 7</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/28/the-real-threat-of-windows-phone-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2010 19:48:34 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/28/the-real-threat-of-windows-phone-7/</guid><description>Many people say that Windows Phone 7 is a threat to iPhone because they are bringing in a super platform with a choice of multiple designs and multiple carriers with great Enterprise and gaming support and maintaining the lucrative integration that iPhone provides. Many also say that Windows Phone 7 is a threat to Android because it solves the problem of Apple&amp;rsquo;s draconian policies, gives choice to customers and all this without fragmenting the OS all over the place.</description><content>&lt;p>Many people say that Windows Phone 7 is a threat to iPhone because they are bringing in a super platform with a choice of multiple designs and multiple carriers with great Enterprise and gaming support and maintaining the lucrative integration that iPhone provides. Many also say that Windows Phone 7 is a threat to Android because it solves the problem of Apple&amp;rsquo;s draconian policies, gives choice to customers and all this without fragmenting the OS all over the place.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, I beg to differ. Windows Phone 7 is a threat to the world wide web and web apps. It plans to help the developers and users by going one up on fragmentation of Android but in the process will fragment the web app world itself. This is because the browser in WP7 is based on Internet Explorer 7. Yes, not IE 9, not IE8, but IE7, which is already four years old now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right now, if you have to do a web app, you can do it in HTML5, CSS3 etc and assume that it will work over most mobile handsets out there. Enter WP7 with its archaic browser and the developer has one more headache to solve. His app will be, in most cases, incompatible with the &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; platform and so he will have to code another version that works on IE7 as well. This will not only result in wasted time and effort but in fact, the developer may even have to hold back on features that might not work well on this ugly duckling which will hold the whole pack down for God knows how much more time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, there it is. If the Android fragmentation reports are true, you can just buy another handset like an iPhone but this comeback-from-the-grave monster will fragment the mobile web app world itself so that you won&amp;rsquo;t have any reprieve whichever phone you buy. So, I appeal to you. If you want a better mobile future, talk about it, write about it and let Microsoft know that it can and must do better.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Android vs iPhone: Security Models</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/25/android-vs-iphone-security-models/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2010 22:02:49 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/25/android-vs-iphone-security-models/</guid><description>Android and iPhone OS (iOS) have been at loggerheads for quite some time now. This is a take on which has a better security model to protect its users. I thought of writing it up because there have been a lot of discussions around me lately about which platform is more secure and I keep repeating the same points over and over at every one of them, so thought that in future I&amp;rsquo;ll just point them to this page :P</description><content>&lt;p>Android and iPhone OS (iOS) have been at loggerheads for quite some time now. This is a take on which has a better security model to protect its users. I thought of writing it up because there have been a lot of discussions around me lately about which platform is more secure and I keep repeating the same points over and over at every one of them, so thought that in future I&amp;rsquo;ll just point them to this page :P&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Disclaimer:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A. I don&amp;rsquo;t guarantee this post to be absolutely correct as I&amp;rsquo;m no security researcher or expert but I do have some interest in this field and I&amp;rsquo;ve been a developer for some time now on different architectures and OSs especially at OS/driver level and that too in the mobile devices field, so I &amp;ldquo;might&amp;rdquo; actually be right about a few things here and there..&lt;/p>
&lt;p>B. I&amp;rsquo;m an android user myself but not of the fanboy variety. I&amp;rsquo;ll be happy to switch camps any day I get something that appeals to me better. I have love and hate points for almost all platforms available but I&amp;rsquo;m using android because &amp;ldquo;for me&amp;rdquo; it&amp;rsquo;s love points slightly outnumber the hate points.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK, on with the points then. Here is the table that I created for this showing points I considered and which side wins each. Don&amp;rsquo;t start flaming me though just by seeing the table :P I will be discussing the points as well below it.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Android
iPhone&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1. Distribution Medium Security:&lt;/strong> Apple vets every application that is put on the app store while Google&amp;rsquo;s Market Place is unrestricted. How does this affect you security wise?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**a. Approval Process: **The biggest myth is that the vetting process is what will save you from malware on app store. IT WON&amp;rsquo;T. The Apple app approval process isn&amp;rsquo;t defined anywhere but in general it just states that it checks for apps to do what they say they will do. But they don&amp;rsquo;t check the source code of the apps and static analysis of binaries can only take you so far (Heck, they have even been inept at catching a whole lot of apps that were using their disallowed private apis which can be found easily using simple tools) . So, anyone actually wanting to write a malware can do it trivially by making the malicious code to run after the app has been approved. The trigger could be time based or could even be done over the web remotely. The app could even have encrypted payloads or download new pieces of code over the web and run them. So, we can safely say that approval process is something that can&amp;rsquo;t make things secure for you that way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Result: No one wins&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**
**&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>b. Phishing:&lt;/strong> This is where App store can protect you if someone put an app claiming to be from someone that it isn&amp;rsquo;t. e.g. Someone could make an app that claims to be from &amp;ldquo;Bank of America&amp;rdquo;. In apple&amp;rsquo;s case, I&amp;rsquo;m 99.99% sure that the app won&amp;rsquo;t pass the screening but in Android&amp;rsquo;s case, there won&amp;rsquo;t be any hassles for it to reach the marketplace. It could be pulled soon after as google learns about it but still even one person&amp;rsquo;s damage here is much more than what would have happend on iPhone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Result: iPhone wins&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**
**&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2. Local Security:&lt;/strong> What about the security in the OS itself once an app is on your phone? This is an important question because 1.) As I noted above, Apple&amp;rsquo;s app screening process isn&amp;rsquo;t robust enough to catch malware 2.) People can bypass the official distribution medium easily. Android allows to install apps from other sources on most phones by just enabling an option and a huge number of people jailbreak their iPhones and get/use this capability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>a. Permissions:&lt;/strong> On Android, an app has to explicitly declare what capabilities/data of the phone it wants to access/use and the user has to explicitly give it those permissions before it is allowed to install, irrespective of from where/how this app is being installed. So, it works even if you are installing the app from your SD card and even if you have rooted your phone. On iPhone, there is no such mechanism of restricting apps. All apps are equal and can access a lot of resources unhindered without the user knowing. So, while installing a single player only game on android you can immediately be suspicious if the app is asking for internet connection or access to your contacts data but on iPhone you will not come to know about this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Result: Android wins&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**
**&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>b. Environment:&lt;/strong> On both platforms, the apps run in their own sandboxes with unique uuids&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Result: Tie&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**
**&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>3. Open vs Closed:&lt;/strong> Most of the Android code is open source while for iOS, only darwin kernel and some other things like webkit etc are open source. Now, this in itself doesn&amp;rsquo;t gurantee to make Android secure but its code does get a lot of scrutiny from open source community as well as lot of other big name companies with commercial interests in Android which allows it to find and fix more bugs and loopholes than iPhone can.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Result: Slight win for Android&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**
**&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>4. App development model:&lt;/strong> Most apps for Android are written in java while those in iPhone are written in C/Objective-C. While I&amp;rsquo;m myself a big time C lover (Majority of my coding is in C/CPP) but it is indeed a very unforgiving language where you need to be very careful with what you write and has much greater chances of exploits, .e.g, Buffer overflows, as compared to java (Interestingly, all the jailbreaks for iPhone OS have been done using such exploits and have been made available day 0/day 1 mostly.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Result: Slight win for Android&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**
**&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>5. Damage Control:&lt;/strong> What if an app actually got through everything on any of these platforms and started spreading? Both of these platforms have kill switches in the hands of Google/Apple which they can use to remove such malicious apps from the users&amp;rsquo; phones remotely.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Result: Tie&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**
**&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Summary: Well, there is no clear winner. Apple is quite good when it comes to protecting you from phishing (though that advantage goes away if you jailbreak and use alternative means to install apps) and Android has a real sound local security system (though it also has the flaw that users might not always understand why an app is requesting a certain critical permission and install it anyways). So, take your pick and let me know what you picked :) and please do tell me if I&amp;rsquo;m wrong in any of my points or missed out on something that needs to be compared.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Apple is Magical: Daniel Eran Gilder is the Living Proof</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/10/apple-magical-dan-eran-gilder/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 04:49:53 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/10/apple-magical-dan-eran-gilder/</guid><description>Update: Removed the post as the person in consideration has contacted me with the explanation of what went down. I’m not sure if it is completely true or this is just as a response to this post but anyways, as I had contended in the original post that it was a stupid little thing that didn’t really warrant any attention or a post but I still did it just because I’m weird, so in the light of the developments, I think it’s best to remove the rants and focus on actual discussion.</description><content>&lt;p>Update: Removed the post as the person in consideration has contacted me with the explanation of what went down. I’m not sure if it is completely true or this is just as a response to this post but anyways, as I had contended in the original post that it was a stupid little thing that didn’t really warrant any attention or a post but I still did it just because I’m weird, so in the light of the developments, I think it’s best to remove the rants and focus on actual discussion. I’ll be discussing the points put out by Dan over his blog or might make a post about them here..&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Do They Really Know How To Sell Something In India?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/26/do-they-really-know-how-to-sell-something-in-india/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 14:45:46 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/26/do-they-really-know-how-to-sell-something-in-india/</guid><description>Update: UK Ad Authorities have declared iPhone ad as &amp;ldquo;misleading&amp;rdquo;. I guess then they should declare it plain fraud in India.
This is a short rant about two of the &amp;ldquo;big&amp;rdquo; products launched recently in India in the last one week and how the people behind their sales/marketing teams either try to take the Indian customer for a ride, or shaft themselves.
iPhone: The big icon. Bharti Airtel/Vodafone claimed lakhs of pre-registrations, yet no one lined up to buy it.</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="http://www.mobileburn.com/news.jsp?Id=5176">UK Ad Authorities have declared iPhone ad as &amp;ldquo;misleading&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/a> I guess then they should declare it plain fraud in India.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a short rant about two of the &amp;ldquo;big&amp;rdquo; products launched recently in India in the last one week and how the people behind their sales/marketing teams either try to take the Indian customer for a ride, or shaft themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>iPhone&lt;/strong>: The big icon. Bharti Airtel/Vodafone claimed lakhs of pre-registrations, yet no one lined up to buy it. Anyways, to the point. The ads all over the print, digital and broadcast media in India list out 3 major points in one sentence:&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>1. **A 3G Phone:** My a$$. They haven't even finalized auction details for 3G spectrum in India yet.
2. **Desktop Class Browser:** Without Flash?
3. **Push E-mail:** Oh, the one that Apple already pulled the plug on?
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Anyways, even if this were to be true, nobody would have bought it for the steep price for something that hardly even performs properly as a phone.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>BIG TV&lt;/strong>: This is the &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; big one, from the stable of none other than Reliance/Anil Dhirubhai Ambani. Ok, it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be good, very good. I checked out &lt;a href="http://bigtv.co.in">their website&lt;/a> to see how good. What do I get?&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>1. A flash only site. No fallback. Did they get it coded from a high-school flash junkie?
2. After 15 minutes of looking around clicking on 10s of links, going in circles, I'm still confused. What exactly are their packages. There are so many rates and offers floating around. Everything promising something different, but wait, not available for your region. There are so many channels, more than your current DTH, but one second, WHAT exactly are thos channels. No list? For all I care, they could be endless streams of Doordarshan and ETV regional ones. (Please repeat the question I asked in point 1 here again)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Makes me wonder, do they really want to sell anything or Anil just made this out for fun, having a roaring time watching realtime website logs seeing people getting stuck and frustrated in the maze.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>More iPhone 3G Nonsense Uncovered: No Tethering</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/06/14/more-iphone-3g-nonsense-uncovered-no-tethering/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2008 15:57:50 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/06/14/more-iphone-3g-nonsense-uncovered-no-tethering/</guid><description>iPhone 3G, the “supposedly” latest and greatest handhled, just continues to amaze me, with its ridiculousness of course. I mean first they dare to call a machine a smartphone that can’t run more than one app a time, need you to send the unit back even for a battery change, fix the glaring mistakes of its predecessor and call them “features” and make you believe that you are getting it all for cheap while covertly telling you that you need a minimum of 2 year 70$ contract to get it and need to pay through every hole for even software updates.</description><content>&lt;p>iPhone 3G, the “supposedly” latest and greatest handhled, just continues to amaze me, with its ridiculousness of course. I mean first they dare to call a machine a smartphone that can’t run more than one app a time, need you to send the unit back even for a battery change, fix the glaring mistakes of its predecessor and call them “features” and make you believe that you are getting it all for cheap while covertly telling you that you need a minimum of 2 year 70$ contract to get it and need to pay through every hole for even software updates. And then they don’t stop this, just out is the information that you can’t tether the “data transfer powerhouse” to your laptops/PCs/Macs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>HSDPA/HSUPA my a**. I mean what good is a “3G” device that doesn’t even let you use the potential of the hyper-speeds by connecting to your bigger machines or even doing video calls. Oh right, I forgot, now you can check your e-mail at 50 messages per minute, WOOHOO!!, I’m so l33t.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So far the only good things I’ve noticed about the new release are:The MobileMe aka “sync-with-anything-anywhere” service, which although paid (obviously, its Apple we are talking about here), is still interesting. And the new SDK 2.0 that promises the 3rd party devs the same access to the phone as Apple’s devs, seems to be a step in the right direction though it remains to be seen how much of this is actually followed up on by Apple.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, what do you feel is &lt;strong>THE&lt;/strong> revolutionary thing about this new Cupertino offering? And of course, chime in with your gripes as well.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>The Elusive Super Phone</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/08/the-elusive-super-phone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2008 17:15:28 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/08/the-elusive-super-phone/</guid><description>HTC announce their shiny new Touch Diamond recently. Everyone ooh&amp;rsquo;ed and aah&amp;rsquo;ed while ogling at it until they realized that HTC has taken a step back (or forward towards matching Apple&amp;rsquo;s iPhone crap) by removing the expansion card slot from the phone. Yes, it has 4 GB of internal storage but I&amp;rsquo;d rather have an SDHC card slot with the ever falling prices of solid state memory (an 8 GB Class 6 SDHC card is worth not more than around 60$ these days).</description><content>&lt;p>HTC announce their shiny new Touch Diamond recently. Everyone ooh&amp;rsquo;ed and aah&amp;rsquo;ed while ogling at it until they realized that HTC has taken a step back (or forward towards matching Apple&amp;rsquo;s iPhone crap) by removing the expansion card slot from the phone. Yes, it has 4 GB of internal storage but I&amp;rsquo;d rather have an SDHC card slot with the ever falling prices of solid state memory (an 8 GB Class 6 SDHC card is worth not more than around 60$ these days). With a history of ultimate-gift-to-mankind phones like HTC Tytn, HTC Tytn II (Kaiser), iPhone, etc that excite so much on the first look and then start becoming dimmer and unwanted as the euphoria settles, we are left to wonder when will we see the real &amp;ldquo;Super Phone&amp;rdquo;. The do-it-all-be-all-end-all phone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, my prediction is (Nostradamus style) : **NEVER. **No sir, you are not going to see your dream phone any time soon, or any time at all, for that matter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why do I say that. The reasons are pretty obvious, once we take off our wishful thinking hats and don the smart thinking ones.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**1. ****A new dream every day: **Around 8-10 years ago, I wished I had a cell phone. Around 6 years ago, I wish I had one with a camera. Around 4 years ago, I wish I had a phone with Mp3 player and expandable memory. 3 years ago I wished for a smart phone. Now, I wish for&amp;hellip;. You get it. By the time something comes out, our dreams have already moved on. After all they  aren&amp;rsquo;t called &amp;ldquo;dreams&amp;rdquo; just like that ;)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**2. Where is the money: **You might be ready to give a fortune (and your first born son) for that ultimate phone, but the evil-phone-conglomerate wants much more than that. They want you to be slaves. They don&amp;rsquo;t want the world to spend a huge amount in one go and then stop. They need to mint more money and too much more frequently than you&amp;rsquo;d like to spend. This is why the strategy works. Give out a phone that has slim form factor, nice UI, wi-fi, but then make the processor crappy (Touch), then lure them with a better processor but take out the wi-fi (Touch Dual), Add the wi-fi back and slap in a keyboard too, but keep&amp;rsquo;em wanting for &lt;a href="http:///2008/01/28/htc-the-best-windows-mobile-business-unit.html">better graphics&lt;/a> (Kaiser), give &amp;rsquo;em a shiny new toy, but then lock it down in every possible (iCrap). So, you&amp;rsquo;d be stuck in the vicious circle of &amp;ldquo;upgrades&amp;rdquo; and keep the phone factory churning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, my dear fellow phone lovers, stop wasting your time waiting for that ultimate phone, and go &amp;ldquo;upgrade&amp;rdquo; at once, because &amp;ldquo;that&amp;rdquo; phone with just &amp;ldquo;that&amp;rdquo; one more feature&amp;hellip;ISN&amp;rsquo;T COMING&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Nokia + Windows Mobile = Let's Kick Some &lt;InsertWMPhoneMakerName> Butt</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/08/nokia-windows-mobile-lets-kick-some-butt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2008 05:00:58 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/08/nokia-windows-mobile-lets-kick-some-butt/</guid><description>As everyone knows, I’m an out-and-out Windows Mobile worshipper. It’s like a girlfriend, who is very difficult to manage and understand at first, but is a great source of joy if you know how to manage her. I don’t like any other phones now; the extensibility given by WM will do that to you.
I also “admire” Nokia because of the quality and reliability they provide with their phones. Having worked for them in a project (Nokia Networks/Nokia Seimens Networks actually), I know how much testing they put in before releasing something.</description><content>&lt;p>As everyone knows, I’m an out-and-out Windows Mobile worshipper. It’s like a girlfriend, who is very difficult to manage and understand at first, but is a great source of joy if you know how to manage her. I don’t like any other phones now; the extensibility given by WM will do that to you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also “admire” Nokia because of the quality and reliability they provide with their phones. Having worked for them in a project (Nokia Networks/Nokia Seimens Networks actually), I know how much testing they put in before releasing something. That coupled with the recent &lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/28/htc-the-best-windows-mobile-business-unit.html">crap-doings&lt;/a> by even the largest of the WM Phone companies like HTC, have made me try to look elsewhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, if this &lt;a href="http://www.itwire.com/content/view/16510/127/">news&lt;/a> comes true, then we are in for a treat, as the two giants might just come together to give us a sweet little toy for our “smart” cravings &lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/smile3.gif" alt="">. Read the news and let us know how you feel about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PS: Don’t even mention iPhone/iPod/iTouch or any other iCrap.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>