<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Coupon on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/coupon/</link><description>Recent content in Coupon on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2008 14:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/coupon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Contest: Free 20$ SiteGround Web Hosting Coupon</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/12/12/contest-free-20-siteground-web-hosting-coupon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2008 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/12/12/contest-free-20-siteground-web-hosting-coupon/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have a coupon to give away for the excellent &lt;a href="http://www.siteground.com">SiteGround Web Hosting&lt;/a>. This coupon will take off 20$ from anything you want to buy from them. If you have an existing website with them, then also you can use this to take off 20$ from your bill. So, what do you have to do? Just follow the 2 simple steps listed below, and I’ll choose one lucky winner at random to give it away.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>I have a coupon to give away for the excellent &lt;a href="http://www.siteground.com">SiteGround Web Hosting&lt;/a>. This coupon will take off 20$ from anything you want to buy from them. If you have an existing website with them, then also you can use this to take off 20$ from your bill. So, what do you have to do? Just follow the 2 simple steps listed below, and I’ll choose one lucky winner at random to give it away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Step 1. Subscribe (free) to receive this blog’s updates through email using the subscribe through email box on the right (which reads &amp;ldquo;Free Email Updates&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Step 2. Leave a comment on this post mentioning your email ID with which you registered so that I know that you have registered (you can leave a small part of your username in your email ID if you want).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then just sit back and relax, or better still, read a few other nice posts on my blog and comment on them :). I’ll choose the winner in a few days and let you guys know right here. So, stay tuned.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What are you waiting for? I’d get those fingers moving if I were you ;). Good Luck.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>