<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Code on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/categories/code/</link><description>Recent content in Code on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 02:01:05 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/categories/code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Integrating SDL2 with bazel on macOS</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2019/12/31/sdl2-macos-bazel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 02:01:05 +0530</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2019/12/31/sdl2-macos-bazel/</guid><description>Came across bazel build system recently at my new job and found it to be quite nice compared to my earlier mainstays CMake and Make. It's fast and correct, just as their website says. But I also liked it because it's explicit with very little magic. Though examples in the wild are a bit less since it is a fairly recent entrant compared to its competitors. For a personal side project, I needed to use SDL2 and it was the first time I had to use an external/pre-built library with bazel.</description></item><item><title>Create a bit.ly like shorturl static website</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/09/17/create-bitly-clone-shorturl-static-website/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 23:46:24 +0530</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/09/17/create-bitly-clone-shorturl-static-website/</guid><description>I decided to create my own shorturl website last week for personal use and ended up developing a python project (deecubes)that can be used by anyone to do the same. This is a post to explain what/why/how about it.
Why my own shorturl website? So far I had been using sites like bit.ly or TinyURL whenever I needed to generate a shorturl (e.g. for giving to someone for easily remember, noting down on paper, putting links on resume, etc) but I had concerns that:</description></item><item><title>Fixing the problem of matplotlib and ggplot not showing graphs in python</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2016/06/29/fixing-the-problem-of-matplotlib-and-ggplot-not-showing-graphs-in-python/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 14:20:55 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2016/06/29/fixing-the-problem-of-matplotlib-and-ggplot-not-showing-graphs-in-python/</guid><description>While trying to make some graphs for one of my side projects recently, I came across an issue that both matplotlib and ggplot did not show up the graphs. I was able to save the graphs to an image file just fine, but if I tried to show them directly on screen while running the script, it just printed a number and exited. After tearing apart my hair for some time, I checked the backend being used by matplot lib:</description></item><item><title>NTP Driver For ESP8266</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2015/03/01/ntp-driver-for-esp8266/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 08:02:22 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2015/03/01/ntp-driver-for-esp8266/</guid><description>I'm building a smartwatch project based around the new IoT posterkid on the block, ESP8266. Apart from the usual &amp;ldquo;smart&amp;rdquo; stuff, it does still need to display correct time :) and hence, the need for an ntp driver/client. I couldn't find anyone working on that yet, so wrote up a quick and dirty implementation here:
NTP Implementation for ESP8266
ESP8266 Smartwatch NTP Demo It still has a lot of stuff left to be done to make it good enough for the smartwatch project but it works.</description></item><item><title>Weekend Hack: Shoutcast2Dropbox - Automatic Shoutcast Stations To Dropbox Recorder</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2015/02/16/weekend-hack-shoutcast2dropbox-automatic-shoutcast-stations-to-dropbox-recorder/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 03:00:19 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2015/02/16/weekend-hack-shoutcast2dropbox-automatic-shoutcast-stations-to-dropbox-recorder/</guid><description>So I got bored of listening to same old songs on my phone over and over and Rdio announced a streaming plan for India. With a sigh of relief I subscribed immediately and it was stellar at home with its wonderful 32 million song collection and chromecast support to boot. The experience during the commute daily was underwhelming. Couple the spotty airtel data connection with no one station covering all songs I would love and it makes for a frustrating commute with long gaps all over.</description></item><item><title>Browser controlled Raspberry Pi Camera Car</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2014/08/03/browser-controlled-raspberry-pi-camera-car/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2014 15:33:12 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2014/08/03/browser-controlled-raspberry-pi-camera-car/</guid><description>Spent this weekend building a remote controlled car with a live camera feed with a Raspberry Pi doing the communication and brains duty. Pretty nice real time movement control and camera pan/tilt control through websockets with a live stream feeding back to any browser directly from the car through mjpg-streamer
(PS: Video is at the bottom of the post. Browser/video on TV courtesy ChromeCast. Casted my Nexus 5 screen to the TV simultaneously while controlling the car :) )</description></item><item><title>[Xposed Mod] Bypass Exchange Security Policy for Nexus and other AOSP devices</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/10/14/xposed-mod-bypass-exchange-security-policy-for-nexus-4-android-4-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 14:13:10 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/10/14/xposed-mod-bypass-exchange-security-policy-for-nexus-4-android-4-3/</guid><description>Exchange Security Bypass Xposed Mode for Nexus 4/5/7 and other AOSP based devices (Android 4.3 / 4.4)
Update: This has now been tested to work successfully on all stock or nearly stock JellyBean (4.3) and KitKat (4.4) ROMs on Nexus 4 / Nexus 5 / Nexus 7. Other AOSP ROMs like CM11 should work as well.
This mod should be used along with Xposed ( http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=1574401 ). Xposed is this awesome framework developed by rovo89 which allows you to carry out mods to your device without changing any files (well except one &amp;ldquo;app_process&amp;rdquo; as part of the xposed installer).</description></item><item><title>Display Message on Samsung TVs in Python (Samsung MessageBox Service Exploitation)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/07/14/samsung-tv-message-box-python/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 14:07:15 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/07/14/samsung-tv-message-box-python/</guid><description>This script is the result of a weekend's hacking to get my TV to display incoming calls/texts which I miss invariably because the phone is buried under a sofa or in a different room. Earlier I had done this using my Odroid U2 and Tasker/AutoRemote but this was limiting as this meant that I could see the notifications only when I was watching something through the Odroid. Samsung TVs, which are DLNA enabled, also include a hidden service called &amp;ldquo;Message Box&amp;rdquo; which can display different information on the TV natively irrespective of which display mode/input mode you are in.</description></item><item><title>The 80 Column Coding Rule</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/02/25/the-80-column-coding-rule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 18:48:21 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/02/25/the-80-column-coding-rule/</guid><description>I've followed the 80 column rule almost always when I code, i.e., I keep a soft limit of keeping my lines of my code limited to 80 characters max. unless breaking up the line really messes up the readability of the code.
I was asked recently why do I bother now in this age of 24&amp;rdquo; widescreen monitors (and above) with resolutions of 720p at the bare minimum. I could certainly afford to have more than double that limit staring back at me from the screen without overflowing.</description></item><item><title>Adding Lyrics to SharkZapper for Grooveshark</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/09/23/adding-lyrics-to-sharkzapper-for-grooveshark/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2011 09:12:06 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/09/23/adding-lyrics-to-sharkzapper-for-grooveshark/</guid><description>I bet all of you know about grooveshark, the awesome music service. And sharkzapper is a cool chrome extension that puts the control and information about anything playing in your grooveshark chrome tab into a little button on the address bar. It is a very good extension but I felt that what it was missing was lyrics. Before I could comment on the extension's chrome market page, I noticed that it has a github repository.</description></item><item><title>Remote Bandwidth Stats</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/08/21/remote-bandwidth-stats/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 17:44:24 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/08/21/remote-bandwidth-stats/</guid><description>This post is about my open source remote bandwidth usage stats logger project.
I've been wanting to log the internet bandwidth usage at my home for quite some time since I don't really find the stats put out by my ISP to be completely accurate. But I have multiple devices at home that access the internet so it is not feasible to install a bandwidth monitor individually on all these devices as I'd still need to add up all logs and many of such devices don't even have a way to install a monitoring software installed (e.</description></item><item><title>Making Kinect Work With PS3</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/03/20/making-kinect-work-with-ps3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2011 15:36:51 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/03/20/making-kinect-work-with-ps3/</guid><description>This post describes my first attempt at making Kinect work with a PS3. Microsoft's new XBOX 360 accessory, kinect has made a powerful entry into the market, becoming the fastest selling gadget of all time. Looks like their &amp;ldquo;You are the controller&amp;rdquo; tagline is working. Of course, Sony's &amp;ldquo;similar&amp;rdquo; accessory Move is selling well too but is far behind kinect adoption probably because nothing beats the lure of making something work with just &amp;ldquo;The Force&amp;rdquo; ;).</description></item><item><title>Ubuntu Maverick uinput Problem Solved</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/02/21/ubuntu-maverick-uinput-problem-solved/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 19:33:37 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/02/21/ubuntu-maverick-uinput-problem-solved/</guid><description>I've been playing around with linux uinput infrastructure for one of my ideas (Details coming soon ;) ). &amp;ldquo;uinput&amp;rdquo; is basically a mechanism in linux that allows user space applications to inject input events (mouse/keyboard or anything else) into the system. But the problem I faced was that my programs were compiling and running without any errors but I just couldn't see the effect happening, i.e., the events weren't getting injected into the system.</description></item><item><title>Android Dev Tip: App Not Showing on X10 Mini Marketplace</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/07/android-dev-tip-app-not-showing-on-x10-mini-marketplace/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2010 21:18:06 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/07/android-dev-tip-app-not-showing-on-x10-mini-marketplace/</guid><description>Many Android Developers (and users) get confused that why a certain app isn't showing up on the new Xperia X10 Mini (and few other) phones. This happens even if they support all android versions and have published their apps for all countries, so that shouldn't be the issue. I came across this as well when few people mentioned that they couldn't find my app Wi-Fi Keep Alive in the X10 mini marketplace.</description></item><item><title>Android App Wi-Fi Keep Alive updated to 1.4.1</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/22/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive-updated-1-4-0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2010 16:58:07 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/22/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive-updated-1-4-0/</guid><description>Update: Made a minor update for a small bug that can make wi-fi keep reconnecting in quick succession.
Pushed out a new update to my Android App Wi-Fi Keep Alive today. This update brings in another work around for the issue where the wi-fi is alive on the phone and it is also connected to the network but is somehow unable to send/receive any packets to the network. The new work around will automatically re-associate your phone with the wi-fi router if it detects such a situation.</description></item><item><title>BadTokenException Error In Android Dialog</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/08/badtokenexception-android-dialog-getapplicationcontext/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2010 11:24:14 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/08/badtokenexception-android-dialog-getapplicationcontext/</guid><description>If you are creating a custom Dialog for Android, and following the Android Developers’ Creating Dialogs tutorial, then most likely you would have faced a Force Close with this exception showing up in logcat. I did too. Although I figured it out quickly, it might not be easy to find out for many, so posting it here for reference. Basically, the code given in the tutorial goes something like this:</description></item><item><title>How To Debug Android Widgets</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/13/how-to-debug-android-widgets/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 18:42:42 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/13/how-to-debug-android-widgets/</guid><description>For most new android app developers (like me), it is a bit puzzling how to debug the android widgets or how to put a breakpoint in an android widget code. For normal applications, it is quite simple as when you press &amp;ldquo;debug&amp;rdquo; on the eclipse toolbar, it launches the emulator (or connects to existing emulator/device), syncs your application and launches its main activity and puts the control in your hands if you have put a breakpoint.</description></item><item><title>Quick Sync Settings</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/12/quick-sync-settings/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2010 21:14:54 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/12/quick-sync-settings/</guid><description>This is a very small android app to open the accounts and sync settings in one click. We all need to disable the sync settings of a particular account sometimes but keep all other items still syncing. For example, for most of the day I'm at work, in front of my office PC so I don't need to keep my work email syncing which causes unnecessary drain on my battery but I do need to keep other things, like my google calendar, syncing still.</description></item><item><title>Real Time Data Plotting with GNUPlot</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/12/29/real-time-plot-gnuplot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2009 11:15:51 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/12/29/real-time-plot-gnuplot/</guid><description>I wrote this script a few days ago to plot real-time / streaming data with gnuplot. The motivation was that I needed to test a piece of code for a touchscreen driver that I had written at work. The issue was that the UI wasn’t quite ready yet, so I wanted to test just the driver to be working fine. Now, the very first thought for the software to use that came to me was “gnuplot” but I found that it can’t really do this in an easy way.</description></item><item><title>Continuous Monitoring With Tail Fails</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/12/23/continuous-monitor-tail-fails/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2009 18:10:44 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/12/23/continuous-monitor-tail-fails/</guid><description>If you can't get tail command to continuously monitor a file, then read on. I was working on a script yesterday, a part of which depended on continuous monitoring of a text file. I had used our trusty old &amp;ldquo;tail&amp;rdquo; command for this but while testing by manually putting in some data into the file, it was failing but curiously it was working fine when used in actual scenario. Befuddled, I did a simple test.</description></item><item><title>Compiling Latest FireFly (mt-daapd) for ASUS WL-500W</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/07/03/compiling-latest-firefly-mt-daapd-asus-wl-500w/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2009 10:28:32 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/07/03/compiling-latest-firefly-mt-daapd-asus-wl-500w/</guid><description>FireFly is a nice DAAP based media server that allows you to listen to your music collection anywhere using any DAAP based client like iTunes, with other players (like Winamp, Rhythmbox, VLC, etc) using plugins, or it even has its own dedicated php/flash/java based clients that can be fired up on any platform any computer giving you instant nirvana.
Many people, like me, use it on their Routers or NAS boxes to access their music anywhere without having to keep their home PC running or lugging around external drives.</description></item><item><title>Project: Figlet Online - Text To ASCII Converter Tool</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/24/figlet-online-text-to-ascii-converter-tool/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2009 14:00:29 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/24/figlet-online-text-to-ascii-converter-tool/</guid><description>Figlet is a brilliant tool to convert text to amazing ASCII Art that I have used for many years. This weekend I thought of creating an online version of it, so that anyone can use it even if they can't install it on their systems. It is pretty easy to use. The drill is just to choose the font you want (and there is a very extensive collection of more than 250 to choose from), input the text that you want to be ASCII'fied, press a button and you are done.</description></item><item><title>[TIP] Add Directories Recursively To Perforce (P4) Depot</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/03/add-directories-recursively-to-perforce-p4-depot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2009 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/03/add-directories-recursively-to-perforce-p4-depot/</guid><description>Perforce is an excellent revision control system for the code but the GUIs (P4WIN and P4V) are too slow to be productive. Hence, I like to do most of my work through command lines. Now, the other day I needed to add a directory and all its subdirectories and files to the repository (or perforce depot). This is a trivial task through the GUI. Just drag the top level directory onto the changelist area and the GUI takes care of everything but there is no straightforward way to do this through command line, until, I discovered the &amp;ldquo;-x&amp;rdquo; option of P4.</description></item><item><title>Project: My WordPress Plugin Shantz WP Prefix Suffix Updated to 1.1.4</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/02/wordpress-plugin-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-114/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2009 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/02/wordpress-plugin-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-114/</guid><description>Here comes another update, and this time it is a majorly recommended one. For those who are still living under a rock (just kidding :P), this is a plugin that allows you to add any kind of text/html/css/php/javascript code to any of your posts or pages with lots of controls over what to display, where to display, etc etc. So, you could use it as an ad-manager or a copyright notice adder (to thwart those feed scrapers) or just add some friendly messages or related posts, etc for your readers.</description></item><item><title>Project: Shantz WordPress Prefix Suffix Updated to 1.1.2</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/19/project-shantz-wordpress-prefix-suffix-updated-to-112/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2009 18:30:15 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/19/project-shantz-wordpress-prefix-suffix-updated-to-112/</guid><description>My WordPress Plugin &amp;ldquo;Shantz Wordpress Prefix Suffix&amp;rdquo; has just been updated to version 1.1.2. For those who don't know, this is a super-light and easy to use plugin that allows you to add any text or html/javascript/php code to your posts, be it the top of the posts, bottom of the posts or even in the middle. And you get a lot of options to control all this. I use it even on my site, to create links for my other blogs, adding copyright notices and even for advertisements (google adsense, chitika premium, etc).</description></item><item><title>Project: Shantz XWinWrap Update to 0.3</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/16/project-shantz-xwinwrap-update-to-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2009 18:30:03 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/16/project-shantz-xwinwrap-update-to-03/</guid><description>Here is another update for the fans of XWinWrap, the tiny program that allows you to run animated wallpapers on your system. You could use screensavers, movies and what not as your desktop background. This update fixes a segfault that many users were facing, a new debug option to print some debug mesages to get some info if it is not working for you and a new hack option for giving a &amp;ldquo;desktop window&amp;rdquo; name to the program.</description></item><item><title>Project: Shantz-WP-Prefix-Suffix Updated to 1.1.0</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/20/project-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-to-110/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 04:08:17 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/20/project-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-to-110/</guid><description>Well, its not just prefix suffix any more, because I added an option to add things in the middle of the posts as well. I got this idea because people told me that this was one of the most sought after option as advertisements (e.g. google adsense, adbrite, etc) give maximum click through rate when placed smack dab in the middle of the content. What’s more is that it is configurable and you can choose how many paragraphs and/or words should be skipped from the start of the post before you add whatever you want, be it text, css, html, php or javascript.</description></item><item><title>Project: My WordPress Plugin Shantz-WP-Prefix-Suffix Updated To 1.0.5</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/31/project-my-wordpress-plugin-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-to-105/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 15:48:40 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/31/project-my-wordpress-plugin-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-to-105/</guid><description>For those who are new to this plugin, Shantz WP Prefix Suffix is a light-weight and easy to use plugin which allows you to add any text, HTML/CSS/PHP/Javascript code to your posts and/or pages as prefix and/or suffix. (That includes even any new or old posts and pages and even your feed) Examples of use cases could be to include your copyright message, advertisements (like adsense, etc), permalinks, your other site links, any other custom messages.</description></item><item><title>Project: ShantzTodayChanger Is Now Open Source’d</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/30/project-shantztodaychanger-is-now-open-sourced/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2008 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/30/project-shantztodaychanger-is-now-open-sourced/</guid><description>For those who don’t know ShantzTodayChanger is a small Windows Mobile tool that allows you to cycle through your wallpapers/themes or run applications after specified intervals of time automatically and provides you a lot of tweaking options to control this.
Sometime back I formatted my laptop which I dual booted between Windows XP and Linux (Ubuntu, if you may ask). Now I installed Hardy Heron back onto thenew system within an hour but just can’t get myself motivated to “finish” the Windows install by getting and installing all the drivers after having to sit through hours pointing, clicking and rebooting to get just the base installed.</description></item><item><title>Google Releases Android Source Code</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/21/google-releases-android-source-code/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2008 17:57:52 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/21/google-releases-android-source-code/</guid><description>FOSS (Free and Open Source Software) community rejoices today as google finally lived upto their promise of releasing the android source code. Now, the things that is left to be evaluated is that how much of it is actually true, or whether there are some binary blobs still in there. Moreover, it remains to be seen that how much this converts into a “community” project instead of being ruled by Google with an iron hand.</description></item><item><title>Project: Shantz-XwinWrap Updated to 0.02</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/18/project-shantz-xwinwrap-updated-to-002/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2008 11:03:48 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/18/project-shantz-xwinwrap-updated-to-002/</guid><description>As some of you know that I've taken up the development of the ultra-cool xwinwrap tool that allows you to use movies, screensavers etc as wallpapers for you linux desktops. Here is version 0.02 for you consumption that fixes a bug because of which the generated window was overlapping other windows.
The download file has plain executable binaries as well as deb packages for Ubuntu. Moreover, I've included both 32 bit as well as 64 bit versions.</description></item><item><title>Project: My WordPress Plugin "Shantz WP Prefix Suffix" Updated to 1.0.4</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/15/project-my-wordpress-plugin-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-to-104/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2008 12:48:42 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/15/project-my-wordpress-plugin-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-to-104/</guid><description>For those who don't know Shantz-WP-Prefix-Suffix is a WordPress plugin that allows you to add any text and/or HTML/CSS/PHP/Javascript code to the top or bottom of your posts (e.g. see my site links at top of each post and the copyright link and permalink at the bottom of each) I've updated it to version 1.0.4 which allows you to add PHP code to the top or bottom of your posts now.</description></item><item><title>Project: Shantz Pidgin Away Alerts (splert) Updated to 0.03</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/03/project-shantz-pidgin-away-alerts-splert-updated-to-003/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 21:19:08 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/03/project-shantz-pidgin-away-alerts-splert-updated-to-003/</guid><description>I updated my project splert to version 0.03 today.For those who don't know splert is a tool that lets you convert the multi-client instant messenger pidgin (connects to gtalk, msn, yahoo, jabber, etc) into a full blown answering machine and much more.
The main changes are:
Now you can use other 3rd party twitter bots with it to get updates through twitter since the official twitter bot is down since a long time and there are no chances of coming back soon.</description></item><item><title>TIP: A Post For Pidgin Plugin Developers</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/23/tip-a-post-for-pidgin-plugin-developers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 15:30:32 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/23/tip-a-post-for-pidgin-plugin-developers/</guid><description>Recently I wrote a small autoreply-answering-machine app for pidgin with a simple premise. Send custom automatic replies to different people when they message you and came across a strange bug. It never sent the reply when you received the first message from someone. I was using the &amp;ldquo;ReceivedImMessage&amp;rdquo; signal over d-bus (or &amp;ldquo;received-im-message&amp;rdquo; for the plugin writers). What I found initially looked to be a gross and basic error by pidgin developers, but later found that it is indeed a good design and thought that I'll make a post about it for the benefit of fellow pidgin plugin/app developers.</description></item><item><title>Shantz XWinWrap: The "Moving" Wallpaper Fun Continues</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/03/shantz-xwinwrap-the-moving-wallpaper-fun-continues/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 14:46:02 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/03/shantz-xwinwrap-the-moving-wallpaper-fun-continues/</guid><description>XWinWrap is a small utility written a loooong time ago that allowed you to stick most of the apps to your desktop background (Thanks to fsckin for introducing me to it). What this meant was you could use an animated screensaver (like glmatrix, electric sheep, etc) or even a movie, and use it as your wallpaper. But only one version of this app was released, and it had a few problems, like it wasn't exactly &amp;ldquo;sticking&amp;rdquo; to the background and geometry option didn't work as well.</description></item><item><title>Project: Splert - A Custom Answering Machine And More for IMs</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/18/project-splert-a-custom-answering-machine-and-more-for-ims/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 17:00:09 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/18/project-splert-a-custom-answering-machine-and-more-for-ims/</guid><description>Update Aug 25 2008: Updated to v0.02 and also added 32 bit package. Hit the link given below to download.
You must have heard of (or used) the auto-reply features given by today's instant messengers that are sent to the ones messaging you while you are not at your desk. But those are one-size-fits-all kind of messages. So, I wrote this simple tool a few months ago to turn Pidgin, everyone’s favourite multi-client Instant Messenger (works with gtalk, msn, yahoo, aim etc), into a customized answering machine (and more) when you are away from your computer.</description></item><item><title>Project: Shantz Webcam Autolocker</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/11/project-shantz-webcam-autolocker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2008 17:51:31 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/11/project-shantz-webcam-autolocker/</guid><description>Sometimes I do some things that even I can't explain why I did &amp;lsquo;em. Did this one in one of those times as well. This is a simple script to monitor motion in front of your PC, auto-lock it when you are away and auto-unlock it when you come back. Did it just because I was really bogged down by the shitload of work that I've been doing for the past few weeks (and even weekends as well), so wanted to take a break for a few minutes, and just chanced over my own &amp;ldquo;Home Security Using a Webcam and Twitter&amp;rdquo; post, so thought of doing something related to motion detection again.</description></item><item><title>Hi BIOS! My Name Is "Linux", Or Is It?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/03/hi-bios-my-name-is-linux-or-is-it/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2008 17:44:30 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/03/hi-bios-my-name-is-linux-or-is-it/</guid><description>A couple of days ago, I read this on Matthew Garrette’s blog, where he tells us about a vendor’s BIOS trying to figure out the OS type/version and setting things around on deciding the OS it is running. The call in question was _OSI(“Linux”). He goes on to say that the action the firmware takes, on finding out if the OS is linux, was probably inaccurate and it was good that linux kernel DOES NOT identify itself as “Linux” and returns false for the _OSI(“Linux”) and instead returns true when probed for Windows.</description></item><item><title>My Brief History With Computers</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/06/23/my-brief-history-with-computers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2008 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/06/23/my-brief-history-with-computers/</guid><description>I’m going to be bespectacled and have been advised to reduce and limit my computer usage considerably. A bit of nostalgia set in on hearing this and I thought about my short journey so far in this wonderland of solid-state and otherwise.
**First time I touched a computer. 1989, at school in 2nd standard
**First command I typed on a computer. “dir”, 1990, 3rd standard
**First game I played on a computer.</description></item><item><title>Want To Program Smartly In C? Use GLib</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/03/smart-programming-in-c-using-glib/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2008 15:30:16 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/03/smart-programming-in-c-using-glib/</guid><description>GLib - An Introduction:
GLib is a utility library for C, which augments the standard C library in several purposeful ways to make your life that much easier while programming. GLib has the following things to offer you:
**1. Portability: **The main issue that haunts any C developer is the portability of code. One cannot rely on the standard C library for this as you may find many functions that work differently under different platforms are aren't there at all sometimes.</description></item><item><title>Project: shantz-wp-prefix-suffix Updated to 1.0.2</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/07/project-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-to-102/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2008 03:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/07/project-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-to-102/</guid><description>Many users reported errors while activating the version 1.0.1 of my WordPress plugin shantz-wp-prefix-suffix. I tracked it down to a typo that crept into the release somehow.</description></item><item><title>Hack: Fixing The WordPress i3theme Sidebar Issue (Part II)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/06/hack-fixing-the-wordpress-i3theme-sidebar-issue-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2008 14:20:25 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/06/hack-fixing-the-wordpress-i3theme-sidebar-issue-part-ii/</guid><description>Some time back I had posted a little hack to fix an issue that users of i3theme have, i.e., their right sidebar drops to below the main content area in IE6. But it wasn't that good as it took care of only the situation when this phenomena was caused by the tag cloud widget. So, here is a little modification I did to fix the issue more properly.
Go to your wp-content/themes/folder and open the style.</description></item><item><title>HACK: Fixing The Code Syntax Highlighter WordPress Plugins To Work With WYSIWYG</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/23/hack-fixing-the-code-syntax-highlighter-wordpress-plugins-to-work-with-wysiwyg/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2008 17:18:22 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/23/hack-fixing-the-code-syntax-highlighter-wordpress-plugins-to-work-with-wysiwyg/</guid><description>There are many code syntax highlighter plugins available for WordPress (e.g. iG Syntax Highlighter, WP-Syntax, etc) but almost all of them have a problem. They want you to write the code in &amp;ldquo;HTML editing mode&amp;rdquo;. If you use any kind of WYSIWYG or visual editors (like built in TinyMCE or offline clients&amp;rsquo; similar modes), there is a grave problem. Your code becomes garbled. e.g.:
If you intend to write:
It might turn out as:</description></item><item><title>Project: Windows Mobile Tool ShantzTodayChanger Updated to version 1.53</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/22/project-windows-mobile-tool-shantztodaychanger-updated-to-version-153/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2008 20:49:17 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/22/project-windows-mobile-tool-shantztodaychanger-updated-to-version-153/</guid><description>ShantzTodayChanger is a little tool written by me for your Windows Mobile based phones (WM5/WM6) which will cycle ur today background or theme after a set interval of time. It has a lot of features and options and you can even use it to achieve something other than changing wallpapers as well (e.g. running applications at set times) but that depends on your imagination.
Changes in this version:
1.53 - 23-March-08 -&amp;gt; RECOMMENDED UPDATE</description></item><item><title>Hack: WordPress function 'wp_list_pages' to output page description (or other custom fields) in your page lists</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/19/hack-wordpress-function-wp_list_pages-to-output-page-description-or-other-custom-fields-in-your-page-lists/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2008 03:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/19/hack-wordpress-function-wp_list_pages-to-output-page-description-or-other-custom-fields-in-your-page-lists/</guid><description>Disclaimer: I'm neither a WordPress guru nor a PHP expert. This is what it is, a dirtly little hack, otherwise I'd have called it an &amp;ldquo;enhancement&amp;rdquo; Now onto the main things.
**Aim: **You would have used wp_list_pages (or plugins like dd-list-subpages, that use it) to display a list of your pages/subpages on a particular page. e.g., I use it on my &amp;ldquo;Projects&amp;rdquo; pages hierarchy to list all the relevant projects under a particular heading.</description></item><item><title>Project: Shantz Copy Basket (Compatible with linux as well as windows)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/16/project-shantz-copy-basket-compatible-with-linux-as-well-as-windows/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2008 13:26:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/16/project-shantz-copy-basket-compatible-with-linux-as-well-as-windows/</guid><description>I’m sure you have copied/moved files on your computer from one place to another. And I’m sure often you have to do more than just “single-shot” copying that is copy a few files to one place, move a few to another, and copy yet some more to one more location. Well, I had to do this quite a few times (e.g. I ran out of disk space recently on a partition and had to empty out my “Movies” and “Songs” folders to move a few movies/songs each to all other partitions/disks according to the space available).</description></item><item><title>Project: shantz-wp-qotd and shantz-wp-prefix-suffix updated</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/15/project-shantz-wp-qotd-and-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2008 17:26:52 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/15/project-shantz-wp-qotd-and-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated/</guid><description>Just some news on my WordPress plugins front. shantz-wp-qotd has been updated to version 1.2.1 and shantz-wp-prefix-suffix has been updated to 1.0.1. It is just a minor update meant for people still using a WordPress version &amp;lt; 2.1. The update makes the &amp;ldquo;page exclusion&amp;rdquo; feature of both the plugins (i.e. the option to prevent the plugins from acting on &amp;ldquo;pages&amp;rdquo;) compatible with WP &amp;lt; 2.1 as well.
Go to their respective pages for downloads:</description></item><item><title>Ubuntu TIP: Automating Package Installation – apt-get to the rescue</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/06/ubuntu-tip-automating-package-installation-apt-get-to-the-rescue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2008 03:30:20 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/06/ubuntu-tip-automating-package-installation-apt-get-to-the-rescue/</guid><description>Admin Note: Rahul is a long time friend of mine, and is a well known geek amongst his friends and colleagues. I'm happy to announce that he will be enriching this site from time-to-time as a guest editor/author. First up is a small tid-bit of a script that he wrote to ease up his life between installations and reinstallations of everyone's favourite OS: Ubuntu. Over to his post..
Have you ever had to reinstall your ubuntu installation, and then bear the pain of manually installing the applications you've come to love (i mean use :)) everyday?</description></item><item><title>Project: shantz-wp-qotd Updated and shantz-wp-prefix-suffix released</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/24/project-shantz-wp-qotd-updated-and-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-released/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2008 09:44:24 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/24/project-shantz-wp-qotd-updated-and-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-released/</guid><description>I updated my wordpress plugin shantz-wp-qotd. (A feature rich, customizable wordpress quotes plugin) today to version 1.2.0. The new version has the following changes:
Added option to exclude pages from displaying quotes
Fixed a bug that quotes source selection checkboxes always remain checked after updating settings.
Cosmetic: Fixed a few spelling mistakes :)</description></item><item><title>Project: "shantz-wp-qotd ", My Wordpress Plugin, Updated to 1.1.0</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/17/project-shantz-wp-qotd-my-wordpress-plugin-update-to-110/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2008 15:44:18 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/17/project-shantz-wp-qotd-my-wordpress-plugin-update-to-110/</guid><description>For the uninitiated:
I made a few additions / modifications to the code and the plugin has been updated to 1.1.0. The changes are:
Added Custom tag support for adding quotes anywhere in your posts/pages
Added Custom quote separator support and multi-line quotes support
Config Screenshots:
I recommend that you update to this new version asap, as apart from the above mentioned changes, the code is a bit more cleaner as well, which would run a bit better IMO and also help in any modification if you have in mind.</description></item><item><title>My First WordPress Plugin: Please Welcome shantz-wp-qotd</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/10/my-first-wordpress-plugin-please-welcome-shantz-wp-qotd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 11:00:27 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/10/my-first-wordpress-plugin-please-welcome-shantz-wp-qotd/</guid><description>Motivated by Ronald’s ultimate wordpress plugin tutorial at devlounge, I decided that the best way to learn something is to use it in a live project. Armed with my laptop and multiple flasks of coffee, the marathon began on Friday night. My only experience with web-related development so far had been around 8–10 years ago as a kid when, just like everybody else at that time, I was fascinated by HTML and did a “read-through” of HTML 4.</description></item><item><title>Site Updates: More Content For You</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/site-updates-more-content-for-you/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 19:36:42 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/site-updates-more-content-for-you/</guid><description>I've added a few new sections to the blog. Do check them out. Here is a list of the new sections along with their descriptions.
[Projects]: Although I wouldn't put myself in the category of an excellent developer but I can sure type in a few lines that can compile without an error and also manage to carry out a task or two. So, this page will list some of those little things that I write to weed out a few niggles or scratch a few itches of mine.</description></item></channel></rss>