<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SpiderOak on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/spideroak/</link><description>Recent content in SpiderOak on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 14:26:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/spideroak/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dropbox Online Storage Public/Shared Folders: A Word Of Caution</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/16/dropbox-online-storage-publicshared-folders-a-word-of-caution/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 14:26:50 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/16/dropbox-online-storage-publicshared-folders-a-word-of-caution/</guid><description>Update: In a thread about this post at Dropbox forums, it was brought to my notice that Dropbox has now changed its terms to remove the objectionable clause.
If you use dropbox (A popular online storage service with free 2 GB space), and use (or intend to use) its public or shared folders feature, then you must know something about the EULA (End Users&amp;rsquo; LIcense Agreement). Yes, the one that you clicked &amp;ldquo;I Agree&amp;rdquo; on, without even reading one word of.</description></item><item><title>SpiderOak Promotion Code For Free Upgrade To 10 GB</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/12/spideroak-promotion-code-for-free-upgrade-to-10-gb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2008 20:58:32 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/12/spideroak-promotion-code-for-free-upgrade-to-10-gb/</guid><description>Just a small shout out to let you guys know that you can use the discount coupon code “linkup” while signing up the excellent online backup service SpiderOak to get a major bump to 10 GB from the 2 GB that they give to normal accounts.
For those who don’t know SpiderOak is a great online data backup service, with its major strengths being truly cross paltform (Mac/Linux/Windows – 32 bit as well as 64 bit), easy interface, rsync like differential backups to save time and disk space, versioned file history, web as well as client interface, unlimited number of devices, unlimited bandwidth, etc etc.</description></item></channel></rss>