<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pandora Stops on Sleep Android on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/pandora-stops-on-sleep-android/</link><description>Recent content in Pandora Stops on Sleep Android on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2010 16:58:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/pandora-stops-on-sleep-android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Android App Wi-Fi Keep Alive updated to 1.4.1</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/22/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive-updated-1-4-0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2010 16:58:07 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/22/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive-updated-1-4-0/</guid><description>Update: Made a minor update for a small bug that can make wi-fi keep reconnecting in quick succession.
Pushed out a new update to my Android App Wi-Fi Keep Alive today. This update brings in another work around for the issue where the wi-fi is alive on the phone and it is also connected to the network but is somehow unable to send/receive any packets to the network. The new work around will automatically re-associate your phone with the wi-fi router if it detects such a situation.</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update:&lt;/strong> Made a minor update for a small bug that can make wi-fi keep reconnecting in quick succession.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pushed out a new update to my Android App Wi-Fi Keep Alive today. This update brings in another work around for the issue where the wi-fi is alive on the phone and it is also connected to the network but is somehow unable to send/receive any packets to the network. The new work around will automatically re-associate your phone with the wi-fi router if it detects such a situation. This seems to make it work properly again for sometime. When it fails again, the workaround kicks in automatically again. This is not an ideal &amp;ldquo;fix&amp;rdquo; as such because streaming apps like Pandora radio etc might have a hiccup because of this but it is unavoidable as of now and atleast the notifications for mails and other things etc will work fine because this state stops even the mobile data network from taking over since the phone perceives that wi-fi is connected but is not working actually.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other things include support for small screen devices like Xperia X10 mini, some optimizations for size and speed, some icon sizes and UI tweaks for compatibility with different screen sizes and android versions. Please try it out from the market as usual and let me know how it goes.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>