<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>android programming on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/android-programming/</link><description>Recent content in android programming on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2010 19:44:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/android-programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Solving The Android Permissions And Malware Puzzle</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/13/android-permissions-malware/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2010 19:44:59 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/13/android-permissions-malware/</guid><description>There has been a spate of security reports recently about Android apps being malware or suspicious. Most of these were found baseless but at least one was indeed correct (e.g. The Russian Trojan app). We also know that Android has a very good security model but even then, the rest of the reports also makes one think and focus on why an apps requires the permissions that it states it needs?</description></item><item><title>Android Dev Tip: App Not Showing on X10 Mini Marketplace</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/07/android-dev-tip-app-not-showing-on-x10-mini-marketplace/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2010 21:18:06 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/07/android-dev-tip-app-not-showing-on-x10-mini-marketplace/</guid><description>Many Android Developers (and users) get confused that why a certain app isn&amp;rsquo;t showing up on the new Xperia X10 Mini (and few other) phones. This happens even if they support all android versions and have published their apps for all countries, so that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the issue. I came across this as well when few people mentioned that they couldn&amp;rsquo;t find my app Wi-Fi Keep Alive in the X10 mini marketplace.</description></item><item><title>How To Debug Android Widgets</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/13/how-to-debug-android-widgets/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 18:42:42 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/13/how-to-debug-android-widgets/</guid><description>For most new android app developers (like me), it is a bit puzzling how to debug the android widgets or how to put a breakpoint in an android widget code. For normal applications, it is quite simple as when you press &amp;ldquo;debug&amp;rdquo; on the eclipse toolbar, it launches the emulator (or connects to existing emulator/device), syncs your application and launches its main activity and puts the control in your hands if you have put a breakpoint.</description></item></channel></rss>