<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Wordpress Blog on</title><link>/tags/wordpress-blog/</link><description>Recent content in Wordpress Blog on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2008 15:44:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/wordpress-blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Project: "shantz-wp-qotd ", My Wordpress Plugin, Updated to 1.1.0</title><link>/posts/project-shantz-wp-qotd-my-wordpress-plugin-update-to-110/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2008 15:44:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/project-shantz-wp-qotd-my-wordpress-plugin-update-to-110/</guid><description>For the uninitiated:
I made a few additions / modifications to the code and the plugin has been updated to 1.1.0. The changes are:
Added Custom tag support for adding quotes anywhere in your posts/pages
Added Custom quote separator support and multi-line quotes support
Config Screenshots:
I recommend that you update to this new version asap, as apart from the above mentioned changes, the code is a bit more cleaner as well, which would run a bit better IMO and also help in any modification if you have in mind.</description></item><item><title>Shantz WordPress QOTD</title><link>/posts/shantz-wordpress-qotd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 10:22:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/shantz-wordpress-qotd/</guid><description>Shantz WP QOTD is a plugin to add quotes to your wordpress blog in a few easy clicks. It adds quotes to your posts and your sidebars with a multitude of options for sources and customization.
== Description ==
There are many quotes plugins out there. This one has been started with a view to have the best of features and options, ease of use and multiple sources to get the quotes from.</description></item><item><title>Tips: Configure FTP upload support for wordpress in Blogjet</title><link>/posts/tips-configure-ftp-upload-support-for-wordpress-in-blogjet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2008 14:36:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/tips-configure-ftp-upload-support-for-wordpress-in-blogjet/</guid><description>A few days ago, I had written about a wonderful blogging tool Blogjet. Now, if you host a wordpress blog, you’d be aware of the fact that for wordpress to be able to upload yor files (images, attachements in post etc) to the server, you have to make the upload directory writable by all. Now, this is a BIG security risk. Some people go to the lengths of CHMOD’ding their upload directory for a short while and after upload, restoring the apt file permissions back.</description></item></channel></rss>