<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tasker on</title><link>/tags/tasker/</link><description>Recent content in Tasker on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 09:03:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/tasker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Tasker Night Mode Profile For Android</title><link>/2012/10/17/my-tasker-night-mode-profile-for-android/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 09:03:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2012/10/17/my-tasker-night-mode-profile-for-android/</guid><description>If there are two things that irritate me the most when I go to sleep, they are: Sync notifications going off and battery drained off in the morning (worst case being drained off before alarm time, making me late for work). I used to have a simple profile that turned off auto sync between 11 PM to 7 AM but it didn&amp;rsquo;t always work well because I work past 11 quite a lot and don&amp;rsquo;t usually have a fixed sleep time.</description><content>&lt;p>If there are two things that irritate me the most when I go to sleep, they are: Sync notifications going off and battery drained off in the morning (worst case being drained off before alarm time, making me late for work). I used to have a simple profile that turned off auto sync between 11 PM to 7 AM but it didn&amp;rsquo;t always work well because I work past 11 quite a lot and don&amp;rsquo;t usually have a fixed sleep time. Similarly I get up at different times. Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;m not even home and still the profile runs, making me lose sync.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(For the impatient, if you want to use it, I&amp;rsquo;ve uploaded my profiles to &lt;a href="https://github.com/shantanugoel/tasker">my github account&lt;/a>.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, I set up and quick and simple but much better working night mode profile. It consists 3 different profiles actually as listed below:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Night Mode -&amp;gt; This actually turns on the night mode based on a host of different combinations listed later in the post.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Alarm Detection -&amp;gt; Detects when the alarm goes off&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Unlock Detection -&amp;gt; Detects when the phone display is unlocked.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Home Detection -&amp;gt; Detects if I&amp;rsquo;m at home&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The basic premise behind this night mode setup is:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The phone should detect that I&amp;rsquo;m sleeping by taking a combination of following scenarios:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The location should be at home (Done by home detection profile using &amp;ldquo;Cell Near&amp;rdquo;. I use this mostly because it is more accurate than network location and works indoors as well which GPS doesn&amp;rsquo;t do and is very light on battery as well)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Time should be between 11 PM to 7 AM (my likely sleep time)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Display should not have been unlocked in the last 30 minutes (i.e. make sure I&amp;rsquo;m not actively using the phone)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s dark in the room (Make sure that lights are turned off. Need to turn on ambient light sensor to work with screen off in tasker settings for this)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Once all the above conditions are established, my phone is fairly certain by now that I&amp;rsquo;m indeed sleeping :) and turns off auto sync&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The night mode still has to check whether the conditions still exist after every half hour or so (e.g. I might not be sleeping yet but lights turned off to allow my wife to sleep and I didn&amp;rsquo;t fiddle with the phone for some time)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If I unlock the phone any time at night, it should tell my phone immediately that I&amp;rsquo;m not sleeping and it deactivates the night mode (for the next 30 minutes or so when night mode check kicks in again)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When the alarm goes off, night mode should be stopped since I&amp;rsquo;m obviously awake now&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>There are quite a few other checks and balances incorporated to make sure all these 4 profiles don&amp;rsquo;t go out of sync and also do as less as possible to preserve battery.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Tested this setup for past few weeks and it works pretty well. If you want to use it, I&amp;rsquo;ve uploaded my profiles to &lt;a href="https://github.com/shantanugoel/tasker">my github account&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Improvements/Changes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Exchange sync still bypasses the auto sync turn off settings. So need to either buy &amp;ldquo;Synker&amp;rdquo; to control exchange sync directly or figure out a way to connect droidwall to tasker to cut the internet connection for exchange app.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The home mode xml in the account does not have anything in cell tower locations ;), so you need to open it in tasker and scan for your own cell towers&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>I just turn off auto sync for me in night mode (want to receive sounds for other notifications, texts etc), you can edit the profile to suit your other needs&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can change the timings as well as per your needs&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>I have some prints done to a file in these profiles, mainly for debugging. You can remove those once you are certain the setup works well for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Let me know if you can think of any other ways to make this more robust. I&amp;rsquo;ll post the rest of my tasker profiles as well soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item><item><title>Setup Call Recording With Android App Tasker On Nexus One</title><link>/2010/09/24/setup-call-recording-android-app-tasker-nexus-one/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2010 10:01:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/09/24/setup-call-recording-android-app-tasker-nexus-one/</guid><description>I wanted to record calls on my Android phone (Nexus one). The easy way would have been to download an app but I like tinkering. And given that I recently bought Tasker, android’s very own swiss knife, I thought I should give it a run. After just an hour I was able to create my very own call recorder (some time went into trial and error with things as this was my first major task with tasker and also some things didn’t work with nexus one, which I will note below).</description><content>&lt;p>I wanted to record calls on my Android phone (Nexus one). The easy way would have been to download an app but I like tinkering. And given that I recently bought &lt;a href="http://tasker.dinglisch.net/">Tasker&lt;/a>, android’s very own swiss knife, I thought I should give it a run. After just an hour I was able to create my very own call recorder (some time went into trial and error with things as this was my first major task with tasker and also some things didn’t work with nexus one, which I will note below). I’ll outline the process to set it up here in as much detail as possible and will also provide the profiles. Please note that I made this setup for nexus one but it should work on pretty much any android phone and, in fact, it might work even better on your phone by making a few tweaks that I will outline as Nexus one doesn’t allow jacking into the call streams directly but your phone might.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, let’s begin. My visioned scenario is like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you start a call (incoming or outgoing), i.e., when both the parties have picked up the phone, a notification should appear in the status bar.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Clicking on this notification should start recording the call. It should also give way to another notification now.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>This new notification should stop the call recording when clicked.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you don’t stop the call recording, the recording should automatically stop when the call ends.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>To achieve the steps mentioned above, you will have to create “4” profiles in tasker. The xml files for these profiles are provided in a zip at the end of this article that you can download and import into tasker directly. If you want to understand more about whats going on, here are the details of each profile so that you can understand and modify them according to your needs. These profiles are:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Profile 1. Call Started&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tasker description:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Profile: Call started
Event: Phone Offhook
Enter: 11
Execute, Abort New Task
A0: Variable Clear [ Name:%RECORDING ]
A1: Notify [ Title:Record Call Text: Icon: Number: Permanent: ]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Notes:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>None&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Profile 2. Record Call&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tasker description:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Profile: Record call
Event: Notification Click
Enter: Record Call
Execute, Abort New Task
A0: Notify Cancel [ Title:Record Call Warn Not Exist: ]
A1: Variable Set [ Name:%RECORDING To:1 Do Maths: Append: ]
A2: In-Call Volume [ Level:5 Display: Sound: ]
A3: Speakerphone [ Set:On ]
A4: Flash [ Text:Started Recording Long: ]
A5: Notify [ Title:Stop Record Call Text: Icon: Number: Permanent: ]
A6: Record Audio [ File:shantz/call-%CNUM-%CDATE-%CTIME Source:Microphone MaxSize: ]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Notes: **&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note the steps A2, A3 and A6. Basically Nexus one has a limitation that you cannot record directly from the call streams. So, I’m doing the recording from the microphone and this works best if the phone is in speakerphone mode. So, I’m turning up the call volume and setting speakerphone mode in A2 and A3 respectively. You can try tweaking these 2 steps (having different call volumes and not engaging speakerphone mode and you might have passable results without doing these as well). Also, try using “Call”, “Incoming Call”, “Outgoing Call” etc as sources in step A6 instead of microphone to check if your phone supports direct call stream recording. If it does, then you will have excellent recording quality and you can also remove steps A2 and A3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Profile 3. Stop Record Call&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tasker description:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Profile: Stop record call
Event: Notification Click
Enter: Stop Record Call
Execute, Abort New Task
A0: Record Audio Stop [ ]
A1: Notify Cancel [ Title:Record Call Warn Not Exist: ]
A2: Notify Cancel [ Title:Stop Record Call Warn Not Exist: ]
A3: Flash [ Text:Stopped Recording Long: ]
A4: Variable Clear [ Name:%RECORDING ]
A5: Speakerphone [ Set:Off ]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Notes: **&lt;/p>
&lt;p>None&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Profile 4. Call Complete&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tasker description:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Profile: Call complete
Event: Phone Idle
Enter: Stop Record Call
Execute, Abort New Task
A0: Record Audio Stop [ ]
A1: Notify Cancel [ Title:Record Call Warn Not Exist: ]
A2: Notify Cancel [ Title:Stop Record Call Warn Not Exist: ]
A3: Flash [ Text:Stopped Recording Long: ]
A4: Variable Clear [ Name:%RECORDING ]
A5: Speakerphone [ Set:Off ]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Notes: **&lt;/p>
&lt;p>None&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://tech.shantanugoel.com/resources/downloads/android-tasker-call-record-profiles.zip">Download: Android Tasker Call Record Profiles&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And we are done, you can download the profile xml files in the zip file linked here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me know if you need any clarifications on the above steps. I would also love to get your suggestions to make this better or if you have any of your own tasker tips and tricks. I’ll be posting more of my tasker adventures soon :)&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>