<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Wysiwyg on</title><link>/tags/wysiwyg/</link><description>Recent content in Wysiwyg on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2008 17:18:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/wysiwyg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HACK: Fixing The Code Syntax Highlighter WordPress Plugins To Work With WYSIWYG</title><link>/2008/03/23/hack-fixing-the-code-syntax-highlighter-wordpress-plugins-to-work-with-wysiwyg/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2008 17:18:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/03/23/hack-fixing-the-code-syntax-highlighter-wordpress-plugins-to-work-with-wysiwyg/</guid><description>There are many code syntax highlighter plugins available for WordPress (e.g. iG Syntax Highlighter, WP-Syntax, etc) but almost all of them have a problem. They want you to write the code in &amp;ldquo;HTML editing mode&amp;rdquo;. If you use any kind of WYSIWYG or visual editors (like built in TinyMCE or offline clients&amp;rsquo; similar modes), there is a grave problem. Your code becomes garbled. e.g.:
If you intend to write:
It might turn out as:</description><content>&lt;p>There are many code syntax highlighter plugins available for WordPress (e.g. iG Syntax Highlighter, WP-Syntax, etc) but almost all of them have a problem. They want you to write the code in &amp;ldquo;HTML editing mode&amp;rdquo;. If you use any kind of WYSIWYG or visual editors (like built in TinyMCE or offline clients&amp;rsquo; similar modes), there is a grave problem. Your code becomes garbled. e.g.:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you intend to write:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>It might turn out as:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>blockquote&amp;gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> cat abc &amp;gt; /dev/null&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The issue here is that the code highlighting plugins use the &amp;ldquo;exact&amp;rdquo; text entered within the [ code ] (or similar) tags, and since we used the WYSIWYG/visual editors, they add html formatting tags to the code and also convert some special characters into HTML entities (e.g. &amp;gt; into &amp;gt;, &amp;lt; into &amp;lt;, white space into  , etc).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The workaround is that you can write the code in html editing mode. But the problem here is that if you happen to switch to the visual mode or edit your post in this mode any time later, the problem will come back which makes editing posts a pain. So, here is a simple hack that will let you write your code in visual/WYSIWYG mode without doing anything special.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Note: **Although this hack is for &lt;a href="http://blog.igeek.info/still-fresh/2006/02/25/code-for-fun/">iG:Synatx Highlighter&lt;/a> plugin, but it can be added similarly to other plugins as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Step 1) Open the file syntax_hilite.php.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Step 2) Go to line no. 191 and delete the following 3 lines:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Step 3) At the same place (from where you deleted the lines), add the following lines:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Step 4) Save the file. That&amp;rsquo;s it. You&amp;rsquo;re done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What we just did was strip out all the extraneous html formatting added by your editor and then convert the html entities into the characters that we want.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**IMPORTANT: **After this hack, you should write your code in visual mode. If you want to display some html code to your readers and write it in html mode of the editor then it might go boink. Otherwise it should be simple enough to create a new tag so that one set html editor code works and for another set, visual editor code works. But I would definitely recommend against it and anyways writing all code in visual mode, just like your other parts of your posts as its much more intuitive to write and easier to maintain and port to newer platforms.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>BlogJet - Blog Faster, Blog Better (Now In Linux too, with a hidden bonus)</title><link>/2008/01/29/blogjet-blog-faster-blog-better-now-in-linux-too-with-a-hidden-bonus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2008 15:30:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/01/29/blogjet-blog-faster-blog-better-now-in-linux-too-with-a-hidden-bonus/</guid><description>A quick googling for best desktop blogging client would yield just a few (read millions/gazillions) results. Having researched the subject a lot, my choices were finally limited down to BlogJet and BlogDesk, as per my feature set requirement goes (Primarily, off line editing, draft, WYSIWYG editing, categories, tagging support, pinging, trackbacks support, timestamping, past post editing, automatic image uploading) BUT there is one little problem. Both of these don’t work on Linux.</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;a href="/img/uploads/blogjet_in_linux.png">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/img/uploads/blogjet_in_linux.png">&lt;img src="/img/uploads/blogjet_in_linux_thumb1.jpg" alt="Blogjet_in_linux">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A quick googling for &lt;em>&lt;a href="http://www.google.co.in/search?q=best+desktop+blogging+client&amp;amp;ie=utf-8&amp;amp;oe=utf-8&amp;amp;aq=t&amp;amp;rls=com.ubuntu:en-US:official&amp;amp;client=firefox-a">best desktop blogging client&lt;/a>&lt;/em> would yield just a few (read millions/gazillions) results. Having researched the subject a lot, my choices were finally limited down to &lt;a href="http://www.codingrobots.com/blogjet/">BlogJet&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.blogdesk.org/en/index.htm">BlogDesk&lt;/a>, as per my feature set requirement goes (Primarily, off line editing, draft, WYSIWYG editing, categories, tagging support, pinging, trackbacks support, timestamping, past post editing, automatic image uploading) BUT there is one little problem. Both of these don’t work on Linux.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>In fact, the current crop of Linux based blog clients is at best childish, compared to these. A piece of software called &lt;a href="http://www.larryborsato.com/bleezer/">Bleezer&lt;/a> did offer a good set of features and supported linux as well, but turned out it was so crash-y, hogged up enormous amounts of ram, and had other issues that come usually packed with all java apps. But I wasn’t gonna boot into WinDUHs, just for one sole software, was I?? Sure, I wasn’t &lt;img src="/img/uploads/smile1.gif" alt="">. I tried the usual routine of trying to run them through wine but it wasn’t supported. I resorted to my faithful ol’ google, and chanced across &lt;a href="http://www.thetechandcents.com/2007/11/running-zoundry-blog-editor-under-wine.html">this little nugget&lt;/a>, with step by step instructions to achieve my goal. And it had a bonus. It told me about &lt;a href="http://www.tatanka.com.br/ies4linux/page/Main_Page">IEs4Linux&lt;/a> (IE’s For Linux). yes, you read correctly. You can run Internet Explorer on your Linux box as well. All this in under 10 minutes (Ubuntu wins again). And yeah, don’t forget to say thanks to me (and &lt;a href="http://www.thetechandcents.com/2007/11/running-zoundry-blog-editor-under-wine.html">Alex&lt;/a> as well).&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>