<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>wysiwyg on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/wysiwyg/</link><description>Recent content in wysiwyg on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2008 17:18:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/wysiwyg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HACK: Fixing The Code Syntax Highlighter WordPress Plugins To Work With WYSIWYG</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/23/hack-fixing-the-code-syntax-highlighter-wordpress-plugins-to-work-with-wysiwyg/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2008 17:18:22 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/23/hack-fixing-the-code-syntax-highlighter-wordpress-plugins-to-work-with-wysiwyg/</guid><description>There are many code syntax highlighter plugins available for WordPress (e.g. iG Syntax Highlighter, WP-Syntax, etc) but almost all of them have a problem. They want you to write the code in &amp;ldquo;HTML editing mode&amp;rdquo;. If you use any kind of WYSIWYG or visual editors (like built in TinyMCE or offline clients&amp;rsquo; similar modes), there is a grave problem. Your code becomes garbled. e.g.:
If you intend to write:
It might turn out as:</description></item><item><title>BlogJet - Blog Faster, Blog Better (Now In Linux too, with a hidden bonus)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/29/blogjet-blog-faster-blog-better-now-in-linux-too-with-a-hidden-bonus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2008 15:30:27 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/29/blogjet-blog-faster-blog-better-now-in-linux-too-with-a-hidden-bonus/</guid><description>A quick googling for best desktop blogging client would yield just a few (read millions/gazillions) results. Having researched the subject a lot, my choices were finally limited down to BlogJet and BlogDesk, as per my feature set requirement goes (Primarily, off line editing, draft, WYSIWYG editing, categories, tagging support, pinging, trackbacks support, timestamping, past post editing, automatic image uploading) BUT there is one little problem. Both of these don’t work on Linux.</description></item></channel></rss>