<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Debian on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/debian/</link><description>Recent content in Debian on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2009 18:30:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/debian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Project: Shantz XWinWrap Update to 0.3</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/16/project-shantz-xwinwrap-update-to-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2009 18:30:03 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/16/project-shantz-xwinwrap-update-to-03/</guid><description>Here is another update for the fans of XWinWrap, the tiny program that allows you to run animated wallpapers on your system. You could use screensavers, movies and what not as your desktop background. This update fixes a segfault that many users were facing, a new debug option to print some debug mesages to get some info if it is not working for you and a new hack option for giving a &amp;ldquo;desktop window&amp;rdquo; name to the program.</description><content>&lt;p>Here is another update for the fans of XWinWrap, the tiny program that allows you to run animated wallpapers on your system. You could use screensavers, movies and what not as your desktop background. This update fixes a segfault that many users were facing, a new debug option to print some debug mesages to get some info if it is not working for you and a new hack option for giving a &amp;ldquo;desktop window&amp;rdquo; name to the program. On many systems, the desktop is drawn by another program. e.g. in Ubuntu with Gnome environment, the desktop is managed by Nautilus, which creates a special window called &amp;ldquo;Desktop&amp;rdquo; and places it over your real desktop. This window name can be different in different systems. To find out what is yours, just run &amp;ldquo;xwininfo&amp;rdquo; in a terminal. Your cursor will become a &amp;ldquo;+&amp;rdquo; sign. Click anywhere on an empty area on your desktop, which will give you the window name of the transparent window, if any, that is covering your desktop. Pass this info to xwinwrap using the option &amp;ldquo;-d windowname&amp;rdquo; and it would help it to run better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As usual, 32 bit as well as 64 bit binary files are available as downloads. For users of Debian and derived operating systems (like Ubuntu, Mepis, etc), deb packages are also included for both architectures for easy installation. Source code is also available, of course.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Project: Shantz Pidgin Away Alerts (splert) Updated to 0.03</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/03/project-shantz-pidgin-away-alerts-splert-updated-to-003/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 21:19:08 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/03/project-shantz-pidgin-away-alerts-splert-updated-to-003/</guid><description>I updated my project splert to version 0.03 today.For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know splert is a tool that lets you convert the multi-client instant messenger pidgin (connects to gtalk, msn, yahoo, jabber, etc) into a full blown answering machine and much more.
The main changes are:
Now you can use other 3rd party twitter bots with it to get updates through twitter since the official twitter bot is down since a long time and there are no chances of coming back soon.</description><content>&lt;p>I updated my project splert to version 0.03 today.For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know splert is a tool that lets you convert the multi-client instant messenger pidgin (connects to gtalk, msn, yahoo, jabber, etc) into a full blown answering machine and much more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main changes are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Now you can use other 3rd party twitter bots with it to get updates through twitter since the official twitter bot is down since a long time and there are no chances of coming back soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can also use it even when you are not &amp;ldquo;away&amp;rdquo; by specifying the status when you want it to work. (e.g. any, available, unavailable, invisible, etc. Use splert -h to see all available status types). As an example, you can use this to selectively talk to people when you are busy.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>(As usual, binary files as well as 32 bit and 64 bit ubuntu/debian deb packages are available)&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>