<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Asus WL-500W Hacks on</title><link>/tags/asus-wl-500w-hacks/</link><description>Recent content in Asus WL-500W Hacks on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 12:16:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/asus-wl-500w-hacks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cannot Change Channel Problem With Asus WL-500W</title><link>/2010/07/13/cannot-change-channel-problem-with-asus-wl-500w/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 12:16:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/07/13/cannot-change-channel-problem-with-asus-wl-500w/</guid><description>Recently I found an issue with my asus wl-500w wi-fi router that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to change the channel on which it was transmitting. I moved to a new location which was totally jam-packed with other wi-fi networks using same channel as mine which was hampeing my connection. I tried for umpteen number of times. Changing the channel through the web configuration did not give any error but I found that it was still transmitting at channel 1.</description><content>&lt;p>Recently I found an issue with my asus wl-500w wi-fi router that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to change the channel on which it was transmitting. I moved to a new location which was totally jam-packed with other wi-fi networks using same channel as mine which was hampeing my connection. I tried for umpteen number of times. Changing the channel through the web configuration did not give any error but I found that it was still transmitting at channel 1. I confirmed by checking on the &amp;ldquo;Status &amp;amp; Log&amp;rdquo; page, checking the logs, and running &amp;ldquo;wl status&amp;rdquo; command through ssh and they all confirmed that it was transmitting at channel 1 only, no matter what I set it to in the configuration. I even opened an issue in the firmware project for the custom firmware (by oleg and lly) that I am using but they weren&amp;rsquo;t able to help me as the wi-fi drivers are binary only.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But by sheer chance, I stumbled upon the solution finally by trial and error. The solution is that you should set the &amp;ldquo;Bandwidth&amp;rdquo; to 20 MHz in wi-fi configuration if you are using 802.11 G. If you set it to 40 MHz then it gets stuck somehow but as soon as I changed it to 20 MHz, I was able to see the channel change immediately after reboot. Here is the screenshot of the page where you can find this setting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/img/uploads/asus-wl-500-w-change-channel.jpg">&lt;img src="/img/uploads/asus-wl-500-w-change-channel-thumb.jpg" alt="">&lt;/a>&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>[TIP] Asus WL-500W Hacks:How To Reset Web Admin Password</title><link>/2009/01/23/tip-asus-wl-500w-hackshow-to-reset-web-admin-password/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2009 22:41:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/01/23/tip-asus-wl-500w-hackshow-to-reset-web-admin-password/</guid><description>Most of you must be knowing by now that I bought the amazing Asus WL-500W router a few days back. This router builds on the great lineage it has in its predecessors, the WL-500g, WL-500g Deluxe, WL-500gP, WL-500gP v2 etc, and shines ahead with being much more than a router, rather a complete headless linux PC. Anyways, to the point. In most routers/modems, if you forget the password to your web-administration gui (which generally resides as 192.</description><content>&lt;p>Most of you must be knowing by now that I bought the amazing Asus WL-500W router a few days back. This router builds on the great lineage it has in its predecessors, the WL-500g, WL-500g Deluxe, WL-500gP, WL-500gP v2 etc, and shines ahead with being much more than a router, rather a complete headless linux PC. Anyways, to the point. In most routers/modems, if you forget the password to your web-administration gui (which generally resides as 192.168.1.1), the only option left is to reset the router, thereby losing all your settings etc. But not so with this little beast. If you remember your ssh password (which BTW is available if you have installed a custom firmware on our router), then you can just login through it to your router and execute the following commands to save your skin:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>nvram get http_passwd&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This will display the current web administration password.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>nvram set http_passwd=&amp;quot;NewPasswd&amp;quot;&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This will set the new password. But remember that you have to enter another command (given below) to make sure that your new password is saved.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>nvram commit&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, just reboot and enjoy :)&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>