<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Internet Explorer on</title><link>/tags/internet-explorer/</link><description>Recent content in Internet Explorer on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2010 19:48:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/internet-explorer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Real Threat Of Windows Phone 7</title><link>/2010/10/28/the-real-threat-of-windows-phone-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2010 19:48:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/10/28/the-real-threat-of-windows-phone-7/</guid><description>Many people say that Windows Phone 7 is a threat to iPhone because they are bringing in a super platform with a choice of multiple designs and multiple carriers with great Enterprise and gaming support and maintaining the lucrative integration that iPhone provides. Many also say that Windows Phone 7 is a threat to Android because it solves the problem of Apple&amp;rsquo;s draconian policies, gives choice to customers and all this without fragmenting the OS all over the place.</description><content>&lt;p>Many people say that Windows Phone 7 is a threat to iPhone because they are bringing in a super platform with a choice of multiple designs and multiple carriers with great Enterprise and gaming support and maintaining the lucrative integration that iPhone provides. Many also say that Windows Phone 7 is a threat to Android because it solves the problem of Apple&amp;rsquo;s draconian policies, gives choice to customers and all this without fragmenting the OS all over the place.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, I beg to differ. Windows Phone 7 is a threat to the world wide web and web apps. It plans to help the developers and users by going one up on fragmentation of Android but in the process will fragment the web app world itself. This is because the browser in WP7 is based on Internet Explorer 7. Yes, not IE 9, not IE8, but IE7, which is already four years old now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right now, if you have to do a web app, you can do it in HTML5, CSS3 etc and assume that it will work over most mobile handsets out there. Enter WP7 with its archaic browser and the developer has one more headache to solve. His app will be, in most cases, incompatible with the &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; platform and so he will have to code another version that works on IE7 as well. This will not only result in wasted time and effort but in fact, the developer may even have to hold back on features that might not work well on this ugly duckling which will hold the whole pack down for God knows how much more time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, there it is. If the Android fragmentation reports are true, you can just buy another handset like an iPhone but this comeback-from-the-grave monster will fragment the mobile web app world itself so that you won&amp;rsquo;t have any reprieve whichever phone you buy. So, I appeal to you. If you want a better mobile future, talk about it, write about it and let Microsoft know that it can and must do better.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Hack: Fixing The WordPress i3theme Sidebar Issue (Part II)</title><link>/2008/04/06/hack-fixing-the-wordpress-i3theme-sidebar-issue-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2008 14:20:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/04/06/hack-fixing-the-wordpress-i3theme-sidebar-issue-part-ii/</guid><description>Some time back I had posted a little hack to fix an issue that users of i3theme have, i.e., their right sidebar drops to below the main content area in IE6. But it wasn&amp;rsquo;t that good as it took care of only the situation when this phenomena was caused by the tag cloud widget. So, here is a little modification I did to fix the issue more properly.
Go to your wp-content/themes/ folder and open the style.</description><content>&lt;p>Some time back I had &lt;a href="/2008/02/04/hack-wordpress-i3theme-ie6-sidebar-problem-solved.html">posted a little hack&lt;/a> to fix an issue that users of &lt;a href="http://www.mangoorange.com/2008/02/10/i3theme-16-is-finally-here-and-more/">i3theme&lt;/a> have, i.e., their right sidebar drops to below the main content area in IE6. But it wasn&amp;rsquo;t that good as it took care of only the situation when this phenomena was caused by the tag cloud widget. So, here is a little modification I did to fix the issue more properly.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Go to your wp-content/themes/&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> folder and open the style.css file in your favourite text editor.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Search for &amp;ldquo;#sidebar&amp;rdquo; (without the quotes) until you reach the following code:&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>#sidebar-right,
#sidebar-left {
width: 210px;
color: #666666;
line-height: 160%;
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>Now, modify this code to look like:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>#sidebar-right,
#sidebar-left {
width: 210px;
color: #666666;
line-height: 160%;
word-wrap: break-word;
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;ol start="4">
&lt;li>That&amp;rsquo;s it. Save your file and you are done.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>So what does it do? Basically I just added an attribute &amp;ldquo;word-wrap: break-word&amp;rdquo; to the sidebar handling. So, if there is a word that cannot fit in the sidebar width, the word will be broken to continue in the next line and thus the sidebar alignment will remain intact. let me know if you face any issues with this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note&lt;/strong> that this particular word-wrap property is Internet Explorer specific. Firefox (and other browsers) will ignore it, but since the problem with sidebar alignment occurs only with IE, so it will enable IE to display your site properly.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>BlogJet - Blog Faster, Blog Better (Now In Linux too, with a hidden bonus)</title><link>/2008/01/29/blogjet-blog-faster-blog-better-now-in-linux-too-with-a-hidden-bonus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2008 15:30:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/01/29/blogjet-blog-faster-blog-better-now-in-linux-too-with-a-hidden-bonus/</guid><description>A quick googling for best desktop blogging client would yield just a few (read millions/gazillions) results. Having researched the subject a lot, my choices were finally limited down to BlogJet and BlogDesk, as per my feature set requirement goes (Primarily, off line editing, draft, WYSIWYG editing, categories, tagging support, pinging, trackbacks support, timestamping, past post editing, automatic image uploading) BUT there is one little problem. Both of these don’t work on Linux.</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;a href="/img/uploads/blogjet_in_linux.png">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/img/uploads/blogjet_in_linux.png">&lt;img src="/img/uploads/blogjet_in_linux_thumb1.jpg" alt="Blogjet_in_linux">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A quick googling for &lt;em>&lt;a href="http://www.google.co.in/search?q=best+desktop+blogging+client&amp;amp;ie=utf-8&amp;amp;oe=utf-8&amp;amp;aq=t&amp;amp;rls=com.ubuntu:en-US:official&amp;amp;client=firefox-a">best desktop blogging client&lt;/a>&lt;/em> would yield just a few (read millions/gazillions) results. Having researched the subject a lot, my choices were finally limited down to &lt;a href="http://www.codingrobots.com/blogjet/">BlogJet&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.blogdesk.org/en/index.htm">BlogDesk&lt;/a>, as per my feature set requirement goes (Primarily, off line editing, draft, WYSIWYG editing, categories, tagging support, pinging, trackbacks support, timestamping, past post editing, automatic image uploading) BUT there is one little problem. Both of these don’t work on Linux.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>In fact, the current crop of Linux based blog clients is at best childish, compared to these. A piece of software called &lt;a href="http://www.larryborsato.com/bleezer/">Bleezer&lt;/a> did offer a good set of features and supported linux as well, but turned out it was so crash-y, hogged up enormous amounts of ram, and had other issues that come usually packed with all java apps. But I wasn’t gonna boot into WinDUHs, just for one sole software, was I?? Sure, I wasn’t &lt;img src="/img/uploads/smile1.gif" alt="">. I tried the usual routine of trying to run them through wine but it wasn’t supported. I resorted to my faithful ol’ google, and chanced across &lt;a href="http://www.thetechandcents.com/2007/11/running-zoundry-blog-editor-under-wine.html">this little nugget&lt;/a>, with step by step instructions to achieve my goal. And it had a bonus. It told me about &lt;a href="http://www.tatanka.com.br/ies4linux/page/Main_Page">IEs4Linux&lt;/a> (IE’s For Linux). yes, you read correctly. You can run Internet Explorer on your Linux box as well. All this in under 10 minutes (Ubuntu wins again). And yeah, don’t forget to say thanks to me (and &lt;a href="http://www.thetechandcents.com/2007/11/running-zoundry-blog-editor-under-wine.html">Alex&lt;/a> as well).&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>