<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Internet Explorer on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/internet-explorer/</link><description>Recent content in Internet Explorer on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2010 19:48:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/internet-explorer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Real Threat Of Windows Phone 7</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/28/the-real-threat-of-windows-phone-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2010 19:48:34 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/28/the-real-threat-of-windows-phone-7/</guid><description>Many people say that Windows Phone 7 is a threat to iPhone because they are bringing in a super platform with a choice of multiple designs and multiple carriers with great Enterprise and gaming support and maintaining the lucrative integration that iPhone provides. Many also say that Windows Phone 7 is a threat to Android because it solves the problem of Apple&amp;rsquo;s draconian policies, gives choice to customers and all this without fragmenting the OS all over the place.</description></item><item><title>Hack: Fixing The WordPress i3theme Sidebar Issue (Part II)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/06/hack-fixing-the-wordpress-i3theme-sidebar-issue-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2008 14:20:25 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/06/hack-fixing-the-wordpress-i3theme-sidebar-issue-part-ii/</guid><description>Some time back I had posted a little hack to fix an issue that users of i3theme have, i.e., their right sidebar drops to below the main content area in IE6. But it wasn&amp;rsquo;t that good as it took care of only the situation when this phenomena was caused by the tag cloud widget. So, here is a little modification I did to fix the issue more properly.
Go to your wp-content/themes/ folder and open the style.</description></item><item><title>BlogJet - Blog Faster, Blog Better (Now In Linux too, with a hidden bonus)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/29/blogjet-blog-faster-blog-better-now-in-linux-too-with-a-hidden-bonus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2008 15:30:27 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/29/blogjet-blog-faster-blog-better-now-in-linux-too-with-a-hidden-bonus/</guid><description>A quick googling for best desktop blogging client would yield just a few (read millions/gazillions) results. Having researched the subject a lot, my choices were finally limited down to BlogJet and BlogDesk, as per my feature set requirement goes (Primarily, off line editing, draft, WYSIWYG editing, categories, tagging support, pinging, trackbacks support, timestamping, past post editing, automatic image uploading) BUT there is one little problem. Both of these don’t work on Linux.</description></item></channel></rss>