<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ubuntu on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/ubuntu/</link><description>Recent content in Ubuntu on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 19:33:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/ubuntu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ubuntu Maverick uinput Problem Solved</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/02/21/ubuntu-maverick-uinput-problem-solved/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 19:33:37 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/02/21/ubuntu-maverick-uinput-problem-solved/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with linux uinput infrastructure for one of my ideas (Details coming soon ;) ). &amp;ldquo;uinput&amp;rdquo; is basically a mechanism in linux that allows user space applications to inject input events (mouse/keyboard or anything else) into the system. But the problem I faced was that my programs were compiling and running without any errors but I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t see the effect happening, i.e., the events weren&amp;rsquo;t getting injected into the system.</description><content>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with linux uinput infrastructure for one of my ideas (Details coming soon ;) ). &amp;ldquo;uinput&amp;rdquo; is basically a mechanism in linux that allows user space applications to inject input events (mouse/keyboard or anything else) into the system. But the problem I faced was that my programs were compiling and running without any errors but I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t see the effect happening, i.e., the events weren&amp;rsquo;t getting injected into the system. I am using Ubuntu Maverick Meerkat (10.10) and when I searched on the net, I saw various other folks are facing the same issue. I finally got it working and here is how.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First problem I came across was that I was using &amp;ldquo;/dev/input/uinput&amp;rdquo; path in my programs but it seems it is changed to &amp;ldquo;/dev/uinput&amp;rdquo; in Ubuntu. Changing this got me past some runtime errors I was getting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then I thought that the issue was because uinput module wasn&amp;rsquo;t getting loaded because even after specifically doing a modprobe, I still couldn&amp;rsquo;t see it loaded when I did lsmod. This was strange because the /dev/uinput node was present. On looking under /lib, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even find the uinput.ko file. But then I found that the reason for this is that in Ubuntu Maverick, uinput is not a module anymore. It is built into the kernel now. (See this &lt;a href="https://bugs.launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/bluez/+bug/584812">launchpad bug&lt;/a>.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, having figured that the above was a false alarm, I was at a loss how to explain this. But then I tried just changing the permissions of the uinput node to 0666 (i.e. writable by all users) and ran my program without sudo and it worked like a charm. Searching for sudo along with uinput lead me to &lt;a href="https://bugs.launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/sudo/+bug/609645">these&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://www.sudo.ws/bugs/show_bug.cgi?id=388">bugs&lt;/a> which confirms that the problem is because of this only. So, if you are facing this issue, you can either change the uinput node permissions or install the sudo patch described in the bug discussion page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me know if this worked for you as well :)&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Is Android Open Source Or Not?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/25/android-open-source-or-not/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 11:31:06 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/25/android-open-source-or-not/</guid><description>Is Android really open source or not? That is the question being asked by almost everyone. A lot of people, especially those influenced by RDF or those who are in the news industry with no idea about OS and open source but were asked by their boss to get a scoop on this pronto, tend to bring up a few keywords and then twist them around in the way they see fit to make sure it says Android isn&amp;rsquo;t open.</description><content>&lt;p>Is Android really open source or not? That is the question being asked by almost everyone. A lot of people, especially those influenced by &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reality_distortion_field">RDF&lt;/a> or those who are in the news industry with no idea about OS and open source but were asked by their boss to get a scoop on this pronto, tend to bring up a few keywords and then twist them around in the way they see fit to make sure it says Android isn&amp;rsquo;t open. They don&amp;rsquo;t need to be correct, they only need the article to &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>sound correct&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo; by picking up sentences out of context or putting quotes only from people who agree with them. This will convince their boss and 99% of their readers who have no idea about all these things either. But the boss is happy he got a story and associated clicks. Readers are happy because they got the points to float around in their next forum flame war. They don&amp;rsquo;t have to read when someone corrects them. They have made their points and rest is all someone making noises like a rat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lot out of the rest of the people, who are indeed informed, make the mistake of thinking that &amp;ldquo;Open Source = GPL&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Open Source = Free Software&amp;rdquo;, which is not true. Open source is similar to free software but is one that choses to keep more options open. In short, Free Software Movement, as the one evangelized by FSF, is a subset of open source that tries to achieve freedom of software by restriction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please also note that many people including Steve Jobs confuse people more by interchanging between open and open source. An android phone that you get may not be open, the android market may be open, etc but this discussion is purely about open-source.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyways, with asbestos underwear on, I write this post to speak my mind about this matter by talking about various points thrown up by the above mentioned classes. Since this is going to be a long post, I&amp;rsquo;ll mention here the things it is going to cover:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Allegations against Android&amp;rsquo;s open-source nature. Are they true?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Does OSI Foundation (&lt;a href="http://www.opensource.org">Open source Initiative&lt;/a>) think that Android is open source?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Android and open source in layman terms&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Takeaways/conclusion&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update&lt;/strong>: Updated the article as per Tony and Kasper&amp;rsquo;s comments below. Thanks Kasper and Tony for your valuable inputs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="android-and-open-source-allegations-and-answers">Android and Open Source: Allegations and Answers&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allegation&lt;/strong>: Google does a lot of development in private for few months and then releases the code to public.
&lt;strong>Answer&lt;/strong>: Almost every open source project I know does this. Do you think every person who works on an open source project pushes his code to the mainline 10 times when re writes a 10 line code? No. He completes the feature, tests it and then pushes it out. Individuals might do it sooner, companies might do it later but everyone pushes out their code when they feel things are fairly ready. So, Google choses to do the &amp;ldquo;push&amp;rdquo; every few months when they think their new feature set is ready. This, of course, is more influenced by the fact that they need to be competitive in the aggressive mobile market and hence not let the competitors know about the exact features but still it is well within the limits of open source. And they are doing it before/with the binary release as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also to be noted here is the fact that the &amp;ldquo;code dump&amp;rdquo; is done only for major releases. Minor fixes and even features keep trickling into the code base every now and then and these allow others to make fixes as well. e.g. Cyanogen was able to bring &amp;ldquo;802.11n&amp;rdquo; capability and was able to include various fixes including one for wi-fi sleep policies before they actually made into an OTA update for any phone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allegation&lt;/strong>: Only google employees can check in code to mainline.
&lt;strong>Answer&lt;/strong>: Every open source project has only a select few folks who can check in code. Most of the open source projects start with only their founders having commit access. They may or may not give commit accesses to anyone else. Check out various open source projects on sourceforge, googlecode, etc and you will find this. Most of the projects that do choose to give commit access to others, start doing it after some time when they feel the project is mature enough and they are confident enough in someone else. Android is just a hatchling, around 2 years old. It has begun making strides only now so Google may even choose to take the latter path but I can understand if Google wants to keep this as their control point because of the hustle and bustle of the mobile OS world which is much more rapid and cut throat than the desktop OS and this does not make them closed. Not only that, but seeing how everyone in the mobile world is so trigger happy with suing everyone else, it creates a legal issue for them as they would be the ones to answer if someone else brings this upon them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allegation&lt;/strong>: Google only accepts their own code into official android and nobody else&amp;rsquo;s.
&lt;strong>Answer&lt;/strong>: This one is hilarious. Obviously, anyone who says this hasn&amp;rsquo;t actually been to review.android.com. Just go their and check whether any merged changes have non-google, non-android email ids. Anyone can upload their patches there but the accepted ones are fairly low. This problem is present in every popular open source project, even the Linux kernel. But is more pronounced in the case of android because Google&amp;rsquo;s android team is much smaller than the number of persons working on other projects and there is red tape of a big company involved. If you want to get your patch in, just like the kernel, you need to engage with them. Talk to them in the relevant bug report, comment the code properly, give them a reason to not avoid your patch. But yes, the process is still very slow and it is eons faster to just contribute to a fork like cyanogenmod. I do hope that google does get better in this regard soon though.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allegation&lt;/strong>: It is not possible to make a full android build from the public code tree of android.
&lt;strong>Answer&lt;/strong>: BS. Cyanogen does just fine with his full AOSP builds. People argue that Google does not release the modem/baseband code but they idiotically fail to realize that the baseband code is not part of Android at all. It is the IP of the baseband manufacturer and is specific to each hardware. Android is just the code that runs on apps hardware. Google does not indeed release the code of their built in google apps (gtalk/gmail etc) though but they are already working towards that and these apps will not be a part of the base Android system anymore. These would be standalone apps and even now you don&amp;rsquo;t need them to make a fully working android build.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allegation&lt;/strong>: &amp;ldquo;Android&amp;rdquo; is a registered trademark and is held by Google.
&lt;strong>Answer&lt;/strong>: Linus holds the trademark for &amp;ldquo;Linux&amp;rdquo;, Mozilla foundation holds the trademark for &amp;ldquo;Firefox&amp;rdquo;, Canonical holds the trademark for &amp;ldquo;Ubuntu&amp;rdquo;. Get the drift? Basically, it is completely possible and allowed for an open source software to be trademarked.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allegation&lt;/strong>: Google doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop the carriers/OEMs from locking down the phones, adding bloatware or custom UIs.
&lt;strong>Answer&lt;/strong>: This is an issue with carriers/OEMs and not Android. Google uses the apache software license (ASL), which is a permissive license (like MIT, BSD, etc) and hence does not stop the carriers from doing such a thing (In fact, this is the very foundation of being open, check the next passage about OSI foundation, point no. 9). Many people say they should, but if they did then they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be open anymore, would they?
Even Linus Torvalds is against making such a stipulation of not allowing locking of phones and this is the biggest reason why the Linux Kernel (and lot of other open source projects) didn&amp;rsquo;t move to FSF&amp;rsquo;s (&lt;a href="http://www.fsf.org">Free Software Foundation&lt;/a>) GPL v3. I wonder why no one calls the Linux kernel closed hmmmm&amp;hellip;
BTW, if you are so serious about unlocked/rootable phones then buy a dev phone directly from google or get one from Synapse.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="android-and-open-source-osi-foundation">Android and Open Source: OSI Foundation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The OSI foundation has a few guidelines to determine whether something is open source or not under their &lt;a href="http://www.opensource.org/osd.html">Open Source Definition&lt;/a>. Android uses the OSI compatible Apache Software License (ASL) but still let&amp;rsquo;s see whether Android comes up to all of them or not. If it is in conflict with even one of the requisites, we will call Android closed.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Allow free redistribution - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Give out un-obfuscated source code - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Allow modifications and derived works - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Allow distribution of modifications (as patches) or modified software as a whole. Can restrict the modified versions from using original name of software - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No discrimination against any person or groups - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No restriction of using the software on any device or field - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No additional license needed - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No product-specific license - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No restriction on software distributed along with original software - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Technology neutral, i.e., no preference for an individual technology or user interface - Check
So, Android is true to each and every point that being open demands to it. In fact, points 9 and 10 are fundamental in making it open but alas, people less oriented with open software tend to term this as being closed (as seen in the last allegation above)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="android-and-open-source-from-a-laymans-view-point">Android and Open Source: From a layman&amp;rsquo;s view point&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Apart from the above, I would also like to share a few &amp;ldquo;layman-examples&amp;rdquo; which will let you understand for yourself why Android is open:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>You can see all the official android OS code without any restrictions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can download it, fork it, modify it without asking google&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can port it to any device without asking google&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can develop and sell your phone with Android without asking google
Now compare that with any other mobile OS you know.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="android-and-open-source-conclusion">Android and Open Source: Conclusion&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>So, the takeaways from the above wall of text are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Android is open-source&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Android is permissively open-source instead of being restrictive&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Android can do better in terms of community driven development but is perhaps held back by pace of competition and legalities involved. But, this in no way makes it non-open-source.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Let me know if you have any corrections or allegations to make :)&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>What does caret (^) in an apt-get command mean?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/23/apt-get-caret/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2010 18:03:06 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/23/apt-get-caret/</guid><description>If you have come across a tutorial or just someone on a forum who tells you to install something in Debian/Ubuntu that involves using apt-get, it is ok for you but when they tell you that you need to use a caret symbol (^) at the end, that&amp;rsquo;s where you become curious. What is even more weird is that when you search for the name of the package that the given command seems to install cannot be found using apt-cache search.</description><content>&lt;p>If you have come across a tutorial or just someone on a forum who tells you to install something in Debian/Ubuntu that involves using apt-get, it is ok for you but when they tell you that you need to use a caret symbol (^) at the end, that&amp;rsquo;s where you become curious. What is even more weird is that when you search for the name of the package that the given command seems to install cannot be found using apt-cache search. e.g. You will see this used most often when someone tells you how to install LAMP server setup (Linux-Apache-MySQL-PHP) by using the command &amp;ldquo;sudo apt-get install lamp-server^&amp;rdquo;. If you miss the caret at the end or try to search for lamp-server, it just doesn&amp;rsquo;t work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, the answer is that the caret symbol is a short form for performing a task that otherwise the program &amp;ldquo;tasksel&amp;rdquo; would have done with the given package name. tasksel is a program to ease the installation of commonly used things that go together for a particular use. e.g. In the above instance of LAMP, the four packages and their dependencies are always used together, so tasksel provides a sort of a meta-package or meta-task that can be run by the user with a single command and then tasksel will take it upon itself to install all of them and set them up correctly for your use. Now, apt-get provides a way to perform that same task by itself without you having to install tasksel first and all you have to do is to give that same package name to apt-get but just append a caret at the end to tell apt-get that it is a tasksel package/task identifier and not a regular package name in debian/ubuntu repositories.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hope that clears things up :)&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Clearing the FUD around Ubuntu Application Review Process</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/21/clearing-the-fud-around-ubuntu-application-review-process/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2010 19:44:24 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/21/clearing-the-fud-around-ubuntu-application-review-process/</guid><description>An application review process was announced today for getting your apps into Ubuntu “extras” repository. But like most other announcements of new things, this one was met as well with as much criticism as the praise it got. A lot of the criticism is FUD though, although mostly unintentional and caused by ignorance of some facts behind it. I’ll try to address some of these concerns here to the best of my knowledge from what I’ve been reading over the past some time about this development.</description><content>&lt;p>An application review process was &lt;a href="http://www.jonobacon.org/2010/09/20/announcing-the-ubuntu-application-review-process/">announced today&lt;/a> for getting your apps into Ubuntu “extras” repository. But like most other announcements of new things, this one was met as well with as much criticism as the praise it got. A lot of the criticism is FUD though, although mostly unintentional and caused by ignorance of some facts behind it. I’ll try to address some of these concerns here to the best of my knowledge from what I’ve been reading over the past some time about this development.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before we begin, here are the terms listed out for an app to be eligible for the new repository:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>only new applications that are not present in an existing official Ubuntu repository (such as main/universe) are eligible in this process (e.g a new version of an application in an existing official repository is not eligible). Also no other software can depend on the application being submitted (e.g. development libraries are not eligible), only executable applications (and content that is part of them) are eligible, and not stand-alone content, documentation or media, and applications must be Open Source and available under an OSI approved license.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Now, the concerns that are floating around are many. Some are genuine queries and many are straight attacks dishing out evil conspiracy theories :P. The concerns can be summarised as:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Closed source and paid apps are being given the boot by Ubuntu. They should have allowed them.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Why can’t we have updates for existing apps in this repository?&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Why only standalone apps are allowed. Libraries are equally important.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Why should the software be packaged for /opt. This involves more headache for the developers.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Standalone media and content should have been allowed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Well, to answer these, all you need to understand is the “premise” and concept behind the repository where this software will go and the reasoning behind the review process will unfold itself. The repository governed by this review process is meant to be for “maintainable” pieces of software that would generally go to other universe/main etc repos but couldn’t make it into this release of Ubuntu because the developers were a bit late. This process and feature now gives a chance to the developers to still get their app to public instead of waiting for next release cycle and also allows end-users to use new apps without having to upgrade their version of Ubuntu . There is a separate “partners” repository where closed source and paid apps can go so there is no conflict there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Only allowing standalone apps and not updates and dependencies is so obvious. It would soon go out of hand exponentially if you allowed dependencies since one thing needs another library updated, then that would need another and yet another and so on and before you know it, you would be back at square one, that is upgrading to the next version of Ubuntu itself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The only thing that I found out of the place was not allowing standalone content but probably they didn’t allow it because such content can be had by end users without a repo easily and would ease the burden of repo maintainers and reviewers by lessening the entries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’d also like to point out that this is just a beginning and the process (and the people behind it) would definitely be maturing from all the feedback they get from the community. Think of it as an alpha release ;). Jono Bacon summed it up very nicely in this comment of his that he made elsewhere:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>this is an &lt;em>experimental&lt;/em> process; it is a work in progress, it will evolve, and the kinks will be ironed out. The process was approved by the Ubuntu Technical Board who are all seasoned Ubuntu developers (Matt Zimmerman, Colin Watson, Martin Pitt, Mark Shuttleworth, and Kees Cook), and much of what you refer to as &amp;ldquo;restrictions&amp;rdquo; were requested by them for the purpose of delivering a nimble process that is stable and secure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To be clear: you can think of this process as a &amp;ldquo;light-weight&amp;rdquo; equivalent to our traditional MOTU development process; it is intended to provide a method in which app devs can get content in Ubuntu, whereas our traditional development processes have be orientated around the needs of Operating System integrators.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As such, this is a first step; sure it is not perfect, but I would like to invite you to make it better; I think this would be a more valuable contribution than just ranting about it on here. Our goal is to make Ubuntu better and to make it more attractive to app developers, and this process will evolve and improve (as was made clear throughout the discussion of this).&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>So, what do you think about it? I, for one, am pretty excited..&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>grub and knetworkmanager problems in Kubuntu Karmic</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/11/08/grub-knetworkmanager-kubuntu-karmic/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2009 12:08:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/11/08/grub-knetworkmanager-kubuntu-karmic/</guid><description>I generally move from LTS to LTS releases of Ubuntu but reluctantly had to update my system to Karmic when my old HDD gave in. I also thought of trying out Kubuntu (KDE based) this time as I had heard that its doing a lot of interesting things (Akonadi/Nepomuk etc) and that with 4.3.1 it is stable as well. The installation went fine, all over within less than half an hour and then the problems started.</description><content>&lt;p>I generally move from &lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/21/ubuntu-what-exactly-does-lts-mean.html">LTS&lt;/a> to LTS releases of Ubuntu but reluctantly had to update my system to Karmic when my old HDD gave in. I also thought of trying out Kubuntu (KDE based) this time as I had heard that its doing a lot of interesting things (Akonadi/Nepomuk etc) and that with 4.3.1 it is stable as well. The installation went fine, all over within less than half an hour and then the problems started. Here are the 2 main issues that I faced along with their solutions, in the hope that if someone else runs into same issues does not have to waste time (and hair) on it :)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1. Bootloader Issue:&lt;/strong> I dual boot my system along with Win XP (Needed for some office work) and generally install the bootloader onto a separate boot partition instead of overwriting the MBR. But this time when I did the same, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t boot (not even the grub menu). When I did this, the very helpful message that I got on restarting after installing kubuntu was “Error loading operating system”. I could still go back to my good windows install by setting the boot flag onto its partition. I mucked around with it a lot, trying to install grub2 again and found that actually it fails when I try to do the above (install on a partition). I also tried copying the boot sector from my /boot partition to C: and use ntldr to boot into linux but that also didn’t work. This lead me to believe that the same thing happened during my main installation and the installer failed to tell me anything about it. I tried then to install it on MBR but that also mucked up things and I couldn’t even get the error message, a cursor just kept blinking. Finally, the solution. I had to install kubuntu again and this time selected to overwrite MBR (this is default, BTW).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2. Wi-Fi Connection Issue:&lt;/strong> Second immediate issue was with knetworkmanager. It failed to start my wi-fi module (even after installing restricted drivers). I disabled and enabled wi-fi, so that brought some life to it (wi-fi led started glowing) but it still couldn’t scan for any access points. I could do the scan through command line and see my AP but my AP is WPA2 secured and I didn’t want to mess around with wpa-supplicant stuff. Solution: Installed Wicd. And it worked automagically.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hope this helps someone else who faces the same issue. Looks like my idea of moving to kubuntu wasn’t a good one (especially because I had 2 lockups during the 1 hour I used it for in the wee hours of this morning). I’ll probably give it another week or so before taking the decision whether to move back to ubuntu or not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One good thing to take away from this though: For the first time I could really appreciate the live CD installer that these linux distros give. As I could search about the various issues I had without having a second computer. But then again, it’s not that good as well because it means that so far I never had any installation issues at all…&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Making Frets On Fire Work With Pulse Aludio - pasuspender</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/08/23/make-frets-on-fire-work-pulse-audio-pasuspender/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2009 18:18:45 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/08/23/make-frets-on-fire-work-pulse-audio-pasuspender/</guid><description>I recently got hold of a Guitar Hero controller for my PS3 but the game still had some time to come so I tried it out on my laptop with Frets on Fire (rather FoFix). But when I started it, it was crashing with some weird error about not being able to open mixer devices. Searching on the google, I came to know this is happening because of Pulse Audio as this application needs direct access to the sound devices and finally I came upon **pasuspender.</description><content>&lt;p>I recently got hold of a Guitar Hero controller for my PS3 but the game still had some time to come so I tried it out on my laptop with Frets on Fire (rather FoFix). But when I started it, it was crashing with some weird error about not being able to open mixer devices. Searching on the google, I came to know this is happening because of Pulse Audio as this application needs direct access to the sound devices and finally I came upon **pasuspender. **This little tool allows you to do that with ease. Just run it in the following way:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>pasuspender -- ./FretsOnFire&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it will start working just fine. You can use the same trick for any other application that needs direct access to the sound devices. What pasuspender does is that it will suspend pulse audio and allow the application to access them directly and when the application is terminated, normal functioning will resume.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Why You Should Not Upgrade to Ubuntu Jaunty Jackalope (9.04)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/05/04/ubuntu-904-jaunty-jackalope-upgrade-graphics-problem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2009 17:46:40 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/05/04/ubuntu-904-jaunty-jackalope-upgrade-graphics-problem/</guid><description>Update: It has come to my notice that many people do not know about this (and other problems listed in comments of this post). Please digg and reddit this post so that more people can be made aware of it before they upgrade unknowingly.
You should not upgrade to Ubuntu 9.04 (aka Jaunty Jackalope), released a few weeks ago, if:
You have an older ATI graphics card (prior to R500, .</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update: It has come to my notice that many people do not know about this (and other problems listed in comments of this post). Please &lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://digg.com/linux_unix/Why_You_Should_Not_Upgrade_to_Ubuntu_Jaunty_Jackalope_9_04">&lt;strong>digg&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/8hzkt/why_you_should_not_upgrade_to_ubuntu_jaunty/">&lt;strong>reddit&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> this post so that more people can be made aware of it before they upgrade unknowingly.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You should not upgrade to Ubuntu 9.04 (aka Jaunty Jackalope), released a few weeks ago, if:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You have an older ATI graphics card (prior to R500, .e.g xpress 200m)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You like to have 3D support (read compiz/games, etc)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>This is because of the following reasons:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Ubuntu Jaunty Jackalope has the new version of X.org server (1.6)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The open source graphics drivers for ATI do not have 3D support&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The only version of the ATI properietary drivers (fglrx\Catalyst) compatible with X.org server 1.6 is 9.4&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Support for older cards (mentioned above) was dropped from fglrx 9.4&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>So, basically right now you are in a soup and it seems to me that this is going to remain this way unless someone figures out how to backport x.org 1.5 onto Jauntu, which is going to be a hell of a task, IMHO :P&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But, if you are a simple person, who looks beyond the gloss of the 3D and marvels at the beauty that the rest of the system holds, then go right ahead and dive in :)&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Project: Shantz XWinWrap Update to 0.3</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/16/project-shantz-xwinwrap-update-to-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2009 18:30:03 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/16/project-shantz-xwinwrap-update-to-03/</guid><description>Here is another update for the fans of XWinWrap, the tiny program that allows you to run animated wallpapers on your system. You could use screensavers, movies and what not as your desktop background. This update fixes a segfault that many users were facing, a new debug option to print some debug mesages to get some info if it is not working for you and a new hack option for giving a &amp;ldquo;desktop window&amp;rdquo; name to the program.</description><content>&lt;p>Here is another update for the fans of XWinWrap, the tiny program that allows you to run animated wallpapers on your system. You could use screensavers, movies and what not as your desktop background. This update fixes a segfault that many users were facing, a new debug option to print some debug mesages to get some info if it is not working for you and a new hack option for giving a &amp;ldquo;desktop window&amp;rdquo; name to the program. On many systems, the desktop is drawn by another program. e.g. in Ubuntu with Gnome environment, the desktop is managed by Nautilus, which creates a special window called &amp;ldquo;Desktop&amp;rdquo; and places it over your real desktop. This window name can be different in different systems. To find out what is yours, just run &amp;ldquo;xwininfo&amp;rdquo; in a terminal. Your cursor will become a &amp;ldquo;+&amp;rdquo; sign. Click anywhere on an empty area on your desktop, which will give you the window name of the transparent window, if any, that is covering your desktop. Pass this info to xwinwrap using the option &amp;ldquo;-d windowname&amp;rdquo; and it would help it to run better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As usual, 32 bit as well as 64 bit binary files are available as downloads. For users of Debian and derived operating systems (like Ubuntu, Mepis, etc), deb packages are also included for both architectures for easy installation. Source code is also available, of course.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>[TIP] Ubuntu 1 MB /tmp Partition Problem</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/10/tip-ubuntu-1-mb-tmp-partition-problem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2009 00:30:31 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/10/tip-ubuntu-1-mb-tmp-partition-problem/</guid><description>Recently someone asked me about an issue he was facing with his Ubuntu Hardy Heron installation. Many of the applications, that he regularly used, were misbehaving. e.g., he couldn&amp;rsquo;t play flash videos in firefox, downloads were failing, installation of new applications were failing, etc. Everything was giving errors of not enough disk space even though he had quite a few GBs left on his drive. A few of the error messages pointed out that there wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough space in /tmp.</description><content>&lt;p>Recently someone asked me about an issue he was facing with his Ubuntu Hardy Heron installation. Many of the applications, that he regularly used, were misbehaving. e.g., he couldn&amp;rsquo;t play flash videos in firefox, downloads were failing, installation of new applications were failing, etc. Everything was giving errors of not enough disk space even though he had quite a few GBs left on his drive. A few of the error messages pointed out that there wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough space in /tmp. And indeed, he was unable to store anything more than 1 MB inside this particular directory. After a quick look I found out the issue. Ubuntu had created another partition with /tmp being its mount point and its maz size was set to 1 MB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A search told me that this occurs if you happen to run out of disk space on your root partition some time, so Ubuntu automatically limits the size of /tmp to squeeze as much out of the remaining space as it can. Ideally, original behaviour of /tmp should be restored once you recover some space but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen. The solution? Well, it is pretty simple. Just follow these steps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Step 1. Open up /etc/mtab in your favourite editor. e.g. gksudo gedit /etc/mtab&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Step 2. Look for a line that looks something like below example and delete it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>overflow /tmp tmpfs rw,size=1048576,mode=1777 0 0&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Step 3. Save the file and restart your computer. That&amp;rsquo;s it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, this problem might not just be Ubuntu specific though and might happen with other distros as well. So, if you come across such an issue, try out this solution.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>[Ubuntu TIP] Solved: Totem Cannot Detect UPnP Media Server</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/31/ubuntu-tip-solved-totem-cannot-detect-upnp-media-server/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 17:46:28 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/31/ubuntu-tip-solved-totem-cannot-detect-upnp-media-server/</guid><description>First a bit of background. A UPnP media server can serve your media files (video / audio / pictures) over the network to any compatible player. Some of the most known examples of these media servers are MediaTomb, TVersity, ushare, etc. In linux, few players can play media off these servers natively, but many require a plugin / library called &amp;ldquo;coherence&amp;rdquo;. e.g. the default media players (Totem and RhythmBox) can detect and play media from media servers once you install coherence (&amp;ldquo;sudo apt-get install python-coherence&amp;rdquo;).</description><content>&lt;p>First a bit of background. A UPnP media server can serve your media files (video / audio / pictures) over the network to any compatible player. Some of the most known examples of these media servers are MediaTomb, TVersity, ushare, etc. In linux, few players can play media off these servers natively, but many require a plugin / library called &amp;ldquo;coherence&amp;rdquo;. e.g. the default media players (Totem and RhythmBox) can detect and play media from media servers once you install coherence (&amp;ldquo;sudo apt-get install python-coherence&amp;rdquo;). This works, BUT you will see that many times Totem will stop detecting the server suddenly. It happens to me quite a bit (The server I use is Mediatomb). First I thought that the problem is with Media Tomb, but my PS3 continued to play videos from it over wi-fi without any issues, so that was ruled out. I tried many things but in the end, the solution turned out to be pretty simple. The problem seems to be that the coherence library hangs some times. Simple thing is to just restart it. So, all you need to do is run the following command:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>sudo killall coherence&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, just restart Totem and it will work fine now (Totem will invoke coherence again automatically). :)&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Project: Shantz-XwinWrap Updated to 0.02</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/18/project-shantz-xwinwrap-updated-to-002/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2008 11:03:48 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/18/project-shantz-xwinwrap-updated-to-002/</guid><description>As some of you know that I&amp;rsquo;ve taken up the development of the ultra-cool xwinwrap tool that allows you to use movies, screensavers etc as wallpapers for you linux desktops. Here is version 0.02 for you consumption that fixes a bug because of which the generated window was overlapping other windows.
The download file has plain executable binaries as well as deb packages for Ubuntu. Moreover, I&amp;rsquo;ve included both 32 bit as well as 64 bit versions.</description><content>&lt;p>As some of you know that I&amp;rsquo;ve taken up the development of the ultra-cool xwinwrap tool that allows you to use movies, screensavers etc as wallpapers for you linux desktops. Here is version 0.02 for you consumption that fixes a bug because of which the generated window was overlapping other windows.&lt;br>
The download file has plain executable binaries as well as deb packages for Ubuntu. Moreover, I&amp;rsquo;ve included both 32 bit as well as 64 bit versions.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Project: Shantz Pidgin Away Alerts (splert) Updated to 0.03</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/03/project-shantz-pidgin-away-alerts-splert-updated-to-003/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 21:19:08 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/03/project-shantz-pidgin-away-alerts-splert-updated-to-003/</guid><description>I updated my project splert to version 0.03 today.For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know splert is a tool that lets you convert the multi-client instant messenger pidgin (connects to gtalk, msn, yahoo, jabber, etc) into a full blown answering machine and much more.
The main changes are:
Now you can use other 3rd party twitter bots with it to get updates through twitter since the official twitter bot is down since a long time and there are no chances of coming back soon.</description><content>&lt;p>I updated my project splert to version 0.03 today.For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know splert is a tool that lets you convert the multi-client instant messenger pidgin (connects to gtalk, msn, yahoo, jabber, etc) into a full blown answering machine and much more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main changes are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Now you can use other 3rd party twitter bots with it to get updates through twitter since the official twitter bot is down since a long time and there are no chances of coming back soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can also use it even when you are not &amp;ldquo;away&amp;rdquo; by specifying the status when you want it to work. (e.g. any, available, unavailable, invisible, etc. Use splert -h to see all available status types). As an example, you can use this to selectively talk to people when you are busy.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>(As usual, binary files as well as 32 bit and 64 bit ubuntu/debian deb packages are available)&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>A Breath Of Fresh Air: My New Ubuntu Desktop</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/21/a-breath-of-fresh-air-my-new-ubuntu-desktop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2008 18:54:53 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/21/a-breath-of-fresh-air-my-new-ubuntu-desktop/</guid><description>**UPDATE: **Surprisingly this post has found favour with “digg”ers :). Check the bottom of the post for some more info about the setup
UPDATE2: On popular demand, I&amp;rsquo;ve uploaded my .conkyrc. Download Conky Configuration file by clicking here and save as .conkyrc in your home folder.
After loitering around for so long, I finally got my lazy bum off the bed and installed Hardy Heron (8.04.1) onto my aging laptop. I’ve never been a sucker for eye-candy stuff, prefering to have more resources available for real work, instead of ooh-aahing over nice looking things all around my desktop.</description><content>&lt;p>**UPDATE: **Surprisingly this post has found favour with “digg”ers :). Check the bottom of the post for some more info about the setup&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>UPDATE2&lt;/strong>: On popular demand, I&amp;rsquo;ve uploaded my .conkyrc. &lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/files/conkyrc.txt">Download Conky Configuration file by clicking here&lt;/a> and save as .conkyrc in your home folder.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After loitering around for so long, I finally got my lazy bum off the bed and installed Hardy Heron (8.04.1) onto my aging laptop. I’ve never been a sucker for eye-candy stuff, prefering to have more resources available for real work, instead of ooh-aahing over nice looking things all around my desktop. Well, but then I fell prey. I thought of giving another try to the thingamagic that compiz-fusion is, moreso since I didn’t have to go through loads of installing nuances like feisty because of it being already integrated in Hardy. An emerald install and a few minutes of tinkering later, I had a cool looking screen staring back at me. Here is a preview screenshot for your eyes but obviously the static screenshot wont show the amazing dynamic effects of CF. Let me see how many days I keep this up before going back to my plain-jane self. Click on the pic for full view:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/desktop.jpg">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/desktop_thumb.jpg" alt="My all new and shiny desktop">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me know if you have any suggestions to improve it further, or want more pics/vids of my new lappy in action, or have any of your own to share.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Update: Setup info:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Base Theme: Ubuntu Studio (basically for icon set. Download ubuntustudio-look package for this)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Controls : From Xenon theme (Inbuilt in Ubuntu)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Wallpaper is something named “lotus” or something. Downloaded from interfacelift.com&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Compiz Fusion with almost all effects turned on. Ofcourse you can’t see most of them in the still image&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Emerald theme engine for glassy and rounded window borders (Download “emerald” package)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Dock at the bottom is avant window navigator (awn. Download package avant-window-navigator)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On right side, stats etc are from conky (Download package conky)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Misc: Turned transparency on for most things including gnome-terminal, gnome-panel, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Salient points:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The memory being consumed right now is around 850 MB. Thats with lots of applications, all CF effects turned on, most things having glass and transparent effects, and even my apache web server and mysql are running in background. And after that also, most memory (around 200 MB) is being eaten by firefox, leading to this high usage.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The setup boots up with just a shade over 300 MB being used, even though I’ve set CF and emerald on by default at boot and even apache and mysql start running on startup. :)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item><item><title>Ubuntu: What exactly does LTS mean?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/20/ubuntu-what-exactly-does-lts-mean/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 21:29:10 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/20/ubuntu-what-exactly-does-lts-mean/</guid><description>With the recent release of Ubuntu 8.04 (Hardy Heron), a lot of hype was generated (Overhype or well-deserved, that’s for another post). One of the main highlights of all the stories, news and reviews doing the rounds are that this is an LTS version. But many people, mostly those who are new to Ubuntu, and even a few who are already using it, are not sure what LTS really means.</description><content>&lt;p>With the recent release of Ubuntu 8.04 (Hardy Heron), a lot of hype was generated (Overhype or well-deserved, that’s for another post). One of the main highlights of all the stories, news and reviews doing the rounds are that this is an LTS version. But many people, mostly those who are new to Ubuntu, and even a few who are already using it, are not sure what LTS really means.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Literally expanded, it stands for &lt;strong>Long Term Support&lt;/strong>. Yeah right, but what does it actually mean. Does it mean I’ll keep getting updates till eternity or what? The explanation is quite simple really.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Long Term:&lt;/strong> What it means is that while a normal non-LTS is supported for 18 months, an LTS version will be supported for 3 years or 36 months (and 5 years for the server version).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Support: **Now, don’t just jump into downloading it and installing on reading the long term part. This DOES NOT mean that you’ll continue getting newer versions of favourite software packages till that time. This only means that you’ll continue getting “security updates” for 3 (or 5) years. What’s the difference, some might ask, as they think that the newest version of a software is the most secure. However it is not so. A newer version may bring more features, but also more code to become vulnerable to bugs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, in a nutshell, to understand the situation, let’s take an example. If Hardy has a software X with version 1.3, and after 2 years the software moves to version 2.5, you’ll not be able to get version 2.5 from the hardy repositories but a version “1.x-ubuntuy”, which will have all the security and major bug fixes for that software, but not the new features that you might see in later versions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I just did this post so that people don’t jump into it by getting a wrong impression about LTS and later on be disappointed on learning the fact. So, now you can make an informed decision.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Keep Tab On Home Security With A Webcam And Twitter</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/14/keep-tab-on-home-security-with-a-webcam-and-twitter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2008 04:00:13 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/14/keep-tab-on-home-security-with-a-webcam-and-twitter/</guid><description>Worried about someone breaking into your house in your absence? Or just need to keep a tab on who enters your room while you are away? Well, all you need is a webcam, a linux PC/laptop and a twitter account. And you are set for real time updates through twitter about all that goes on at your abode behind your back (can even receive a text message/sms on your phone). Keep reading for the very simple setup you need.</description><content>&lt;p>Worried about someone breaking into your house in your absence? Or just need to keep a tab on who enters your room while you are away? Well, all you need is a webcam, a linux PC/laptop and a twitter account. And you are set for real time updates through twitter about all that goes on at your abode behind your back (can even receive a text message/sms on your phone). Keep reading for the very simple setup you need.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1.) Download and install &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://www.lavrsen.dk/twiki/bin/view/Motion/DownloadFiles">motion&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo; on your computer. For ubuntu users, this is as simple as running&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>2.) Setup your motion configuration file. (Usually at /etc/motion/motion.conf). There are quite a lot of options available. You might want to tweak it a lot according to ur needs later on but the most important ones that you can begin with are (leave the rest untouched for now):&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2a.) Add/edit the option &amp;ldquo;target_dir&amp;rdquo; to point to the directory where you want to save the images of the event when motion is detected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2b.) Add/edit the option &amp;ldquo;locate&amp;rdquo; and set it to &amp;ldquo;on&amp;rdquo; so that you get a nice square box around the detected moving object/person.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2c.) Add/edit the option &amp;ldquo;webcam_port&amp;rdquo; and set it to, say, &amp;ldquo;8000&amp;rdquo;. Motion includes a mini http server so now, you can use it to view the actual images of the happening when you get the update and check for false alarms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3.) Now, comes the most important part, about getting the update.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>motion has an option called &amp;ldquo;on_motion_detected&amp;rdquo; and here you can specify any command or program that you want to run when motion is detected. To get the update on your twitter account, use one of the following three methods with this option.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3a.) Using curl. If you have curl installed in your system, then you can use the following value for the on_motion_detected option:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>3b.) Using wget. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have curl, you can even use wget for this. Use the following value:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>3c.) Using my perl script. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have curl as well as wget, you can even use my perl script (attached below) for this. The value will now be:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;ol start="4">
&lt;li>Now connect your webcam and start motion (Just type &amp;ldquo;motion&amp;rdquo; on command line and press enter). Wait for someone to break in, or just roam around in front of the camera yourself and have fun as you receive a message on your phone about the &amp;ldquo;motion&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>PS: For receiving a text message on your phone, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to turn on the &amp;ldquo;Device Updates&amp;rdquo; option in your twitter account, otherwise you need to open the twitter web page to check the status.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The script: &lt;a href="http://tech.shantanugoel.com/resources/downloads/twitter.pl">Twitter Updating Perl Script&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me know if you put this to some other exciting uses or have any questions about the method described above.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Tip: Getting Your Webcam To Work In Ubuntu</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/10/tip-getting-your-webcam-to-work-in-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2008 19:17:42 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/10/tip-getting-your-webcam-to-work-in-ubuntu/</guid><description>I have an old noname cheapo webcam, that I dusted out of my junk (why? More on that in a post coming soon). I hoped that it would work in my Ubuntu setup out of the box like most of my other hardware. I connected it to my laptop&amp;rsquo;s usb port. dmesg gave the following output:
[21328.211333] usb 1-1: new full speed USB device using ohci_hcd and address 2 [21328.319698] usb 1-1: configuration #1 chosen from 1 choice [21328.</description><content>&lt;p>I have an old noname cheapo webcam, that I dusted out of my junk (why? More on that in a post coming soon). I hoped that it would work in my Ubuntu setup out of the box like most of my other hardware. I connected it to my laptop&amp;rsquo;s usb port. dmesg gave the following output:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.211333] usb 1-1: new full speed USB device using ohci_hcd and address 2
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.319698] usb 1-1: configuration #1 chosen from 1 choice
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.439705] Linux video capture interface: v2.00
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.458509] zc0301: V4L2 driver for ZC0301[P] Image Processor and Control Chip v1:1.05
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.459113] usb 1-1: ZC0301[P] Image Processor and Control Chip detected (vid/pid 0x0AC8/0x301B)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.520576] usb 1-1: PB-0330 image sensor detected
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.870287] usb 1-1: Initialization succeeded
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.870919] usb 1-1: V4L2 device registered as /dev/video0
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.871001] usbcore: registered new interface driver zc0301
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.913737] usbcore: registered new interface driver gspca
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.913811] ubuntu/media/gspcav1/gspca_core.c: gspca driver 01.00.12 registered
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Great! Everything set up, I thought. But running various programs, camorama, camE, kopete, everything gave weird errors like &amp;ldquo;Connection could not be made&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;device not ready&amp;rdquo; or just showed a blank screen. But soon, after  few trial and errors, I found the solution. Basically the &amp;ldquo;zc0301&amp;rdquo; module is the culprit and all you have to do to get your camera working is prevent it from loading. So, this is what I did:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>sudo modprobe -r gspca
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>sudo modprobe -r zc0301
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>sudo modprobe gspca
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>And voila! the webcam started working like magic. Of course, this tip is only for webcams that use this particular chip. And if you want to make this change permanent so that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to run these commands everytime you want to use your webcam, all you have to do is add the following line to your /etc/modprobe.d/blacklist file&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>blacklist zc0301&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This would prevent the module from loading whenever you connect your webcam to your computer. Let me know if this worked for you or if you have some of your own tips/tricks/hacks to get this or other webcams working on linux.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Windows App Alternatives For Linux: MSPaint</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/28/windows-app-alternatives-for-linux-mspaint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2008 15:30:44 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/28/windows-app-alternatives-for-linux-mspaint/</guid><description>Some of you might know that I was in the hunt for a decent mspaint alternative recently. Note that I didn&amp;rsquo;t go for GIMP / Inkscape etc because they were overkill for what I wanted to do. Many a times, I just wanted to touch up a screenshot or make a simple flow image by drawing a few boxes, use a few pointing arrows, and add some text here and there.</description><content>&lt;p>Some of you might know that I was in the hunt for a decent mspaint alternative &lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/03/wanted-a-good-paint-program-for-linux.html">recently&lt;/a>. Note that I didn&amp;rsquo;t go for GIMP / Inkscape etc because they were overkill for what I wanted to do. Many a times, I just wanted to touch up a screenshot or make a simple flow image by drawing a few boxes, use a few pointing arrows, and add some text here and there. All this could be done with the previous mentioned programs as well but took a bit more steps than I wanted (stroking the selections / paths for lines, boxes, circles, and even then, no arrows). I didn&amp;rsquo;t find an adequate replacement at the time but got it now, so thought of writing about it. Basically I came across 4 apps: tuxpaint, gpaint, kolourpaint and mtpaint. Won&amp;rsquo;t discuss tuxpaint here cuz I found it a little too kiddish.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>gpaint: (Available in Ubuntu repositories) gpaint is a very simplistic program that has a mspaint look and feel but feels a bit lacking. It can do basic procedures like basic shape selections, lines, boxes but that&amp;rsquo;s it. No polygon selections, brush, color picker, etc, and yeah no arrows. Moreover, it saves only in pngs.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/gpaint.png">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/gpaint-thumb.png" alt="gpaint screenshot">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>kolourpaint: (Available in Ubuntu Repositories) kolourpaint is very close to mspaint. Infact it does a bit more than mspaint. It has all the things that I mentioned as missing in gpaint, plus has basic image manipulation effects as well. I liked it quite a bit, but it had 2 drawbacks for me, still no arrows, and it depends on KDE/Qt libraries.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/kolourpaint.png">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/kolourpaint-thumb.png" alt="kolourpaint screenshot">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>mtpaint: (Available in Ubuntu Repositories from Gutsy onwards. Rest of the folks can search for a package on net, or find a suitable package or source &lt;a href="http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=155874&amp;amp;package_id=173703">here&lt;/a>) This is the software that got me most excited. It is actually a kind of lower-intermediate package that lies somewhere between mspaint and a very basic, poor man&amp;rsquo;s GIMP. It has all the features ok kolourpaint, (plus arrows at last :-) ), a small smattering of basic effects (gaussian, edge detection, blur, embossing), can work with gifs also (handles transparency and animation quite well). So, this is the one I would be sticking to for now.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/mtpaint.png">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/mtpaint-thumb.png" alt="mtpaint screenshot">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am using mtpaint now for my basic needs. Hope the article benefitted you as well. If I missed out on some package, then do let me know.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>5 Reasons I Like Linux (And 5 Why I Dislike It)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/19/5-reasons-i-like-linux-and-5-why-i-dislike-it/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2008 20:20:40 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/19/5-reasons-i-like-linux-and-5-why-i-dislike-it/</guid><description>Disclaimer Notes:
I wrote this because these things just came into my mind today while I was reading about the impending “Hardy Heron” release related things and saw that there is a lot of FUD being spread still. So, thought of jotting down my likes/dislikes and not making it a linux v/s windows campaign. Though at a few places, it might be necessary to compare the two just to put things into perspective.</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Disclaimer Notes:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>I wrote this because these things just came into my mind today while I was reading about the impending “Hardy Heron” release related things and saw that there is a lot of FUD being spread still. So, thought of jotting down my likes/dislikes and not making it a linux v/s windows campaign. Though at a few places, it might be necessary to compare the two just to put things into perspective.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>These are reasons why “&lt;strong>I&lt;/strong>” like/dislike Linux and not why others might like/dislike it although you might find common patterns.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Most of my recent experience is with Ubuntu these days, so most examples would be from it as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>These reasons are purely from an end-user’s perspective and not from a linux developer’s perspective. So, I’m not taking into factor that I can change the kernel (or most other things’) source code because “generally” I don’t.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>This post is quite long. And if you have a flame to send out my way (which you are most welcome to do), please read it in its entirety before doing so, because many things I say at some point have some caveats covered at another point.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>5 Reasons why I like Linux:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These reasons aren’t listed in any particular order. All of them are quite important for me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1. Light on Resources&lt;/strong>: I must say that Linux is what still keeps my more than 3 years old laptop running in a prim condition with the latest and greatest of everything from technology stand-point as well as eye-candy stuff. An example: With almost every effect of Compiz Fusion turned on, hordes of screenlets and AWN enabled, an Apache/MySQL/PHP based server running, and a dozen of other applications (firefox, nautilus, terminal, GIMP, RhythmBox, Open Office Word Processor, VLC player, etc) open, my setup consumes around 500 MB of RAM. While on the other hand, if I was using Vista, It’d have demanded atleast 1 GB of RAM just to run Aero, forget about the rest of the things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2. Cost&lt;/strong>: This is a big factor for me. Almost everything is free or atleast has a free alternative available. Most of the times I’ve found these free software to be much better than commercial software in terms of feature sets as well as stability. But even otherwise, when there are cases where the free alternative a bit lagging as compared to the commercial one (e.g. GIMP v/s Photoshop), I haven’t felt that my needs have ever outgrown the free software.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>3. Ease of Use&lt;/strong>: Doing “stuff” on linux is just so easy. By “stuff”, I mean everything from doing some normal day chores, downloading files, customizing things, automating routine tasks, etc. The backbone for this is “the terminal” (not the movie :P). I can do almost anything I want from the console. It not only saves me time and frustration in executing a program, waiting for the GUI to load and then go through a series of clicks but also allows me to batch up everything into one pretty little command. Moreover, every thing has so many options that I can configure to my liking. (More on the “options” later below)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>4. Getting Software&lt;/strong>: Getting software couldn’t be more easy.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>It generally involves typing in “sudo apt-get install &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->”, pressing enter, and that’s it. The latest version is ready to roll on your machine.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Reboots are minimal. Even after thinking for quite long, it’s very hard to recall any time when I had to “log-off” my system (let alone reboot) after installing a software (or even a driver)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Updates are automatic, and not just for the OS or a few core components, but for all the software that I installed through repositories (but not for the ones which I installed from my local deb’s or compilations, which is understandable of course)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The latest fixes/patches are available very quickly. Moreover, the revision cycle for most distros lies between 6–12 months and hence, even a complete desktop upgrade is quickly available as well (as compared to the 7 year period after which Vista came out). You can even “upgrade” to the latest distro revision without having to wipe everything, though I generally prefer a clean install.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>5. Security&lt;/strong>:Now, I agree with everyone that the reason why we don’t see many viruses for linux is because the user base is very less as compared to other OS’s but I also believe that this is not the “only” reason.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The thing is that since most of the software is open source, so exploits are found quite quickly and patched and released rapidly. While in a closed source environments, even if a white hat reports it, the exploits go on un-noticed, un-worked upon by the developers (A good example is the recent falling of Vista during the “Pwn to Own” contest because of a known but unpatched vulnerability by Adobe, not a fault of Vista in this case though but you get my drift).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The security model otherwise is also quite tight and its very hard for someone to exploit it till the time you use common sense along with it. (A linux virus can easily wipe ur “/home” without acqurining root permissions).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>5 Reasons why I dislike Linux&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These reasons irk me the most but aren’t enough for to make me move away from Linux. I mention them because getting them right would make my Linux expereince that much more joyful and probably others feels the same too. Moreover, this is not a gripe and is not a command/order to “the Linux guys” out there to fix it, because linux is of, by and for the community. And being a part of this community, I share the burden of this equally and would like to help out in making it better in whatever ways possible, developing, testing, suggesting things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**1. Getting Software: **I had mentioned about how easy it is to get software from most distros’ repositories with a single command. However, getting and installing software is also a challenge that many people face in linux. After sometime your particular version of the distro stops updating the software and will include only security fixes and such. Now, there are many good people who would backport software for your version but not all the time. You can download pacakges off the internet (debs’ for ubuntu) but they might not work because of too many inter-mingled dependencies. Compiling is another option but many times, it can spiral out of hand. I hope we can better softwares like GDebi that could make this much more easier.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**2. Options: **Earlier I listed having so many options as one of my reasons to like Linux. But, sometimes, too many options tend to get to my head. This gets even more difficult when you have too many choices but no clue about what means what and which one is the best. However, the community is continously trying to make this right. A lot of documentation projects are going on, and the mailing lists, IRC networks and other forums also give out a lot of information. Especially for Ubuntu, I find a huge community based support system which always helps me out. (PS – The Ubuntu Forums are the nicest forums you’ll ever come across. I am yet to come across a post that contains words like “RTFM” or “n00b”)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>3. Ease Of Use:&lt;/strong> Some times, just some times, the lack of a GUI for common things irks me and I wish in respect of a few things (read wi-fi) that things could “just work”. But I guess this is a trade-off that I can live with, and moreover this situation is also improving especilly due to the efforts taken by Ubuntu, Mandriva, Fedora, GNOME and KDE. (Special thanks to nm-applet ;-) ). Moreover, Hardy Heron, b43 and the latest linux kernels promise to solve the wi-fi setup issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>4. Browsing&lt;/strong>: The browsing experience on linux isn’t too great. But this is not a fault of Linux as such. This is due to companies providing adequate linux support (e.g. java plugins for 64 bit) and too many sites optimizing their code for IE. But again, there is hope for this as we can already run IE on linux (IEs4Linux) plus SUN has promised a 64 bit java firefox plugin with the next JRE.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**5. Drivers: **This is again due to companies not giving proper linux support for their hardware and not even releasing their hardware details for the OSS community to develop their own drivers. However, I can understand that giving out hardware details might not be an option for these companies considering the competition, and also proper software support might be a bit unfeasible due to a smaller consumer base. But again, more and more companies are seeing the light now and releasing proper drivers for linux, with Nvidia and ATi taking the lead (When will Creative listen?). And a special thanks to the OSS community for making working drivers despite all this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>So, this is it. After reading back through what I just wrote, I am dead sure that I will stick to Linux as the trade-offs are too meagre for me. Will you?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Download pidgin 2.4.1 For Ubuntu Feisty Fawn (amd64/x86_64)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/04/download-pidgin-241-for-ubuntu-feisty-fawn-amd64x86_64/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2008 17:19:02 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/04/download-pidgin-241-for-ubuntu-feisty-fawn-amd64x86_64/</guid><description>pidgin is everybody&amp;rsquo;s favourite IM client. Lifehacker includes it in its list of top 5 IM clients. Obviously I use it too, but one drawback of being lazy and not switching over to Gutsy Gibbon was that I was stuck with version 2.2.0 for a long time. But recently I began a new journey towards d-bus programming and chose pidgin as my companion. Found out that 2.2.0 has some serious d-bus issues on amd64 that were fixed in 2.</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/logo.pidgin.png" alt="Logo.pidgin">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>pidgin is everybody&amp;rsquo;s favourite IM client. Lifehacker includes it in its list of top 5 IM clients. Obviously I use it too, but one drawback of being lazy and not switching over to Gutsy Gibbon was that I was stuck with version 2.2.0 for a long time. But recently I began a new journey towards d-bus programming and chose pidgin as my companion. Found out that 2.2.0 has some serious d-bus issues on amd64 that were fixed in 2.4.0. Hence, installed all the dependencies, compiled the latest version today from source and installed it. Just thought of putting it out for my fellow Feisty users who are looking to upgrade as well but don&amp;rsquo;t want to go through the mess of compiling from source.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So download it from the below given link. However, since it is a relatively big package (around 8.5 MB), I might pull it if the bandwidth usage becomes too much, so download soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can install it by:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Either using &amp;ldquo;gdebi&amp;rdquo; - A nice deb package installer that will also try to resolve dependencies for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>or by running &amp;ldquo;dpkg -i pidgin_2.4.1-1_amd64.deb&amp;rdquo; on command line.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Let me know if you have any issues with it.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Wanted: A Good Paint Program For Linux</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/03/wanted-a-good-paint-program-for-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2008 12:47:23 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/03/wanted-a-good-paint-program-for-linux/</guid><description>Have been in the hunt for a good basic paint program for linux for so long. I&amp;rsquo;m running a Ubuntu Feisty Fawn (amd64) box (yeah, yeah I didn&amp;rsquo;t upgrade to Gutsy because it sneaked up too quickly onto me and the impending loom of LTS goodness of Hardy was also there). Have been suggested various things so far like GPaint, Kolourpaint, tuxpaint etc but none of them cuts it.
Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, I love GIMP but its an overkill when I have to go through 2 menus, a dialogue box and several clicks, just to make a silly rectangle, but I don&amp;rsquo;t hold anything against it cuz afterall its an &amp;ldquo;Image Manipulation&amp;rdquo; program, not a painting one.</description><content>&lt;p>Have been in the hunt for a good basic paint program for linux for so long. I&amp;rsquo;m running a Ubuntu Feisty Fawn (amd64) box (yeah, yeah I didn&amp;rsquo;t upgrade to Gutsy because it sneaked up too quickly onto me and the impending loom of LTS goodness of Hardy was also there). Have been suggested various things so far like GPaint, Kolourpaint, tuxpaint etc but none of them cuts it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, I love GIMP but its an overkill when I have to go through 2 menus, a dialogue box and several clicks, just to make a silly rectangle, but I don&amp;rsquo;t hold anything against it cuz afterall its an &amp;ldquo;Image Manipulation&amp;rdquo; program, not a painting one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, what do you use/recommend when you have to draw a few basic shapes, connect them through lines and arrows, put in a mashup of few silly pics and colorize it a bit with basic effects? And are there any gnome native ones or do I ultimately have to give in to install KDE dependencies?&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Project: Shantz Copy Basket (Compatible with linux as well as windows)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/16/project-shantz-copy-basket-compatible-with-linux-as-well-as-windows/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2008 13:26:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/16/project-shantz-copy-basket-compatible-with-linux-as-well-as-windows/</guid><description>I’m sure you have copied/moved files on your computer from one place to another. And I’m sure often you have to do more than just “single-shot” copying that is copy a few files to one place, move a few to another, and copy yet some more to one more location. Well, I had to do this quite a few times (e.g. I ran out of disk space recently on a partition and had to empty out my “Movies” and “Songs” folders to move a few movies/songs each to all other partitions/disks according to the space available).</description><content>&lt;p>I’m sure you have copied/moved files on your computer from one place to another. And I’m sure often you have to do more than just “single-shot” copying that is copy a few files to one place, move a few to another, and copy yet some more to one more location. Well, I had to do this quite a few times (e.g. I ran out of disk space recently on a partition and had to empty out my “Movies” and “Songs” folders to move a few movies/songs each to all other partitions/disks according to the space available). Hence, I wrote this little command line program, which behaves like a basket.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can put any number of files from any number of different locations into it in a single shot. It will store their locations and give them an ID. Now, you can copy/move those files to different destinations based on their IDs. What&amp;rsquo;s even better is that your basket will remain intact even across reboots. So, you can continue working on the files in the basket even for days.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Note: **Packages for windows as well as linux have been uploaded. If you have perl, a perl script is also given that works in both platforms without change. I have tested it on Windows XP SP2 and Ubuntu Feisty Fawn 7.04.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Ubuntu TIP: Extending Nautilus, Scripting Your Way To UI Bliss</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/09/ubuntu-tip-extending-nautilus-scripting-your-way-to-ui-bliss/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2008 16:10:18 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/09/ubuntu-tip-extending-nautilus-scripting-your-way-to-ui-bliss/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m back from my vacation and this is a smallish post before we return to our regular programming (I&amp;rsquo;m full of puns ).
Rahul (my friend and guest author on this blog) introduced me to an old-but-useful trick a few days ago that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about. It&amp;rsquo;s about customizing nautilus to display a context menu that has a few of your chosen scripts to weave their magic on the selected object.</description><content>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m back from my vacation and this is a smallish post before we return to our regular programming (I&amp;rsquo;m full of puns &lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/smile3.gif" alt=""> ).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rahul (my friend and guest author on this blog) introduced me to an old-but-useful trick a few days ago that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about. It&amp;rsquo;s about customizing nautilus to display a context menu that has a few of your chosen scripts to weave their magic on the selected object. And the procedure to do this is summarized in just two steps:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Write your script.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Save it in ~/.gnome2/nautilus-scripts and make it executable&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Of course, if you don&amp;rsquo;t know scripting the first step itself is quite daunting, but you can get a lot of pre-cooked scripts on the internet by searching for &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;amp;q=nautilus+scripts&amp;amp;btnG=Google+Search">nautilus scripts&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo;. e.g. take a look at &lt;a href="http://g-scripts.sourceforge.net/">g-scripts homepage&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To get you started immediately, here is a crude example to open a terminal/console window in any folder/path through right-click menu:&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Step 1) Write your script (any scripting language: shell, perl, python, etc):&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Step 2) Save it in ~/.gnome2/nautilus-scripts, name it as &amp;ldquo;Terminal&amp;rdquo; and make it executable.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Step 3) Now, you should see a &amp;ldquo;Scripts&amp;rdquo; option in your right-click menu as shown below. Clicking on &amp;ldquo;Terminal&amp;rdquo; will open a new terminal window with the present working directory being set to the selected folder.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/nautilus_scripts.png">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/nautilus_scripts_thumb.jpg" alt="Nautilus_scripts">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note:&lt;/strong> If you don&amp;rsquo;t see the &amp;ldquo;scripts&amp;rdquo; menu option (or your script name in the extended menu), then just run&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Let me know if you face any problems with this or have any other questions.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote></content></item><item><title>Ubuntu TIP: Automating Package Installation – apt-get to the rescue</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/06/ubuntu-tip-automating-package-installation--apt-get-to-the-rescue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2008 03:30:20 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/06/ubuntu-tip-automating-package-installation--apt-get-to-the-rescue/</guid><description>Admin Note: Rahul is a long time friend of mine, and is a well known geek amongst his friends and colleagues. I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce that he will be enriching this site from time-to-time as a guest editor/author. First up is a small tid-bit of a script that he wrote to ease up his life between installations and reinstallations of everyone&amp;rsquo;s favourite OS: Ubuntu. Over to his post..
Have you ever had to reinstall your ubuntu installation, and then bear the pain of manually installing the applications you&amp;rsquo;ve come to love (i mean use :)) everyday?</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Admin Note:&lt;/strong> Rahul is a long time friend of mine, and is a well known geek amongst his friends and colleagues. I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce that he will be enriching this site from time-to-time as a guest editor/author. First up is a small tid-bit of a script that he wrote to ease up his life between installations and reinstallations of everyone&amp;rsquo;s favourite OS: Ubuntu. Over to his post..&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have you ever had to reinstall your ubuntu installation, and then bear the pain of manually installing the applications you&amp;rsquo;ve come to love (i mean use :)) everyday? If yes, then cheer up buddy, because all you really need is some magic (read scripting), some typing and spend some time digging the package names of your favourite applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To get started, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to type the package information in a configuration file. The format of the file is really simple&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Any line starting with a # is ignored&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Blank lines are ignored&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Any other line, the first word is taken as the package name you want to install&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>In case you do not specify the configFile (e.g. package-names.lst), it will bug you to manually enter packages names :D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What this script does is&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>read package names from the file specified (or bug user for package names in case filename is not specified)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>install these packages&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s it. And if everything runs fine, you should have a system will all your beloved apps installed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The below snippet from the sample configuration file would install the packages – hardinfo, gmountiso, devilspie and nautilus-open-terminal. The lines for sysinfo and istanbul would be ignored. In case you later wish to install these packages, all you need to do is uncomment the line, and run the script again :).&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Note:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>The script will fail in case the package cannot be found using the repositories enabled on your system.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>In case you use additional repositories, you must add these manually to your apt configuration file, and do&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>The hard part is not the installation, but setting up the applications to your likings :D&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote></content></item><item><title>TIP: Switching Soundcards In Ubuntu</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/12/tip-switching-soundcards-in-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2008 18:00:47 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/12/tip-switching-soundcards-in-ubuntu/</guid><description>If you have multiple soundcards in your system and have to switch between them regularly (e.g. laptop owners like me, who use an external soundcard while being docked to groove to the highest and the lowest of frequencies through those 7.1 channels and use the in-built sound card while on the move) you would definitely be under-whelmed by the less-than-stellar performance of ubuntu in switching between the sound cards. For me at least, ubuntu (fiesty 7.</description><content>&lt;p>If you have multiple soundcards in your system and have to switch between them regularly (e.g. laptop owners like me, who use an external soundcard while being docked to groove to the highest and the lowest of frequencies through those 7.1 channels and use the in-built sound card while on the move) you would definitely be under-whelmed by the less-than-stellar performance of ubuntu in switching between the sound cards. For me at least, ubuntu (fiesty 7.04 amd64) never seems to recognize that I&amp;rsquo;ve connected the speakers to my Audigy 2 ZS Notebook PCMCIA card, and merrily continues to huff-puff through the tinny laptop speakers until I manually go into the sound preferences, switch over to multichannel playback and vice versa. Well, I still haven&amp;rsquo;t found an automated solution for the switching, but here is a little cli-magic to do this in a click.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have alsa on ur system, just use the command &amp;ldquo;asoundconf list&amp;rdquo; first to list out all the soundcards connected to your system. e.g. on my system, the output is&lt;/p>
&lt;p>$asoundconf list&lt;br>
IXP&lt;br>
AUDIGY2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here, IXP is my internal sound card and AUDIGY2 is my external (PCMCIA) sound card. Now, all you need to is use &amp;ldquo;asoundconf set-default-card &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&amp;rdquo; to switch over to any card desired. So, what I did was make 2 bash scripts, and insert this command in them with each having one of my soundcards&amp;rsquo; names.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>script 1 - setixp.sh&lt;/p>
&lt;p>#!/bin/bash&lt;br>
asoundconf set-default-card IXP&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Similarly, script 2 - setaudigy.sh&lt;/p>
&lt;p>#!/bin/bash&lt;br>
asoundconf set-default-card AUDIGY2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, all that remains is save the two scripts (maybe in ur home directory or ur desktop), and make them executable (use &amp;ldquo;chmod +x &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&amp;rdquo;). Now, whenever you want to switch to a card, just double-click on the appropriate script, and watch the sound getting redirected. oops, make that &amp;ldquo;hear&amp;rdquo; the sound :P.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Ubuntu Nuggets: Window list settings in panel</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/01/ubuntu-nuggets-window-list-settings-in-panel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 19:06:13 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/01/ubuntu-nuggets-window-list-settings-in-panel/</guid><description>I am pretty sure that all of you must be fed of that one windows taking up the whole task bar in the panel. Like this:
Well, you can change that. Plus, all you windows-to-linux converts must also be thinking of how to squeeze in a few more windows into the task bar. A &amp;ldquo;grouping of similar windows&amp;rdquo; option like windows would have been just nice. Well, that can be done too, and without any shell scripting, config file modifying, etc.</description><content>&lt;p>I am pretty sure that all of you must be fed of that one windows taking up the whole task bar in the panel. Like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/titlebar1.jpg">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/titlebar1_thumb.jpg" alt="Titlebar1">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, you can change that. Plus, all you windows-to-linux converts must also be thinking of how to squeeze in a few more windows into the task bar. A &amp;ldquo;grouping of similar windows&amp;rdquo; option like windows would have been just nice. Well, that can be done too, and without any shell scripting, config file modifying, etc. It&amp;rsquo;s all in the GUI for a change &lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/smile1.gif" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All you need to do is:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Right click on the window list area, as shown by the red ellipse mark in the figure and click on &amp;ldquo;preferences&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/titlebar2.jpg">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/titlebar2_thumb.jpg" alt="Titlebar2">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>You will get a window as shown below. Now, in the options marked by the black ellipse, you can choose the grouping option for the windows that you open to get more space and a windows like effect.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/window_list_pref1.jpg">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/window_list_pref1_thumb.jpg" alt="Window_list_pref1">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>If you click on the &amp;ldquo;size&amp;rdquo; tab, you can modify the &amp;ldquo;maximum&amp;rdquo; width value to control how much space any window title can take on the title bar. You can also specify the minimum width if you wish to.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/window_list_pref2.jpg">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/window_list_pref2_thumb.jpg" alt="Window_list_pref2">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="4">
&lt;li>Click Close and you are done. Now, wasn&amp;rsquo;t that easy. Here is a screenshot of how that window title we saw in the first pic looks after this change.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/titlebar.jpg">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/titlebar_thumb.jpg" alt="Titlebar">&lt;/a>&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>BlogJet - Blog Faster, Blog Better (Now In Linux too, with a hidden bonus)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/29/blogjet-blog-faster-blog-better-now-in-linux-too-with-a-hidden-bonus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2008 15:30:27 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/29/blogjet-blog-faster-blog-better-now-in-linux-too-with-a-hidden-bonus/</guid><description>A quick googling for best desktop blogging client would yield just a few (read millions/gazillions) results. Having researched the subject a lot, my choices were finally limited down to BlogJet and BlogDesk, as per my feature set requirement goes (Primarily, off line editing, draft, WYSIWYG editing, categories, tagging support, pinging, trackbacks support, timestamping, past post editing, automatic image uploading) BUT there is one little problem. Both of these don’t work on Linux.</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/blogjet_in_linux.png">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/blogjet_in_linux.png">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/blogjet_in_linux_thumb1.jpg" alt="Blogjet_in_linux">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A quick googling for &lt;em>&lt;a href="http://www.google.co.in/search?q=best+desktop+blogging+client&amp;amp;ie=utf-8&amp;amp;oe=utf-8&amp;amp;aq=t&amp;amp;rls=com.ubuntu:en-US:official&amp;amp;client=firefox-a">best desktop blogging client&lt;/a>&lt;/em> would yield just a few (read millions/gazillions) results. Having researched the subject a lot, my choices were finally limited down to &lt;a href="http://www.codingrobots.com/blogjet/">BlogJet&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.blogdesk.org/en/index.htm">BlogDesk&lt;/a>, as per my feature set requirement goes (Primarily, off line editing, draft, WYSIWYG editing, categories, tagging support, pinging, trackbacks support, timestamping, past post editing, automatic image uploading) BUT there is one little problem. Both of these don’t work on Linux.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>In fact, the current crop of Linux based blog clients is at best childish, compared to these. A piece of software called &lt;a href="http://www.larryborsato.com/bleezer/">Bleezer&lt;/a> did offer a good set of features and supported linux as well, but turned out it was so crash-y, hogged up enormous amounts of ram, and had other issues that come usually packed with all java apps. But I wasn’t gonna boot into WinDUHs, just for one sole software, was I?? Sure, I wasn’t &lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/smile1.gif" alt="">. I tried the usual routine of trying to run them through wine but it wasn’t supported. I resorted to my faithful ol’ google, and chanced across &lt;a href="http://www.thetechandcents.com/2007/11/running-zoundry-blog-editor-under-wine.html">this little nugget&lt;/a>, with step by step instructions to achieve my goal. And it had a bonus. It told me about &lt;a href="http://www.tatanka.com.br/ies4linux/page/Main_Page">IEs4Linux&lt;/a> (IE’s For Linux). yes, you read correctly. You can run Internet Explorer on your Linux box as well. All this in under 10 minutes (Ubuntu wins again). And yeah, don’t forget to say thanks to me (and &lt;a href="http://www.thetechandcents.com/2007/11/running-zoundry-blog-editor-under-wine.html">Alex&lt;/a> as well).&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>