<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Performance on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/performance/</link><description>Recent content in Performance on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 11:14:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/performance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HTC Video Drivers: But This Is Not A Post About HTC</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/26/htc-video-drivers-but-this-is-not-a-post-about-htc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 11:14:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/26/htc-video-drivers-but-this-is-not-a-post-about-htc/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a post about irresponsible/careless journalism/bloggism. For Gizmodo, getting that post about HTC’s latest press release out the door took precedence over actually **reading **the release properly and then commenting over it. The gizmodo poster’s comment is:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>……but HTC&amp;rsquo;s finally released a statement saying that a fix is coming. They say that the &lt;strong>video acceleration &lt;em>will&lt;/em> be supported in the future, and will be included in software upgrades for current devices&lt;/strong>…….&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>This is a post about irresponsible/careless journalism/bloggism. For Gizmodo, getting that post about HTC’s latest press release out the door took precedence over actually **reading **the release properly and then commenting over it. The gizmodo poster’s comment is:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>……but HTC&amp;rsquo;s finally released a statement saying that a fix is coming. They say that the &lt;strong>video acceleration &lt;em>will&lt;/em> be supported in the future, and will be included in software upgrades for current devices&lt;/strong>…….&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I’m still puzzled, after reading and rereading HTC’s (pretty short) statement 10 times over and I can’t find where it is mentioned that they will provide video acceleration for the current devices. My point is that if you don’t read it yourself, then better not release it to your readers, (or atleast refrain from commenting on it improperly, if you must be ahead in the “race”).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Read the statement below (and for actual post on Gizmodo, click &lt;a href="http://gizmodo.com/360514/htc-says-software-fix-is-coming-for-lousy-video-drivers">here&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Some of our top engineers have investigated video performance on our devices and have discovered a fix that they claim will dramatically improve performance for common on-screen tasks like scrolling and the like. Their fix would help most of our recent touch-screen products including the Touch family of devices and TYTN II / Tilt, Mogul / XV6900. The update is in testing and we hope to release it soon. However this fix is not a new video driver to utilize hardware acceleration; it is a software optimization. Video drivers are a much more complicated issue that involves companies and engineers beyond HTC alone. We do not want to lead anyone to believe they should expect these. To explain why we are not releasing video acceleration instead of the optimization I offer you our official statement&amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;HTC DOES plan to offer software upgrades that will increase feature functionality, over the air wireless speeds and other enhancements for some of the phones being criticized, but we do not anticipate including any additional support for the video acceleration issues cited in customer complaints. It is important for customers to understand that bringing this functionality to market is not a trivial driver update and requires extensive software development and time. HTC will utilize hardware video acceleration like the ATI Imageon in many upcoming products. Our users have made it clear that they expect our products to offer an improved visual experience, and we have included this feedback into planning and development of future products. To address lingering questions about HTC&amp;rsquo;s current MSM 7xxx devices, it is important to establish that a chipset like an MSM7xxx is a platform with a vast multitude of features that enable a wide range of devices with varied functionality. It is common that devices built on platforms like Qualcomm&amp;rsquo;s will not enable every feature or function. In addition to making sure the required hardware is present, unlocking extended capabilities of chipsets like the MSM 7xxx requires in-depth and time consuming software development, complicated licensing negotiations, potential intellectual property negotiations, added licensing fees, and in the case of devices that are sold through operators, the desire of the operator to include the additional functionality. To make an informed decision about which handset suits them best, consumers should look at the product specification itself instead of using the underlying chipset specifications to define what the product could potentially become.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The video drivers for HTC Wizard are now out. They are in beta stage but are working fine for me. You can find them &lt;a href="http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=364066">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></content></item></channel></rss>