<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>permissions on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/permissions/</link><description>Recent content in permissions on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2010 19:44:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/permissions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Solving The Android Permissions And Malware Puzzle</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/13/android-permissions-malware/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2010 19:44:59 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/13/android-permissions-malware/</guid><description>There has been a spate of security reports recently about Android apps being malware or suspicious. Most of these were found baseless but at least one was indeed correct (e.g. The Russian Trojan app). We also know that Android has a very good security model but even then, the rest of the reports also makes one think and focus on why an apps requires the permissions that it states it needs?</description></item><item><title>Android vs iPhone: Security Models</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/25/android-vs-iphone-security-models/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2010 22:02:49 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/25/android-vs-iphone-security-models/</guid><description>Android and iPhone OS (iOS) have been at loggerheads for quite some time now. This is a take on which has a better security model to protect its users. I thought of writing it up because there have been a lot of discussions around me lately about which platform is more secure and I keep repeating the same points over and over at every one of them, so thought that in future I&amp;rsquo;ll just point them to this page :P</description></item><item><title>Migrating From PHP4 To PHP5: Solving WP-Cache (and maybe other) Issues</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/07/migrating-from-php4-to-php5-solving-wp-cache-and-maybe-other-issues/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2008 13:37:17 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/07/migrating-from-php4-to-php5-solving-wp-cache-and-maybe-other-issues/</guid><description>Situation: You are migrating your WordPress blog from PHP4 to PHP5 (intentionally or being forced to as you web host won&amp;rsquo;t support PHP4 anymore). Most of the times, this is as simple as adding some simple lines to .htaccess (e.g. AddHandler application/x-httpd-php5 .php ). And you might not notice any issues. But many of you still do. The issues range from weird page layouts, to some controls not working, to some errors popping up here and there, and probably your blog not even displaying.</description></item></channel></rss>