<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>firefox on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/firefox/</link><description>Recent content in firefox on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2008 16:59:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/firefox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Firefox Incognito / Private Browsing Mode - Part II</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/11/firefox-incognito-private-browsing-mode-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2008 16:59:33 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/11/firefox-incognito-private-browsing-mode-part-ii/</guid><description>A few people (e.g. Varun) told me my previous post differed from the way how google chrome / Microsoft IE8 handle Incognito (Private Browsing) mode. The main consideration was that while chrome/IE8 don't write anything to disk at all, the firefox method is an after-effect, i.e., writing to disk and then clearing it up while closing the window. Well, true but nothing is non-rectificable :). So this is a post about a method that one can use to go &amp;ldquo;really&amp;rdquo; undercover with firefox.</description></item><item><title>Firefox Incognito Mode Is Here: Move Over Chrome/IE8</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/10/firefox-incognito-mode-is-here-move-over-chromeie8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2008 17:49:41 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/10/firefox-incognito-mode-is-here-move-over-chromeie8/</guid><description>Update: Part 2 of this post is now up here to allay some of the drawbacks that were pointed out.
There has been so much hype over the “Incognito” (or Private Browsing) mode of Google Chrome / Microsoft IE8, with many internet users screeming Hallelujiah. But I don’t understand what the hoopla is all about. This mode has always been there in Mozilla firefox as well. You just need to devote less than one minute (yes, you read that right, less than one minute) to set it up.</description></item><item><title>Page Rank 7: True Or Google Glitch?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/30/page-rank-7-true-or-google-glitch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2008 20:33:51 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/30/page-rank-7-true-or-google-glitch/</guid><description>I installed google toolbar (linux version) today in firefox and for this blog, it says that its page rank is 7. I can't believe my eyes. I suppose it's a google glitch may be (but have a wishful thinking at the back of mind that its true :-) ).
Are you getting the same result for this blog (or weird page rank results for other places that you frequent?)</description></item><item><title>5 Reasons I Like Linux (And 5 Why I Dislike It)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/19/5-reasons-i-like-linux-and-5-why-i-dislike-it/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2008 20:20:40 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/19/5-reasons-i-like-linux-and-5-why-i-dislike-it/</guid><description>Disclaimer Notes:
I wrote this because these things just came into my mind today while I was reading about the impending “Hardy Heron” release related things and saw that there is a lot of FUD being spread still. So, thought of jotting down my likes/dislikes and not making it a linux v/s windows campaign. Though at a few places, it might be necessary to compare the two just to put things into perspective.</description></item></channel></rss>