<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Themes on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/themes/</link><description>Recent content in Themes on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2008 20:49:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/themes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Project: Windows Mobile Tool ShantzTodayChanger Updated to version 1.53</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/22/project-windows-mobile-tool-shantztodaychanger-updated-to-version-153/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2008 20:49:17 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/22/project-windows-mobile-tool-shantztodaychanger-updated-to-version-153/</guid><description>ShantzTodayChanger is a little tool written by me for your Windows Mobile based phones (WM5/WM6) which will cycle ur today background or theme after a set interval of time. It has a lot of features and options and you can even use it to achieve something other than changing wallpapers as well (e.g. running applications at set times) but that depends on your imagination.
Changes in this version:
1.53 - 23-March-08 -&amp;gt; RECOMMENDED UPDATE</description></item><item><title>Idea Factory: Some Of My Latest Musings</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/01/idea-factory-some-of-my-latest-wonderings/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 03:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/01/idea-factory-some-of-my-latest-wonderings/</guid><description>jeffro2pt0 has a little contest going on his blog, giving out coupons to wpdesigners.com which lets you get atleast 12 WordPress themes for just 5$. Only thing you have to do is give a unique idea that could help improve wordpress. Now, I don’t want anymore themes (actually I’m a cheap-skate who can’t spend even 5$ for a theme, unless one of you decides to get me one ), but I got a few ideas instantly.</description></item><item><title>Project: ShantzTodayChanger (Windows Mobile Tool To Cycle Themes/Wallpapers Automatically)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/project-shantztodaychanger-windows-mobile-tool-to-cycle-themeswallpapers-automatically/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 19:45:07 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/project-shantztodaychanger-windows-mobile-tool-to-cycle-themeswallpapers-automatically/</guid><description>The newly launched [&amp;ldquo;Projects&amp;rdquo;] section is hereby inaugarated with a Windows Mobile Tool developed by me, called “[ShantzTodayChanger]”. This is a little tool for your Windows Mobile based phones (Compatible with WM5/WM6 but not WM2003) which will cycle ur today background or theme after a set interval of time. It has a lot of features and options that you can discover by reading the text below. And you can even use this options to achieve something other than changing wallpapers as well but that depends on your imagination.</description></item></channel></rss>