<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Feisty Fawn on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/feisty-fawn/</link><description>Recent content in Feisty Fawn on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2008 17:19:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/feisty-fawn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Download pidgin 2.4.1 For Ubuntu Feisty Fawn (amd64/x86_64)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/04/download-pidgin-241-for-ubuntu-feisty-fawn-amd64x86_64/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2008 17:19:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/04/download-pidgin-241-for-ubuntu-feisty-fawn-amd64x86_64/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/logo.pidgin.png" alt="Logo.pidgin">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>pidgin is everybody&amp;rsquo;s favourite IM client. Lifehacker includes it in its list of top 5 IM clients. Obviously I use it too, but one drawback of being lazy and not switching over to Gutsy Gibbon was that I was stuck with version 2.2.0 for a long time. But recently I began a new journey towards d-bus programming and chose pidgin as my companion. Found out that 2.2.0 has some serious d-bus issues on amd64 that were fixed in 2.4.0. Hence, installed all the dependencies, compiled the latest version today from source and installed it. Just thought of putting it out for my fellow Feisty users who are looking to upgrade as well but don&amp;rsquo;t want to go through the mess of compiling from source.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/logo.pidgin.png" alt="Logo.pidgin">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>pidgin is everybody&amp;rsquo;s favourite IM client. Lifehacker includes it in its list of top 5 IM clients. Obviously I use it too, but one drawback of being lazy and not switching over to Gutsy Gibbon was that I was stuck with version 2.2.0 for a long time. But recently I began a new journey towards d-bus programming and chose pidgin as my companion. Found out that 2.2.0 has some serious d-bus issues on amd64 that were fixed in 2.4.0. Hence, installed all the dependencies, compiled the latest version today from source and installed it. Just thought of putting it out for my fellow Feisty users who are looking to upgrade as well but don&amp;rsquo;t want to go through the mess of compiling from source.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So download it from the below given link. However, since it is a relatively big package (around 8.5 MB), I might pull it if the bandwidth usage becomes too much, so download soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can install it by:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Either using &amp;ldquo;gdebi&amp;rdquo; - A nice deb package installer that will also try to resolve dependencies for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>or by running &amp;ldquo;dpkg -i pidgin_2.4.1-1_amd64.deb&amp;rdquo; on command line.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Let me know if you have any issues with it.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Project: Shantz Copy Basket (Compatible with linux as well as windows)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/16/project-shantz-copy-basket-compatible-with-linux-as-well-as-windows/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2008 13:26:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/16/project-shantz-copy-basket-compatible-with-linux-as-well-as-windows/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m sure you have copied/moved files on your computer from one place to another. And I’m sure often you have to do more than just “single-shot” copying that is copy a few files to one place, move a few to another, and copy yet some more to one more location. Well, I had to do this quite a few times (e.g. I ran out of disk space recently on a partition and had to empty out my “Movies” and “Songs” folders to move a few movies/songs each to all other partitions/disks according to the space available). Hence, I wrote this little command line program, which behaves like a basket.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>I’m sure you have copied/moved files on your computer from one place to another. And I’m sure often you have to do more than just “single-shot” copying that is copy a few files to one place, move a few to another, and copy yet some more to one more location. Well, I had to do this quite a few times (e.g. I ran out of disk space recently on a partition and had to empty out my “Movies” and “Songs” folders to move a few movies/songs each to all other partitions/disks according to the space available). Hence, I wrote this little command line program, which behaves like a basket.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can put any number of files from any number of different locations into it in a single shot. It will store their locations and give them an ID. Now, you can copy/move those files to different destinations based on their IDs. What&amp;rsquo;s even better is that your basket will remain intact even across reboots. So, you can continue working on the files in the basket even for days.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Note: **Packages for windows as well as linux have been uploaded. If you have perl, a perl script is also given that works in both platforms without change. I have tested it on Windows XP SP2 and Ubuntu Feisty Fawn 7.04.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>