<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in Linux on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 16:55:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apple, Anti-Malware, Patents</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/02/15/apple-anti-malware-patents/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 16:55:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/02/15/apple-anti-malware-patents/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently, there has been this trend. Blogs look for patents filed by companies and then report on each of them as if they are second coming of Jesus in technology. Especially if it is Apple who is doing the filings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few days ago, this &lt;a href="http://www.zdnet.com/apples-new-wave-anti-malware-patent-takes-a-leaf-out-of-qubes-book-7000011118/">new patent&lt;/a> showed up about Apple&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;new wave approach to fighting malware&amp;rdquo; with the author giving up half-researched commentary on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was intrigued by this news (if you can call it that), not because it’s something new but instead because process isolation is hardly a new concept. The author mentions &amp;ldquo;Qubes OS&amp;rdquo; as the one to be original inventor before Apple but in fact, it has been used for years (eg chrooting/containers in linux) and more popular recently in Android’s uid based approach. Even Qualcomm (and other SoC vendors) have stuff that helps in this space with Trustzone based isolation between processor entities at hardware level.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>Recently, there has been this trend. Blogs look for patents filed by companies and then report on each of them as if they are second coming of Jesus in technology. Especially if it is Apple who is doing the filings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few days ago, this &lt;a href="http://www.zdnet.com/apples-new-wave-anti-malware-patent-takes-a-leaf-out-of-qubes-book-7000011118/">new patent&lt;/a> showed up about Apple&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;new wave approach to fighting malware&amp;rdquo; with the author giving up half-researched commentary on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was intrigued by this news (if you can call it that), not because it’s something new but instead because process isolation is hardly a new concept. The author mentions &amp;ldquo;Qubes OS&amp;rdquo; as the one to be original inventor before Apple but in fact, it has been used for years (eg chrooting/containers in linux) and more popular recently in Android’s uid based approach. Even Qualcomm (and other SoC vendors) have stuff that helps in this space with Trustzone based isolation between processor entities at hardware level.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, I wanted to check out what’s new here (which was not immediately clear and probably no one else tried to see it because the patent link is wrong in the article and it links to some display patent, not the one in question). The correct patent is this: &lt;a href="http://www.freepatentsonline.com/RE43987.html">http://www.freepatentsonline.com/RE43987.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After going through the mangled language that any patent embodies, it is clear that “conceptually” it is similar to what has been done till now, but the approach is different. On the whole, the basic difference seems to be that linux uses chrooting, android uses separate users, Qubes adds a virtualization layer to achieve the above and Apple goes one further (not necessarily better) and makes it real/physical separate processor instead of a virtual one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, I’m still not sold on this and it doesn’t seem foolproof. (I’m not a security expert by any means, so please take the below with a tablespoon full of salt and you are free to add corrections or throw me out the window ;) ) In fact, it doesn’t seem much better than the current system but has an add-on of cost (extra physical processor, dedicated circuitry/components) and losing ease of use. Some points to be noted:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The burden is still mostly on user. The user still needs to keep all his anti-malware programs updated all the time and be alert for each indication on the system and allow/disallow things to happen in system all the time to keep it protected. This approach is not going to save the system in any way if any of the above steps falter. Which is, pretty similar to what we see today.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The approach does not mention aversion of several crucial points:&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>a. If processor P2 itself is compromised by the malware, then it is rendered useless in the scenario where P2 itself is tasked with scanning the memory/files on Memory M2 for malware. It can be made to just report “all clean” by malware as the scanning engine running on P2 is still accessible by network content in the same way it would have been on P1 in a non-dual-processor system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b. P2 is connected to the video display subsystem and this can be used to malware’s advantage to trick user into clicking on wrong areas or doing wrong things in the same way as it is today&lt;/p>
&lt;p>c. It says keypresses can be encrypted by P1 and decrypted by Network device 190 to allow P2 to not know what was pressed. But this again seems to not require the above approach. First, it requires a special network device now, not a generic one as mentioned in the patent. Second, since the network device itself needs to be configurable now for this, there is another attack vector there. This is, however, somewhat similar to what existing SoC solutions do in mobile space but that is better/feasible because the other end is a software entity and the mechanics of how it works is different.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>d. For online gaming etc, where the influx of data is huge and needs to be processed in real time, P1 takes this data directly from M2 once P2 signals availability. Not sure, how is this different then from having a single processor system without the above isolation?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>e. Several other things which I can keep typing about till my keys wear out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>TL;DR&lt;/strong>: This patent on its own may be a new idea (rather a new twist to an existing concept) but it is hardly something that can be put into practice and maybe the reason why Apple hasn’t actually produced anything with this, yet. It might become better with other ideas coupled (which Apple may have filed separate patents for but are currently unknown).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aside: Why do patents cite archaic things? Every patent gives examples of some old stuff. E.g. Even though this patent was filed in 2011, it refers to Pentium 4 as an example of processors and Quake 3 Arena as an example of online games?&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Bugs: What you see is not always what it is</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2012/07/23/bugs-what-you-see-is-not-always-what-it-is/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 04:46:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2012/07/23/bugs-what-you-see-is-not-always-what-it-is/</guid><description>&lt;p>Came across a neat nugget of historical information today that &lt;a href="http://www.ibiblio.org/harris/500milemail.html">yet again&lt;/a> proves that the software/hardware bug behavior that you may see on the surface might imply something totally opposite to what the problem actually is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &amp;ldquo;bug&amp;rdquo; existed back in the old times of the floppy drives. These drives seemed to fail very quickly on linux systems compared to MS DOS/Windows. Now, a normal observer would say linux had bad handling of the drives or was doing something messy that made these drives crap out ever so often. But as it turned out, the issue was the complete opposite. The real reason behind this problem was that linux was rock solid and stable compared to MS Dos.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>Came across a neat nugget of historical information today that &lt;a href="http://www.ibiblio.org/harris/500milemail.html">yet again&lt;/a> proves that the software/hardware bug behavior that you may see on the surface might imply something totally opposite to what the problem actually is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &amp;ldquo;bug&amp;rdquo; existed back in the old times of the floppy drives. These drives seemed to fail very quickly on linux systems compared to MS DOS/Windows. Now, a normal observer would say linux had bad handling of the drives or was doing something messy that made these drives crap out ever so often. But as it turned out, the issue was the complete opposite. The real reason behind this problem was that linux was rock solid and stable compared to MS Dos.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Woah!! Hold on a minute, you say. How can being stable lead to hardware failure? Well, since DOS used to crash (or had to be rebooted) so often, it used to do a check on the floppy at boot up which used to shake up any dust on the drive. Since no such frequent reboots were required in linux, it caused a dust build up on the drive ultimately leading to it&amp;rsquo;s premature demise :(. Solution: A special program &amp;ldquo;diskseekd&amp;rdquo; whose sole purpose was to check the disk periodically to shake the dust out of the system and keep it happily working. Learned something nice today, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? :) Below is an excerpt frm the man page of diskseekd&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Several people have noticed that Linux has a bad tendency of killing floppy drives. These failures remained completely mysterious, until somebody noticed that they were due to huge layers of dust accumulating in the floppy drives. This cannot happen under Messy Dos, because this excuse for an operating system is so unstable that it crashes roughly every 20 minutes (actually less if you are running Windows). When rebooting, the BIOS seeks the drive, and by doing this, it shakes the dust out of the drive mechanism. diskseekd simulates this effect by seeking the drive periodically. If it is called as diskseek, the drive is seeked only once.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></content></item><item><title>Remote Bandwidth Stats</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/08/21/remote-bandwidth-stats/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 17:44:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/08/21/remote-bandwidth-stats/</guid><description>&lt;p>This post is about my open source remote bandwidth usage stats logger project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to log the internet bandwidth usage at my home for quite some time since I don&amp;rsquo;t really find the stats put out by my ISP to be completely accurate. But I have multiple devices at home that access the internet so it is not feasible to install a bandwidth monitor individually on all these devices as I&amp;rsquo;d still need to add up all logs and many of such devices don&amp;rsquo;t even have a way to install a monitoring software installed (e.g. my PS3, my TV, my media players, etc). So, I thought of monitoring the usage at my router. It is a smart one (Asus wl-500w) and I can install various linux software on it but then it requires a hard disk to run most of them which I don&amp;rsquo;t turn on all the time. Moreover, even if I could run the software directly from router flash, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have enough space to store the logs (neither is it a good idea to keep writing to the flash often).&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>This post is about my open source remote bandwidth usage stats logger project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to log the internet bandwidth usage at my home for quite some time since I don&amp;rsquo;t really find the stats put out by my ISP to be completely accurate. But I have multiple devices at home that access the internet so it is not feasible to install a bandwidth monitor individually on all these devices as I&amp;rsquo;d still need to add up all logs and many of such devices don&amp;rsquo;t even have a way to install a monitoring software installed (e.g. my PS3, my TV, my media players, etc). So, I thought of monitoring the usage at my router. It is a smart one (Asus wl-500w) and I can install various linux software on it but then it requires a hard disk to run most of them which I don&amp;rsquo;t turn on all the time. Moreover, even if I could run the software directly from router flash, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have enough space to store the logs (neither is it a good idea to keep writing to the flash often).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hence I came up with the idea of a light weight remote bandwidth usage logger where in the router has to do the bare minimum possible (here, it just has to make a GET call to a webpage with current status of received and transmitted bytes, accomplished by a single line of wget command). The system is completely open source and is intelligent enough to keep track of things even if router reboots or the bytes count wraps around the 4 GB limit (because of 32 bit data structures used). The logging and parsing is all done on server side and provides various useful things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Few of the features of the system:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Very lightweight in CPU/RAM resource usage on host as well as server&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Outputs easy to browse html and graphs&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>User defined directory structure to decide the granularity that is wanted&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>yearly, monthly, daily stats and graphs&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Provides quick access to extra stats like last time the host connected, last known host IP etc&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Provides total download/upload numbers as well as detailed&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Estimates uptime of remote host&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Can use a DNS name or IP to avoid (or call out) spurious amounts of usage logged by a spurious IP&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The code and all files can be found at github: &lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://github.com/shantanugoel/remote-bandwidth-stats">Remote-Bandwidth-Stats&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The screenshots of the web pages generated by the system can be seen below. Please let me know if you find any issues with the programs or would like to request any new features.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/remote-bandwidth-stats-year-thumb.png" />
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/remote-bandwidth-stats-month-thumb.png" />
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/remote-bandwidth-stats-day-thumb.png" />
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Is Android Open Source Or Not?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/25/android-open-source-or-not/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 11:31:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/25/android-open-source-or-not/</guid><description>&lt;p>Is Android really open source or not? That is the question being asked by almost everyone. A lot of people, especially those influenced by &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reality_distortion_field">RDF&lt;/a> or those who are in the news industry with no idea about OS and open source but were asked by their boss to get a scoop on this pronto, tend to bring up a few keywords and then twist them around in the way they see fit to make sure it says Android isn&amp;rsquo;t open. They don&amp;rsquo;t need to be correct, they only need the article to &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>sound correct&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo; by picking up sentences out of context or putting quotes only from people who agree with them. This will convince their boss and 99% of their readers who have no idea about all these things either. But the boss is happy he got a story and associated clicks. Readers are happy because they got the points to float around in their next forum flame war. They don&amp;rsquo;t have to read when someone corrects them. They have made their points and rest is all someone making noises like a rat.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>Is Android really open source or not? That is the question being asked by almost everyone. A lot of people, especially those influenced by &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reality_distortion_field">RDF&lt;/a> or those who are in the news industry with no idea about OS and open source but were asked by their boss to get a scoop on this pronto, tend to bring up a few keywords and then twist them around in the way they see fit to make sure it says Android isn&amp;rsquo;t open. They don&amp;rsquo;t need to be correct, they only need the article to &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>sound correct&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo; by picking up sentences out of context or putting quotes only from people who agree with them. This will convince their boss and 99% of their readers who have no idea about all these things either. But the boss is happy he got a story and associated clicks. Readers are happy because they got the points to float around in their next forum flame war. They don&amp;rsquo;t have to read when someone corrects them. They have made their points and rest is all someone making noises like a rat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lot out of the rest of the people, who are indeed informed, make the mistake of thinking that &amp;ldquo;Open Source = GPL&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Open Source = Free Software&amp;rdquo;, which is not true. Open source is similar to free software but is one that choses to keep more options open. In short, Free Software Movement, as the one evangelized by FSF, is a subset of open source that tries to achieve freedom of software by restriction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please also note that many people including Steve Jobs confuse people more by interchanging between open and open source. An android phone that you get may not be open, the android market may be open, etc but this discussion is purely about open-source.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyways, with asbestos underwear on, I write this post to speak my mind about this matter by talking about various points thrown up by the above mentioned classes. Since this is going to be a long post, I&amp;rsquo;ll mention here the things it is going to cover:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Allegations against Android&amp;rsquo;s open-source nature. Are they true?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Does OSI Foundation (&lt;a href="http://www.opensource.org">Open source Initiative&lt;/a>) think that Android is open source?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Android and open source in layman terms&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Takeaways/conclusion&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update&lt;/strong>: Updated the article as per Tony and Kasper&amp;rsquo;s comments below. Thanks Kasper and Tony for your valuable inputs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="android-and-open-source-allegations-and-answers">Android and Open Source: Allegations and Answers&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allegation&lt;/strong>: Google does a lot of development in private for few months and then releases the code to public.
&lt;strong>Answer&lt;/strong>: Almost every open source project I know does this. Do you think every person who works on an open source project pushes his code to the mainline 10 times when re writes a 10 line code? No. He completes the feature, tests it and then pushes it out. Individuals might do it sooner, companies might do it later but everyone pushes out their code when they feel things are fairly ready. So, Google choses to do the &amp;ldquo;push&amp;rdquo; every few months when they think their new feature set is ready. This, of course, is more influenced by the fact that they need to be competitive in the aggressive mobile market and hence not let the competitors know about the exact features but still it is well within the limits of open source. And they are doing it before/with the binary release as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also to be noted here is the fact that the &amp;ldquo;code dump&amp;rdquo; is done only for major releases. Minor fixes and even features keep trickling into the code base every now and then and these allow others to make fixes as well. e.g. Cyanogen was able to bring &amp;ldquo;802.11n&amp;rdquo; capability and was able to include various fixes including one for wi-fi sleep policies before they actually made into an OTA update for any phone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allegation&lt;/strong>: Only google employees can check in code to mainline.
&lt;strong>Answer&lt;/strong>: Every open source project has only a select few folks who can check in code. Most of the open source projects start with only their founders having commit access. They may or may not give commit accesses to anyone else. Check out various open source projects on sourceforge, googlecode, etc and you will find this. Most of the projects that do choose to give commit access to others, start doing it after some time when they feel the project is mature enough and they are confident enough in someone else. Android is just a hatchling, around 2 years old. It has begun making strides only now so Google may even choose to take the latter path but I can understand if Google wants to keep this as their control point because of the hustle and bustle of the mobile OS world which is much more rapid and cut throat than the desktop OS and this does not make them closed. Not only that, but seeing how everyone in the mobile world is so trigger happy with suing everyone else, it creates a legal issue for them as they would be the ones to answer if someone else brings this upon them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allegation&lt;/strong>: Google only accepts their own code into official android and nobody else&amp;rsquo;s.
&lt;strong>Answer&lt;/strong>: This one is hilarious. Obviously, anyone who says this hasn&amp;rsquo;t actually been to review.android.com. Just go their and check whether any merged changes have non-google, non-android email ids. Anyone can upload their patches there but the accepted ones are fairly low. This problem is present in every popular open source project, even the Linux kernel. But is more pronounced in the case of android because Google&amp;rsquo;s android team is much smaller than the number of persons working on other projects and there is red tape of a big company involved. If you want to get your patch in, just like the kernel, you need to engage with them. Talk to them in the relevant bug report, comment the code properly, give them a reason to not avoid your patch. But yes, the process is still very slow and it is eons faster to just contribute to a fork like cyanogenmod. I do hope that google does get better in this regard soon though.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allegation&lt;/strong>: It is not possible to make a full android build from the public code tree of android.
&lt;strong>Answer&lt;/strong>: BS. Cyanogen does just fine with his full AOSP builds. People argue that Google does not release the modem/baseband code but they idiotically fail to realize that the baseband code is not part of Android at all. It is the IP of the baseband manufacturer and is specific to each hardware. Android is just the code that runs on apps hardware. Google does not indeed release the code of their built in google apps (gtalk/gmail etc) though but they are already working towards that and these apps will not be a part of the base Android system anymore. These would be standalone apps and even now you don&amp;rsquo;t need them to make a fully working android build.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allegation&lt;/strong>: &amp;ldquo;Android&amp;rdquo; is a registered trademark and is held by Google.
&lt;strong>Answer&lt;/strong>: Linus holds the trademark for &amp;ldquo;Linux&amp;rdquo;, Mozilla foundation holds the trademark for &amp;ldquo;Firefox&amp;rdquo;, Canonical holds the trademark for &amp;ldquo;Ubuntu&amp;rdquo;. Get the drift? Basically, it is completely possible and allowed for an open source software to be trademarked.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allegation&lt;/strong>: Google doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop the carriers/OEMs from locking down the phones, adding bloatware or custom UIs.
&lt;strong>Answer&lt;/strong>: This is an issue with carriers/OEMs and not Android. Google uses the apache software license (ASL), which is a permissive license (like MIT, BSD, etc) and hence does not stop the carriers from doing such a thing (In fact, this is the very foundation of being open, check the next passage about OSI foundation, point no. 9). Many people say they should, but if they did then they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be open anymore, would they?
Even Linus Torvalds is against making such a stipulation of not allowing locking of phones and this is the biggest reason why the Linux Kernel (and lot of other open source projects) didn&amp;rsquo;t move to FSF&amp;rsquo;s (&lt;a href="http://www.fsf.org">Free Software Foundation&lt;/a>) GPL v3. I wonder why no one calls the Linux kernel closed hmmmm&amp;hellip;
BTW, if you are so serious about unlocked/rootable phones then buy a dev phone directly from google or get one from Synapse.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="android-and-open-source-osi-foundation">Android and Open Source: OSI Foundation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The OSI foundation has a few guidelines to determine whether something is open source or not under their &lt;a href="http://www.opensource.org/osd.html">Open Source Definition&lt;/a>. Android uses the OSI compatible Apache Software License (ASL) but still let&amp;rsquo;s see whether Android comes up to all of them or not. If it is in conflict with even one of the requisites, we will call Android closed.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Allow free redistribution - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Give out un-obfuscated source code - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Allow modifications and derived works - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Allow distribution of modifications (as patches) or modified software as a whole. Can restrict the modified versions from using original name of software - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No discrimination against any person or groups - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No restriction of using the software on any device or field - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No additional license needed - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No product-specific license - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No restriction on software distributed along with original software - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Technology neutral, i.e., no preference for an individual technology or user interface - Check
So, Android is true to each and every point that being open demands to it. In fact, points 9 and 10 are fundamental in making it open but alas, people less oriented with open software tend to term this as being closed (as seen in the last allegation above)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="android-and-open-source-from-a-laymans-view-point">Android and Open Source: From a layman&amp;rsquo;s view point&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Apart from the above, I would also like to share a few &amp;ldquo;layman-examples&amp;rdquo; which will let you understand for yourself why Android is open:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>You can see all the official android OS code without any restrictions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can download it, fork it, modify it without asking google&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can port it to any device without asking google&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can develop and sell your phone with Android without asking google
Now compare that with any other mobile OS you know.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="android-and-open-source-conclusion">Android and Open Source: Conclusion&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>So, the takeaways from the above wall of text are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Android is open-source&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Android is permissively open-source instead of being restrictive&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Android can do better in terms of community driven development but is perhaps held back by pace of competition and legalities involved. But, this in no way makes it non-open-source.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Let me know if you have any corrections or allegations to make :)&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Clearing the FUD around Ubuntu Application Review Process</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/21/clearing-the-fud-around-ubuntu-application-review-process/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2010 19:44:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/21/clearing-the-fud-around-ubuntu-application-review-process/</guid><description>&lt;p>An application review process was &lt;a href="http://www.jonobacon.org/2010/09/20/announcing-the-ubuntu-application-review-process/">announced today&lt;/a> for getting your apps into Ubuntu “extras” repository. But like most other announcements of new things, this one was met as well with as much criticism as the praise it got. A lot of the criticism is FUD though, although mostly unintentional and caused by ignorance of some facts behind it. I’ll try to address some of these concerns here to the best of my knowledge from what I’ve been reading over the past some time about this development.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>An application review process was &lt;a href="http://www.jonobacon.org/2010/09/20/announcing-the-ubuntu-application-review-process/">announced today&lt;/a> for getting your apps into Ubuntu “extras” repository. But like most other announcements of new things, this one was met as well with as much criticism as the praise it got. A lot of the criticism is FUD though, although mostly unintentional and caused by ignorance of some facts behind it. I’ll try to address some of these concerns here to the best of my knowledge from what I’ve been reading over the past some time about this development.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before we begin, here are the terms listed out for an app to be eligible for the new repository:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>only new applications that are not present in an existing official Ubuntu repository (such as main/universe) are eligible in this process (e.g a new version of an application in an existing official repository is not eligible). Also no other software can depend on the application being submitted (e.g. development libraries are not eligible), only executable applications (and content that is part of them) are eligible, and not stand-alone content, documentation or media, and applications must be Open Source and available under an OSI approved license.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Now, the concerns that are floating around are many. Some are genuine queries and many are straight attacks dishing out evil conspiracy theories :P. The concerns can be summarised as:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Closed source and paid apps are being given the boot by Ubuntu. They should have allowed them.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Why can’t we have updates for existing apps in this repository?&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Why only standalone apps are allowed. Libraries are equally important.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Why should the software be packaged for /opt. This involves more headache for the developers.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Standalone media and content should have been allowed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Well, to answer these, all you need to understand is the “premise” and concept behind the repository where this software will go and the reasoning behind the review process will unfold itself. The repository governed by this review process is meant to be for “maintainable” pieces of software that would generally go to other universe/main etc repos but couldn’t make it into this release of Ubuntu because the developers were a bit late. This process and feature now gives a chance to the developers to still get their app to public instead of waiting for next release cycle and also allows end-users to use new apps without having to upgrade their version of Ubuntu . There is a separate “partners” repository where closed source and paid apps can go so there is no conflict there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Only allowing standalone apps and not updates and dependencies is so obvious. It would soon go out of hand exponentially if you allowed dependencies since one thing needs another library updated, then that would need another and yet another and so on and before you know it, you would be back at square one, that is upgrading to the next version of Ubuntu itself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The only thing that I found out of the place was not allowing standalone content but probably they didn’t allow it because such content can be had by end users without a repo easily and would ease the burden of repo maintainers and reviewers by lessening the entries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’d also like to point out that this is just a beginning and the process (and the people behind it) would definitely be maturing from all the feedback they get from the community. Think of it as an alpha release ;). Jono Bacon summed it up very nicely in this comment of his that he made elsewhere:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>this is an &lt;em>experimental&lt;/em> process; it is a work in progress, it will evolve, and the kinks will be ironed out. The process was approved by the Ubuntu Technical Board who are all seasoned Ubuntu developers (Matt Zimmerman, Colin Watson, Martin Pitt, Mark Shuttleworth, and Kees Cook), and much of what you refer to as &amp;ldquo;restrictions&amp;rdquo; were requested by them for the purpose of delivering a nimble process that is stable and secure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To be clear: you can think of this process as a &amp;ldquo;light-weight&amp;rdquo; equivalent to our traditional MOTU development process; it is intended to provide a method in which app devs can get content in Ubuntu, whereas our traditional development processes have be orientated around the needs of Operating System integrators.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As such, this is a first step; sure it is not perfect, but I would like to invite you to make it better; I think this would be a more valuable contribution than just ranting about it on here. Our goal is to make Ubuntu better and to make it more attractive to app developers, and this process will evolve and improve (as was made clear throughout the discussion of this).&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>So, what do you think about it? I, for one, am pretty excited..&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Continuous Monitoring With Tail Fails</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/12/23/continuous-monitor-tail-fails/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2009 18:10:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/12/23/continuous-monitor-tail-fails/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you can&amp;rsquo;t get tail command to continuously monitor a file, then read on. I was working on a script yesterday, a part of which depended on continuous monitoring of a text file. I had used our trusty old &amp;ldquo;tail&amp;rdquo; command for this but while testing by manually putting in some data into the file, it was failing but curiously it was working fine when used in actual scenario. Befuddled, I did a simple test. I created a simple text file &amp;ldquo;a.txt&amp;rdquo; with a few lines of data and then ran the following command.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>If you can&amp;rsquo;t get tail command to continuously monitor a file, then read on. I was working on a script yesterday, a part of which depended on continuous monitoring of a text file. I had used our trusty old &amp;ldquo;tail&amp;rdquo; command for this but while testing by manually putting in some data into the file, it was failing but curiously it was working fine when used in actual scenario. Befuddled, I did a simple test. I created a simple text file &amp;ldquo;a.txt&amp;rdquo; with a few lines of data and then ran the following command.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>tail -f a.txt&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It showed the last few lines of the file and kept waiting. So far so good. Then I opened the file in vim editor, wrote a few more lines, saved the file and then waited but nothing in the window that was running the tail command. Thinking that the data might be buffered and not flushed to the disc yet, I ran the sync command but still nothing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then I got a hint that when I used the &amp;ldquo;-F&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;&amp;ndash;follow=name&amp;rdquo; option instead of &amp;ldquo;-f&amp;rdquo;, the tail command was able to detect the change just fine, the only problem being that in this mode, it prints the last few lines again, not just the newly added line. The main difference in these new options is that tail command tracks the file for changes by its name and not by the file descriptor, and then it dawned on me. The problem is not in the tail command but my testing method itself. When I save the file opened in vim, it creates a new file with a new inode while the one opened by tail is still the old one (which is now a temporary file which has actually been deleted). When I quit tail, then the kernel deletes the file automatically. This is also confirmed by running &amp;ldquo;lsof | grep a.txt&amp;rdquo; (lsof lists the open files and then we find the ones related to a.txt). The output shown is;&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>tail 11966 shantanu 3r REG 8,6 8 224954 /home/shantanu/dev/perl/plot/a.txt~ (deleted)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>vim 12576 shantanu 9u REG 8,6 12288 210918 /home/shantanu/dev/perl/plot/.a.txt.swp
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>which shows what we had discussed above. This gets worked around when I use the -F option because then tail periodically reopens the file by name and reads it again, thus bypassing the above issue. Then I simply tried running tail again on the same file and doing something like &amp;ldquo;echo abc &amp;raquo; a.txt&amp;rdquo; and I could see the behaviour as expected with tail immediately detecting the change and displaying it in its window. Hope this helps if you have been pulling out your hair thinking you have gone crazy as your favourite little tool that you have been using for so many years has suddenly stopped working and no one else apart from you is even complaining :P&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Making Frets On Fire Work With Pulse Aludio - pasuspender</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/08/23/make-frets-on-fire-work-pulse-audio-pasuspender/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2009 18:18:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/08/23/make-frets-on-fire-work-pulse-audio-pasuspender/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently got hold of a Guitar Hero controller for my PS3 but the game still had some time to come so I tried it out on my laptop with Frets on Fire (rather FoFix). But when I started it, it was crashing with some weird error about not being able to open mixer devices. Searching on the google, I came to know this is happening because of Pulse Audio as this application needs direct access to the sound devices and finally I came upon **pasuspender. **This little tool allows you to do that with ease. Just run it in the following way:&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>I recently got hold of a Guitar Hero controller for my PS3 but the game still had some time to come so I tried it out on my laptop with Frets on Fire (rather FoFix). But when I started it, it was crashing with some weird error about not being able to open mixer devices. Searching on the google, I came to know this is happening because of Pulse Audio as this application needs direct access to the sound devices and finally I came upon **pasuspender. **This little tool allows you to do that with ease. Just run it in the following way:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>pasuspender -- ./FretsOnFire&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it will start working just fine. You can use the same trick for any other application that needs direct access to the sound devices. What pasuspender does is that it will suspend pulse audio and allow the application to access them directly and when the application is terminated, normal functioning will resume.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Why You Should Not Upgrade to Ubuntu Jaunty Jackalope (9.04)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/05/04/ubuntu-904-jaunty-jackalope-upgrade-graphics-problem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2009 17:46:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/05/04/ubuntu-904-jaunty-jackalope-upgrade-graphics-problem/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update: It has come to my notice that many people do not know about this (and other problems listed in comments of this post). Please &lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://digg.com/linux_unix/Why_You_Should_Not_Upgrade_to_Ubuntu_Jaunty_Jackalope_9_04">&lt;strong>digg&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/8hzkt/why_you_should_not_upgrade_to_ubuntu_jaunty/">&lt;strong>reddit&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> this post so that more people can be made aware of it before they upgrade unknowingly.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You should not upgrade to Ubuntu 9.04 (aka Jaunty Jackalope), released a few weeks ago, if:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You have an older ATI graphics card (prior to R500, .e.g xpress 200m)&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update: It has come to my notice that many people do not know about this (and other problems listed in comments of this post). Please &lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://digg.com/linux_unix/Why_You_Should_Not_Upgrade_to_Ubuntu_Jaunty_Jackalope_9_04">&lt;strong>digg&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/8hzkt/why_you_should_not_upgrade_to_ubuntu_jaunty/">&lt;strong>reddit&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> this post so that more people can be made aware of it before they upgrade unknowingly.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You should not upgrade to Ubuntu 9.04 (aka Jaunty Jackalope), released a few weeks ago, if:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You have an older ATI graphics card (prior to R500, .e.g xpress 200m)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You like to have 3D support (read compiz/games, etc)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>This is because of the following reasons:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Ubuntu Jaunty Jackalope has the new version of X.org server (1.6)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The open source graphics drivers for ATI do not have 3D support&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The only version of the ATI properietary drivers (fglrx\Catalyst) compatible with X.org server 1.6 is 9.4&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Support for older cards (mentioned above) was dropped from fglrx 9.4&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>So, basically right now you are in a soup and it seems to me that this is going to remain this way unless someone figures out how to backport x.org 1.5 onto Jauntu, which is going to be a hell of a task, IMHO :P&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But, if you are a simple person, who looks beyond the gloss of the 3D and marvels at the beauty that the rest of the system holds, then go right ahead and dive in :)&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Shutdown Script For Asus WL-500W With Oleg Firmware</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/09/shutdown-script-asus-wl-500w-oleg-firmware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 13:30:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/09/shutdown-script-asus-wl-500w-oleg-firmware/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you have an &lt;a href="http://tech.shantanugoel.com/tag/asus-wl-500w">Asus WL-500W&lt;/a>, the DIYers&amp;rsquo; favourite wireless router, and have installed the Oleg custom firmware on it, then you would have set up a shutdown script for it, that allows your router to shut down gracefully. This is especially important if you have a USB hard disk attached to it. There are many such scripts available in Oleg&amp;rsquo;s firmware that you can tweak. All of these reside in &amp;ldquo;/usr/local/sbin/&amp;rdquo;. The one that we are going to talk about today is named &amp;ldquo;pre-shutdown&amp;rdquo; and it is exceuted just before the router is about to shutdown. Here is my script that will stop all the programs that have been started, finalizes all data accesses for the hard drive, unmounts all the partitions and if they can&amp;rsquo;t be unmounted, then mounts them as read only to reduce the risks, and then allows the router to continue shutdown. Although this script is written for Asus WL-500W but it will work with most other routers that use oleg or unslung firmware (like Linksys NSLU2, Asus WL-500G, WL-500gP etc):&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>If you have an &lt;a href="http://tech.shantanugoel.com/tag/asus-wl-500w">Asus WL-500W&lt;/a>, the DIYers&amp;rsquo; favourite wireless router, and have installed the Oleg custom firmware on it, then you would have set up a shutdown script for it, that allows your router to shut down gracefully. This is especially important if you have a USB hard disk attached to it. There are many such scripts available in Oleg&amp;rsquo;s firmware that you can tweak. All of these reside in &amp;ldquo;/usr/local/sbin/&amp;rdquo;. The one that we are going to talk about today is named &amp;ldquo;pre-shutdown&amp;rdquo; and it is exceuted just before the router is about to shutdown. Here is my script that will stop all the programs that have been started, finalizes all data accesses for the hard drive, unmounts all the partitions and if they can&amp;rsquo;t be unmounted, then mounts them as read only to reduce the risks, and then allows the router to continue shutdown. Although this script is written for Asus WL-500W but it will work with most other routers that use oleg or unslung firmware (like Linksys NSLU2, Asus WL-500G, WL-500gP etc):&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#75715e">#! /bin/sh
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#75715e">&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>/opt/etc/init.d/rc.unslung stop
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>sleep 5s
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>sync
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>sleep 5s
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">for&lt;/span> i in &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">`&lt;/span>cat /proc/mounts | awk &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#39;/ext3/{print($1)}&amp;#39;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">`&lt;/span> ; &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">do&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> umount $i
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">if&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">[&lt;/span> $? !&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">0&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">]&lt;/span> ; &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">then&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> echo &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;Could not unmount &lt;/span>$i&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">. Mounting as read only&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> mount -oremount,ro $i
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">else&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> echo &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;Unmount &lt;/span>$i&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">.&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">fi&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">done&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>swapoff -a
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>sleep 1s
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></content></item><item><title>[TIP] Add Directories Recursively To Perforce (P4) Depot</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/03/add-directories-recursively-to-perforce-p4-depot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2009 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/03/add-directories-recursively-to-perforce-p4-depot/</guid><description>&lt;p>Perforce is an excellent revision control system for the code but the GUIs (P4WIN and P4V) are too slow to be productive. Hence, I like to do most of my work through command lines. Now, the other day I needed to add a directory and all its subdirectories and files to the repository (or perforce depot). This is a trivial task through the GUI. Just drag the top level directory onto the changelist area and the GUI takes care of everything but there is no straightforward way to do this through command line, until, I discovered the &amp;ldquo;-x&amp;rdquo; option of P4. So, here it is how to achieve this. Run the following command after cd&amp;rsquo;ing to the directory you want to add:&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>Perforce is an excellent revision control system for the code but the GUIs (P4WIN and P4V) are too slow to be productive. Hence, I like to do most of my work through command lines. Now, the other day I needed to add a directory and all its subdirectories and files to the repository (or perforce depot). This is a trivial task through the GUI. Just drag the top level directory onto the changelist area and the GUI takes care of everything but there is no straightforward way to do this through command line, until, I discovered the &amp;ldquo;-x&amp;rdquo; option of P4. So, here it is how to achieve this. Run the following command after cd&amp;rsquo;ing to the directory you want to add:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For Unix/Linux (or if you have the unix utils installed in windows through GNUWin32, UnixUtils or Cygwin):&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>find . -type f -print | p4 -x - add
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>For Windows:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>dir /b /s /a-d | p4 -x - add
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>If you have your own tips and tricks about perforce to carry out tasks easily that do not seem so simple in the first go through command line, please do let me know.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Project: Shantz XWinWrap Update to 0.3</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/16/project-shantz-xwinwrap-update-to-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2009 18:30:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/16/project-shantz-xwinwrap-update-to-03/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here is another update for the fans of XWinWrap, the tiny program that allows you to run animated wallpapers on your system. You could use screensavers, movies and what not as your desktop background. This update fixes a segfault that many users were facing, a new debug option to print some debug mesages to get some info if it is not working for you and a new hack option for giving a &amp;ldquo;desktop window&amp;rdquo; name to the program. On many systems, the desktop is drawn by another program. e.g. in Ubuntu with Gnome environment, the desktop is managed by Nautilus, which creates a special window called &amp;ldquo;Desktop&amp;rdquo; and places it over your real desktop. This window name can be different in different systems. To find out what is yours, just run &amp;ldquo;xwininfo&amp;rdquo; in a terminal. Your cursor will become a &amp;ldquo;+&amp;rdquo; sign. Click anywhere on an empty area on your desktop, which will give you the window name of the transparent window, if any, that is covering your desktop. Pass this info to xwinwrap using the option &amp;ldquo;-d windowname&amp;rdquo; and it would help it to run better.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>Here is another update for the fans of XWinWrap, the tiny program that allows you to run animated wallpapers on your system. You could use screensavers, movies and what not as your desktop background. This update fixes a segfault that many users were facing, a new debug option to print some debug mesages to get some info if it is not working for you and a new hack option for giving a &amp;ldquo;desktop window&amp;rdquo; name to the program. On many systems, the desktop is drawn by another program. e.g. in Ubuntu with Gnome environment, the desktop is managed by Nautilus, which creates a special window called &amp;ldquo;Desktop&amp;rdquo; and places it over your real desktop. This window name can be different in different systems. To find out what is yours, just run &amp;ldquo;xwininfo&amp;rdquo; in a terminal. Your cursor will become a &amp;ldquo;+&amp;rdquo; sign. Click anywhere on an empty area on your desktop, which will give you the window name of the transparent window, if any, that is covering your desktop. Pass this info to xwinwrap using the option &amp;ldquo;-d windowname&amp;rdquo; and it would help it to run better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As usual, 32 bit as well as 64 bit binary files are available as downloads. For users of Debian and derived operating systems (like Ubuntu, Mepis, etc), deb packages are also included for both architectures for easy installation. Source code is also available, of course.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>[Ubuntu TIP] Solved: Totem Cannot Detect UPnP Media Server</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/31/ubuntu-tip-solved-totem-cannot-detect-upnp-media-server/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 17:46:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/31/ubuntu-tip-solved-totem-cannot-detect-upnp-media-server/</guid><description>&lt;p>First a bit of background. A UPnP media server can serve your media files (video / audio / pictures) over the network to any compatible player. Some of the most known examples of these media servers are MediaTomb, TVersity, ushare, etc. In linux, few players can play media off these servers natively, but many require a plugin / library called &amp;ldquo;coherence&amp;rdquo;. e.g. the default media players (Totem and RhythmBox) can detect and play media from media servers once you install coherence (&amp;ldquo;sudo apt-get install python-coherence&amp;rdquo;). This works, BUT you will see that many times Totem will stop detecting the server suddenly. It happens to me quite a bit (The server I use is Mediatomb). First I thought that the problem is with Media Tomb, but my PS3 continued to play videos from it over wi-fi without any issues, so that was ruled out. I tried many things but in the end, the solution turned out to be pretty simple. The problem seems to be that the coherence library hangs some times. Simple thing is to just restart it. So, all you need to do is run the following command:&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>First a bit of background. A UPnP media server can serve your media files (video / audio / pictures) over the network to any compatible player. Some of the most known examples of these media servers are MediaTomb, TVersity, ushare, etc. In linux, few players can play media off these servers natively, but many require a plugin / library called &amp;ldquo;coherence&amp;rdquo;. e.g. the default media players (Totem and RhythmBox) can detect and play media from media servers once you install coherence (&amp;ldquo;sudo apt-get install python-coherence&amp;rdquo;). This works, BUT you will see that many times Totem will stop detecting the server suddenly. It happens to me quite a bit (The server I use is Mediatomb). First I thought that the problem is with Media Tomb, but my PS3 continued to play videos from it over wi-fi without any issues, so that was ruled out. I tried many things but in the end, the solution turned out to be pretty simple. The problem seems to be that the coherence library hangs some times. Simple thing is to just restart it. So, all you need to do is run the following command:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>sudo killall coherence&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, just restart Totem and it will work fine now (Totem will invoke coherence again automatically). :)&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Tip: Commands To Find Out The Shell You Are Using</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/27/tip-commands-to-find-out-the-shell-you-are-using/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2009 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/27/tip-commands-to-find-out-the-shell-you-are-using/</guid><description>&lt;p>Many times you might not be sure about which shell you are currently using. Especially if you are not on your system and logging into someone else&amp;rsquo;s, or maybe ssh&amp;rsquo;ing into a remote server. Worry not, because here are few simple commands that you can use to find out which shell you are using currently.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Command (Note: This one is a bit unreliable as it might not work with non-bash shells or on redirection. Pls check the comments for details. Thanks to Shantanu Kumar and renoX for pointing this out.):&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>Many times you might not be sure about which shell you are currently using. Especially if you are not on your system and logging into someone else&amp;rsquo;s, or maybe ssh&amp;rsquo;ing into a remote server. Worry not, because here are few simple commands that you can use to find out which shell you are using currently.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Command (Note: This one is a bit unreliable as it might not work with non-bash shells or on redirection. Pls check the comments for details. Thanks to Shantanu Kumar and renoX for pointing this out.):&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>echo $SHELL&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Output on my system:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>/bin/bash&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Command:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>echo $0&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Output on my system:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>bash&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Command:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>ps -p $$&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Output on my system:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>7772 pts/0 00:00:00 bash&lt;/code>&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>[TIP] Asus WL-500W Hacks:How To Reset Web Admin Password</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/23/tip-asus-wl-500w-hackshow-to-reset-web-admin-password/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2009 22:41:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/23/tip-asus-wl-500w-hackshow-to-reset-web-admin-password/</guid><description>&lt;p>Most of you must be knowing by now that I bought the amazing Asus WL-500W router a few days back. This router builds on the great lineage it has in its predecessors, the WL-500g, WL-500g Deluxe, WL-500gP, WL-500gP v2 etc, and shines ahead with being much more than a router, rather a complete headless linux PC. Anyways, to the point. In most routers/modems, if you forget the password to your web-administration gui (which generally resides as 192.168.1.1), the only option left is to reset the router, thereby losing all your settings etc. But not so with this little beast. If you remember your ssh password (which BTW is available if you have installed a custom firmware on our router), then you can just login through it to your router and execute the following commands to save your skin:&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>Most of you must be knowing by now that I bought the amazing Asus WL-500W router a few days back. This router builds on the great lineage it has in its predecessors, the WL-500g, WL-500g Deluxe, WL-500gP, WL-500gP v2 etc, and shines ahead with being much more than a router, rather a complete headless linux PC. Anyways, to the point. In most routers/modems, if you forget the password to your web-administration gui (which generally resides as 192.168.1.1), the only option left is to reset the router, thereby losing all your settings etc. But not so with this little beast. If you remember your ssh password (which BTW is available if you have installed a custom firmware on our router), then you can just login through it to your router and execute the following commands to save your skin:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>nvram get http_passwd&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This will display the current web administration password.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>nvram set http_passwd=&amp;quot;NewPasswd&amp;quot;&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This will set the new password. But remember that you have to enter another command (given below) to make sure that your new password is saved.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>nvram commit&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, just reboot and enjoy :)&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Project: Shantz-XwinWrap Updated to 0.02</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/18/project-shantz-xwinwrap-updated-to-002/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2008 11:03:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/18/project-shantz-xwinwrap-updated-to-002/</guid><description>&lt;p>As some of you know that I&amp;rsquo;ve taken up the development of the ultra-cool xwinwrap tool that allows you to use movies, screensavers etc as wallpapers for you linux desktops. Here is version 0.02 for you consumption that fixes a bug because of which the generated window was overlapping other windows.&lt;br>
The download file has plain executable binaries as well as deb packages for Ubuntu. Moreover, I&amp;rsquo;ve included both 32 bit as well as 64 bit versions.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>As some of you know that I&amp;rsquo;ve taken up the development of the ultra-cool xwinwrap tool that allows you to use movies, screensavers etc as wallpapers for you linux desktops. Here is version 0.02 for you consumption that fixes a bug because of which the generated window was overlapping other windows.&lt;br>
The download file has plain executable binaries as well as deb packages for Ubuntu. Moreover, I&amp;rsquo;ve included both 32 bit as well as 64 bit versions.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Project: Shantz Pidgin Away Alerts (splert) Updated to 0.03</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/03/project-shantz-pidgin-away-alerts-splert-updated-to-003/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 21:19:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/03/project-shantz-pidgin-away-alerts-splert-updated-to-003/</guid><description>&lt;p>I updated my project splert to version 0.03 today.For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know splert is a tool that lets you convert the multi-client instant messenger pidgin (connects to gtalk, msn, yahoo, jabber, etc) into a full blown answering machine and much more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main changes are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Now you can use other 3rd party twitter bots with it to get updates through twitter since the official twitter bot is down since a long time and there are no chances of coming back soon.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>I updated my project splert to version 0.03 today.For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know splert is a tool that lets you convert the multi-client instant messenger pidgin (connects to gtalk, msn, yahoo, jabber, etc) into a full blown answering machine and much more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main changes are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Now you can use other 3rd party twitter bots with it to get updates through twitter since the official twitter bot is down since a long time and there are no chances of coming back soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can also use it even when you are not &amp;ldquo;away&amp;rdquo; by specifying the status when you want it to work. (e.g. any, available, unavailable, invisible, etc. Use splert -h to see all available status types). As an example, you can use this to selectively talk to people when you are busy.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>(As usual, binary files as well as 32 bit and 64 bit ubuntu/debian deb packages are available)&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>SpiderOak Promotion Code For Free Upgrade To 10 GB</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/12/spideroak-promotion-code-for-free-upgrade-to-10-gb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2008 20:58:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/12/spideroak-promotion-code-for-free-upgrade-to-10-gb/</guid><description>&lt;p>Just a small shout out to let you guys know that you can use the discount coupon code “linkup” while signing up the excellent online backup service &lt;a href="http://spideroak.com/">SpiderOak&lt;/a> to get a major bump to 10 GB from the 2 GB that they give to normal accounts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For those who don’t know SpiderOak is a great online data backup service, with its major strengths being truly cross paltform (Mac/Linux/Windows – 32 bit as well as 64 bit), easy interface, rsync like differential backups to save time and disk space, versioned file history, web as well as client interface, unlimited number of devices, unlimited bandwidth, etc etc.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>Just a small shout out to let you guys know that you can use the discount coupon code “linkup” while signing up the excellent online backup service &lt;a href="http://spideroak.com/">SpiderOak&lt;/a> to get a major bump to 10 GB from the 2 GB that they give to normal accounts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For those who don’t know SpiderOak is a great online data backup service, with its major strengths being truly cross paltform (Mac/Linux/Windows – 32 bit as well as 64 bit), easy interface, rsync like differential backups to save time and disk space, versioned file history, web as well as client interface, unlimited number of devices, unlimited bandwidth, etc etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BTW, let me know if you use any other good online backup services. And what are your views about &lt;a href="http://getdropbox.com/">Dropbox&lt;/a> that just came out of beta and even released a linux client finally…&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Shantz XWinWrap: The "Moving" Wallpaper Fun Continues</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/03/shantz-xwinwrap-the-moving-wallpaper-fun-continues/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 14:46:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/03/shantz-xwinwrap-the-moving-wallpaper-fun-continues/</guid><description>&lt;p>XWinWrap is a small utility written a loooong time ago that allowed you to stick most of the apps to your desktop background (Thanks to &lt;a href="http://www.fsckin.com/2008/04/14/fun-with-xwinwrap-in-compiz-fusion/">fsckin&lt;/a> for introducing me to it). What this meant was you could use an animated screensaver (like glmatrix, electric sheep, etc) or even a movie, and use it as your wallpaper. But only one version of this app was released, and it had a few problems, like it wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly &amp;ldquo;sticking&amp;rdquo; to the background and geometry option didn&amp;rsquo;t work as well.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>XWinWrap is a small utility written a loooong time ago that allowed you to stick most of the apps to your desktop background (Thanks to &lt;a href="http://www.fsckin.com/2008/04/14/fun-with-xwinwrap-in-compiz-fusion/">fsckin&lt;/a> for introducing me to it). What this meant was you could use an animated screensaver (like glmatrix, electric sheep, etc) or even a movie, and use it as your wallpaper. But only one version of this app was released, and it had a few problems, like it wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly &amp;ldquo;sticking&amp;rdquo; to the background and geometry option didn&amp;rsquo;t work as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seeing no-one picking it up, I decided to give it a bit of polish last weekend by fixing the above problems and also add a few features.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I hope to continue on the good work that was done by the original author and provide an even better xwinwrap to you all. Pour in those ideas about what features you&amp;rsquo;d like to see in this.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Shantz XWinWrap</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/03/shantz-xwinwrap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 14:41:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/03/shantz-xwinwrap/</guid><description>&lt;p>XWinWrap is a small utility written a loooong time ago that allowed you to stick most of the apps to your desktop background. What this meant was you could use an animated screensaver (like glmatrix, electric sheep, etc) or even a movie, and use it as your wallpaper. But only one version of this app was ever released, and it had a few problems, like:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Well, sticking didn&amp;rsquo;t work. So if you did a &amp;ldquo;minimize all&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;go to desktop&amp;rdquo; kind of thing, your &amp;ldquo;wallpaper&amp;rdquo; got minimized as well.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>XWinWrap is a small utility written a loooong time ago that allowed you to stick most of the apps to your desktop background. What this meant was you could use an animated screensaver (like glmatrix, electric sheep, etc) or even a movie, and use it as your wallpaper. But only one version of this app was ever released, and it had a few problems, like:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Well, sticking didn&amp;rsquo;t work. So if you did a &amp;ldquo;minimize all&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;go to desktop&amp;rdquo; kind of thing, your &amp;ldquo;wallpaper&amp;rdquo; got minimized as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The geometry option didn&amp;rsquo;t work, so you could not create, e.g., a small matrix window surrounded by your original wallpaper.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Seeing no-one picking it up, I decided to give it a bit of polish last weekend by fixing the above problems and also add a few features. And here it is, in its new avatar &amp;ldquo;Shantz XWinWrap&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Video:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/k8BCyhAHKSc?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Usage&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Notes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The download file above contains 32 bit as well as 64 bit binaries. (Deb packages for ubuntu/debian are also included in the same file)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Though a lot of options are shown below, the only ones you&amp;rsquo;d most likely need are &amp;ldquo;fs&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;g&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;ov&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sh&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The modified source code can be browsed/downloaded from the &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/xwinwrap">Shantz XWinWrap Launchpad Bzr repository&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>xwinwrap [-g {w}x{h}+{x}+{y}] [-ni] [-argb] [-fs] [-s] [-st] [-sp] [-a] [-b] [-nf] [-o OPACITY] [-sh SHAPE] [-ov] -- COMMAND ARG1...
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>Options:
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-g    - Specify Geometry (w=width, h=height, x=x-coord, y=y-coord. ex: -g 640x480+100+100)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-ni   - Ignore Input
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-d - Desktop Window Hack. Provide name of the &amp;#34;Desktop&amp;#34; window as parameter
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-argb - RGB
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-fs   - Full Screen
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-s    - Sticky
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-st   - Skip Taskbar
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-sp   - Skip Pager
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-a    - Above
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-b    - Below
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-nf   - No Focus
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-o    - Opacity value between 0 to 1 (ex: -o 0.20)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-sh   - Shape of window (choose between rectangle, circle or triangle. Default is rectangle)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-ov   - Set override_redirect flag (For seamless desktop background integration)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-debug - Enable Debug messages
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Examples:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Examples use glmatrix however you can use something like mplayer, vlc, electric sheep etc instead of these)&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>To run glmatrix in fullscreen wallpaper mode&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>./xwinwrap -ov -fs -- /usr/lib/xscreensaver/glmatrix -root -window-id WID
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>To run glmatrix in a small window wallpaper mode&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>./xwinwrap -ov -g 400x400+400+200 -- /usr/lib/xscreensaver/glmatrix -root -window-id WID
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>To run glmatrix in small circle wallpaper mode&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>./xwinwrap -ov -g 400x400+400+200 -sh circle -- /usr/lib/xscreensaver/glmatrix -root -window-id WID
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>To run glmatrix in small triangular wallpaper mode&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>./xwinwrap -ov -g 400x400+400+200 -sh triangle -- /usr/lib/xscreensaver/glmatrix -root -window-id WID
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>&lt;strong>ChangeLog:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>15-Feb-2009:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed the bug where XFetchName returning a NULL for &amp;ldquo;name&amp;rdquo; resulted in a crash. Props to Kevin&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Provided an option to specify the desktop window name.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Added Debug messages.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>18-Oct-2008:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Fixed a bug where the generated window overlapped other windows.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>28-Aug-2008:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed &amp;ldquo;sticky&amp;rdquo;, now it sticks like a true wallpaper to your desktop.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed &amp;ldquo;geometry&amp;rdquo; option. Now you can create smaller windows and draw/position them anywhere on your screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Added non-rectangular shaped windows option. Now, you can create circular or triangular windows with xwinwrap to get that cool effect.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></content></item><item><title>Project: Splert - A Custom Answering Machine And More for IMs</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/18/project-splert-a-custom-answering-machine-and-more-for-ims/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 17:00:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/18/project-splert-a-custom-answering-machine-and-more-for-ims/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update Aug 25 2008&lt;/strong>: Updated to v0.02 and also added 32 bit package. Hit the link given below to download.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You must have heard of (or used) the auto-reply features given by today&amp;rsquo;s instant messengers that are sent to the ones messaging you while you are not at your desk. But those are one-size-fits-all kind of messages. So, I wrote this simple tool a few months ago to turn Pidgin, everyone’s favourite multi-client Instant Messenger (works with gtalk, msn, yahoo, aim etc), into a &lt;strong>customized answering machine (and more)&lt;/strong> when you are away from your computer. Basically it allows you to divide up your contact list into groups based on email IDs and execute actions based on when someone from a particular group messages you while you are away. e.g. For general friends, you can keep a message like “Will talk to you later when I come back”, or if someone from office IMs you, it’ll send them your phone number “Call me at XXXXXX if urgent”. And if you boss is the one pinging you, you could direct the message towards your twitter account so that you get it as an SMS on your phone immediately.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update Aug 25 2008&lt;/strong>: Updated to v0.02 and also added 32 bit package. Hit the link given below to download.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You must have heard of (or used) the auto-reply features given by today&amp;rsquo;s instant messengers that are sent to the ones messaging you while you are not at your desk. But those are one-size-fits-all kind of messages. So, I wrote this simple tool a few months ago to turn Pidgin, everyone’s favourite multi-client Instant Messenger (works with gtalk, msn, yahoo, aim etc), into a &lt;strong>customized answering machine (and more)&lt;/strong> when you are away from your computer. Basically it allows you to divide up your contact list into groups based on email IDs and execute actions based on when someone from a particular group messages you while you are away. e.g. For general friends, you can keep a message like “Will talk to you later when I come back”, or if someone from office IMs you, it’ll send them your phone number “Call me at XXXXXX if urgent”. And if you boss is the one pinging you, you could direct the message towards your twitter account so that you get it as an SMS on your phone immediately.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Splert: Shantz Pidgin Away Alerts</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/18/splert-shantz-pidgin-away-alerts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 16:55:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/18/splert-shantz-pidgin-away-alerts/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a simple tool I wrote a few months ago to turn Pidgin, everyone’s favourite multi-client Instant Messenger (works with gtalk, msn, yahoo, aim etc), into a &lt;strong>customized answering machine (and more)&lt;/strong> when you are away from your computer. Basically it allows you to divide up your contact list into groups based on email IDs and execute actions based on when someone from a particular group messages you while you are away. e.g. For general friends, you can keep a message like “Will talk to you later when I come back”, or if someone from office IMs you, it’ll send them your phone number “Call me at XXXXXX if urgent”. And if you boss is the one pinging you, you could direct the message towards your twitter account so that you get it as an SMS on your phone immediately.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>This is a simple tool I wrote a few months ago to turn Pidgin, everyone’s favourite multi-client Instant Messenger (works with gtalk, msn, yahoo, aim etc), into a &lt;strong>customized answering machine (and more)&lt;/strong> when you are away from your computer. Basically it allows you to divide up your contact list into groups based on email IDs and execute actions based on when someone from a particular group messages you while you are away. e.g. For general friends, you can keep a message like “Will talk to you later when I come back”, or if someone from office IMs you, it’ll send them your phone number “Call me at XXXXXX if urgent”. And if you boss is the one pinging you, you could direct the message towards your twitter account so that you get it as an SMS on your phone immediately.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Time is short, so here are the details:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Features:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Group based rule execution, each group can contain any number of email IDs&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Custom replies for each group.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Integrates with twitter and will forward the message to your twitter account (or send a direct message to some other account) if you so desire. (Temporarily disabled since Twitter has blocked their IM bot)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Runs as a separate process over d-bus instead of running as a pidgin plugin, so much lesser chances of crashing.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Prerequisites:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Pidgin &amp;gt; 2.4.1&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Linux&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Download:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Usage:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Unzip the attached package anywhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Either install using the deb package or just copy the splert binary and config.txt to a folder of your choice&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Modify the “config.txt” file according to your needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Run splert. (or run splert -h for checking out the available options though you wouldn’t need them most of the times)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Config File:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Config file fields and formats are explained fully in the sample config file included in the attached file. However, here is a very basic sample configuration:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-ini" data-lang="ini">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">[Office]&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">user&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">bar@bar.com; abc@abc.com&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">message&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;Please Call me at 9876543210&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">twitter&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">0&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">[Friends]&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">user&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">foo@foo.com&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">message&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;Not Here. Will talk to you later&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">[VIP]&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">user&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">boss@boss.com&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">message&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;Got your message. Will Contact you asap&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">twitter&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">1&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">twitterto&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">my2ndtwitteracct&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>&lt;strong>ChangeLog:&lt;/strong>
0.03 - Oct04 2008 -&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Added option to specify twitter bot id (e.g. &lt;a href="mailto:twitterspy@jabber.org">twitterspy@jabber.org&lt;/a>) using option &amp;ldquo;-t/-twitterbot&amp;rdquo;. However, you need to do any &amp;ldquo;extra&amp;rdquo; stuff manually. e.g. logging in using twlogin command with twitterspy.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added option to specify the status when you want to send messages instead of just when being away. Use &amp;ldquo;-s/&amp;ndash;status&amp;rdquo; option to do this.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>0.02 - Aug25 2008 -&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Fixed bug where response was not sent for 1st message received&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added 32 bit package&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>0.01 - Aug15 2008 - Initial Version&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please let me know if you like it or found some issues with it. Also, let me know if you would like me to add any features to it.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Project: Shantz Webcam Autolocker</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/11/project-shantz-webcam-autolocker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2008 17:51:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/11/project-shantz-webcam-autolocker/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sometimes I do some things that even I can&amp;rsquo;t explain why I did &amp;rsquo;em. Did this one in one of those times as well. This is a simple script to monitor motion in front of your PC, auto-lock it when you are away and auto-unlock it when you come back. Did it just because I was really bogged down by the shitload of work that I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing for the past few weeks (and even weekends as well), so wanted to take a break for a few minutes, and just chanced over my own &amp;ldquo;Home Security Using a Webcam and Twitter&amp;rdquo; post, so thought of doing something related to motion detection again.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>Sometimes I do some things that even I can&amp;rsquo;t explain why I did &amp;rsquo;em. Did this one in one of those times as well. This is a simple script to monitor motion in front of your PC, auto-lock it when you are away and auto-unlock it when you come back. Did it just because I was really bogged down by the shitload of work that I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing for the past few weeks (and even weekends as well), so wanted to take a break for a few minutes, and just chanced over my own &amp;ldquo;Home Security Using a Webcam and Twitter&amp;rdquo; post, so thought of doing something related to motion detection again.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Hi BIOS! My Name Is "Linux", Or Is It?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/03/hi-bios-my-name-is-linux-or-is-it/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2008 17:44:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/03/hi-bios-my-name-is-linux-or-is-it/</guid><description>&lt;p>A couple of days ago, I read &lt;a href="http://mjg59.livejournal.com/96270.html">this&lt;/a> on Matthew Garrette’s blog, where he tells us about a vendor’s BIOS trying to figure out the OS type/version and setting things around on deciding the OS it is running. The call in question was _OSI(“Linux”). He goes on to say that the action the firmware takes, on finding out if the OS is linux, was probably inaccurate and it was good that linux kernel DOES NOT identify itself as “Linux” and returns false for the _OSI(“Linux”) and instead returns true when probed for Windows.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>A couple of days ago, I read &lt;a href="http://mjg59.livejournal.com/96270.html">this&lt;/a> on Matthew Garrette’s blog, where he tells us about a vendor’s BIOS trying to figure out the OS type/version and setting things around on deciding the OS it is running. The call in question was _OSI(“Linux”). He goes on to say that the action the firmware takes, on finding out if the OS is linux, was probably inaccurate and it was good that linux kernel DOES NOT identify itself as “Linux” and returns false for the _OSI(“Linux”) and instead returns true when probed for Windows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That got me thinking, the first thought being that isn’t this a BIG flaw in the kernel. I mean, trying to make the firmware aware of the OS and doing things accordingly is a good thing, right? Vendors can provide workarounds for OS flaws in this way. e.g. the thermal critical temperature event workaround that HP has for Windows Vista. If we are just emulating Vista here, then aren’t we inheriting their bugs as well? But “Never make judgements straightaway”, I have learnt in the past. So, thought about reading it a bit more. After some googling around, I came to know the sound reasoning behind the decision.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Why not return true for _OSI(“Linux”)?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>The difference between Linux and Windows is that the linux kernel is a continuously (and rapidly) moving target. When somebody probes for Windows 98 or Windows 2000 or Windows Vista, they can be sure about the behaviour, but Linux is too generic for us. The bug in one version of the kernel can be fixed in another one, and the behaviour changes, so one cannot rely on _OSI(“Linux”) as there is no generic/constant “Linux” interface.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>Why not then support _OSI(“Linux.xx.xx.xx”) or something equivalent to signify the kernel version?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>This is also not reliable because which kernel would this be, the mainline, Ubuntu’s kernel, Fedora’s kernel, Suse’s kernel, or some user patched kernel? Moreover, the bugs fixed in later kernel versions are often backported to earlier versions by various distros. So, again one cannot rely on the kernel version as such, and there are just too many different kernel branches out there for a vendor to check against.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>Why to return true for something like _OS(“Windows 2006”)?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>What I found out is that they do it because most vendors do most checks only if they find Windows and hence, it becomes a necessity to return true for this, for now.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="4">
&lt;li>But what does that mean, is it always going to remain the same?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Basically, what the kernel guys want is a better usage of the _OSI strings. They want the BIOS developers to check for a “capability” rather than a platform or platform version. Because consistent behaviour might be expected when checked for a platform like Windows (Actually its a platform + its version because there are separate strings for Windows 98, Windows ME, Windows NT, Windows Vista, etc) because they are slow moving targets with major changes to ACPI behaviour done only with the next version of the OS that is released after many years, but this is not true for faster targets like linux where changes happen often and can even be backported. So, essentially the situation will remain the same until vendors straighten out their code.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="5">
&lt;li>But is it justified for the linux developers/users to expect this to be followed by the vendors?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>This is a tough question with no straight answer. Even though linux users are in minority but still they are significant in number, and if they pay the same money for the hardware as their windows counterparts, they should get the same level of firmware support as well. However, that said, it is also true that the vendors have to draw the line somewhere and given the rapidly changing behaviour of the kernel they cannot always be expected to keep up, especially with all the costs involved. Thats why the kernel community wants them to be aware of these inherent flaws in their design and move to a system (check for capability, not for platform) where they don’t have to “keep up” anymore. And meanwhile they absorb the strain into the kernel/drivers, emulating as Windows, and trying to make the workarounds for Windows bugs in their code instead. And they have started efforts to make the vendors aware of this linux peculiarity and are trying to document the linux behaviour&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reading material: Thomas Renninger wrote this doc” &lt;a href="ftp://ftp.suse.com/pub/people/trenn/ACPI_BIOS_on_Linux_guide/acpi_guideline_for_vendors.pdf">ACPI BIOS Guideline For Linux&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m convinced with the reasoning. But as always, one man cannot look at all the angles and I might have missed the one that makes this all junk. Are you convinced too? Or do you have any other angle to provide?&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>A Breath Of Fresh Air: My New Ubuntu Desktop</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/21/a-breath-of-fresh-air-my-new-ubuntu-desktop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2008 18:54:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/21/a-breath-of-fresh-air-my-new-ubuntu-desktop/</guid><description>&lt;p>**UPDATE: **Surprisingly this post has found favour with “digg”ers :). Check the bottom of the post for some more info about the setup&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>UPDATE2&lt;/strong>: On popular demand, I&amp;rsquo;ve uploaded my .conkyrc. &lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/files/conkyrc.txt">Download Conky Configuration file by clicking here&lt;/a> and save as .conkyrc in your home folder.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After loitering around for so long, I finally got my lazy bum off the bed and installed Hardy Heron (8.04.1) onto my aging laptop. I’ve never been a sucker for eye-candy stuff, prefering to have more resources available for real work, instead of ooh-aahing over nice looking things all around my desktop. Well, but then I fell prey. I thought of giving another try to the thingamagic that compiz-fusion is, moreso since I didn’t have to go through loads of installing nuances like feisty because of it being already integrated in Hardy. An emerald install and a few minutes of tinkering later, I had a cool looking screen staring back at me. Here is a preview screenshot for your eyes but obviously the static screenshot wont show the amazing dynamic effects of CF. Let me see how many days I keep this up before going back to my plain-jane self. Click on the pic for full view:&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>**UPDATE: **Surprisingly this post has found favour with “digg”ers :). Check the bottom of the post for some more info about the setup&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>UPDATE2&lt;/strong>: On popular demand, I&amp;rsquo;ve uploaded my .conkyrc. &lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/files/conkyrc.txt">Download Conky Configuration file by clicking here&lt;/a> and save as .conkyrc in your home folder.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After loitering around for so long, I finally got my lazy bum off the bed and installed Hardy Heron (8.04.1) onto my aging laptop. I’ve never been a sucker for eye-candy stuff, prefering to have more resources available for real work, instead of ooh-aahing over nice looking things all around my desktop. Well, but then I fell prey. I thought of giving another try to the thingamagic that compiz-fusion is, moreso since I didn’t have to go through loads of installing nuances like feisty because of it being already integrated in Hardy. An emerald install and a few minutes of tinkering later, I had a cool looking screen staring back at me. Here is a preview screenshot for your eyes but obviously the static screenshot wont show the amazing dynamic effects of CF. Let me see how many days I keep this up before going back to my plain-jane self. Click on the pic for full view:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/desktop.jpg">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/desktop_thumb.jpg" alt="My all new and shiny desktop">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me know if you have any suggestions to improve it further, or want more pics/vids of my new lappy in action, or have any of your own to share.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Update: Setup info:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Base Theme: Ubuntu Studio (basically for icon set. Download ubuntustudio-look package for this)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Controls : From Xenon theme (Inbuilt in Ubuntu)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Wallpaper is something named “lotus” or something. Downloaded from interfacelift.com&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Compiz Fusion with almost all effects turned on. Ofcourse you can’t see most of them in the still image&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Emerald theme engine for glassy and rounded window borders (Download “emerald” package)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Dock at the bottom is avant window navigator (awn. Download package avant-window-navigator)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On right side, stats etc are from conky (Download package conky)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Misc: Turned transparency on for most things including gnome-terminal, gnome-panel, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Salient points:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The memory being consumed right now is around 850 MB. Thats with lots of applications, all CF effects turned on, most things having glass and transparent effects, and even my apache web server and mysql are running in background. And after that also, most memory (around 200 MB) is being eaten by firefox, leading to this high usage.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The setup boots up with just a shade over 300 MB being used, even though I’ve set CF and emerald on by default at boot and even apache and mysql start running on startup. :)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item><item><title>The Biggest Flaw in Gnome UI</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/07/the-biggest-flaw-in-gnome-ui/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2008 14:28:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/07/the-biggest-flaw-in-gnome-ui/</guid><description>&lt;p>Everywhere you go, any building you enter, any OS you operate, any settings window you open, one rule remains set in stone, “THE ESCAPE DOOR”. Always give an exit path, a way to make it all go away, make it look like nothing happened. But Gnome seems to think otherwise. Any settings window you open, all you see is a “close” button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/gnome_2Dui_2Dflaw.jpg">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/gnome_2Dui_2Dflaw_thumb.jpg" alt="Gnome-ui-flaw">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I made a few changes and then tried to “undo” them by using the following methods:&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>Everywhere you go, any building you enter, any OS you operate, any settings window you open, one rule remains set in stone, “THE ESCAPE DOOR”. Always give an exit path, a way to make it all go away, make it look like nothing happened. But Gnome seems to think otherwise. Any settings window you open, all you see is a “close” button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/gnome_2Dui_2Dflaw.jpg">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/gnome_2Dui_2Dflaw_thumb.jpg" alt="Gnome-ui-flaw">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I made a few changes and then tried to “undo” them by using the following methods:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Pressing the “close” button.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Pressing the little “x” on the upper right corner.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Pressing the “Escape” key.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Pressing “Alt+F4”.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>But no dice. Every method leads to saving of changes. The same thing occurs with EVERY dialogue box you can find in Gnome. I hate to say that this is something Windows seems to have got right (Maybe their UI designers are better than their OS programmers). What’s even more surprising is that even cross-platform apps (e.g. Firefox) give the “Apply” and “Cancel” buttons in Windows but not in Linux.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I hope Gnome developers listen and patch this up, or if there is any “hidden” tricks up your sleeve that will allow me to “go back in time”, please do let me know.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>My Brief History With Computers</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/06/23/my-brief-history-with-computers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2008 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/06/23/my-brief-history-with-computers/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m going to be bespectacled and have been advised to reduce and limit my computer usage considerably. A bit of nostalgia set in on hearing this and I thought about my short journey so far in this wonderland of solid-state and otherwise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First time I touched a computer&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
1989, at school in 2nd standard&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First command I typed on a computer&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;dir&amp;rdquo;, 1990, 3rd standard&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First game I played on a computer&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;bricks&amp;rdquo;, 1991, 4th standard&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>I’m going to be bespectacled and have been advised to reduce and limit my computer usage considerably. A bit of nostalgia set in on hearing this and I thought about my short journey so far in this wonderland of solid-state and otherwise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First time I touched a computer&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
1989, at school in 2nd standard&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First command I typed on a computer&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;dir&amp;rdquo;, 1990, 3rd standard&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First game I played on a computer&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;bricks&amp;rdquo;, 1991, 4th standard&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First Colored game I played on a computer&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;Dangerous Dave&amp;rdquo;, 1991, 4th standard&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First program I wrote on a computer&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;Hello, Ankit!&amp;rdquo; in basic, 1992, 5th standard (The pre-teenage rebel in me substituted the &amp;ldquo;world&amp;rdquo; by &amp;ldquo;Ankit&amp;rdquo;. Why &amp;ldquo;Ankit&amp;rdquo;? That&amp;rsquo;s a mystery ;-) )&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First time I held a mouse&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
1992, 5th standard, Windows 3.0&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First Windows Program I used&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
PaintBrush (MSPaint today), 1992, 5th standard&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First &amp;ldquo;3d&amp;rdquo; game I played&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Wolfenstein 3D (or Wolf), 1993, 6th standard&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First hack&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;Remote controlling&amp;rdquo; friend&amp;rsquo;s school PC by swapping the mouse cords, 1993, 6th standard&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First movie I watched on a computer&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;The wonderful world of Plants&amp;rdquo; or something similar, 1993, 6th standard&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First introduction to the internet&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
1994, 7th standard, A demo by an ISP to the whole school.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First site I opened on the internet&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
disneyland.com, 1994, 7th standard&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First commercial movie I watched on a computer&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;Who Framed Roger Rabbit&amp;rdquo;, 1995, 8th standard&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First introduction to Linux&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Suse 4.x, 1996, 9th standard&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First self-taught language learnt&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
HTML, 1997, 10th standard&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First Computer at home&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Celeron 466 MHz, 64 MB RAM, 8GB HDD, for around 60k, 1998, 11th standard&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First C program&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;Hello, Shantanu!&amp;rdquo;, 1998, 11th standard (Now, do you get it?)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First net connection at home&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
1998, 11th standard, ISP:Glide dial up. around 250 bucks for 5 hours at 56 kbps + telephone usage charges.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First Quake III Arena game&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
2000, almost at the end of 12th standard&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First major gaming session&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
2000, QIII Arena, 11 hours straight, Tier1-Tier5, 2 days before my CET exam (Entrance test for my engineering college). For the record, I was so obsessed with QIII back then that I even had a quicky 5-minute game (DM17 map) in the 45 minute break I got during the exam as my home was quite near the exam center.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; hack&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
2001, B.E., First year. Wrote and installed a TSR onto a friend&amp;rsquo;s system to print out &amp;ldquo;U R Doomed&amp;rdquo; whenever he typed something.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First Linux self-install&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Red Hat 7.0, 2001, B.E., First year&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Longest Gaming Session till date&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
December 2001, B.E., 2nd year. Deus Ex, 26 hours with 4-5 breaks spanning from 2-15 minutes max. Finished with all the alternate endings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First major Q3 Arena lan-tournament&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Early 2002, B.E. 2nd year. At NSIT Innovision tech fest.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First Blog&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;a href="http://iamhuman.blogspot.com/">http://iamhuman.blogspot.com&lt;/a>, 2004, B.E., Final year&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First program in the corporate world&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Optimization and multi-channelization of H.264 stitching, 2004&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First real project in the corporate world&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Epsilon, the new low cost BTS (Base Transceiver Station) by Nokia, 2004&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First Laptop&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
2005, Compaq Presario R4025, AMD64 2.0 GHz, 1GB RAM, 128 MB gfx Card. US$1300&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First Windows Mobile Program&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;a href="http://tech.shantanugoel.com/projects/windows-mobile/shantztodaychanger">ShantzTodayChanger&lt;/a>, 2007&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Finally bought first domain name&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;a href="http://shantanugoel.com/">http://shantanugoel.com&lt;/a>, 2008&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These “firsts” aren’t anything big in themeselves but have been an important part of my life in one or the other way making my love for computers growing at an even faster pace. So what are your nostalgic moments with your beloved machine?&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Keep Tab On Home Security With A Webcam And Twitter</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/14/keep-tab-on-home-security-with-a-webcam-and-twitter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2008 04:00:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/14/keep-tab-on-home-security-with-a-webcam-and-twitter/</guid><description>&lt;p>Worried about someone breaking into your house in your absence? Or just need to keep a tab on who enters your room while you are away? Well, all you need is a webcam, a linux PC/laptop and a twitter account. And you are set for real time updates through twitter about all that goes on at your abode behind your back (can even receive a text message/sms on your phone). Keep reading for the very simple setup you need.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>Worried about someone breaking into your house in your absence? Or just need to keep a tab on who enters your room while you are away? Well, all you need is a webcam, a linux PC/laptop and a twitter account. And you are set for real time updates through twitter about all that goes on at your abode behind your back (can even receive a text message/sms on your phone). Keep reading for the very simple setup you need.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Download and install &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://www.lavrsen.dk/twiki/bin/view/Motion/DownloadFiles">motion&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo; on your computer. For ubuntu users, this is as simple as running&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>sudo apt-get install motion
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Setup your motion configuration file. (Usually at /etc/motion/motion.conf). There are quite a lot of options available. You might want to tweak it a lot according to ur needs later on but the most important ones that you can begin with are (leave the rest untouched for now):&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a. Add/edit the option &amp;ldquo;target_dir&amp;rdquo; to point to the directory where you want to save the images of the event when motion is detected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b. Add/edit the option &amp;ldquo;locate&amp;rdquo; and set it to &amp;ldquo;on&amp;rdquo; so that you get a nice square box around the detected moving object/person.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>c. Add/edit the option &amp;ldquo;webcam_port&amp;rdquo; and set it to, say, &amp;ldquo;8000&amp;rdquo;. Motion includes a mini http server so now, you can use it to view the actual images of the happening when you get the update and check for false alarms.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Now, comes the most important part, about getting the update.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>motion has an option called &amp;ldquo;on_motion_detected&amp;rdquo; and here you can specify any command or program that you want to run when motion is detected. To get the update on your twitter account, use one of the following three methods with this option.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a. Using curl. If you have curl installed in your system, then you can use the following value for the on_motion_detected option:&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>curl -u yourusername:yourpassword -d status&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;Motion Detected! Check Immediately&amp;#34;&lt;/span> https://twitter.com/statuses/update.xml
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>b. Using wget. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have curl, you can even use wget with the following command:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>wget --post-data &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;status=Motion Detected! Check Immediately&amp;#34;&lt;/span> --http-user&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>yourusername --http-password&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>yourpassword https://twitter.com/statuses/update.xml -O /dev/null
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>c. Using my perl script. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have curl as well as wget, you can even use my perl script (attached below) for this. The value will now be:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>/path/to/script/twitter.pl &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;Motion Detected! Check Immediately&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;ol start="4">
&lt;li>Now connect your webcam and start motion (Just type &amp;ldquo;motion&amp;rdquo; on command line and press enter). Wait for someone to break in, or just roam around in front of the camera yourself and have fun as you receive a message on your phone about the &amp;ldquo;motion&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>PS: For receiving a text message on your phone, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to turn on the &amp;ldquo;Device Updates&amp;rdquo; option in your twitter account, otherwise you need to open the twitter web page to check the status.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The script: &lt;a href="http://tech.shantanugoel.com/resources/downloads/twitter.pl">Twitter Updating Perl Script&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me know if you put this to some other exciting uses or have any questions about the method described above.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#75715e">#!/bin/bash
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#75715e">&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#75715e">#Script to capture images from webcam and upload them to a server&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#75715e">#Author: Shantanu Goel&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#75715e">#Email: shantanu.goel@gmail.com&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>REMOTE_SERVER&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;your.remote.server.com&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>REMOTE_USER&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;username&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>REMOTE_DIR&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;/path/to/remote/dir&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>LOCAL_DIR&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;/path/to/local/dir&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>WEBCAM_DEV&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;/dev/video0&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>WEBCAM_RESOLUTION&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;640x480&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>WEBCAM_DELAY&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;5&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>fswebcam -d $WEBCAM_DEV -r $WEBCAM_RESOLUTION -D $WEBCAM_DELAY $LOCAL_DIR/webcam.jpg
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>scp $LOCAL_DIR/webcam.jpg $REMOTE_USER@$REMOTE_SERVER:$REMOTE_DIR/
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></content></item><item><title>Fun With Webcam In Linux</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/12/fun-with-webcam-in-linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2008 03:57:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/12/fun-with-webcam-in-linux/</guid><description>&lt;p>Did you know that instead of installing special software to view your webcam video, you can simply use mplayer for the same purpose, and with a lot of fine control. e.g. try running the following command with your webcam attached to your computer.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>mplayer -fps &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">15&lt;/span> tv:// -tv driver&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>v4l2:width&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>640:height&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>480:device&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>/dev/video0
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>And you can use mencoder to capture and encode video from your webcam:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>mencoder tv:// -tv driver&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>v4l2:width&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>60:height&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>40:fps&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>60:device&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>/dev/video0 -nosound -ovc lavc -lavcopts vcodec&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>mjpeg -o test.avi
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Have fun playing with the huge number of options available. You could even cat the test.avi file into a folder of your web server and have instant streaming video :-) .&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>Did you know that instead of installing special software to view your webcam video, you can simply use mplayer for the same purpose, and with a lot of fine control. e.g. try running the following command with your webcam attached to your computer.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>mplayer -fps &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">15&lt;/span> tv:// -tv driver&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>v4l2:width&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>640:height&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>480:device&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>/dev/video0
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>And you can use mencoder to capture and encode video from your webcam:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>mencoder tv:// -tv driver&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>v4l2:width&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>60:height&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>40:fps&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>60:device&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>/dev/video0 -nosound -ovc lavc -lavcopts vcodec&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>mjpeg -o test.avi
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Have fun playing with the huge number of options available. You could even cat the test.avi file into a folder of your web server and have instant streaming video :-) .&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Tip: Getting Your Webcam To Work In Ubuntu</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/10/tip-getting-your-webcam-to-work-in-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2008 19:17:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/10/tip-getting-your-webcam-to-work-in-ubuntu/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have an old noname cheapo webcam, that I dusted out of my junk (why? More on that in a post coming soon). I hoped that it would work in my Ubuntu setup out of the box like most of my other hardware. I connected it to my laptop&amp;rsquo;s usb port. dmesg gave the following output:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.211333] usb 1-1: new full speed USB device using ohci_hcd and address 2
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.319698] usb 1-1: configuration #1 chosen from 1 choice
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.439705] Linux video capture interface: v2.00
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.458509] zc0301: V4L2 driver for ZC0301[P] Image Processor and Control Chip v1:1.05
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.459113] usb 1-1: ZC0301[P] Image Processor and Control Chip detected (vid/pid 0x0AC8/0x301B)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.520576] usb 1-1: PB-0330 image sensor detected
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.870287] usb 1-1: Initialization succeeded
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.870919] usb 1-1: V4L2 device registered as /dev/video0
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.871001] usbcore: registered new interface driver zc0301
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.913737] usbcore: registered new interface driver gspca
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.913811] ubuntu/media/gspcav1/gspca_core.c: gspca driver 01.00.12 registered
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Great! Everything set up, I thought. But running various programs, camorama, camE, kopete, everything gave weird errors like &amp;ldquo;Connection could not be made&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;device not ready&amp;rdquo; or just showed a blank screen. But soon, after  few trial and errors, I found the solution. Basically the &amp;ldquo;zc0301&amp;rdquo; module is the culprit and all you have to do to get your camera working is prevent it from loading. So, this is what I did:&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>I have an old noname cheapo webcam, that I dusted out of my junk (why? More on that in a post coming soon). I hoped that it would work in my Ubuntu setup out of the box like most of my other hardware. I connected it to my laptop&amp;rsquo;s usb port. dmesg gave the following output:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.211333] usb 1-1: new full speed USB device using ohci_hcd and address 2
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.319698] usb 1-1: configuration #1 chosen from 1 choice
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.439705] Linux video capture interface: v2.00
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.458509] zc0301: V4L2 driver for ZC0301[P] Image Processor and Control Chip v1:1.05
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.459113] usb 1-1: ZC0301[P] Image Processor and Control Chip detected (vid/pid 0x0AC8/0x301B)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.520576] usb 1-1: PB-0330 image sensor detected
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.870287] usb 1-1: Initialization succeeded
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.870919] usb 1-1: V4L2 device registered as /dev/video0
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.871001] usbcore: registered new interface driver zc0301
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.913737] usbcore: registered new interface driver gspca
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[21328.913811] ubuntu/media/gspcav1/gspca_core.c: gspca driver 01.00.12 registered
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Great! Everything set up, I thought. But running various programs, camorama, camE, kopete, everything gave weird errors like &amp;ldquo;Connection could not be made&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;device not ready&amp;rdquo; or just showed a blank screen. But soon, after  few trial and errors, I found the solution. Basically the &amp;ldquo;zc0301&amp;rdquo; module is the culprit and all you have to do to get your camera working is prevent it from loading. So, this is what I did:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>sudo modprobe -r gspca
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>sudo modprobe -r zc0301
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>sudo modprobe gspca
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>And voila! the webcam started working like magic. Of course, this tip is only for webcams that use this particular chip. And if you want to make this change permanent so that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to run these commands everytime you want to use your webcam, all you have to do is add the following line to your /etc/modprobe.d/blacklist file&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>blacklist zc0301&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This would prevent the module from loading whenever you connect your webcam to your computer. Let me know if this worked for you or if you have some of your own tips/tricks/hacks to get this or other webcams working on linux.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Want To Program Smartly In C? Use GLib</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/03/smart-programming-in-c-using-glib/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2008 15:30:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/03/smart-programming-in-c-using-glib/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>GLib - An Introduction:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://library.gnome.org/devel/glib/">GLib&lt;/a> is a utility library for C, which augments the standard C library in several purposeful ways to make your life that much easier while programming. GLib has the following things to offer you:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**1. Portability: **The main issue that haunts any C developer is the portability of code. One cannot rely on the standard C library for this as you may find many functions that work differently under different platforms are aren&amp;rsquo;t there at all sometimes. GLib ensures that the all the functionality exposed by it remains consistent across platforms, so that you can rest assured that your code will work the way its supposed to work irrespective of the Operating System it&amp;rsquo;s being used for (Of course, this assumes that you have ensured about portability aspects of your non-GLib related source code). Moreover, GLib is available for a vast array of contemporary Operating Systems including GNU/Linux, Microsoft Windows and Mac OS X.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>&lt;strong>GLib - An Introduction:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://library.gnome.org/devel/glib/">GLib&lt;/a> is a utility library for C, which augments the standard C library in several purposeful ways to make your life that much easier while programming. GLib has the following things to offer you:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**1. Portability: **The main issue that haunts any C developer is the portability of code. One cannot rely on the standard C library for this as you may find many functions that work differently under different platforms are aren&amp;rsquo;t there at all sometimes. GLib ensures that the all the functionality exposed by it remains consistent across platforms, so that you can rest assured that your code will work the way its supposed to work irrespective of the Operating System it&amp;rsquo;s being used for (Of course, this assumes that you have ensured about portability aspects of your non-GLib related source code). Moreover, GLib is available for a vast array of contemporary Operating Systems including GNU/Linux, Microsoft Windows and Mac OS X.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**2. Security: **Though you still need to be careful about things like freeing allocated memories properly, etc but GLib does ensure that all its functionality is secure. Moreover, GLib has a policy of ensuring that all its functions are threadsafe. This saves you from a lot of checks and balances and locks and scheduling considerations if you had written all this yourself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>3. Useful Data Types:&lt;/strong> GLib exposes a lot of data types. Some are very basic that maintain portability across OS&amp;rsquo;s and 32-bit and 64-bit systems. e.g. you can rest assured that gint32 will always be 32 bit and gint64 will always be 64 bit data types.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apart from this, it also provides a lot of derived data types e.g. singly linked lists, doubly linked lists, hash tables, stacks, queues, trees, and much more. It&amp;rsquo;d basically cover most of you data structure needs that you&amp;rsquo;d have otherwise had to implement yourselves. And it also provides helper functions that makes working with them so much more easier. If you have ever used Perl, and have wished that C programming could be a bit faster like it, you will be pleasantly surprised.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**4. Utility Functions: **GLib also provides various utility functions to ease out your manipulation of data. Some of the functions are meant as more secure and portable replacements for those provided with standard C library, while rest are meant to provide other useful functionality which you earlier had to implement in your code. Some of the major areas covered by GLib&amp;rsquo;s utility functions are String manipulation, character set manipulation and conversion (including unicode and base64), using regular expressions, file manipulation, shell functions, config file parsing (my favourite), etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>End Note:&lt;/strong> I can understand that there would be a lot of people who believe that use of GLib is dumbing down programming in C. After all, we take pride being in control of our code and this is why we love progrmming in C because we have options to do things in our own way. Yes, that is all true but there comes a time where you&amp;rsquo;d like to spend more time in developing the core functionality of your app, or focus more on giving a rapid shape to your new idea, rather than reinventing the wheel and fumbling around with writing the helper functions. So, keeping that in mind I believe GLib is wonderful piece of code that has enabled me to churn out new apps that much faster.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Page Rank 7: True Or Google Glitch?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/30/page-rank-7-true-or-google-glitch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2008 20:33:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/30/page-rank-7-true-or-google-glitch/</guid><description>&lt;p>I installed google toolbar (linux version) today in firefox and for this blog, it says that its page rank is &lt;strong>7&lt;/strong>. I can&amp;rsquo;t believe my eyes. I suppose it&amp;rsquo;s a google glitch may be (but have a wishful thinking at the back of mind that its true :-) ).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Are you getting the same result for this blog (or weird page rank results for other places that you frequent?)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/tech_shantanugoel_com_pagerank_7.jpg">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/tech_shantanugoel_com_pagerank_7_thumb.jpg" alt="tech_shantanugoel_com_pagerank_7_thumb">&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>I installed google toolbar (linux version) today in firefox and for this blog, it says that its page rank is &lt;strong>7&lt;/strong>. I can&amp;rsquo;t believe my eyes. I suppose it&amp;rsquo;s a google glitch may be (but have a wishful thinking at the back of mind that its true :-) ).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Are you getting the same result for this blog (or weird page rank results for other places that you frequent?)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/tech_shantanugoel_com_pagerank_7.jpg">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/tech_shantanugoel_com_pagerank_7_thumb.jpg" alt="tech_shantanugoel_com_pagerank_7_thumb">&lt;/a>&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Windows App Alternatives For Linux: MSPaint</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/28/windows-app-alternatives-for-linux-mspaint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2008 15:30:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/28/windows-app-alternatives-for-linux-mspaint/</guid><description>&lt;p>Some of you might know that I was in the hunt for a decent mspaint alternative &lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/03/wanted-a-good-paint-program-for-linux.html">recently&lt;/a>. Note that I didn&amp;rsquo;t go for GIMP / Inkscape etc because they were overkill for what I wanted to do. Many a times, I just wanted to touch up a screenshot or make a simple flow image by drawing a few boxes, use a few pointing arrows, and add some text here and there. All this could be done with the previous mentioned programs as well but took a bit more steps than I wanted (stroking the selections / paths for lines, boxes, circles, and even then, no arrows). I didn&amp;rsquo;t find an adequate replacement at the time but got it now, so thought of writing about it. Basically I came across 4 apps: tuxpaint, gpaint, kolourpaint and mtpaint. Won&amp;rsquo;t discuss tuxpaint here cuz I found it a little too kiddish.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>Some of you might know that I was in the hunt for a decent mspaint alternative &lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/03/wanted-a-good-paint-program-for-linux.html">recently&lt;/a>. Note that I didn&amp;rsquo;t go for GIMP / Inkscape etc because they were overkill for what I wanted to do. Many a times, I just wanted to touch up a screenshot or make a simple flow image by drawing a few boxes, use a few pointing arrows, and add some text here and there. All this could be done with the previous mentioned programs as well but took a bit more steps than I wanted (stroking the selections / paths for lines, boxes, circles, and even then, no arrows). I didn&amp;rsquo;t find an adequate replacement at the time but got it now, so thought of writing about it. Basically I came across 4 apps: tuxpaint, gpaint, kolourpaint and mtpaint. Won&amp;rsquo;t discuss tuxpaint here cuz I found it a little too kiddish.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>gpaint: (Available in Ubuntu repositories) gpaint is a very simplistic program that has a mspaint look and feel but feels a bit lacking. It can do basic procedures like basic shape selections, lines, boxes but that&amp;rsquo;s it. No polygon selections, brush, color picker, etc, and yeah no arrows. Moreover, it saves only in pngs.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/gpaint.png">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/gpaint-thumb.png" alt="gpaint screenshot">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>kolourpaint: (Available in Ubuntu Repositories) kolourpaint is very close to mspaint. Infact it does a bit more than mspaint. It has all the things that I mentioned as missing in gpaint, plus has basic image manipulation effects as well. I liked it quite a bit, but it had 2 drawbacks for me, still no arrows, and it depends on KDE/Qt libraries.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/kolourpaint.png">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/kolourpaint-thumb.png" alt="kolourpaint screenshot">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>mtpaint: (Available in Ubuntu Repositories from Gutsy onwards. Rest of the folks can search for a package on net, or find a suitable package or source &lt;a href="http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=155874&amp;amp;package_id=173703">here&lt;/a>) This is the software that got me most excited. It is actually a kind of lower-intermediate package that lies somewhere between mspaint and a very basic, poor man&amp;rsquo;s GIMP. It has all the features ok kolourpaint, (plus arrows at last :-) ), a small smattering of basic effects (gaussian, edge detection, blur, embossing), can work with gifs also (handles transparency and animation quite well). So, this is the one I would be sticking to for now.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/mtpaint.png">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/mtpaint-thumb.png" alt="mtpaint screenshot">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am using mtpaint now for my basic needs. Hope the article benefitted you as well. If I missed out on some package, then do let me know.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>ImageMagick: Weaving Magic With Your Pictures</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/26/imagemagick-weaving-magic-with-your-pictures/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2008 06:23:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/26/imagemagick-weaving-magic-with-your-pictures/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve known about ImageMagick tools for quite some time now but never dabbled with it. A couple of weeks ago I played with it for some time (notice the new cascaded polaroid pics header above) and was amazed even more. Few of its shining features:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>It has almost unlimited features to manipulate your images through its tools like convert, montage, mogrify etc and their long list of options.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>It is available for Windows, Linux and Mac as well.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>I’ve known about ImageMagick tools for quite some time now but never dabbled with it. A couple of weeks ago I played with it for some time (notice the new cascaded polaroid pics header above) and was amazed even more. Few of its shining features:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>It has almost unlimited features to manipulate your images through its tools like convert, montage, mogrify etc and their long list of options.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>It is available for Windows, Linux and Mac as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Runs on web servers also (most of those nifty image sites use it for run time image manipulation)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>It is amazingly fast.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Runs on the command line, which means batching of operations can be done and is also good for butter fingered people like me who are clumsy with GUI based image manipulation programs&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Has modules for interfacing with C, perl, php, C++, C#, java, etc. So, you can create your own applications around it.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>It’s FREE (as in speech and as in beer)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>It has an amazing documentation over at imagemagick.org and also a very thriving community, so help is just a few clicks away.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>As a very rudimentary sample of what it can do for you, take a look at my blog’s header above. I just gave it a few pics and ran a command, and it resized them, turned them into polaroid pics, rotated them at random angles, made the background transparent, strung them together to make a webpage header/banner.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since the command was specific for the number and names of images, I made a simple perl script to automate the command making process so you can also download this script (link at the end of post) and run it to create your own header. (You might want to tweak the $w and $h variables in the script to specify your header’s width and height). Running it would be like&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>./pano.pl &amp;lt;imagenames&amp;gt;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>e.g.
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>./pano.pl myimages/*
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>After I made this script, I came across &lt;a href="http://stason.org/photos/gallery/">Stas Bekman’s photo gallery&lt;/a> which has a much better and cool stack effect with photos. And he generously agreed to share his script (much more sophisticated than my my few lines) with me. His script is also attached below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me know if you use any of these scripts (as it is or after modifying them) to create any cool effects.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>5 Reasons I Like Linux (And 5 Why I Dislike It)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/19/5-reasons-i-like-linux-and-5-why-i-dislike-it/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2008 20:20:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/19/5-reasons-i-like-linux-and-5-why-i-dislike-it/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Disclaimer Notes:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>I wrote this because these things just came into my mind today while I was reading about the impending &amp;ldquo;Hardy Heron&amp;rdquo; release related things and saw that there is a lot of FUD being spread still. So, thought of jotting down my likes/dislikes and not making it a linux v/s windows campaign. Though at a few places, it might be necessary to compare the two just to put things into perspective.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Disclaimer Notes:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>I wrote this because these things just came into my mind today while I was reading about the impending &amp;ldquo;Hardy Heron&amp;rdquo; release related things and saw that there is a lot of FUD being spread still. So, thought of jotting down my likes/dislikes and not making it a linux v/s windows campaign. Though at a few places, it might be necessary to compare the two just to put things into perspective.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>These are reasons why &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>I&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo; like/dislike Linux and not why others might like/dislike it although you might find common patterns.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Most of my recent experience is with Ubuntu these days, so most examples would be from it as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>These reasons are purely from an end-user&amp;rsquo;s perspective and not from a linux developer&amp;rsquo;s perspective. So, I&amp;rsquo;m not taking into factor that I can change the kernel (or most other things&amp;rsquo;) source code because &amp;ldquo;generally&amp;rdquo; I don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>This post is quite long. And if you have a flame to send out my way (which you are most welcome to do), please read it in its entirety before doing so, because many things I say at some point have some caveats covered at another point.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>5 Reasons why I like Linux:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Light on Resources&lt;/strong>: I must say that Linux is what still keeps my more than 3 years old laptop running in a prim condition with the latest and greatest of everything from technology stand-point as well as eye-candy stuff. An example: With almost every effect of Compiz Fusion turned on, hordes of screenlets and AWN enabled, an Apache/MySQL/PHP based server running, and a dozen of other applications (firefox, nautilus, terminal, GIMP, RhythmBox, Open Office Word Processor, VLC player, etc) open, my setup consumes around 500 MB of RAM. While on the other hand, if I was using Vista, It&amp;rsquo;d have demanded atleast 1 GB of RAM just to run Aero, forget about the rest of the things.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Cost&lt;/strong>: This is a big factor for me. Almost everything is free or atleast has a free alternative available. Most of the times I&amp;rsquo;ve found these free software to be much better than commercial software in terms of feature sets as well as stability. But even otherwise, when there are cases where the free alternative a bit lagging as compared to the commercial one (e.g. GIMP v/s Photoshop), I haven&amp;rsquo;t felt that my needs have ever outgrown the free software.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Ease of Use&lt;/strong>: Doing &amp;ldquo;stuff&amp;rdquo; on linux is just so easy. By &amp;ldquo;stuff&amp;rdquo;, I mean everything from doing some normal day chores, downloading files, customizing things, automating routine tasks, etc. The backbone for this is &amp;ldquo;the terminal&amp;rdquo; (not the movie :P). I can do almost anything I want from the console. It not only saves me time and frustration in executing a program, waiting for the GUI to load and then go through a series of clicks but also allows me to batch up everything into one pretty little command. Moreover, every thing has so many options that I can configure to my liking. (More on the &amp;ldquo;options&amp;rdquo; later below)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Getting Software&lt;/strong>: Getting software couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more easy.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>It generally involves typing in &lt;code>sudo apt-get install &amp;lt;software&amp;gt;&lt;/code>, pressing enter, and that&amp;rsquo;s it. The latest version is ready to roll on your machine.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Reboots are minimal. Even after thinking for quite long, it&amp;rsquo;s very hard to recall any time when I had to &amp;ldquo;log-off&amp;rdquo; my system (let alone reboot) after installing a software (or even a driver)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Updates are automatic, and not just for the OS or a few core components, but for all the software that I installed through repositories (but not for the ones which I installed from my local deb&amp;rsquo;s or compilations, which is understandable of course)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The latest fixes/patches are available very quickly. Moreover, the revision cycle for most distros lies between 6–12 months and hence, even a complete desktop upgrade is quickly available as well (as compared to the 7 year period after which Vista came out). You can even &amp;ldquo;upgrade&amp;rdquo; to the latest distro revision without having to wipe everything, though I generally prefer a clean install.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Security&lt;/strong>: Now, I agree with everyone that the reason why we don&amp;rsquo;t see many viruses for linux is because the user base is very less as compared to other OS&amp;rsquo;s but I also believe that this is not the &amp;ldquo;only&amp;rdquo; reason.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The thing is that since most of the software is open source, so exploits are found quite quickly and patched and released rapidly. While in a closed source environments, even if a white hat reports it, the exploits go on un-noticed, un-worked upon by the developers (A good example is the recent falling of Vista during the &amp;ldquo;Pwn to Own&amp;rdquo; contest because of a known but unpatched vulnerability by Adobe, not a fault of Vista in this case though but you get my drift).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The security model otherwise is also quite tight and its very hard for someone to exploit it till the time you use common sense along with it. (A linux virus can easily wipe your &amp;ldquo;/home&amp;rdquo; without acquiring root permissions).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>5 Reasons why I dislike Linux&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These reasons irk me the most but aren&amp;rsquo;t enough for to make me move away from Linux. I mention them because getting them right would make my Linux expereince that much more joyful and probably others feels the same too. Moreover, this is not a gripe and is not a command/order to &amp;ldquo;the Linux guys&amp;rdquo; out there to fix it, because linux is of, by and for the community. And being a part of this community, I share the burden of this equally and would like to help out in making it better in whatever ways possible, developing, testing, suggesting things.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Getting Software:&lt;/strong> I had mentioned about how easy it is to get software from most distros&amp;rsquo; repositories with a single command. However, getting and installing software is also a challenge that many people face in linux. After sometime your particular version of the distro stops updating the software and will include only security fixes and such. Now, there are many good people who would backport software for your version but not all the time. You can download pacakges off the internet (debs&amp;rsquo; for ubuntu) but they might not work because of too many inter-mingled dependencies. Compiling is another option but many times, it can spiral out of hand. I hope we can better softwares like GDebi that could make this much more easier.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Options:&lt;/strong> Earlier I listed having so many options as one of my reasons to like Linux. But, sometimes, too many options tend to get to my head. This gets even more difficult when you have too many choices but no clue about what means what and which one is the best. However, the community is continously trying to make this right. A lot of documentation projects are going on, and the mailing lists, IRC networks and other forums also give out a lot of information. Especially for Ubuntu, I find a huge community based support system which always helps me out. (PS – The Ubuntu Forums are the nicest forums you&amp;rsquo;ll ever come across. I am yet to come across a post that contains words like &amp;ldquo;RTFM&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;n00b&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Ease Of Use:&lt;/strong> Some times, just some times, the lack of a GUI for common things irks me and I wish in respect of a few things (read wi-fi) that things could &amp;ldquo;just work&amp;rdquo;. But I guess this is a trade-off that I can live with, and moreover this situation is also improving especilly due to the efforts taken by Ubuntu, Mandriva, Fedora, GNOME and KDE. (Special thanks to nm-applet ;-) ). Moreover, Hardy Heron, b43 and the latest linux kernels promise to solve the wi-fi setup issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Browsing&lt;/strong>: The browsing experience on linux isn&amp;rsquo;t too great. But this is not a fault of Linux as such. This is due to companies providing adequate linux support (e.g. java plugins for 64 bit) and too many sites optimizing their code for IE. But again, there is hope for this as we can already run IE on linux (IEs4Linux) plus SUN has promised a 64 bit java firefox plugin with the next JRE.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Drivers:&lt;/strong> This is again due to companies not giving proper linux support for their hardware and not even releasing their hardware details for the OSS community to develop their own drivers. However, I can understand that giving out hardware details might not be an option for these companies considering the competition, and also proper software support might be a bit unfeasible due to a smaller consumer base. But again, more and more companies are seeing the light now and releasing proper drivers for linux, with Nvidia and ATi taking the lead (When will Creative listen?). And a special thanks to the OSS community for making working drivers despite all this.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>So, this is it. After reading back through what I just wrote, I am dead sure that I will stick to Linux as the trade-offs are too meagre for me. Will you?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Wanted: A Good Paint Program For Linux</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/03/wanted-a-good-paint-program-for-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2008 12:47:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/03/wanted-a-good-paint-program-for-linux/</guid><description>&lt;p>Have been in the hunt for a good basic paint program for linux for so long. I&amp;rsquo;m running a Ubuntu Feisty Fawn (amd64) box (yeah, yeah I didn&amp;rsquo;t upgrade to Gutsy because it sneaked up too quickly onto me and the impending loom of LTS goodness of Hardy was also there). Have been suggested various things so far like GPaint, Kolourpaint, tuxpaint etc but none of them cuts it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, I love GIMP but its an overkill when I have to go through 2 menus, a dialogue box and several clicks, just to make a silly rectangle, but I don&amp;rsquo;t hold anything against it cuz afterall its an &amp;ldquo;Image Manipulation&amp;rdquo; program, not a painting one.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>Have been in the hunt for a good basic paint program for linux for so long. I&amp;rsquo;m running a Ubuntu Feisty Fawn (amd64) box (yeah, yeah I didn&amp;rsquo;t upgrade to Gutsy because it sneaked up too quickly onto me and the impending loom of LTS goodness of Hardy was also there). Have been suggested various things so far like GPaint, Kolourpaint, tuxpaint etc but none of them cuts it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, I love GIMP but its an overkill when I have to go through 2 menus, a dialogue box and several clicks, just to make a silly rectangle, but I don&amp;rsquo;t hold anything against it cuz afterall its an &amp;ldquo;Image Manipulation&amp;rdquo; program, not a painting one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, what do you use/recommend when you have to draw a few basic shapes, connect them through lines and arrows, put in a mashup of few silly pics and colorize it a bit with basic effects? And are there any gnome native ones or do I ultimately have to give in to install KDE dependencies?&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>TIP: Make Those Linux Samba Shares Accessible From Windows Mobile</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/30/tip-make-those-linux-samba-shares-accessible-from-windows-mobile/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2008 10:30:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/30/tip-make-those-linux-samba-shares-accessible-from-windows-mobile/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you have ever needed to share files between your Linux and Windows computers, you have obviously used &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Samba_(software)">Samba&lt;/a>, and have been quite happy with the way it seamlessly provides access to and from shared folders/files from Windows and Linux. However, many people complain that although their smb/Samba shares are accessible from Windows, they are not able to do the same with their Windows Mobile devices. e.g., using a tool called &amp;ldquo;Resco Explorer&amp;rdquo; on Windows Mobile, all they get while searching for their linux based Samba shares is the following screenshot:&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>If you have ever needed to share files between your Linux and Windows computers, you have obviously used &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Samba_(software)">Samba&lt;/a>, and have been quite happy with the way it seamlessly provides access to and from shared folders/files from Windows and Linux. However, many people complain that although their smb/Samba shares are accessible from Windows, they are not able to do the same with their Windows Mobile devices. e.g., using a tool called &amp;ldquo;Resco Explorer&amp;rdquo; on Windows Mobile, all they get while searching for their linux based Samba shares is the following screenshot:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/1_cant_find_computer.jpg" alt="Cannot Find Computer on Network">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, there is no big magic trick to get an access to those shares, as they are already accessibly. You just need to do one more teeny little step to access them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The trick is that on Windows Mobile it will not detect your computer as having a shareable folder and will not show it, and it will thus not show a list of shared folders. So, what you need to do is enter the path to the folder you want to access. e.g.: If your computer&amp;rsquo;s name is &amp;ldquo;MyComp&amp;rdquo; and the folder you want to access is &amp;ldquo;MyFolder&amp;rdquo;, then you need to give the path &amp;ldquo;\MyComp\MyFolder&amp;rdquo; to the application on Windows Mobile from which you are trying to access your shares and it&amp;rsquo;ll connect without any problems. Of course, it&amp;rsquo;ll ask you for your username/pwd for which you need to enter your linux user name and password. Below screenshots tell you how to do this with Resco Explorer, however the same method can be used for other applications like Total Commander, Windows Mobile File Explorer, etc as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Enter Path and click share.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/2_enter_full_path.jpg" alt="Enter Full Path">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>Enter User Name / Password&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/3_enter_user_password.jpg" alt="Enter User Name And Password">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>Its done :-)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/4_its_done.jpg" alt="Access To Share Is Done">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me know if you face any issues with this.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Project: Shantz Copy Basket (Compatible with linux as well as windows)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/16/project-shantz-copy-basket-compatible-with-linux-as-well-as-windows/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2008 13:26:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/16/project-shantz-copy-basket-compatible-with-linux-as-well-as-windows/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m sure you have copied/moved files on your computer from one place to another. And I’m sure often you have to do more than just “single-shot” copying that is copy a few files to one place, move a few to another, and copy yet some more to one more location. Well, I had to do this quite a few times (e.g. I ran out of disk space recently on a partition and had to empty out my “Movies” and “Songs” folders to move a few movies/songs each to all other partitions/disks according to the space available). Hence, I wrote this little command line program, which behaves like a basket.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>I’m sure you have copied/moved files on your computer from one place to another. And I’m sure often you have to do more than just “single-shot” copying that is copy a few files to one place, move a few to another, and copy yet some more to one more location. Well, I had to do this quite a few times (e.g. I ran out of disk space recently on a partition and had to empty out my “Movies” and “Songs” folders to move a few movies/songs each to all other partitions/disks according to the space available). Hence, I wrote this little command line program, which behaves like a basket.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can put any number of files from any number of different locations into it in a single shot. It will store their locations and give them an ID. Now, you can copy/move those files to different destinations based on their IDs. What&amp;rsquo;s even better is that your basket will remain intact even across reboots. So, you can continue working on the files in the basket even for days.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Note: **Packages for windows as well as linux have been uploaded. If you have perl, a perl script is also given that works in both platforms without change. I have tested it on Windows XP SP2 and Ubuntu Feisty Fawn 7.04.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Ubuntu TIP: Automating Package Installation – apt-get to the rescue</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/06/ubuntu-tip-automating-package-installation--apt-get-to-the-rescue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2008 03:30:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/06/ubuntu-tip-automating-package-installation--apt-get-to-the-rescue/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Admin Note:&lt;/strong> Rahul is a long time friend of mine, and is a well known geek amongst his friends and colleagues. I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce that he will be enriching this site from time-to-time as a guest editor/author. First up is a small tid-bit of a script that he wrote to ease up his life between installations and reinstallations of everyone&amp;rsquo;s favourite OS: Ubuntu. Over to his post..&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have you ever had to reinstall your ubuntu installation, and then bear the pain of manually installing the applications you&amp;rsquo;ve come to love (i mean use :)) everyday? If yes, then cheer up buddy, because all you really need is some magic (read scripting), some typing and spend some time digging the package names of your favourite applications.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Admin Note:&lt;/strong> Rahul is a long time friend of mine, and is a well known geek amongst his friends and colleagues. I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce that he will be enriching this site from time-to-time as a guest editor/author. First up is a small tid-bit of a script that he wrote to ease up his life between installations and reinstallations of everyone&amp;rsquo;s favourite OS: Ubuntu. Over to his post..&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have you ever had to reinstall your ubuntu installation, and then bear the pain of manually installing the applications you&amp;rsquo;ve come to love (i mean use :)) everyday? If yes, then cheer up buddy, because all you really need is some magic (read scripting), some typing and spend some time digging the package names of your favourite applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To get started, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to type the package information in a configuration file. The format of the file is really simple&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Any line starting with a # is ignored&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Blank lines are ignored&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Any other line, the first word is taken as the package name you want to install&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>chmod +x rapt-client-install-packages.sh
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Run this script as root (or using sudo command)&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>sudo ./rapt-client-install-packages.sh configFile&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-go" data-lang="go">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">In&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">case&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">you&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">do&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">not&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">specify&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">the&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">configFile&lt;/span> (&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">e&lt;/span>.&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">g&lt;/span>. &lt;span style="color:#f92672">package&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">-&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">names&lt;/span>.&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">lst&lt;/span>), &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">it&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">will&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">bug&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">you&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">to&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">manually&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">enter&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">packages&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">names&lt;/span> :&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">D&lt;/span>.
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">What&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">this&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">script&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">does&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">is&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">1.&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">read&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">package&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">names&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">from&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">the&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">file&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">specified&lt;/span> (&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">or&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">bug&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">user&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">for&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">package&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">names&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">in&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">case&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">filename&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">is&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">not&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">specified&lt;/span>)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">2.&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">install&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">these&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">packages&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">That&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#960050;background-color:#1e0010">&amp;#39;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">s&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">it&lt;/span>. &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">And&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">if&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">everything&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">runs&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">fine&lt;/span>, &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">you&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">should&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">have&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">a&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">system&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">will&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">all&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">your&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">beloved&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">apps&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">installed&lt;/span>.
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">The&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">below&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">snippet&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">from&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">the&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">sample&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">configuration&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">file&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">would&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">install&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">the&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">packages&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#960050;background-color:#1e0010">–&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">hardinfo&lt;/span>, &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">gmountiso&lt;/span>, &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">devilspie&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">and&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">nautilus&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">-&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">open&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">-&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">terminal&lt;/span>. &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">The&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">lines&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">for&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">sysinfo&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">and&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">istanbul&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">would&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">be&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">ignored&lt;/span>. &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">In&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">case&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">you&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">later&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">wish&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">to&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">install&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">these&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">packages&lt;/span>, &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">all&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">you&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">need&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">to&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">do&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">is&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">uncomment&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">the&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">line&lt;/span>, &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">and&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">run&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">the&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">script&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">again&lt;/span> :).
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>#sysinfo = UNIX/Linux system information
hardinfo = UNIX/Linux hardware information
gmountiso = a PyGTK GUI to mount your cd images
#istanbul = Desktop session recorder
devilspie = find windows and perform actions on them
nautilus-open-terminal = nautilus plugin for opening terminals in arbitrary local paths&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-go" data-lang="go">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">Note&lt;/span>:
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span>&amp;gt;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span>&amp;gt;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span>&amp;gt; &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">1.&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">The&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">script&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">will&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">fail&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">in&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">case&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">the&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">package&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">cannot&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">be&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">found&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">using&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">the&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">repositories&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">enabled&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">on&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">your&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">system&lt;/span>.
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span>&amp;gt;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span>&amp;gt; &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">2.&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">In&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">case&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">you&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">use&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">additional&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">repositories&lt;/span>, &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">you&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">must&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">add&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">these&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">manually&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">to&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">your&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">apt&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">configuration&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">file&lt;/span>, &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">and&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">do&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">``&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#960050;background-color:#1e0010">`&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">bash&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">sudo&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">apt&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">-&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">get&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">update&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>The hard part is not the installation, but setting up the applications to your likings :D&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote></content></item><item><title>Linux: Webcam Fun</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/02/linux-webcam-fun/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2008 03:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/02/linux-webcam-fun/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you thought that a webcam is just for getting in visual touch with your distant friends, then you could not be more wrong. There are many other uses e.g., making videos, rudimentary security systems, etc. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that it&amp;rsquo;d be as simple as a a few keystrokes and a couple of clicks, until I stumbled across this article on Linux.com - &lt;a href="http://www.linux.com/feature/126186">Five fun ways to use a Linux webcam&lt;/a>. It lists out the following five things that can be achieved ever so easily with a webcam and your linux box:&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>If you thought that a webcam is just for getting in visual touch with your distant friends, then you could not be more wrong. There are many other uses e.g., making videos, rudimentary security systems, etc. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that it&amp;rsquo;d be as simple as a a few keystrokes and a couple of clicks, until I stumbled across this article on Linux.com - &lt;a href="http://www.linux.com/feature/126186">Five fun ways to use a Linux webcam&lt;/a>. It lists out the following five things that can be achieved ever so easily with a webcam and your linux box:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Record Yourself&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Make a Video Streaming webserver&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Monitor your house&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>ASCIIfy your image&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>More fun with your videos and stills&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Do check it out at the aforementioned link.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>TIP: WordPress Posts Scheduling - Back To The Future (or Blast From The Past?)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/26/tip-wordpress-posts-scheduling-back-to-the-future-or-blast-from-the-past/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/26/tip-wordpress-posts-scheduling-back-to-the-future-or-blast-from-the-past/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you are like me (I mean underpaid, overworked, coding zombie), then the only time you find for blogging is weekends. To keep your readers happy and satisfied through the week, the only options you have are burning the midnight electricity (what? You still use oil? :P) or paying up your son/nephew/wife/etc to push the publish button regularly for the drafts you wrote on weekend. Right? &lt;strong>WRONG&lt;/strong>….&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Matt and his AutoMattic team took care of bonded labour like us, and had the good heart to put in the capability of scheduling posts in WordPress (More commonly known as “&lt;em>future posting&lt;/em>”). So, all you have to do is say “Hey Wordy boy, here is a bagful of my posts, but don’t you dare release them before I’ve gone for my hawaii vacation. And yeah, one at a time so it can keep your tummy full till I return.”&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>If you are like me (I mean underpaid, overworked, coding zombie), then the only time you find for blogging is weekends. To keep your readers happy and satisfied through the week, the only options you have are burning the midnight electricity (what? You still use oil? :P) or paying up your son/nephew/wife/etc to push the publish button regularly for the drafts you wrote on weekend. Right? &lt;strong>WRONG&lt;/strong>….&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Matt and his AutoMattic team took care of bonded labour like us, and had the good heart to put in the capability of scheduling posts in WordPress (More commonly known as “&lt;em>future posting&lt;/em>”). So, all you have to do is say “Hey Wordy boy, here is a bagful of my posts, but don’t you dare release them before I’ve gone for my hawaii vacation. And yeah, one at a time so it can keep your tummy full till I return.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, being honest, you will have to do just a tad little bit more than that, but it’ll be a teeny weeny bit only, I promise. Read on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are using the WordPress web interface to make your posts (are you still living in the darkages? Didn’t you hear about BlogJet, Live Writer, Zoundry?), then all you have to do is that when you make your post, before pressing the publish button, look towards your lower left hand corner (No man, I mean the lower left corner of “the screen”, not your table). You will see something like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/wordpress_future_post_time1.png" alt="Wordpress_future_post_time1">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, all you gotta do is, check that little checkbox that says “Edit Timestamp” and then change the date and time to the time when you want to be actually published. Click “Publish”, and then….well, that’s it. You are done. It will look something like this (the post will be published on Feb 26, 9:30 AM):&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/wordpress_future_post_time2.png" alt="Wordpress_future_post_time2">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But, you are indeed keeping up with the modern times, you say, and are using cool desktop client tools, e.g. ,I use BlogJet (and that too over linux, read &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/29/blogjet-blog-faster-blog-better-now-in-linux-too-with-a-hidden-bonus.html">this&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> for more). So what can we do about that. Its pretty simple really, almost the same thing. Again, look in the lower left corner, and you see:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/blogjet_future_post_time1.png" alt="Blogjet_future_post_time1">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obviously, you are intelligent enough to modify it to look like this before pressing the lovely, earthy publish button:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/blogjet_future_post_time2.png" alt="Blogjet_future_post_time2">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All set? No, there is one little difference in this method. When you are posting through a desktop client, the post time seem to be interpreted in GMT in WordPress, so you have to discount for that. e.g., as an example if my time zone is +6:00 wrt GMT, I have put in the time as 3:30 AM in BlogJet to achieve the same publish time (Feb 26, 09:30 AM local time).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hope this was easy enough for you. If it was, then don’t forget to spend the extra time on weekdays buying groceries and taking some burden off your wife/mom/etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**PS: **This post was future-posted as well, and through BlogJet, if you must ask.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>TIP: Switching Soundcards In Ubuntu</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/12/tip-switching-soundcards-in-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2008 18:00:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/12/tip-switching-soundcards-in-ubuntu/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you have multiple soundcards in your system and have to switch between them regularly (e.g. laptop owners like me, who use an external soundcard while being docked to groove to the highest and the lowest of frequencies through those 7.1 channels and use the in-built sound card while on the move) you would definitely be under-whelmed by the less-than-stellar performance of ubuntu in switching between the sound cards. For me at least, ubuntu (fiesty 7.04 amd64) never seems to recognize that I&amp;rsquo;ve connected the speakers to my Audigy 2 ZS Notebook PCMCIA card, and merrily continues to huff-puff through the tinny laptop speakers until I manually go into the sound preferences, switch over to multichannel playback and vice versa. Well, I still haven&amp;rsquo;t found an automated solution for the switching, but here is a little cli-magic to do this in a click.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>If you have multiple soundcards in your system and have to switch between them regularly (e.g. laptop owners like me, who use an external soundcard while being docked to groove to the highest and the lowest of frequencies through those 7.1 channels and use the in-built sound card while on the move) you would definitely be under-whelmed by the less-than-stellar performance of ubuntu in switching between the sound cards. For me at least, ubuntu (fiesty 7.04 amd64) never seems to recognize that I&amp;rsquo;ve connected the speakers to my Audigy 2 ZS Notebook PCMCIA card, and merrily continues to huff-puff through the tinny laptop speakers until I manually go into the sound preferences, switch over to multichannel playback and vice versa. Well, I still haven&amp;rsquo;t found an automated solution for the switching, but here is a little cli-magic to do this in a click.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have alsa on ur system, just use the command &amp;ldquo;asoundconf list&amp;rdquo; first to list out all the soundcards connected to your system. e.g. on my system, the output is&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>$asoundconf list
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>IXP
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>AUDIGY2
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Here, IXP is my internal sound card and AUDIGY2 is my external (PCMCIA) sound card. Now, all you need to is use &lt;code>asoundconf set-default-card &amp;lt;cardname&amp;gt;&lt;/code> to switch over to any card desired. So, what I did was make 2 bash scripts, and insert this command in them with each having one of my soundcards&amp;rsquo; names.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>script 1 - setixp.sh&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#75715e">#!/bin/bash
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#75715e">&lt;/span>asoundconf set-default-card IXP
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Similarly, script 2 - setaudigy.sh&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#75715e">#!/bin/bash
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#75715e">&lt;/span>asoundconf set-default-card AUDIGY2
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Now, all that remains is save the two scripts (maybe in ur home directory or ur desktop), and make them executable (use &lt;code>chmod +x &amp;lt;scriptname&amp;gt;&lt;/code>). Now, whenever you want to switch to a card, just double-click on the appropriate script, and watch the sound getting redirected. oops, make that &amp;ldquo;hear&amp;rdquo; the sound :P.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Ubuntu Nuggets: Window list settings in panel</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/01/ubuntu-nuggets-window-list-settings-in-panel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 19:06:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/01/ubuntu-nuggets-window-list-settings-in-panel/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am pretty sure that all of you must be fed of that one windows taking up the whole task bar in the panel. Like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/titlebar1.jpg">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/titlebar1_thumb.jpg" alt="Titlebar1">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, you can change that. Plus, all you windows-to-linux converts must also be thinking of how to squeeze in a few more windows into the task bar. A &amp;ldquo;grouping of similar windows&amp;rdquo; option like windows would have been just nice. Well, that can be done too, and without any shell scripting, config file modifying, etc. It&amp;rsquo;s all in the GUI for a change &lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/smile1.gif" alt="">&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>I am pretty sure that all of you must be fed of that one windows taking up the whole task bar in the panel. Like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/titlebar1.jpg">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/titlebar1_thumb.jpg" alt="Titlebar1">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, you can change that. Plus, all you windows-to-linux converts must also be thinking of how to squeeze in a few more windows into the task bar. A &amp;ldquo;grouping of similar windows&amp;rdquo; option like windows would have been just nice. Well, that can be done too, and without any shell scripting, config file modifying, etc. It&amp;rsquo;s all in the GUI for a change &lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/smile1.gif" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All you need to do is:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Right click on the window list area, as shown by the red ellipse mark in the figure and click on &amp;ldquo;preferences&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/titlebar2.jpg">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/titlebar2_thumb.jpg" alt="Titlebar2">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>You will get a window as shown below. Now, in the options marked by the black ellipse, you can choose the grouping option for the windows that you open to get more space and a windows like effect.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/window_list_pref1.jpg">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/window_list_pref1_thumb.jpg" alt="Window_list_pref1">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>If you click on the &amp;ldquo;size&amp;rdquo; tab, you can modify the &amp;ldquo;maximum&amp;rdquo; width value to control how much space any window title can take on the title bar. You can also specify the minimum width if you wish to.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/window_list_pref2.jpg">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/window_list_pref2_thumb.jpg" alt="Window_list_pref2">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="4">
&lt;li>Click Close and you are done. Now, wasn&amp;rsquo;t that easy. Here is a screenshot of how that window title we saw in the first pic looks after this change.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/titlebar.jpg">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/titlebar_thumb.jpg" alt="Titlebar">&lt;/a>&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>BlogJet - Blog Faster, Blog Better (Now In Linux too, with a hidden bonus)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/29/blogjet-blog-faster-blog-better-now-in-linux-too-with-a-hidden-bonus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2008 15:30:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/29/blogjet-blog-faster-blog-better-now-in-linux-too-with-a-hidden-bonus/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/blogjet_in_linux.png" alt="BlogJet in Linux" title="BlogJet in Linux">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/blogjet_in_linux.png">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/blogjet_in_linux_thumb1.jpg" alt="Blogjet in Linux" title="Blogjet in Linux">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A quick googling for &lt;em>&lt;a href="http://www.google.co.in/search?q=best+desktop+blogging+client&amp;amp;ie=utf-8&amp;amp;oe=utf-8&amp;amp;aq=t&amp;amp;rls=com.ubuntu:en-US:official&amp;amp;client=firefox-a">best desktop blogging client&lt;/a>&lt;/em> would yield just a few (read millions/gazillions) results. Having researched the subject a lot, my choices were finally limited down to &lt;a href="http://www.codingrobots.com/blogjet/">BlogJet&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.blogdesk.org/en/index.htm">BlogDesk&lt;/a>, as per my feature set requirement goes (Primarily, off line editing, draft, WYSIWYG editing, categories, tagging support, pinging, trackbacks support, timestamping, past post editing, automatic image uploading) BUT there is one little problem. Both of these don&amp;rsquo;t work on Linux.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/blogjet_in_linux.png" alt="BlogJet in Linux" title="BlogJet in Linux">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/blogjet_in_linux.png">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/blogjet_in_linux_thumb1.jpg" alt="Blogjet in Linux" title="Blogjet in Linux">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A quick googling for &lt;em>&lt;a href="http://www.google.co.in/search?q=best+desktop+blogging+client&amp;amp;ie=utf-8&amp;amp;oe=utf-8&amp;amp;aq=t&amp;amp;rls=com.ubuntu:en-US:official&amp;amp;client=firefox-a">best desktop blogging client&lt;/a>&lt;/em> would yield just a few (read millions/gazillions) results. Having researched the subject a lot, my choices were finally limited down to &lt;a href="http://www.codingrobots.com/blogjet/">BlogJet&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.blogdesk.org/en/index.htm">BlogDesk&lt;/a>, as per my feature set requirement goes (Primarily, off line editing, draft, WYSIWYG editing, categories, tagging support, pinging, trackbacks support, timestamping, past post editing, automatic image uploading) BUT there is one little problem. Both of these don&amp;rsquo;t work on Linux.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In fact, the current crop of Linux based blog clients is at best childish, compared to these. A piece of software called &lt;a href="http://www.larryborsato.com/bleezer/">Bleezer&lt;/a> did offer a good set of features and supported linux as well, but turned out it was so crash-y, hogged up enormous amounts of ram, and had other issues that come usually packed with all java apps. But I wasn&amp;rsquo;t gonna boot into WinDUHs, just for one sole software, was I?? Sure, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/smile1.gif" alt="Smile" title="Smile">. I tried the usual routine of trying to run them through wine but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t supported. I resorted to my faithful ol&amp;rsquo; google, and chanced across &lt;a href="http://www.thetechandcents.com/2007/11/running-zoundry-blog-editor-under-wine.html">this little nugget&lt;/a>, with step by step instructions to achieve my goal. And it had a bonus. It told me about &lt;a href="http://www.tatanka.com.br/ies4linux/page/Main_Page">IEs4Linux&lt;/a> (IE&amp;rsquo;s For Linux). yes, you read correctly. You can run Internet Explorer on your Linux box as well. All this in under 10 minutes (Ubuntu wins again). And yeah,&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>