<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Software on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/software/</link><description>Recent content in Software on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 11:31:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Is Android Open Source Or Not?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/25/android-open-source-or-not/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 11:31:06 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/25/android-open-source-or-not/</guid><description>Is Android really open source or not? That is the question being asked by almost everyone. A lot of people, especially those influenced by RDF or those who are in the news industry with no idea about OS and open source but were asked by their boss to get a scoop on this pronto, tend to bring up a few keywords and then twist them around in the way they see fit to make sure it says Android isn&amp;rsquo;t open.</description></item><item><title>Project: Shantz-XwinWrap Updated to 0.02</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/18/project-shantz-xwinwrap-updated-to-002/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2008 11:03:48 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/18/project-shantz-xwinwrap-updated-to-002/</guid><description>As some of you know that I&amp;rsquo;ve taken up the development of the ultra-cool xwinwrap tool that allows you to use movies, screensavers etc as wallpapers for you linux desktops. Here is version 0.02 for you consumption that fixes a bug because of which the generated window was overlapping other windows.
The download file has plain executable binaries as well as deb packages for Ubuntu. Moreover, I&amp;rsquo;ve included both 32 bit as well as 64 bit versions.</description></item><item><title>Shantz XWinWrap: The "Moving" Wallpaper Fun Continues</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/03/shantz-xwinwrap-the-moving-wallpaper-fun-continues/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 14:46:02 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/03/shantz-xwinwrap-the-moving-wallpaper-fun-continues/</guid><description>XWinWrap is a small utility written a loooong time ago that allowed you to stick most of the apps to your desktop background (Thanks to fsckin for introducing me to it). What this meant was you could use an animated screensaver (like glmatrix, electric sheep, etc) or even a movie, and use it as your wallpaper. But only one version of this app was released, and it had a few problems, like it wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly &amp;ldquo;sticking&amp;rdquo; to the background and geometry option didn&amp;rsquo;t work as well.</description></item><item><title>Shantz XWinWrap</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/03/shantz-xwinwrap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 14:41:44 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/03/shantz-xwinwrap/</guid><description>XWinWrap is a small utility written a loooong time ago that allowed you to stick most of the apps to your desktop background. What this meant was you could use an animated screensaver (like glmatrix, electric sheep, etc) or even a movie, and use it as your wallpaper. But only one version of this app was ever released, and it had a few problems, like:
Well, sticking didn&amp;rsquo;t work.</description></item><item><title>5 Reasons I Like Linux (And 5 Why I Dislike It)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/19/5-reasons-i-like-linux-and-5-why-i-dislike-it/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2008 20:20:40 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/19/5-reasons-i-like-linux-and-5-why-i-dislike-it/</guid><description>Disclaimer Notes:
I wrote this because these things just came into my mind today while I was reading about the impending “Hardy Heron” release related things and saw that there is a lot of FUD being spread still. So, thought of jotting down my likes/dislikes and not making it a linux v/s windows campaign. Though at a few places, it might be necessary to compare the two just to put things into perspective.</description></item><item><title>shantz-csv-to-opml</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/22/shantz-csv-to-opml/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2008 04:53:53 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/22/shantz-csv-to-opml/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION
This is a very simple script that I did for a friend. It can be used to quickly generate blogrolls.
Input: csv file with blog author names and blog links
Output: OPML file that can be imported into many blogging/blogrolling software and websites (e.g. wordpress, blogrolling.com, etc)
Usage:
shantz-csv-to-opml.pl &amp;lt;input file in csv format&amp;gt; &amp;lt;output opml filename&amp;gt; Input File Format: Each line should be like this: &amp;lt;Name of Author&amp;gt;,&amp;lt;bloglink&amp;gt;,&amp;lt;bloglink&amp;gt;... e.</description></item></channel></rss>