<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Software on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/software/</link><description>Recent content in Software on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 11:31:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Is Android Open Source Or Not?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/25/android-open-source-or-not/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 11:31:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/25/android-open-source-or-not/</guid><description>&lt;p>Is Android really open source or not? That is the question being asked by almost everyone. A lot of people, especially those influenced by &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reality_distortion_field">RDF&lt;/a> or those who are in the news industry with no idea about OS and open source but were asked by their boss to get a scoop on this pronto, tend to bring up a few keywords and then twist them around in the way they see fit to make sure it says Android isn&amp;rsquo;t open. They don&amp;rsquo;t need to be correct, they only need the article to &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>sound correct&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo; by picking up sentences out of context or putting quotes only from people who agree with them. This will convince their boss and 99% of their readers who have no idea about all these things either. But the boss is happy he got a story and associated clicks. Readers are happy because they got the points to float around in their next forum flame war. They don&amp;rsquo;t have to read when someone corrects them. They have made their points and rest is all someone making noises like a rat.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>Is Android really open source or not? That is the question being asked by almost everyone. A lot of people, especially those influenced by &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reality_distortion_field">RDF&lt;/a> or those who are in the news industry with no idea about OS and open source but were asked by their boss to get a scoop on this pronto, tend to bring up a few keywords and then twist them around in the way they see fit to make sure it says Android isn&amp;rsquo;t open. They don&amp;rsquo;t need to be correct, they only need the article to &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>sound correct&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo; by picking up sentences out of context or putting quotes only from people who agree with them. This will convince their boss and 99% of their readers who have no idea about all these things either. But the boss is happy he got a story and associated clicks. Readers are happy because they got the points to float around in their next forum flame war. They don&amp;rsquo;t have to read when someone corrects them. They have made their points and rest is all someone making noises like a rat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lot out of the rest of the people, who are indeed informed, make the mistake of thinking that &amp;ldquo;Open Source = GPL&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Open Source = Free Software&amp;rdquo;, which is not true. Open source is similar to free software but is one that choses to keep more options open. In short, Free Software Movement, as the one evangelized by FSF, is a subset of open source that tries to achieve freedom of software by restriction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please also note that many people including Steve Jobs confuse people more by interchanging between open and open source. An android phone that you get may not be open, the android market may be open, etc but this discussion is purely about open-source.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyways, with asbestos underwear on, I write this post to speak my mind about this matter by talking about various points thrown up by the above mentioned classes. Since this is going to be a long post, I&amp;rsquo;ll mention here the things it is going to cover:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Allegations against Android&amp;rsquo;s open-source nature. Are they true?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Does OSI Foundation (&lt;a href="http://www.opensource.org">Open source Initiative&lt;/a>) think that Android is open source?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Android and open source in layman terms&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Takeaways/conclusion&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update&lt;/strong>: Updated the article as per Tony and Kasper&amp;rsquo;s comments below. Thanks Kasper and Tony for your valuable inputs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="android-and-open-source-allegations-and-answers">Android and Open Source: Allegations and Answers&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allegation&lt;/strong>: Google does a lot of development in private for few months and then releases the code to public.
&lt;strong>Answer&lt;/strong>: Almost every open source project I know does this. Do you think every person who works on an open source project pushes his code to the mainline 10 times when re writes a 10 line code? No. He completes the feature, tests it and then pushes it out. Individuals might do it sooner, companies might do it later but everyone pushes out their code when they feel things are fairly ready. So, Google choses to do the &amp;ldquo;push&amp;rdquo; every few months when they think their new feature set is ready. This, of course, is more influenced by the fact that they need to be competitive in the aggressive mobile market and hence not let the competitors know about the exact features but still it is well within the limits of open source. And they are doing it before/with the binary release as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also to be noted here is the fact that the &amp;ldquo;code dump&amp;rdquo; is done only for major releases. Minor fixes and even features keep trickling into the code base every now and then and these allow others to make fixes as well. e.g. Cyanogen was able to bring &amp;ldquo;802.11n&amp;rdquo; capability and was able to include various fixes including one for wi-fi sleep policies before they actually made into an OTA update for any phone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allegation&lt;/strong>: Only google employees can check in code to mainline.
&lt;strong>Answer&lt;/strong>: Every open source project has only a select few folks who can check in code. Most of the open source projects start with only their founders having commit access. They may or may not give commit accesses to anyone else. Check out various open source projects on sourceforge, googlecode, etc and you will find this. Most of the projects that do choose to give commit access to others, start doing it after some time when they feel the project is mature enough and they are confident enough in someone else. Android is just a hatchling, around 2 years old. It has begun making strides only now so Google may even choose to take the latter path but I can understand if Google wants to keep this as their control point because of the hustle and bustle of the mobile OS world which is much more rapid and cut throat than the desktop OS and this does not make them closed. Not only that, but seeing how everyone in the mobile world is so trigger happy with suing everyone else, it creates a legal issue for them as they would be the ones to answer if someone else brings this upon them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allegation&lt;/strong>: Google only accepts their own code into official android and nobody else&amp;rsquo;s.
&lt;strong>Answer&lt;/strong>: This one is hilarious. Obviously, anyone who says this hasn&amp;rsquo;t actually been to review.android.com. Just go their and check whether any merged changes have non-google, non-android email ids. Anyone can upload their patches there but the accepted ones are fairly low. This problem is present in every popular open source project, even the Linux kernel. But is more pronounced in the case of android because Google&amp;rsquo;s android team is much smaller than the number of persons working on other projects and there is red tape of a big company involved. If you want to get your patch in, just like the kernel, you need to engage with them. Talk to them in the relevant bug report, comment the code properly, give them a reason to not avoid your patch. But yes, the process is still very slow and it is eons faster to just contribute to a fork like cyanogenmod. I do hope that google does get better in this regard soon though.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allegation&lt;/strong>: It is not possible to make a full android build from the public code tree of android.
&lt;strong>Answer&lt;/strong>: BS. Cyanogen does just fine with his full AOSP builds. People argue that Google does not release the modem/baseband code but they idiotically fail to realize that the baseband code is not part of Android at all. It is the IP of the baseband manufacturer and is specific to each hardware. Android is just the code that runs on apps hardware. Google does not indeed release the code of their built in google apps (gtalk/gmail etc) though but they are already working towards that and these apps will not be a part of the base Android system anymore. These would be standalone apps and even now you don&amp;rsquo;t need them to make a fully working android build.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allegation&lt;/strong>: &amp;ldquo;Android&amp;rdquo; is a registered trademark and is held by Google.
&lt;strong>Answer&lt;/strong>: Linus holds the trademark for &amp;ldquo;Linux&amp;rdquo;, Mozilla foundation holds the trademark for &amp;ldquo;Firefox&amp;rdquo;, Canonical holds the trademark for &amp;ldquo;Ubuntu&amp;rdquo;. Get the drift? Basically, it is completely possible and allowed for an open source software to be trademarked.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allegation&lt;/strong>: Google doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop the carriers/OEMs from locking down the phones, adding bloatware or custom UIs.
&lt;strong>Answer&lt;/strong>: This is an issue with carriers/OEMs and not Android. Google uses the apache software license (ASL), which is a permissive license (like MIT, BSD, etc) and hence does not stop the carriers from doing such a thing (In fact, this is the very foundation of being open, check the next passage about OSI foundation, point no. 9). Many people say they should, but if they did then they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be open anymore, would they?
Even Linus Torvalds is against making such a stipulation of not allowing locking of phones and this is the biggest reason why the Linux Kernel (and lot of other open source projects) didn&amp;rsquo;t move to FSF&amp;rsquo;s (&lt;a href="http://www.fsf.org">Free Software Foundation&lt;/a>) GPL v3. I wonder why no one calls the Linux kernel closed hmmmm&amp;hellip;
BTW, if you are so serious about unlocked/rootable phones then buy a dev phone directly from google or get one from Synapse.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="android-and-open-source-osi-foundation">Android and Open Source: OSI Foundation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The OSI foundation has a few guidelines to determine whether something is open source or not under their &lt;a href="http://www.opensource.org/osd.html">Open Source Definition&lt;/a>. Android uses the OSI compatible Apache Software License (ASL) but still let&amp;rsquo;s see whether Android comes up to all of them or not. If it is in conflict with even one of the requisites, we will call Android closed.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Allow free redistribution - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Give out un-obfuscated source code - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Allow modifications and derived works - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Allow distribution of modifications (as patches) or modified software as a whole. Can restrict the modified versions from using original name of software - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No discrimination against any person or groups - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No restriction of using the software on any device or field - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No additional license needed - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No product-specific license - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No restriction on software distributed along with original software - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Technology neutral, i.e., no preference for an individual technology or user interface - Check
So, Android is true to each and every point that being open demands to it. In fact, points 9 and 10 are fundamental in making it open but alas, people less oriented with open software tend to term this as being closed (as seen in the last allegation above)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="android-and-open-source-from-a-laymans-view-point">Android and Open Source: From a layman&amp;rsquo;s view point&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Apart from the above, I would also like to share a few &amp;ldquo;layman-examples&amp;rdquo; which will let you understand for yourself why Android is open:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>You can see all the official android OS code without any restrictions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can download it, fork it, modify it without asking google&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can port it to any device without asking google&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can develop and sell your phone with Android without asking google
Now compare that with any other mobile OS you know.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="android-and-open-source-conclusion">Android and Open Source: Conclusion&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>So, the takeaways from the above wall of text are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Android is open-source&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Android is permissively open-source instead of being restrictive&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Android can do better in terms of community driven development but is perhaps held back by pace of competition and legalities involved. But, this in no way makes it non-open-source.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Let me know if you have any corrections or allegations to make :)&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Project: Shantz-XwinWrap Updated to 0.02</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/18/project-shantz-xwinwrap-updated-to-002/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2008 11:03:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/18/project-shantz-xwinwrap-updated-to-002/</guid><description>&lt;p>As some of you know that I&amp;rsquo;ve taken up the development of the ultra-cool xwinwrap tool that allows you to use movies, screensavers etc as wallpapers for you linux desktops. Here is version 0.02 for you consumption that fixes a bug because of which the generated window was overlapping other windows.&lt;br>
The download file has plain executable binaries as well as deb packages for Ubuntu. Moreover, I&amp;rsquo;ve included both 32 bit as well as 64 bit versions.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>As some of you know that I&amp;rsquo;ve taken up the development of the ultra-cool xwinwrap tool that allows you to use movies, screensavers etc as wallpapers for you linux desktops. Here is version 0.02 for you consumption that fixes a bug because of which the generated window was overlapping other windows.&lt;br>
The download file has plain executable binaries as well as deb packages for Ubuntu. Moreover, I&amp;rsquo;ve included both 32 bit as well as 64 bit versions.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Shantz XWinWrap: The "Moving" Wallpaper Fun Continues</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/03/shantz-xwinwrap-the-moving-wallpaper-fun-continues/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 14:46:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/03/shantz-xwinwrap-the-moving-wallpaper-fun-continues/</guid><description>&lt;p>XWinWrap is a small utility written a loooong time ago that allowed you to stick most of the apps to your desktop background (Thanks to &lt;a href="http://www.fsckin.com/2008/04/14/fun-with-xwinwrap-in-compiz-fusion/">fsckin&lt;/a> for introducing me to it). What this meant was you could use an animated screensaver (like glmatrix, electric sheep, etc) or even a movie, and use it as your wallpaper. But only one version of this app was released, and it had a few problems, like it wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly &amp;ldquo;sticking&amp;rdquo; to the background and geometry option didn&amp;rsquo;t work as well.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>XWinWrap is a small utility written a loooong time ago that allowed you to stick most of the apps to your desktop background (Thanks to &lt;a href="http://www.fsckin.com/2008/04/14/fun-with-xwinwrap-in-compiz-fusion/">fsckin&lt;/a> for introducing me to it). What this meant was you could use an animated screensaver (like glmatrix, electric sheep, etc) or even a movie, and use it as your wallpaper. But only one version of this app was released, and it had a few problems, like it wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly &amp;ldquo;sticking&amp;rdquo; to the background and geometry option didn&amp;rsquo;t work as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seeing no-one picking it up, I decided to give it a bit of polish last weekend by fixing the above problems and also add a few features.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I hope to continue on the good work that was done by the original author and provide an even better xwinwrap to you all. Pour in those ideas about what features you&amp;rsquo;d like to see in this.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Shantz XWinWrap</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/03/shantz-xwinwrap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 14:41:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/03/shantz-xwinwrap/</guid><description>&lt;p>XWinWrap is a small utility written a loooong time ago that allowed you to stick most of the apps to your desktop background. What this meant was you could use an animated screensaver (like glmatrix, electric sheep, etc) or even a movie, and use it as your wallpaper. But only one version of this app was ever released, and it had a few problems, like:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Well, sticking didn&amp;rsquo;t work. So if you did a &amp;ldquo;minimize all&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;go to desktop&amp;rdquo; kind of thing, your &amp;ldquo;wallpaper&amp;rdquo; got minimized as well.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>XWinWrap is a small utility written a loooong time ago that allowed you to stick most of the apps to your desktop background. What this meant was you could use an animated screensaver (like glmatrix, electric sheep, etc) or even a movie, and use it as your wallpaper. But only one version of this app was ever released, and it had a few problems, like:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Well, sticking didn&amp;rsquo;t work. So if you did a &amp;ldquo;minimize all&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;go to desktop&amp;rdquo; kind of thing, your &amp;ldquo;wallpaper&amp;rdquo; got minimized as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The geometry option didn&amp;rsquo;t work, so you could not create, e.g., a small matrix window surrounded by your original wallpaper.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Seeing no-one picking it up, I decided to give it a bit of polish last weekend by fixing the above problems and also add a few features. And here it is, in its new avatar &amp;ldquo;Shantz XWinWrap&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Video:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/k8BCyhAHKSc?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Usage&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Notes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The download file above contains 32 bit as well as 64 bit binaries. (Deb packages for ubuntu/debian are also included in the same file)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Though a lot of options are shown below, the only ones you&amp;rsquo;d most likely need are &amp;ldquo;fs&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;g&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;ov&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sh&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The modified source code can be browsed/downloaded from the &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/xwinwrap">Shantz XWinWrap Launchpad Bzr repository&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>xwinwrap [-g {w}x{h}+{x}+{y}] [-ni] [-argb] [-fs] [-s] [-st] [-sp] [-a] [-b] [-nf] [-o OPACITY] [-sh SHAPE] [-ov] -- COMMAND ARG1...
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>Options:
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-g    - Specify Geometry (w=width, h=height, x=x-coord, y=y-coord. ex: -g 640x480+100+100)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-ni   - Ignore Input
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-d - Desktop Window Hack. Provide name of the &amp;#34;Desktop&amp;#34; window as parameter
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-argb - RGB
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-fs   - Full Screen
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-s    - Sticky
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-st   - Skip Taskbar
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-sp   - Skip Pager
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-a    - Above
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-b    - Below
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-nf   - No Focus
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-o    - Opacity value between 0 to 1 (ex: -o 0.20)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-sh   - Shape of window (choose between rectangle, circle or triangle. Default is rectangle)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-ov   - Set override_redirect flag (For seamless desktop background integration)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>-debug - Enable Debug messages
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Examples:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Examples use glmatrix however you can use something like mplayer, vlc, electric sheep etc instead of these)&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>To run glmatrix in fullscreen wallpaper mode&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>./xwinwrap -ov -fs -- /usr/lib/xscreensaver/glmatrix -root -window-id WID
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>To run glmatrix in a small window wallpaper mode&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>./xwinwrap -ov -g 400x400+400+200 -- /usr/lib/xscreensaver/glmatrix -root -window-id WID
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>To run glmatrix in small circle wallpaper mode&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>./xwinwrap -ov -g 400x400+400+200 -sh circle -- /usr/lib/xscreensaver/glmatrix -root -window-id WID
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>To run glmatrix in small triangular wallpaper mode&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>./xwinwrap -ov -g 400x400+400+200 -sh triangle -- /usr/lib/xscreensaver/glmatrix -root -window-id WID
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>&lt;strong>ChangeLog:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>15-Feb-2009:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed the bug where XFetchName returning a NULL for &amp;ldquo;name&amp;rdquo; resulted in a crash. Props to Kevin&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Provided an option to specify the desktop window name.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Added Debug messages.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>18-Oct-2008:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Fixed a bug where the generated window overlapped other windows.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>28-Aug-2008:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed &amp;ldquo;sticky&amp;rdquo;, now it sticks like a true wallpaper to your desktop.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fixed &amp;ldquo;geometry&amp;rdquo; option. Now you can create smaller windows and draw/position them anywhere on your screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Added non-rectangular shaped windows option. Now, you can create circular or triangular windows with xwinwrap to get that cool effect.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></content></item><item><title>5 Reasons I Like Linux (And 5 Why I Dislike It)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/19/5-reasons-i-like-linux-and-5-why-i-dislike-it/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2008 20:20:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/19/5-reasons-i-like-linux-and-5-why-i-dislike-it/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Disclaimer Notes:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>I wrote this because these things just came into my mind today while I was reading about the impending &amp;ldquo;Hardy Heron&amp;rdquo; release related things and saw that there is a lot of FUD being spread still. So, thought of jotting down my likes/dislikes and not making it a linux v/s windows campaign. Though at a few places, it might be necessary to compare the two just to put things into perspective.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Disclaimer Notes:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>I wrote this because these things just came into my mind today while I was reading about the impending &amp;ldquo;Hardy Heron&amp;rdquo; release related things and saw that there is a lot of FUD being spread still. So, thought of jotting down my likes/dislikes and not making it a linux v/s windows campaign. Though at a few places, it might be necessary to compare the two just to put things into perspective.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>These are reasons why &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>I&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo; like/dislike Linux and not why others might like/dislike it although you might find common patterns.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Most of my recent experience is with Ubuntu these days, so most examples would be from it as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>These reasons are purely from an end-user&amp;rsquo;s perspective and not from a linux developer&amp;rsquo;s perspective. So, I&amp;rsquo;m not taking into factor that I can change the kernel (or most other things&amp;rsquo;) source code because &amp;ldquo;generally&amp;rdquo; I don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>This post is quite long. And if you have a flame to send out my way (which you are most welcome to do), please read it in its entirety before doing so, because many things I say at some point have some caveats covered at another point.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>5 Reasons why I like Linux:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Light on Resources&lt;/strong>: I must say that Linux is what still keeps my more than 3 years old laptop running in a prim condition with the latest and greatest of everything from technology stand-point as well as eye-candy stuff. An example: With almost every effect of Compiz Fusion turned on, hordes of screenlets and AWN enabled, an Apache/MySQL/PHP based server running, and a dozen of other applications (firefox, nautilus, terminal, GIMP, RhythmBox, Open Office Word Processor, VLC player, etc) open, my setup consumes around 500 MB of RAM. While on the other hand, if I was using Vista, It&amp;rsquo;d have demanded atleast 1 GB of RAM just to run Aero, forget about the rest of the things.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Cost&lt;/strong>: This is a big factor for me. Almost everything is free or atleast has a free alternative available. Most of the times I&amp;rsquo;ve found these free software to be much better than commercial software in terms of feature sets as well as stability. But even otherwise, when there are cases where the free alternative a bit lagging as compared to the commercial one (e.g. GIMP v/s Photoshop), I haven&amp;rsquo;t felt that my needs have ever outgrown the free software.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Ease of Use&lt;/strong>: Doing &amp;ldquo;stuff&amp;rdquo; on linux is just so easy. By &amp;ldquo;stuff&amp;rdquo;, I mean everything from doing some normal day chores, downloading files, customizing things, automating routine tasks, etc. The backbone for this is &amp;ldquo;the terminal&amp;rdquo; (not the movie :P). I can do almost anything I want from the console. It not only saves me time and frustration in executing a program, waiting for the GUI to load and then go through a series of clicks but also allows me to batch up everything into one pretty little command. Moreover, every thing has so many options that I can configure to my liking. (More on the &amp;ldquo;options&amp;rdquo; later below)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Getting Software&lt;/strong>: Getting software couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more easy.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>It generally involves typing in &lt;code>sudo apt-get install &amp;lt;software&amp;gt;&lt;/code>, pressing enter, and that&amp;rsquo;s it. The latest version is ready to roll on your machine.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Reboots are minimal. Even after thinking for quite long, it&amp;rsquo;s very hard to recall any time when I had to &amp;ldquo;log-off&amp;rdquo; my system (let alone reboot) after installing a software (or even a driver)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Updates are automatic, and not just for the OS or a few core components, but for all the software that I installed through repositories (but not for the ones which I installed from my local deb&amp;rsquo;s or compilations, which is understandable of course)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The latest fixes/patches are available very quickly. Moreover, the revision cycle for most distros lies between 6–12 months and hence, even a complete desktop upgrade is quickly available as well (as compared to the 7 year period after which Vista came out). You can even &amp;ldquo;upgrade&amp;rdquo; to the latest distro revision without having to wipe everything, though I generally prefer a clean install.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Security&lt;/strong>: Now, I agree with everyone that the reason why we don&amp;rsquo;t see many viruses for linux is because the user base is very less as compared to other OS&amp;rsquo;s but I also believe that this is not the &amp;ldquo;only&amp;rdquo; reason.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The thing is that since most of the software is open source, so exploits are found quite quickly and patched and released rapidly. While in a closed source environments, even if a white hat reports it, the exploits go on un-noticed, un-worked upon by the developers (A good example is the recent falling of Vista during the &amp;ldquo;Pwn to Own&amp;rdquo; contest because of a known but unpatched vulnerability by Adobe, not a fault of Vista in this case though but you get my drift).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The security model otherwise is also quite tight and its very hard for someone to exploit it till the time you use common sense along with it. (A linux virus can easily wipe your &amp;ldquo;/home&amp;rdquo; without acquiring root permissions).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>5 Reasons why I dislike Linux&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These reasons irk me the most but aren&amp;rsquo;t enough for to make me move away from Linux. I mention them because getting them right would make my Linux expereince that much more joyful and probably others feels the same too. Moreover, this is not a gripe and is not a command/order to &amp;ldquo;the Linux guys&amp;rdquo; out there to fix it, because linux is of, by and for the community. And being a part of this community, I share the burden of this equally and would like to help out in making it better in whatever ways possible, developing, testing, suggesting things.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Getting Software:&lt;/strong> I had mentioned about how easy it is to get software from most distros&amp;rsquo; repositories with a single command. However, getting and installing software is also a challenge that many people face in linux. After sometime your particular version of the distro stops updating the software and will include only security fixes and such. Now, there are many good people who would backport software for your version but not all the time. You can download pacakges off the internet (debs&amp;rsquo; for ubuntu) but they might not work because of too many inter-mingled dependencies. Compiling is another option but many times, it can spiral out of hand. I hope we can better softwares like GDebi that could make this much more easier.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Options:&lt;/strong> Earlier I listed having so many options as one of my reasons to like Linux. But, sometimes, too many options tend to get to my head. This gets even more difficult when you have too many choices but no clue about what means what and which one is the best. However, the community is continously trying to make this right. A lot of documentation projects are going on, and the mailing lists, IRC networks and other forums also give out a lot of information. Especially for Ubuntu, I find a huge community based support system which always helps me out. (PS – The Ubuntu Forums are the nicest forums you&amp;rsquo;ll ever come across. I am yet to come across a post that contains words like &amp;ldquo;RTFM&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;n00b&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Ease Of Use:&lt;/strong> Some times, just some times, the lack of a GUI for common things irks me and I wish in respect of a few things (read wi-fi) that things could &amp;ldquo;just work&amp;rdquo;. But I guess this is a trade-off that I can live with, and moreover this situation is also improving especilly due to the efforts taken by Ubuntu, Mandriva, Fedora, GNOME and KDE. (Special thanks to nm-applet ;-) ). Moreover, Hardy Heron, b43 and the latest linux kernels promise to solve the wi-fi setup issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Browsing&lt;/strong>: The browsing experience on linux isn&amp;rsquo;t too great. But this is not a fault of Linux as such. This is due to companies providing adequate linux support (e.g. java plugins for 64 bit) and too many sites optimizing their code for IE. But again, there is hope for this as we can already run IE on linux (IEs4Linux) plus SUN has promised a 64 bit java firefox plugin with the next JRE.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Drivers:&lt;/strong> This is again due to companies not giving proper linux support for their hardware and not even releasing their hardware details for the OSS community to develop their own drivers. However, I can understand that giving out hardware details might not be an option for these companies considering the competition, and also proper software support might be a bit unfeasible due to a smaller consumer base. But again, more and more companies are seeing the light now and releasing proper drivers for linux, with Nvidia and ATi taking the lead (When will Creative listen?). And a special thanks to the OSS community for making working drivers despite all this.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>So, this is it. After reading back through what I just wrote, I am dead sure that I will stick to Linux as the trade-offs are too meagre for me. Will you?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>shantz-csv-to-opml</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/22/shantz-csv-to-opml/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2008 04:53:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/22/shantz-csv-to-opml/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>INTRODUCTION&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a very simple script that I did for a friend. It can be used to quickly generate blogrolls.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Input: csv file with blog author names and blog links&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Output: OPML file that can be imported into many blogging/blogrolling software and websites (e.g. wordpress, blogrolling.com, etc)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Usage:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>shantz-csv-to-opml.pl &amp;lt;input file in csv format&amp;gt; &amp;lt;output opml filename&amp;gt;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>Input File Format:
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>Each line should be like this:
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&amp;lt;Name of Author&amp;gt;,&amp;lt;bloglink&amp;gt;,&amp;lt;bloglink&amp;gt;...
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>e.g.
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>Shantanu Goel, http://tech.shantanugoel.com, http://blog.shantanugoel.com
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>There can be any number of blogs for any author, if blogs are more than one, then multiple entries for that author will be made in opml file each indexed with increasing number like Shantanu Goel 1, Shantanu Goel 2, etc&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>&lt;strong>INTRODUCTION&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a very simple script that I did for a friend. It can be used to quickly generate blogrolls.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Input: csv file with blog author names and blog links&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Output: OPML file that can be imported into many blogging/blogrolling software and websites (e.g. wordpress, blogrolling.com, etc)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Usage:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>shantz-csv-to-opml.pl &amp;lt;input file in csv format&amp;gt; &amp;lt;output opml filename&amp;gt;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>Input File Format:
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>Each line should be like this:
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&amp;lt;Name of Author&amp;gt;,&amp;lt;bloglink&amp;gt;,&amp;lt;bloglink&amp;gt;...
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>e.g.
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>Shantanu Goel, http://tech.shantanugoel.com, http://blog.shantanugoel.com
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>There can be any number of blogs for any author, if blogs are more than one, then multiple entries for that author will be made in opml file each indexed with increasing number like Shantanu Goel 1, Shantanu Goel 2, etc&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Version History:
0.1 - Initial Version&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>