<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>program on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/program/</link><description>Recent content in program on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2008 11:03:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/program/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Project: Shantz-XwinWrap Updated to 0.02</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/18/project-shantz-xwinwrap-updated-to-002/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2008 11:03:48 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/18/project-shantz-xwinwrap-updated-to-002/</guid><description>As some of you know that I've taken up the development of the ultra-cool xwinwrap tool that allows you to use movies, screensavers etc as wallpapers for you linux desktops. Here is version 0.02 for you consumption that fixes a bug because of which the generated window was overlapping other windows.
The download file has plain executable binaries as well as deb packages for Ubuntu. Moreover, I've included both 32 bit as well as 64 bit versions.</description></item><item><title>Shantz XWinWrap: The "Moving" Wallpaper Fun Continues</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/03/shantz-xwinwrap-the-moving-wallpaper-fun-continues/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 14:46:02 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/03/shantz-xwinwrap-the-moving-wallpaper-fun-continues/</guid><description>XWinWrap is a small utility written a loooong time ago that allowed you to stick most of the apps to your desktop background (Thanks to fsckin for introducing me to it). What this meant was you could use an animated screensaver (like glmatrix, electric sheep, etc) or even a movie, and use it as your wallpaper. But only one version of this app was released, and it had a few problems, like it wasn't exactly &amp;ldquo;sticking&amp;rdquo; to the background and geometry option didn't work as well.</description></item><item><title>Shantz XWinWrap</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/03/shantz-xwinwrap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 14:41:44 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/03/shantz-xwinwrap/</guid><description>XWinWrap is a small utility written a loooong time ago that allowed you to stick most of the apps to your desktop background. What this meant was you could use an animated screensaver (like glmatrix, electric sheep, etc) or even a movie, and use it as your wallpaper. But only one version of this app was ever released, and it had a few problems, like:
Well, sticking didn't work.</description></item></channel></rss>