<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nexus One on</title><link>/tags/nexus-one/</link><description>Recent content in Nexus One on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 18:16:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/nexus-one/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Android NFC Car BT Audio Setup</title><link>/posts/my-android-nfc-car-bt-audio-setup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 18:16:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/my-android-nfc-car-bt-audio-setup/</guid><description>So, my Nexus One&amp;rsquo;s battery finally lost its last legs and I picked up a new Galaxy Nexus to replace it (easy choice, since it&amp;rsquo;s a nexus device and Google sells it for a bargain at their play store). Anyways, I drift. In the mood to try out the NFC capbilities of my newly acquired gadget I thought of doing something about my car audio setup (previously consisting of a stereo line connecting the aux port of the stereo to the headphone out of Nexus one using tasker to start music when connected).</description></item><item><title>Camera LED As Flashlight on Non-Rooted Android Phones</title><link>/posts/camera-led-flashlight-non-rooted-android-phones/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2010 09:31:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/camera-led-flashlight-non-rooted-android-phones/</guid><description>We all know that Android does not allow the camera LED to be controlled directly from apps and hence, you cannot use the camera LED as a Torch or Flashlight unless you are rooted. There are many flashlight apps on the Android Market Place but none of them will work for you if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a rooted phone. BUT this changed recently. I use a brilliant app called &amp;ldquo;quick settings&amp;rdquo; which keeps an icon in the notification bar and I can pull it down and change any settings without leaving other apps.</description></item><item><title>Android Froyo And Nexus One: Everything We Know</title><link>/posts/android-froyo-nexus-one/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2010 17:44:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/android-froyo-nexus-one/</guid><description>This is an effort from my side to consolidate everything about Android Froyo with respect to Nexus One. It is mainly concentrated towards listing the features/fixes that we have seen in Froyo that weren&amp;rsquo;t announced in Google I/O, things that work with nexus one, things that don&amp;rsquo;t and possible fixes/workarounds known, what the announced features actually feel like in real use etc.** Will keep updating this post as I get more info, get more fixes, etc.</description></item><item><title>Android Froyo Update File</title><link>/posts/android-froyo-update/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2010 19:36:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/android-froyo-update/</guid><description>Just a quick post to tell you how to update your Nexus One to Android 2.2 Froyo immediately without waiting for google to send it to you OTA.
Download this file from google&amp;rsquo;s servers: http://android.clients.google.com/packages/passion/signed-passion-FRF50-from-ERE27.1e519a24.zip
After that just follow the below mentioned steps:
Put it on your SD card and rename to update.zip
Power off then hold trackball and press power again to boot into recovery
Go to Bootloader -&amp;gt; Recovery</description></item></channel></rss>