<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mobile on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/mobile/</link><description>Recent content in Mobile on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 16:55:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/mobile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apple, Anti-Malware, Patents</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/02/15/apple-anti-malware-patents/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 16:55:10 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/02/15/apple-anti-malware-patents/</guid><description>Recently, there has been this trend. Blogs look for patents filed by companies and then report on each of them as if they are second coming of Jesus in technology. Especially if it is Apple who is doing the filings.
A few days ago, this new patent showed up about Apple&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;new wave approach to fighting malware&amp;rdquo; with the author giving up half-researched commentary on it.
I was intrigued by this news (if you can call it that), not because it’s something new but instead because process isolation is hardly a new concept.</description></item><item><title>Odroid U2 Tips: Overscan, emmc Adapter, HDMI-DVI Adapter</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/01/12/odroid-u2-tips-overscan-emmc-adapter-hdmi-dvi-adapter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2013 17:56:52 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/01/12/odroid-u2-tips-overscan-emmc-adapter-hdmi-dvi-adapter/</guid><description>So I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending a few hours on getting my odroid u2 up and running and here are a few tips that I&amp;rsquo;ve come across in the process.
**Overscan: **
So, many TVs have this issue that they miss out on displaying the corners of the image put out by the Odroid U2. The phenomenon is called overscan. Now, all you have to do is select settings such as &amp;ldquo;Just Scan&amp;rdquo; or similar on your TV that allows your TV to display image coming from U2 as is.</description></item><item><title>Odroid U2 is here</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/01/12/odroid-u2-is-here/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2013 17:46:57 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/01/12/odroid-u2-is-here/</guid><description>So, this little baby landed up in my mailbox a couple of days ago :). The Odroid U2. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, it&amp;rsquo;s a cheap dev board based around Samsung&amp;rsquo;s Exynos 4412 SoC and supports Android as well as Ubuntu.
Odroid U2 I&amp;rsquo;ve got quite a few things planned on how to use it and will post more about my adventures with the U2 here soon.</description></item><item><title>Third Party Widgets on Android 4.2 Lock Screen</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2012/11/14/third-party-widgets-on-android-4-2-lock-screen/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2012 14:46:36 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2012/11/14/third-party-widgets-on-android-4-2-lock-screen/</guid><description>One of the features I was really looking forward to with Android 4.2 was lock screen widgets but when I got the update on my Galaxy Nexus that it only had 5 pre-defined stock widgets that could be added to the lock screen.
I headed over to the Android developers site some time later and was pleasantly surprised to see that actually 3rd party widgets can indeed be added to the lock screen.</description></item><item><title>My Tasker Night Mode Profile For Android</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2012/10/17/my-tasker-night-mode-profile-for-android/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 09:03:08 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2012/10/17/my-tasker-night-mode-profile-for-android/</guid><description>If there are two things that irritate me the most when I go to sleep, they are: Sync notifications going off and battery drained off in the morning (worst case being drained off before alarm time, making me late for work). I used to have a simple profile that turned off auto sync between 11 PM to 7 AM but it didn&amp;rsquo;t always work well because I work past 11 quite a lot and don&amp;rsquo;t usually have a fixed sleep time.</description></item><item><title>My Android NFC Car BT Audio Setup</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2012/09/30/my-android-nfc-car-bt-audio-setup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 18:16:22 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2012/09/30/my-android-nfc-car-bt-audio-setup/</guid><description>So, my Nexus One&amp;rsquo;s battery finally lost its last legs and I picked up a new Galaxy Nexus to replace it (easy choice, since it&amp;rsquo;s a nexus device and Google sells it for a bargain at their play store). Anyways, I drift. In the mood to try out the NFC capbilities of my newly acquired gadget I thought of doing something about my car audio setup (previously consisting of a stereo line connecting the aux port of the stereo to the headphone out of Nexus one using tasker to start music when connected).</description></item><item><title>SGX 543MP2 vs Mali-400: Is iPhone 4S GPU Really Twice As Strong As SGS 2?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/10/05/sgx-543mp2-vs-mali-400-is-iphone-4s-gpu-really-twice-as-strong-as-sgs-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2011 20:23:23 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/10/05/sgx-543mp2-vs-mali-400-is-iphone-4s-gpu-really-twice-as-strong-as-sgs-2/</guid><description>Ever since Apple announced the iPhone 4S having &amp;ldquo;A5&amp;rdquo; processor, everyone has been pointing to the below image from a test run by Anandtech and saying that the iPhone 4S will be twice as strong as the Samsung Galaxy S2. I beg to differ.
While the above test doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any discrepancy, one major thing is that the SGX 543MP2 results are from an iPad 2 (a tablet) while the Mali 400 results are from a smartphone.</description></item><item><title>Deconstructing The Samsung Nexus Prime Video</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/10/05/deconstructing-the-samsung-nexus-prime-video/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2011 05:59:28 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/10/05/deconstructing-the-samsung-nexus-prime-video/</guid><description>Samsung just uploaded a teaser video to Youtube which hints at the upcoming Android phone Nexus Prime with IceCream Sandwich. It has a sideways glance at what people believe is the Nexus Prime. I&amp;rsquo;ll deconstruct the image a bit.
The things to take away from here:
The phone will have a curved display like Nexus S
It has a power button on the side (right side, since it&amp;rsquo;s marked with the power icon)</description></item><item><title>Swype 3.25 Beta Pre-release Parse Error Solution</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/08/23/swype-3-25-beta-pre-release-parse-error-solution/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 18:07:44 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/08/23/swype-3-25-beta-pre-release-parse-error-solution/</guid><description>Swype just released their latest beta version 3.25 for Android phones but most of the folks are facing a &amp;ldquo;parse error&amp;rdquo; while trying to update to the latest version. If you are one of such folks, there is a simple solution that I just tried and got working. Instead of updating from the swype installer, you need to update manually. Uninstall your existing swype, then uninstall the existing swype installer on your phone.</description></item><item><title>Huawei Ideos U8150 Review</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/06/05/huawei-ideos-u8150-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2011 15:52:19 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/06/05/huawei-ideos-u8150-review/</guid><description>Recently I received Huawei Ideos U8150 phone for review. This is an Android smartphone meant for the entry level market. I had the phone for a few weeks to put it through its paces and here are some of my thoughts about it. I am not going to expand a lot on the general Android points as we all know about it but will concentrate succinctly and to-the-point on the aspects which can make it or break it for this phone against its competition in the similar price ranges.</description></item><item><title>Google Music Beta Latest APK version 3.0.1 for Android</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/05/27/google-music-latest-apk-android-3-0-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 03:57:10 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/05/27/google-music-latest-apk-android-3-0-1/</guid><description>Google just released the latest version of its Music app that ties into its cloud player service Music Beta. This brings the version upto 3.0.1 and adds a lot of fixes, crashes a lot less and now even works on Samsung Galaxy S with Gingerbread which was broken earlier. If you are outside the US and not able to download the app from the market, then download it from here:http://www.multiupload.com/KIM5LQDL0K</description></item><item><title>iWebLeaf - India's $35 Android Tablet Spawning Fake Innovators?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/04/06/iwebleaf-indias-35-android-tablet-spawning-fake-innovators/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 18:04:44 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/04/06/iwebleaf-indias-35-android-tablet-spawning-fake-innovators/</guid><description>It was just about an year ago that we heard about the $35 Android Tablet from India which would revolutionize the education in developing countries. Mr. Kapil Sibal promoted it with utmost fervor until it was found that the BoM itself of the tablet was more than $50 and none of the guys claimed to have &amp;ldquo;invented&amp;rdquo; it even knew about its existence until a few days before the announcement. Ultimately, it was discovered that the tablet was just a rebranded chinese import which the government wanted to bring down to $35 price point by subsidizing the cost and not by somehow inventing cheaper parts.</description></item><item><title>Google to abandon Android. Spin off separate company</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/04/01/google-to-abandon-android-spin-off-separate-company/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 07:03:06 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/04/01/google-to-abandon-android-spin-off-separate-company/</guid><description>Now, this is mind blowing. I&amp;rsquo;ve just talked to a pretty reliable source within the Android ranks of Google that Google is going to distance itself legally from Android and spin it off in a separate company. The source said that the move can happen very soon and may be announced at Google I/O conference in May. Although details are sketchy and only very few high profile folks know about it within Google, my source says that the probable reason is increasing worries about legal aspects of Android with respect to Patents and IP law suits.</description></item><item><title>Android/iPhone Beware: WP7 Phones have already sold 12 million devices</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/12/04/androidiphone-beware-wp7-phones-have-already-sold-12-million-devices/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 19:16:19 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/12/04/androidiphone-beware-wp7-phones-have-already-sold-12-million-devices/</guid><description>According to TechCrunch, that is. TC has a post on its blog right now (from none other than Michael Arrington) that says Toddlers Pick iPhone Over Windows 7 Phones 10-1. The article says that this is because a toddlers&amp;rsquo; app maker&amp;rsquo;s notes that their app sold 71.5 apps per day on average on the iOS app store, while the number was 7.5 on the WP7 marketplace. Go read the article (it&amp;rsquo;s pretty short) and come back to read the below.</description></item><item><title>Ad-Free (Paid) Angry Birds For Android</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/12/02/ad-free-paid-angry-birds-android/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 13:28:52 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/12/02/ad-free-paid-angry-birds-android/</guid><description>Rovio Mobile has been pretty considerate for the Android lovers and has released their Angry Birds game for free on the Android market. Many people love it but quite a few are annoyed by it because Rovio chose to monetize it by in-game advertisements, and that too placed at awkward places which can hinder the gameplay. Many users have also reported that they are being forced to view video ads as well these days.</description></item><item><title>ZDNet Fail. Answer is Stop Tech Blogging</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/11/19/zdnet-fail-answer-is-stop-tech-blogging/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2010 15:45:04 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/11/19/zdnet-fail-answer-is-stop-tech-blogging/</guid><description>Just read this article over at zdnet. What it basically says is condensed in these two points:
Android is a failure for Google because it is open and carriers/OEMs are stripping off google search from it and putting replacements like baidu/Bing. (BTW, half the people say Android is fail because it is not open and the other half say it is fail because it is open. Which one is it, please decide ;) )</description></item><item><title>A short Tablet/Smartphone survey for a project</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/11/15/short-tablet-smartphone-survey-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2010 04:10:06 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/11/15/short-tablet-smartphone-survey-project/</guid><description>I need a bit of your help in filling out a short survey that I need for a small project of mine that I&amp;rsquo;m doing with a friend. It will take maximum of only 2-3 minutes of your time. Please fill it out below. If you are facing any problems with the survey or have any queries/suggestions etc, please use this contact form to send them to us.
Much Thanks!! :)</description></item><item><title>The Real Threat Of Windows Phone 7</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/28/the-real-threat-of-windows-phone-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2010 19:48:34 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/28/the-real-threat-of-windows-phone-7/</guid><description>Many people say that Windows Phone 7 is a threat to iPhone because they are bringing in a super platform with a choice of multiple designs and multiple carriers with great Enterprise and gaming support and maintaining the lucrative integration that iPhone provides. Many also say that Windows Phone 7 is a threat to Android because it solves the problem of Apple&amp;rsquo;s draconian policies, gives choice to customers and all this without fragmenting the OS all over the place.</description></item><item><title>Is Android Open Source Or Not?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/25/android-open-source-or-not/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 11:31:06 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/25/android-open-source-or-not/</guid><description>Is Android really open source or not? That is the question being asked by almost everyone. A lot of people, especially those influenced by RDF or those who are in the news industry with no idea about OS and open source but were asked by their boss to get a scoop on this pronto, tend to bring up a few keywords and then twist them around in the way they see fit to make sure it says Android isn&amp;rsquo;t open.</description></item><item><title>Android Paid Apps Now Live In India</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/05/android-paid-apps-now-live-in-india/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2010 07:35:39 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/05/android-paid-apps-now-live-in-india/</guid><description>Yes! As of today noon, paid apps are now visible on my Android Nexus One in India. Few salient points (Also, look at the end to see how to get paid apps if you are not able to see them yet):
The marketplace shows approximate prices of each app in Indian Rupees (INR) (Edit: I&amp;rsquo;ve just learned from few tweets that this is a new feature worldwide. People everywhere are now seeing approximate app costs in their local currencies.</description></item><item><title>Carrier Billing Behind Android Paid Apps Market Jump?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/01/carrier-billing-behind-android-paid-apps-market-jump/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 17:19:51 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/01/carrier-billing-behind-android-paid-apps-market-jump/</guid><description>We heard the news today that paid apps in Android market place have been extended to 18 new countries. Could &amp;ldquo;Carrier Billing&amp;rdquo; (Allowing your service operator to add the apps&amp;rsquo; price to your cellphone bill) be the reason behind it? I think so. It was long suggested that Google Checkout and corresponding legal issues in using it across various countries was the reason behind the paid apps not being available in those countries.</description></item><item><title>Android Paid Apps Available In India</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/01/android-paid-apps-india/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 03:40:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/01/android-paid-apps-india/</guid><description>Just got a mail from Google that paid apps are being made available in India. HOORAY!!! In addition, developers from 20 more countries can sell apps on market (Unfortunately, no India in this list) and people from 18 more countries can buy paid apps.
This is a big thing because now 32 countries out of 44 where Android has footprint can buy paid apps. This should take away one of the biggest drawbacks that Android marketplace was facing.</description></item><item><title>Setup Call Recording With Android App Tasker On Nexus One</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/24/setup-call-recording-android-app-tasker-nexus-one/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2010 10:01:16 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/24/setup-call-recording-android-app-tasker-nexus-one/</guid><description>I wanted to record calls on my Android phone (Nexus one). The easy way would have been to download an app but I like tinkering. And given that I recently bought Tasker, android’s very own swiss knife, I thought I should give it a run. After just an hour I was able to create my very own call recorder (some time went into trial and error with things as this was my first major task with tasker and also some things didn’t work with nexus one, which I will note below).</description></item><item><title>The Great Indian $35 Tablet Hoax?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/13/the-great-indian-35-tablet-hoax/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2010 09:59:42 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/13/the-great-indian-35-tablet-hoax/</guid><description>Another nail in the coffin before this Android tablet lives to fulfill the Indian kids’ dreams. Well, not exactly a nail in the coffin. The tablet might still be here, and at the price promised but the thing to note is how low the government can stoop to get bragging rights (and votes). The article elaborates how the IIT/IISC scientists weren’t even aware that such a “project” existed and they were invited to be a part of it just a month before Mr.</description></item><item><title>Android App: Wi-Fi Keep Alive updates</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/09/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive-updates/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2010 05:27:27 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/09/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive-updates/</guid><description>I pushed out a couple of updates to my android app Wi-Fi Keep alive a few weeks ago (mainly related to fixing the resolution and colors of the widget icons) taking the latest version to 1.4.4. This is just to let you know that it will take a while (a few weeks) more to get the pending updates and requests in to the program. I have been pretty ill for the last few weeks and have only just got back up out of the bed and now my development machine has also gone for a toss.</description></item><item><title>Caution: Stay away from making your Android app free for a short time</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/08/caution-stay-away-from-making-your-android-app-free-for-a-short-time/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 06:18:36 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/08/caution-stay-away-from-making-your-android-app-free-for-a-short-time/</guid><description>Just read this over at the Android Developers google forum:
My app had a one-day sale on all platforms and app stores. The price went from 2.99 to free for just today, but now that the sale is over, I need to revert the price back to 2.99. The bad news is, the developer console will not let me change it! I have to pull the app until I can get this resolved.</description></item><item><title>Solving The Android Permissions And Malware Puzzle</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/13/android-permissions-malware/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2010 19:44:59 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/13/android-permissions-malware/</guid><description>There has been a spate of security reports recently about Android apps being malware or suspicious. Most of these were found baseless but at least one was indeed correct (e.g. The Russian Trojan app). We also know that Android has a very good security model but even then, the rest of the reports also makes one think and focus on why an apps requires the permissions that it states it needs?</description></item><item><title>Android Dev Tip: App Not Showing on X10 Mini Marketplace</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/07/android-dev-tip-app-not-showing-on-x10-mini-marketplace/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2010 21:18:06 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/07/android-dev-tip-app-not-showing-on-x10-mini-marketplace/</guid><description>Many Android Developers (and users) get confused that why a certain app isn&amp;rsquo;t showing up on the new Xperia X10 Mini (and few other) phones. This happens even if they support all android versions and have published their apps for all countries, so that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the issue. I came across this as well when few people mentioned that they couldn&amp;rsquo;t find my app Wi-Fi Keep Alive in the X10 mini marketplace.</description></item><item><title>SSH Tunneling On Android</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/02/ssh-tunneling-android/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2010 10:53:36 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/02/ssh-tunneling-android/</guid><description>If you want to have a secure browsing environment or just want to access your home network securely without exposing extra services to the internet and without the mess that comes with setting up and maintaining a VPN server, ssh tunneling is your rescuer. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you how to setup an ssh tunnel to your home network easily. Also look for some bonus tips at the end ;)</description></item><item><title>Android App Wi-Fi Keep Alive updated to 1.4.1</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/22/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive-updated-1-4-0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2010 16:58:07 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/22/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive-updated-1-4-0/</guid><description>Update: Made a minor update for a small bug that can make wi-fi keep reconnecting in quick succession.
Pushed out a new update to my Android App Wi-Fi Keep Alive today. This update brings in another work around for the issue where the wi-fi is alive on the phone and it is also connected to the network but is somehow unable to send/receive any packets to the network. The new work around will automatically re-associate your phone with the wi-fi router if it detects such a situation.</description></item><item><title>BadTokenException Error In Android Dialog</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/08/badtokenexception-android-dialog-getapplicationcontext/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2010 11:24:14 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/08/badtokenexception-android-dialog-getapplicationcontext/</guid><description>If you are creating a custom Dialog for Android, and following the Android Developers’ Creating Dialogs tutorial, then most likely you would have faced a Force Close with this exception showing up in logcat. I did too. Although I figured it out quickly, it might not be easy to find out for many, so posting it here for reference. Basically, the code given in the tutorial goes something like this:</description></item><item><title>Android App: Wi-Fi Keep Alive Updated to 1.2.0</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/03/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive-updated-to-1-2-0/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2010 22:46:36 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/03/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive-updated-to-1-2-0/</guid><description>Just finished uploading the new version 1.2.0 of my android app Wi-Fi Keep Alive to the Android market. This version has a lot of optimizations and also a few workarounds to overcome the issues few guys were facing with Android&amp;rsquo;s in-built handling of wi-fi sleep policies.
Changes done in this version:
Added workarounds to take care of sleep policies not working on some phones
Optimized the code a bit for faster operations</description></item><item><title>Android App: Wi-Fi Keep Alive</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/28/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2010 15:25:48 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/28/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive/</guid><description>I just wrote my second Android App. This again was to scratch an itch of mine but it seems to have become a bit popular already (My first app &amp;ldquo;Quick Sync Settings&amp;rdquo; did around 400 downloads in 20 days but this one has already surpassed that in less than one day). This app basically allows you to change the wi-fi sleep policy on android so that you can keep your wi-fi connected even if the phone goes to sleep (i.</description></item><item><title>Wi-Fi Keep Alive</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/28/wi-fi-keep-alive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2010 15:20:19 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/28/wi-fi-keep-alive/</guid><description>UPDATE Potential work arounds for folks having problem in sleep policies not working correctly have been put in version 1.2.0 onwards. Please redownload to test and let me know. Read below for more details.
Latest Version: 1.4.4 (See below for change log history)
Are you frustrated by your downloads getting broken or worse, switching over to slow and expensive mobile data connections like GPRS/Edge/3G when your wi-fi connection gets dropped by your Android phone when the screen goes off?</description></item><item><title>Android vs iPhone: Security Models</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/25/android-vs-iphone-security-models/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2010 22:02:49 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/25/android-vs-iphone-security-models/</guid><description>Android and iPhone OS (iOS) have been at loggerheads for quite some time now. This is a take on which has a better security model to protect its users. I thought of writing it up because there have been a lot of discussions around me lately about which platform is more secure and I keep repeating the same points over and over at every one of them, so thought that in future I&amp;rsquo;ll just point them to this page :P</description></item><item><title>How To Debug Android Widgets</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/13/how-to-debug-android-widgets/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 18:42:42 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/13/how-to-debug-android-widgets/</guid><description>For most new android app developers (like me), it is a bit puzzling how to debug the android widgets or how to put a breakpoint in an android widget code. For normal applications, it is quite simple as when you press &amp;ldquo;debug&amp;rdquo; on the eclipse toolbar, it launches the emulator (or connects to existing emulator/device), syncs your application and launches its main activity and puts the control in your hands if you have put a breakpoint.</description></item><item><title>Android App: Quickly Open Accounts &amp; Sync Settings</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/12/android-app-quickly-open-accounts-sync-settings/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2010 21:19:35 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/12/android-app-quickly-open-accounts-sync-settings/</guid><description>Just a small post to let you know that I just published a small app in the android market, which scratches an itch of mine and I thought probably it will be help others too. It basically provides a quick, one-click access to the accounts and sync settings of Android. The use case for me was that I need to enable/disable syncing for my work email while I&amp;rsquo;m at work every day as I am already in front of my office PC so don&amp;rsquo;t need to waste battery and be annoyed by mail notifications on phone but still need to keep google calendar syncing.</description></item><item><title>Apple is Magical: Daniel Eran Gilder is the Living Proof</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/10/apple-magical-dan-eran-gilder/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 04:49:53 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/10/apple-magical-dan-eran-gilder/</guid><description>Update: Removed the post as the person in consideration has contacted me with the explanation of what went down. I’m not sure if it is completely true or this is just as a response to this post but anyways, as I had contended in the original post that it was a stupid little thing that didn’t really warrant any attention or a post but I still did it just because I’m weird, so in the light of the developments, I think it’s best to remove the rants and focus on actual discussion.</description></item><item><title>Android Froyo And Nexus One: Everything We Know</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/05/23/android-froyo-nexus-one/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2010 17:44:18 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/05/23/android-froyo-nexus-one/</guid><description>This is an effort from my side to consolidate everything about Android Froyo with respect to Nexus One. It is mainly concentrated towards listing the features/fixes that we have seen in Froyo that weren&amp;rsquo;t announced in Google I/O, things that work with nexus one, things that don&amp;rsquo;t and possible fixes/workarounds known, what the announced features actually feel like in real use etc.** Will keep updating this post as I get more info, get more fixes, etc.</description></item><item><title>Android Froyo Update File</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/05/22/android-froyo-update/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2010 19:36:34 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/05/22/android-froyo-update/</guid><description>Just a quick post to tell you how to update your Nexus One to Android 2.2 Froyo immediately without waiting for google to send it to you OTA.
Download this file from google&amp;rsquo;s servers: http://android.clients.google.com/packages/passion/signed-passion-FRF50-from-ERE27.1e519a24.zip
After that just follow the below mentioned steps:
Put it on your SD card and rename to update.zip
Power off then hold trackball and press power again to boot into recovery</description></item><item><title>Google Releases Android Source Code</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/21/google-releases-android-source-code/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2008 17:57:52 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/21/google-releases-android-source-code/</guid><description>FOSS (Free and Open Source Software) community rejoices today as google finally lived upto their promise of releasing the android source code. Now, the things that is left to be evaluated is that how much of it is actually true, or whether there are some binary blobs still in there. Moreover, it remains to be seen that how much this converts into a “community” project instead of being ruled by Google with an iron hand.</description></item><item><title>Android Devices Trickling In A Few Days Early?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/20/android-devices-trickling-in-a-few-days-early/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2008 19:32:35 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/20/android-devices-trickling-in-a-few-days-early/</guid><description>There is still a day left for the first Android based Device, T-Mobile G1, to come out into the hands of general public but I was in a for a small surprise as I went through my Google Analytics report for the last week. It had a mysterious number of 2 sitting at the bottom of my “Unique Visitors by Operating Systems” filter report. The “mysterious” part coming from the fact that the left most column displayed “Android”.</description></item><item><title>SmartPhones/NextGen Telephony: News That Matters</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/14/smartphonesnextgen-telephony-news-that-matters/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2008 05:08:10 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/14/smartphonesnextgen-telephony-news-that-matters/</guid><description>Just wanted to share some pieces that generated a variety of &amp;ldquo;hmmm&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;ahaa&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;wow&amp;rdquo; from me:
China Mobile set to trial LTE:
China Mobile said it will join Vodafone Group plc and Verizon Wireless in an ongoing trial of LTE technology…….The trials &amp;ndash; which include three powerhouse network operators &amp;ndash; underscore the momentum LTE is gaining as a leading 4G technology possibility vs. WiMAX and Ultra Mobile Broadband.
&amp;ldquo;HMMM&amp;rdquo; - U go LTE!</description></item></channel></rss>