<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tip on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/tip/</link><description>Recent content in Tip on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2009 14:00:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/tip/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>TIP: Perforce - Sync Files In A Label Without Deleting Previous Files</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/27/p4perforce-sync-files-label-without-deleting-previous/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2009 14:00:50 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/27/p4perforce-sync-files-label-without-deleting-previous/</guid><description>If you have used perforce, you&amp;rsquo;d have definitely come across a situation where you wanted to sync files belonging to two different labels, but as soon as you sync the second label, the files from the first label get deleted. P4 help suggests the following ways to achieve this:
p4 sync @label1,label2
or something like
`p4 sync @label1,@label2``
But I&amp;rsquo;ve found that depending on the perforce version you are using, the above commands might not work.</description></item><item><title>An Idea Is All You Need</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/12/an-idea-is-all-you-need-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2008 15:43:32 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/12/an-idea-is-all-you-need-2/</guid><description>Everyone wants to make a name for himself. Everyone wants to do something new and extra-ordinary. People like me (read software engineers) want to develop &amp;ldquo;something&amp;rdquo; cool. BUT, the stage where most of them go wrong is the very first one. Most of them think that the road to develop something cool starts from a particular &amp;ldquo;language&amp;rdquo; or a tool. But I beg to differ. I say the first stage is &amp;ldquo;The Idea&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Ubuntu TIP: Extending Nautilus, Scripting Your Way To UI Bliss</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/09/ubuntu-tip-extending-nautilus-scripting-your-way-to-ui-bliss/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2008 16:10:18 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/09/ubuntu-tip-extending-nautilus-scripting-your-way-to-ui-bliss/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m back from my vacation and this is a smallish post before we return to our regular programming (I&amp;rsquo;m full of puns ).
Rahul (my friend and guest author on this blog) introduced me to an old-but-useful trick a few days ago that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about. It&amp;rsquo;s about customizing nautilus to display a context menu that has a few of your chosen scripts to weave their magic on the selected object.</description></item><item><title>Ubuntu TIP: Automating Package Installation – apt-get to the rescue</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/06/ubuntu-tip-automating-package-installation--apt-get-to-the-rescue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2008 03:30:20 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/06/ubuntu-tip-automating-package-installation--apt-get-to-the-rescue/</guid><description>Admin Note: Rahul is a long time friend of mine, and is a well known geek amongst his friends and colleagues. I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce that he will be enriching this site from time-to-time as a guest editor/author. First up is a small tid-bit of a script that he wrote to ease up his life between installations and reinstallations of everyone&amp;rsquo;s favourite OS: Ubuntu. Over to his post..
Have you ever had to reinstall your ubuntu installation, and then bear the pain of manually installing the applications you&amp;rsquo;ve come to love (i mean use :)) everyday?</description></item></channel></rss>