<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Oleg Custom Firmware on</title><link>/tags/oleg-custom-firmware/</link><description>Recent content in Oleg Custom Firmware on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 12:16:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/oleg-custom-firmware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cannot Change Channel Problem With Asus WL-500W</title><link>/2010/07/13/cannot-change-channel-problem-with-asus-wl-500w/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 12:16:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/07/13/cannot-change-channel-problem-with-asus-wl-500w/</guid><description>Recently I found an issue with my asus wl-500w wi-fi router that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to change the channel on which it was transmitting. I moved to a new location which was totally jam-packed with other wi-fi networks using same channel as mine which was hampeing my connection. I tried for umpteen number of times. Changing the channel through the web configuration did not give any error but I found that it was still transmitting at channel 1.</description><content>&lt;p>Recently I found an issue with my asus wl-500w wi-fi router that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to change the channel on which it was transmitting. I moved to a new location which was totally jam-packed with other wi-fi networks using same channel as mine which was hampeing my connection. I tried for umpteen number of times. Changing the channel through the web configuration did not give any error but I found that it was still transmitting at channel 1. I confirmed by checking on the &amp;ldquo;Status &amp;amp; Log&amp;rdquo; page, checking the logs, and running &amp;ldquo;wl status&amp;rdquo; command through ssh and they all confirmed that it was transmitting at channel 1 only, no matter what I set it to in the configuration. I even opened an issue in the firmware project for the custom firmware (by oleg and lly) that I am using but they weren&amp;rsquo;t able to help me as the wi-fi drivers are binary only.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But by sheer chance, I stumbled upon the solution finally by trial and error. The solution is that you should set the &amp;ldquo;Bandwidth&amp;rdquo; to 20 MHz in wi-fi configuration if you are using 802.11 G. If you set it to 40 MHz then it gets stuck somehow but as soon as I changed it to 20 MHz, I was able to see the channel change immediately after reboot. Here is the screenshot of the page where you can find this setting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/img/uploads/asus-wl-500-w-change-channel.jpg">&lt;img src="/img/uploads/asus-wl-500-w-change-channel-thumb.jpg" alt="">&lt;/a>&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Easiest Way to Shutdown Asus WL-500W</title><link>/2009/07/10/shutdown-asus-wl-500-w/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2009 23:19:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/07/10/shutdown-asus-wl-500-w/</guid><description>If you are a proud owner of an Asus WL-500W wireless router (or maybe another one of the same series like wl-500g, wl-500gp, etc), then you know that this router has a very useful USB port with which you might have attached your external hard disk and have already offloaded all your downloding tasks to it, or maybe using it for various other purposes. Whatever maybe the reason, the main point is that because of this hard disk, now we cannot just turn off the power of the router any more.</description><content>&lt;p>If you are a proud owner of an Asus WL-500W wireless router (or maybe another one of the same series like wl-500g, wl-500gp, etc), then you know that this router has a very useful USB port with which you might have attached your external hard disk and have already offloaded all your downloding tasks to it, or maybe using it for various other purposes. Whatever maybe the reason, the main point is that because of this hard disk, now we cannot just turn off the power of the router any more. It has to be shut down gracefully like a PC. One way is to ssh/telnet to it and then give the &amp;ldquo;halt&amp;rdquo; command but then you have to switch on a PC specially just to turn off your router. Well not any more. I was looking for a better way to do this and just found out the simplest one. And if you are using Oleg&amp;rsquo;s custom firmware then you are in luck too.
With the 1.9.2.7-g version of his firmware, oleg added a new feature with which if you press the **EZ Setup **button at the back of the router for 3 seconds, it executes a script &amp;ldquo;/usr/local/sbin/ez-setup&amp;rdquo;, if present. So, all you gotta do is create a new text file named &amp;ldquo;ez-setup&amp;rdquo;, and paste the following contents in it:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --></content></item></channel></rss>