<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Raspberry-Pi on</title><link>/tags/raspberry-pi/</link><description>Recent content in Raspberry-Pi on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 02:25:17 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/raspberry-pi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fixing the Raspberrypi 4 Ethernet disconnection problem</title><link>/posts/raspberry-pi-4b-ethernet-lan-disconnect/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 02:25:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>/posts/raspberry-pi-4b-ethernet-lan-disconnect/</guid><description>I added a Raspberry Pi 4B recently in my ever expanding homelab. To get the best network with the new gigabit ethernet port on the raspi, and still save power, I added a PoE hat to it so I could power the raspi as well as provide it data through the ethernet port. Everything worked fine except that I ocassionaly got into situations where the raspi stopped responding suddenly. Initially I thought that it&amp;rsquo;s crashing due to some issues and used to just restart it manually.</description></item><item><title>Browser controlled Raspberry Pi Camera Car</title><link>/posts/browser-controlled-raspberry-pi-camera-car/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2014 15:33:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/browser-controlled-raspberry-pi-camera-car/</guid><description>Spent this weekend building a remote controlled car with a live camera feed with a Raspberry Pi doing the communication and brains duty. Pretty nice real time movement control and camera pan/tilt control through websockets with a live stream feeding back to any browser directly from the car through mjpg-streamer
(PS: Video is at the bottom of the post. Browser/video on TV courtesy ChromeCast. Casted my Nexus 5 screen to the TV simultaneously while controlling the car :) )</description></item><item><title>Display Message on Samsung TVs in Python (Samsung MessageBox Service Exploitation)</title><link>/posts/samsung-tv-message-box-python/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 14:07:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/samsung-tv-message-box-python/</guid><description>This script is the result of a weekend&amp;rsquo;s hacking to get my TV to display incoming calls/texts which I miss invariably because the phone is buried under a sofa or in a different room. Earlier I had done this using my Odroid U2 and Tasker/AutoRemote but this was limiting as this meant that I could see the notifications only when I was watching something through the Odroid. Samsung TVs, which are DLNA enabled, also include a hidden service called &amp;ldquo;Message Box&amp;rdquo; which can display different information on the TV natively irrespective of which display mode/input mode you are in.</description></item></channel></rss>