<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>IPhone 3G on</title><link>/tags/iphone-3g/</link><description>Recent content in IPhone 3G on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2008 15:57:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/iphone-3g/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>More iPhone 3G Nonsense Uncovered: No Tethering</title><link>/2008/06/14/more-iphone-3g-nonsense-uncovered-no-tethering/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2008 15:57:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/06/14/more-iphone-3g-nonsense-uncovered-no-tethering/</guid><description>iPhone 3G, the “supposedly” latest and greatest handhled, just continues to amaze me, with its ridiculousness of course. I mean first they dare to call a machine a smartphone that can’t run more than one app a time, need you to send the unit back even for a battery change, fix the glaring mistakes of its predecessor and call them “features” and make you believe that you are getting it all for cheap while covertly telling you that you need a minimum of 2 year 70$ contract to get it and need to pay through every hole for even software updates.</description><content>&lt;p>iPhone 3G, the “supposedly” latest and greatest handhled, just continues to amaze me, with its ridiculousness of course. I mean first they dare to call a machine a smartphone that can’t run more than one app a time, need you to send the unit back even for a battery change, fix the glaring mistakes of its predecessor and call them “features” and make you believe that you are getting it all for cheap while covertly telling you that you need a minimum of 2 year 70$ contract to get it and need to pay through every hole for even software updates. And then they don’t stop this, just out is the information that you can’t tether the “data transfer powerhouse” to your laptops/PCs/Macs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>HSDPA/HSUPA my a**. I mean what good is a “3G” device that doesn’t even let you use the potential of the hyper-speeds by connecting to your bigger machines or even doing video calls. Oh right, I forgot, now you can check your e-mail at 50 messages per minute, WOOHOO!!, I’m so l33t.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So far the only good things I’ve noticed about the new release are:The MobileMe aka “sync-with-anything-anywhere” service, which although paid (obviously, its Apple we are talking about here), is still interesting. And the new SDK 2.0 that promises the 3rd party devs the same access to the phone as Apple’s devs, seems to be a step in the right direction though it remains to be seen how much of this is actually followed up on by Apple.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, what do you feel is &lt;strong>THE&lt;/strong> revolutionary thing about this new Cupertino offering? And of course, chime in with your gripes as well.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>