<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Copy to Different Locations on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/copy-to-different-locations/</link><description>Recent content in Copy to Different Locations on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2008 13:26:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/copy-to-different-locations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Project: Shantz Copy Basket (Compatible with linux as well as windows)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/16/project-shantz-copy-basket-compatible-with-linux-as-well-as-windows/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2008 13:26:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/16/project-shantz-copy-basket-compatible-with-linux-as-well-as-windows/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m sure you have copied/moved files on your computer from one place to another. And I’m sure often you have to do more than just “single-shot” copying that is copy a few files to one place, move a few to another, and copy yet some more to one more location. Well, I had to do this quite a few times (e.g. I ran out of disk space recently on a partition and had to empty out my “Movies” and “Songs” folders to move a few movies/songs each to all other partitions/disks according to the space available). Hence, I wrote this little command line program, which behaves like a basket.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>I’m sure you have copied/moved files on your computer from one place to another. And I’m sure often you have to do more than just “single-shot” copying that is copy a few files to one place, move a few to another, and copy yet some more to one more location. Well, I had to do this quite a few times (e.g. I ran out of disk space recently on a partition and had to empty out my “Movies” and “Songs” folders to move a few movies/songs each to all other partitions/disks according to the space available). Hence, I wrote this little command line program, which behaves like a basket.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can put any number of files from any number of different locations into it in a single shot. It will store their locations and give them an ID. Now, you can copy/move those files to different destinations based on their IDs. What&amp;rsquo;s even better is that your basket will remain intact even across reboots. So, you can continue working on the files in the basket even for days.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Note: **Packages for windows as well as linux have been uploaded. If you have perl, a perl script is also given that works in both platforms without change. I have tested it on Windows XP SP2 and Ubuntu Feisty Fawn 7.04.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>