<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>D-Bus on</title><link>/tags/d-bus/</link><description>Recent content in D-Bus on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 15:30:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/d-bus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>TIP: A Post For Pidgin Plugin Developers</title><link>/2008/09/23/tip-a-post-for-pidgin-plugin-developers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 15:30:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/09/23/tip-a-post-for-pidgin-plugin-developers/</guid><description>Recently I wrote a small autoreply-answering-machine app for pidgin with a simple premise. Send custom automatic replies to different people when they message you and came across a strange bug. It never sent the reply when you received the first message from someone. I was using the &amp;ldquo;ReceivedImMessage&amp;rdquo; signal over d-bus (or &amp;ldquo;received-im-message&amp;rdquo; for the plugin writers). What I found initially looked to be a gross and basic error by pidgin developers, but later found that it is indeed a good design and thought that I&amp;rsquo;ll make a post about it for the benefit of fellow pidgin plugin/app developers.</description><content>&lt;p>Recently I wrote a small autoreply-answering-machine app for pidgin with a simple premise. Send custom automatic replies to different people when they message you and came across a strange bug. It never sent the reply when you received the first message from someone. I was using the &amp;ldquo;ReceivedImMessage&amp;rdquo; signal over d-bus (or &amp;ldquo;received-im-message&amp;rdquo; for the plugin writers). What I found initially looked to be a gross and basic error by pidgin developers, but later found that it is indeed a good design and thought that I&amp;rsquo;ll make a post about it for the benefit of fellow pidgin plugin/app developers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a bit of debugging I saw that when I received the ReceivedImMessage signal for the first message, the &amp;ldquo;Conversation ID&amp;rdquo; field is not a valid value but 0. Thereafter, I got the correct value every time. Searching on the google didn&amp;rsquo;t reveal much except a few other people complaining about the same and someone saying that this is a bug because pidgin first sends the signal and then creates the conversation while it should be the other way round.  Fair enough. But then&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then I came across a short explanation by a pidgin developer, seanegen, (sorry lost the link somewhere). Basically, the reason behind this is that all the checks (e.g. Blacklists etc) are performed after one gets this signal, and hence they dont create the window otherwise it might be created even if you have blocked the person who is sending you the message. Perfect explanation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But, what&amp;rsquo;s the solution. Simple..Use the &amp;ldquo;DisplayedImMessage&amp;rdquo; (or &amp;ldquo;displayed-im-message&amp;rdquo; signal) which is sent, once the conversation has been created. That&amp;rsquo;s it. Hope that this post benefit you.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Project: Splert - A Custom Answering Machine And More for IMs</title><link>/2008/08/18/project-splert-a-custom-answering-machine-and-more-for-ims/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 17:00:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/08/18/project-splert-a-custom-answering-machine-and-more-for-ims/</guid><description>Update Aug 25 2008: Updated to v0.02 and also added 32 bit package. Hit the link given below to download.
You must have heard of (or used) the auto-reply features given by today&amp;rsquo;s instant messengers that are sent to the ones messaging you while you are not at your desk. But those are one-size-fits-all kind of messages. So, I wrote this simple tool a few months ago to turn Pidgin, everyone’s favourite multi-client Instant Messenger (works with gtalk, msn, yahoo, aim etc), into a customized answering machine (and more) when you are away from your computer.</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update Aug 25 2008&lt;/strong>: Updated to v0.02 and also added 32 bit package. Hit the link given below to download.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You must have heard of (or used) the auto-reply features given by today&amp;rsquo;s instant messengers that are sent to the ones messaging you while you are not at your desk. But those are one-size-fits-all kind of messages. So, I wrote this simple tool a few months ago to turn Pidgin, everyone’s favourite multi-client Instant Messenger (works with gtalk, msn, yahoo, aim etc), into a &lt;strong>customized answering machine (and more)&lt;/strong> when you are away from your computer. Basically it allows you to divide up your contact list into groups based on email IDs and execute actions based on when someone from a particular group messages you while you are away. e.g. For general friends, you can keep a message like “Will talk to you later when I come back”, or if someone from office IMs you, it’ll send them your phone number “Call me at XXXXXX if urgent”. And if you boss is the one pinging you, you could direct the message towards your twitter account so that you get it as an SMS on your phone immediately.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Splert: Shantz Pidgin Away Alerts</title><link>/2008/08/18/splert-shantz-pidgin-away-alerts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 16:55:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/08/18/splert-shantz-pidgin-away-alerts/</guid><description>This is a simple tool I wrote a few months ago to turn Pidgin, everyone’s favourite multi-client Instant Messenger (works with gtalk, msn, yahoo, aim etc), into a customized answering machine (and more) when you are away from your computer. Basically it allows you to divide up your contact list into groups based on email IDs and execute actions based on when someone from a particular group messages you while you are away.</description><content>&lt;p>This is a simple tool I wrote a few months ago to turn Pidgin, everyone’s favourite multi-client Instant Messenger (works with gtalk, msn, yahoo, aim etc), into a &lt;strong>customized answering machine (and more)&lt;/strong> when you are away from your computer. Basically it allows you to divide up your contact list into groups based on email IDs and execute actions based on when someone from a particular group messages you while you are away. e.g. For general friends, you can keep a message like “Will talk to you later when I come back”, or if someone from office IMs you, it’ll send them your phone number “Call me at XXXXXX if urgent”. And if you boss is the one pinging you, you could direct the message towards your twitter account so that you get it as an SMS on your phone immediately.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Time is short, so here are the details:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Features:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Group based rule execution, each group can contain any number of email IDs&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Custom replies for each group.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Integrates with twitter and will forward the message to your twitter account (or send a direct message to some other account) if you so desire. (Temporarily disabled since Twitter has blocked their IM bot)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Runs as a separate process over d-bus instead of running as a pidgin plugin, so much lesser chances of crashing.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Prerequisites:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Pidgin &amp;gt; 2.4.1&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Linux&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Download:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Usage:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Unzip the attached package anywhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Either install using the deb package or just copy the splert binary and config.txt to a folder of your choice&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Modify the “config.txt” file according to your needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Run splert. (or run splert -h for checking out the available options though you wouldn’t need them most of the times)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Config File:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Config file fields and formats are explained fully in the sample config file included in the attached file. However, here is a very basic sample configuration:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>[Friends]
user = &lt;a href="mailto:foo@foo.com">foo@foo.com&lt;/a>
message = &amp;ldquo;Not Here. Will talk to you later&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[VIP]
user = &lt;a href="mailto:boss@boss.com">boss@boss.com&lt;/a>
message = &amp;ldquo;Got your message. Will Contact you asap&amp;rdquo;
twitter = 1
twitterto = my2ndtwitteracct&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>ChangeLog:&lt;/strong>
0.03 - Oct04 2008 -&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Added option to specify twitter bot id (e.g. &lt;a href="mailto:twitterspy@jabber.org">twitterspy@jabber.org&lt;/a>) using option &amp;ldquo;-t/-twitterbot&amp;rdquo;. However, you need to do any &amp;ldquo;extra&amp;rdquo; stuff manually. e.g. logging in using twlogin command with twitterspy.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added option to specify the status when you want to send messages instead of just when being away. Use &amp;ldquo;-s/&amp;ndash;status&amp;rdquo; option to do this.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>0.02 - Aug25 2008 -&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Fixed bug where response was not sent for 1st message received&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added 32 bit package&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>0.01 - Aug15 2008 - Initial Version&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please let me know if you like it or found some issues with it. Also, let me know if you would like me to add any features to it.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Download pidgin 2.4.1 For Ubuntu Feisty Fawn (amd64/x86_64)</title><link>/2008/04/04/download-pidgin-241-for-ubuntu-feisty-fawn-amd64x86_64/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2008 17:19:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/04/04/download-pidgin-241-for-ubuntu-feisty-fawn-amd64x86_64/</guid><description>pidgin is everybody&amp;rsquo;s favourite IM client. Lifehacker includes it in its list of top 5 IM clients. Obviously I use it too, but one drawback of being lazy and not switching over to Gutsy Gibbon was that I was stuck with version 2.2.0 for a long time. But recently I began a new journey towards d-bus programming and chose pidgin as my companion. Found out that 2.2.0 has some serious d-bus issues on amd64 that were fixed in 2.</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/img/uploads/logo.pidgin.png" alt="Logo.pidgin">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>pidgin is everybody&amp;rsquo;s favourite IM client. Lifehacker includes it in its list of top 5 IM clients. Obviously I use it too, but one drawback of being lazy and not switching over to Gutsy Gibbon was that I was stuck with version 2.2.0 for a long time. But recently I began a new journey towards d-bus programming and chose pidgin as my companion. Found out that 2.2.0 has some serious d-bus issues on amd64 that were fixed in 2.4.0. Hence, installed all the dependencies, compiled the latest version today from source and installed it. Just thought of putting it out for my fellow Feisty users who are looking to upgrade as well but don&amp;rsquo;t want to go through the mess of compiling from source.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So download it from the below given link. However, since it is a relatively big package (around 8.5 MB), I might pull it if the bandwidth usage becomes too much, so download soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can install it by:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Either using &amp;ldquo;gdebi&amp;rdquo; - A nice deb package installer that will also try to resolve dependencies for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>or by running &amp;ldquo;dpkg -i pidgin_2.4.1-1_amd64.deb&amp;rdquo; on command line.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Let me know if you have any issues with it.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>