<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Stuff on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/categories/stuff/</link><description>Recent content in Stuff on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 16:25:46 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/categories/stuff/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Migrating my hugo blog from Gitlab/AWS S3 to Github Pages with Actions</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2020/01/05/migrate-hugo-blog-gitlab-s3-github-pages-actions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 16:25:46 +0530</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2020/01/05/migrate-hugo-blog-gitlab-s3-github-pages-actions/</guid><description>Until Now - The State of the union This blog is generated using hugo, an awesome static site generator. So far, the workflow I used to deploy it was:
Push commit to the source repository on GitLab GitLab CI kicks off on receiving the push CI downloads latest version of hugo and generates the static site Runs aws-cli to sync the new files to AWS S3 S3 serves the static site Cloudflare provides: DNS services (so I can use https://shantanugoel.</description></item><item><title>Patterbuzz - Your Content Your Way</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/12/07/patterbuzz-your-content-your-way/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 19:29:57 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/12/07/patterbuzz-your-content-your-way/</guid><description>My brother, Amit Goel, has founded a startup &amp;ldquo;Patterbuzz&amp;rdquo; which is aiming to disrupt the digital publishing marketplace. Read on for details about it in his words. I can assure you that you don't want to miss out on this whether you are a publisher or a consumer :)
Welcome Offer: Download the app and register your account before 15th December and get 100 Credits FREE!! to download the content of your choice.</description></item><item><title>Apple, Anti-Malware, Patents</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/02/15/apple-anti-malware-patents/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 16:55:10 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/02/15/apple-anti-malware-patents/</guid><description>Recently, there has been this trend. Blogs look for patents filed by companies and then report on each of them as if they are second coming of Jesus in technology. Especially if it is Apple who is doing the filings.
A few days ago, this new patent showed up about Apple's &amp;ldquo;new wave approach to fighting malware&amp;rdquo; with the author giving up half-researched commentary on it.
I was intrigued by this news (if you can call it that), not because it’s something new but instead because process isolation is hardly a new concept.</description></item><item><title>Bugs: What you see is not always what it is</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2012/07/23/bugs-what-you-see-is-not-always-what-it-is/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 04:46:08 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2012/07/23/bugs-what-you-see-is-not-always-what-it-is/</guid><description>Came across a neat nugget of historical information today that yet again proves that the software/hardware bug behavior that you may see on the surface might imply something totally opposite to what the problem actually is.
The &amp;ldquo;bug&amp;rdquo; existed back in the old times of the floppy drives. These drives seemed to fail very quickly on linux systems compared to MS DOS/Windows. Now, a normal observer would say linux had bad handling of the drives or was doing something messy that made these drives crap out ever so often.</description></item><item><title>Featured in Chip India August 2011 Edition</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/08/01/featured-in-chip-india-august-2011-edition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 03:24:23 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/08/01/featured-in-chip-india-august-2011-edition/</guid><description>My project Kinect on PS3 got featured in this month's Chip magazine :). They have a special gaming edition of Chip Insider which featured the project along with a 2 page interview of mine. If you buy chip, do look out for it on pages 46 and 47. I also have a scanned image of the pages below.</description></item><item><title>PSN Ban-Wave Phishing Scam</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/02/17/psn-ban-wave-phishing-scam/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 09:25:24 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/02/17/psn-ban-wave-phishing-scam/</guid><description>**Update: **I did some more digging and the email and the links actually seem to be legitimate. Good news for many, but bad for those who actually got this email.
BEWARE!! In wake of the recent announcement of a potential Playstation Network ban wave by Sony for the people who are hacking it's gaming console PS3, some nefarious elements seem to be using this as an opportunity to pry on your PSN passwords.</description></item><item><title>Paypal India Goes Even More Downhill. Get Your Money Out</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/01/28/paypal-india-goes-even-more-downhill-get-your-money-out/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2011 19:30:03 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/01/28/paypal-india-goes-even-more-downhill-get-your-money-out/</guid><description>Just received an email from Paypal India. The main parts are these:
With effect from 1 March 2011, you are required to comply with the requirements set out in the notification of the Reserve Bank of India governing the processing and settlement of export-related receipts facilitated by online payment gateways (&amp;ldquo;RBI Guidelines&amp;rdquo;). In order to comply with the RBI Guidelines, our user agreement in India will be amended for the following services as follows:</description></item><item><title>Review of X-Mini Capsule Happy Speakers</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/11/28/review-of-x-mini-capsule-happy-speakers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2010 16:22:18 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/11/28/review-of-x-mini-capsule-happy-speakers/</guid><description>I received a few portable speakers as review pieces from x-mini a few days ago. I tried all of them but thought of posting a review of the most interesting model out of the lot, which is the X-mini Happy. Would also be posting a review soon of one more model that I liked quite a bit which is the X-mini Max II.
In The Package</description></item><item><title>WordPress Global Dashboard &amp; Stats Plugin Problem</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/04/wordpress-global-dashboard-stats-plugin-problem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2010 16:57:30 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/04/wordpress-global-dashboard-stats-plugin-problem/</guid><description>Seems like there is a major problem going on with WordPress.com and it's stats plugin right now. On logging into your WordPress blog, instead of seeing the pretty charts and stats, you will see a login box instead. On logging in, it just redirects back to the same thing again (Dashboard with login page). And if you try logging into your profile over at WordPress.com, then it just redirects back to your main blog associated with your WordPress.</description></item><item><title>Clearing the FUD around Ubuntu Application Review Process</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/21/clearing-the-fud-around-ubuntu-application-review-process/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2010 19:44:24 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/21/clearing-the-fud-around-ubuntu-application-review-process/</guid><description>An application review process was announced today for getting your apps into Ubuntu “extras” repository. But like most other announcements of new things, this one was met as well with as much criticism as the praise it got. A lot of the criticism is FUD though, although mostly unintentional and caused by ignorance of some facts behind it. I’ll try to address some of these concerns here to the best of my knowledge from what I’ve been reading over the past some time about this development.</description></item><item><title>Acer TimelineX 4820TG Mini-Review</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/06/acer-timelinex-4820tg-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2010 12:18:12 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/06/acer-timelinex-4820tg-review/</guid><description>This is a small review of my Acer TimelineX 4820TG that I purchased a few days ago. Now, I won’t be talking numbers (like CPU/GPU performance etc) because these things are almost same as per the component used and have been covered in various other reviews online. What I’ll concentrate more upon are the things that other reviewers don’t look at, or look at purely from numbers perspective which don’t make sense to an average buyer.</description></item><item><title>Wi-Fi Keep Alive</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/28/wi-fi-keep-alive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2010 15:20:19 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/28/wi-fi-keep-alive/</guid><description>UPDATE Potential work arounds for folks having problem in sleep policies not working correctly have been put in version 1.2.0 onwards. Please redownload to test and let me know. Read below for more details.
Latest Version: 1.4.4 (See below for change log history)
Are you frustrated by your downloads getting broken or worse, switching over to slow and expensive mobile data connections like GPRS/Edge/3G when your wi-fi connection gets dropped by your Android phone when the screen goes off?</description></item><item><title>RT-GNUPlot-ter</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/12/29/real-time-streaming-data-plot-gnuplot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2009 10:52:56 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/12/29/real-time-streaming-data-plot-gnuplot/</guid><description>This is a script to plot streaming / real-time data (i.e. plot the points as the data comes in) with gnuplot. The script is written in perl and works in windows as well as linux. Please read on to see the requirements, installation, usage and download link. I should also thank my colleague Rabindra Mandal, who gave me the initial idea and Thanassis Tsiodras, whose script I looked at before creating mine (though mine is quite different in nature.</description></item><item><title>Paradise For Overclockers, Gamers and PC Enthusiasts In India</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/12/07/overclockers-pc-enthusiasts-gamers-india/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2009 18:05:27 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/12/07/overclockers-pc-enthusiasts-gamers-india/</guid><description>This is just to let you know that a few of my friends have started Overclocked, a haven for PC enthusiasts in India. Overclocked is an online store for the people who like to stretch the performance of their machines to the maximum. They store a lot of high end computer stuff that isn't easy to find in India and that too for a reasonable price. They also assemble mean gaming machines while giving you quite a bang for your buck with gauranteed satisfaction, shipped anywhere in India, and that's not all, they can personalize it too with a variety of custom modifications (I really like their laser engravings).</description></item><item><title>Killzone 2 Tips Tricks Tactics And Strategies : Engineer</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/08/09/killzone-2-tips-tricks-tactics-stategies-engineer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2009 16:45:04 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/08/09/killzone-2-tips-tricks-tactics-stategies-engineer/</guid><description>Killzone 2 (KZ2) is one of my most favourite games for the Playstation 3. Killzone 2 is a very different game as compared to the other run-of-the-mill FPS's out there. Now, I might not be the best player out there but I've played my fair share of it. So, I thought of jotting down some quick points for the different classes, how to play them and how to make the most of them according to my opinion.</description></item><item><title>VirtualBox High CPU Usage Problem Solved</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/07/07/virtualbox-high-cpu-usage-problem-solved/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2009 03:36:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/07/07/virtualbox-high-cpu-usage-problem-solved/</guid><description>A few days ago, I had to install Windows XP as a guest OS on my Ubuntu Hardy machine as I needed to carry out some Visual Studio work. What I noticed was that my CPU usage went through the roof (constantly at 100%) even if the guest was completely idle. Result: My laptop was shutting down within a few minutes because the CPU was heating up and its temperature going beyond 75C.</description></item><item><title>Opera Web Server In A Browser: Bad Idea</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/06/17/opera-web-server-browser-bad-idea/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 08:17:04 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/06/17/opera-web-server-browser-bad-idea/</guid><description>Today, the whole word is going gaga over &amp;ldquo;Opera Unite&amp;quot;, the new technology in Opera 10 which will make your web browser a web server as well (and not just that, it will make a whole lot of “sharing” options available). Well, I’m not so excited about it. Technology wise, it is really cool but what they don’t realize is that this is like giving motorized chain-saw or a swiss army knife in the hands of a two-year old.</description></item><item><title>Microtek UPS Problems (And A Solution)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/05/10/microtek-ups-problems-solution/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2009 15:35:02 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/05/10/microtek-ups-problems-solution/</guid><description>I got myself a Microtek 800VA UPS (MDP800+) a couple of weeks ago to save my PS3 from the frequent power outages that we are seeing in Hyderabad but the purpose was rather lost when I found that it worked fine only till the mains power was on. As soon as there was an outage, it couldn’t stop the PS3 from an abrupt shut down. I ran around the pathetic Microtek customer service for days and they finally sent an “engineer” down to my place (after a week) to diagnose the issue and he couldn’t say anything more than that the UPS is meant for a PC and nothing else.</description></item><item><title>Why You Should Not Upgrade to Ubuntu Jaunty Jackalope (9.04)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/05/04/ubuntu-904-jaunty-jackalope-upgrade-graphics-problem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2009 17:46:40 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/05/04/ubuntu-904-jaunty-jackalope-upgrade-graphics-problem/</guid><description>Update: It has come to my notice that many people do not know about this (and other problems listed in comments of this post). Please digg and reddit this post so that more people can be made aware of it before they upgrade unknowingly.
You should not upgrade to Ubuntu 9.04 (aka Jaunty Jackalope), released a few weeks ago, if:
You have an older ATI graphics card (prior to R500, .</description></item><item><title>Figlet Online</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/22/figlet-online/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2009 14:15:54 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/22/figlet-online/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Comments In Google Reader Shared Items Are Here</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/12/google-reader-shared-items-comments/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2009 05:00:22 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/12/google-reader-shared-items-comments/</guid><description>Since quite some time, Google Reader has included the feature to share interesting items with your friends who also use Google Reader. Some time back they also added the option to &amp;ldquo;Share with a Note&amp;rdquo; to add your take to the shared piece. But I always thought there was no way to share back by comments (or see my friends&amp;rsquo; take) about that particular article. One way could have been to post the comments on the original site of the article but that had the drawbacks that:</description></item><item><title>KillZone 2 Steel-Book Edition is here</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/20/killzone-2-steel-book-edition-is-here/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2009 21:47:04 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/20/killzone-2-steel-book-edition-is-here/</guid><description>Note: Please DIGG this post by clicking here or Reddit this post by clicking here.
I'll be one of the proud owners of a very special steel book edition of Killzone 2 very soon. The cool part being that it'd be much before most of the rest of the world gets to even see these little babies because the official release date is still five days away. And the icing on the cake &amp;ldquo;A free classic Art Book&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>WordCamp India Is Here</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/14/wordcamp-india/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2009 20:51:48 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/14/wordcamp-india/</guid><description>Just a little piece of news to all the bloggers, and especially WordPressers (did I just coin a new term?), out there. WordCamp is coming to India. And what's more, Matt is going to be there. (Yes, THE Matt. Oh My, you just don't believe me, do you. Fanboys, it is time to rejoice as I assure you this is THEMatt Mullenweg). It's going to be held on the 21st and 22nd of this Feb at Adobe, Noida (who are the main sponsors for this event).</description></item><item><title>Slow Updates And A Small Nugget Post</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/13/slow-updates-and-a-small-nugget-post/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2009 04:47:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/13/slow-updates-and-a-small-nugget-post/</guid><description>Many readers of this blog have written to me for the slow updates. I apologize for the same. I’ve been swamped by loads of work for quite some time now and haven’t been able to write anything here or update any of my projects, though I have loads of new hacks and tricks that I would write once I’m free and lots in store for most of the projects as well in form of bug fixes and new features.</description></item><item><title>Contest: Free 20$ SiteGround Web Hosting Coupon</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/12/12/contest-free-20-siteground-web-hosting-coupon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2008 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/12/12/contest-free-20-siteground-web-hosting-coupon/</guid><description>I have a coupon to give away for the excellent SiteGround Web Hosting. This coupon will take off 20$ from anything you want to buy from them. If you have an existing website with them, then also you can use this to take off 20$ from your bill. So, what do you have to do? Just follow the 2 simple steps listed below, and I’ll choose one lucky winner at random to give it away.</description></item><item><title>The Solution To Your Problem Is Out There .... Somewhere</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/12/03/the-solution-to-your-problem-is-out-there-somewhere/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2008 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/12/03/the-solution-to-your-problem-is-out-there-somewhere/</guid><description>I got hold of a new Asus WL-500W router for me (Pics &amp;amp; specs coming up soon). The router has open source firmware so people can develop applications for it. One such app (ADOS) is that allows you to configure the router to download stuff directly to a hard disk (connected to router through USB) without the need of keeping the PC switched on. One of the app users reported the following error (Click on the pic to enlarge) that he got while using the app.</description></item><item><title>Call For Google Adsense Maths Class Charity Fund</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/23/call-for-google-adsense-maths-class-charity-fund/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2008 08:25:36 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/23/call-for-google-adsense-maths-class-charity-fund/</guid><description>I hereby call for setting up a charity fund so that we can donate some money to get the poor ol’ Google Adsense some Mathematics/Algebra 101 classes because apparantly it thinks that 0.63 + 0.07 = 0.69.</description></item><item><title>Boycott Novell Protestors Manhandled By National Free Software Conference 2008 Organizers</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/16/boycott-novell-protestors-manhandled-by-national-free-software-conference-2008-organizers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2008 09:38:39 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/16/boycott-novell-protestors-manhandled-by-national-free-software-conference-2008-organizers/</guid><description>This is a really sad day. Not only the organizers of National Conference On Free Software 2008 taking place at CUSAT seem to be utterly misguided when they decided to let Novell be on-board as their main sponsor, they even took the extreme step of bringing in police to silence the lone voices of the Boycott Novell protestors. They seem to be treading on the toes of not just free software but free speech as well, which is against the very ethics of the conference they are holding.</description></item><item><title>A Treat For Google Lovers: Google Solutions Marketplace</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/10/a-treat-for-google-lovers-google-solutions-marketplace/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2008 14:30:22 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/10/a-treat-for-google-lovers-google-solutions-marketplace/</guid><description>Given the ignorant lazy bum I am, until a couple of days ago I was unaware of this magical place called “Google Solutions Marketplace”. According to Google:
Basically it is a boon for both, google product users who depend on various search, enterprise, search and apps related Google offerings, and developers who develop products and services based upon these. Google Solutions Marketplace acts as a bridge between the two to offer a one stop shop where you can buy (or even get for free, in many cases) the brilliant ideas that have been developed by many individuals and companies based on google’s services.</description></item><item><title>Google Adsense : Conflict of Interests?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/07/google-adsense-conflict-of-interests/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2008 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/07/google-adsense-conflict-of-interests/</guid><description>“Google Adsense” has been caught in a conflict of interests with its parent company “Google”. Google piad 140k to teh cause of “Say No to Prop 8” but on the other hand people reported that Google Adsense delivered a substantially huge amount of “Say Yes to Prop 8” advertisements all over the internet, even on sites which are completely out of context with this matter. Not only is this conflicting with the interests of the parent company but also with the “Terms of Use” put forward by Adsense that ads should not have any kind of intolerance or advocacy towards an individual or a group.</description></item><item><title>Creative Open Sources X-Fi Sound Card Driver…Finally</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/07/creative-open-sources-x-fi-sound-card-driverfinally/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2008 04:14:29 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/07/creative-open-sources-x-fi-sound-card-driverfinally/</guid><description>Creative has finally come to its senses and turned to the open source community to raise its X-Fi series of sound cards from the ashes on the linux platform, which got burnt mostly due to the poor quality of the drivers that Creative was giving out. The announcement for releasing the source code, licensed under GPL v2, was made on their forums. For the announcement and download details, click here.</description></item><item><title>Make Money Out Of Nothing: Add Google Adsense For Search To Your 404 Page</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/06/make-money-out-of-nothing-add-google-adsense-for-search-to-your-404-page/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 14:30:28 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/06/make-money-out-of-nothing-add-google-adsense-for-search-to-your-404-page/</guid><description>A 404 page is an error page that is displayed when somebody tries to go to a link on your website that doesn’t exist. This could occur when someone linking to your website or typing in his browser address bar mistypes a url, or maybe that page has been moved or deleted by you. Lost opportunity? Maybe. But definitely not, if you follow this advise. Many people don’t have a 404 page altogether, a few implement with an inane message like “Something went wrong”, a few will try to help out the seemingly lost user by giving a few navigation options linking to home page, archives or most popular posts, etc.</description></item><item><title>Save Your Adsense Account: Put Up That Privacy Policy</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/04/save-your-adsense-account-put-up-that-privacy-policy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 17:35:58 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/04/save-your-adsense-account-put-up-that-privacy-policy/</guid><description>Google is known to be pretty strict with making sure that all Adsense publishers remain conformant to their policies. I’m not very old in this game but had read and heard enough (about google shutting down Adsense accounts without even warning) that I made sure to read their terms and conditions thoroughly. What got my attention was the very last line in the policy:
Now why I wrote this post was that though almost every site I visit has adsense ads, but only a very miniscule fraction of them is abiding with this condition.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Has A Problem: Software Patents Go Up In Smoke</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/31/microsoft-has-a-problem-software-patents-go-up-in-smoke/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 18:35:57 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/31/microsoft-has-a-problem-software-patents-go-up-in-smoke/</guid><description>Just read over at groklaw about a ruling made last night by the US Appeals Court. According to it, the patents granted for business practices would have to undergo specific and stringent testing procedures to check the worthiness of granting a patent to it. Essentially, they are aiming to mandate a passing of &amp;ldquo;machine-or-transformation test&amp;rdquo; as a pre-requisite for granting a patent. This means that a mere &amp;ldquo;idea in my head&amp;rdquo; doesn't qualify for a patent until it is put into practice on a machine or can transform the state of an object for a specific purpose.</description></item><item><title>A Friend In Need Is A Good Webhost Indeed</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/27/a-friend-in-need-is-a-good-webhost-indeed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2008 10:45:09 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/27/a-friend-in-need-is-a-good-webhost-indeed/</guid><description>A webhost that puts building relationships with customers before making money is definitely a good webhost. And this works out to be good for you as well as the webhost in the end. Now, why am I saying this all which should be part of a “Doing Business 101” course. Because, in this world of unprofessional webhosting, where people lure you with fool’s gold, promising everything unlimited and cutting you off with even the slightest of deviation from their “AUP” mumbo jumbo, there still exist good webhosts which promise you very little but are good enough to deliver on them and then some more.</description></item><item><title>Android Devices Trickling In A Few Days Early?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/20/android-devices-trickling-in-a-few-days-early/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2008 19:32:35 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/20/android-devices-trickling-in-a-few-days-early/</guid><description>There is still a day left for the first Android based Device, T-Mobile G1, to come out into the hands of general public but I was in a for a small surprise as I went through my Google Analytics report for the last week. It had a mysterious number of 2 sitting at the bottom of my “Unique Visitors by Operating Systems” filter report. The “mysterious” part coming from the fact that the left most column displayed “Android”.</description></item><item><title>Satellite TV (DTH) In India: A Guide</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/09/satellite-tv-dth-in-india-a-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2008 17:57:57 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/09/satellite-tv-dth-in-india-a-guide/</guid><description>Amit has written a detailed Satellite TV (DTH) Guide and Comparison about the scene in India. He compares the various players that are operating right now and gives suggestions on what should one look at while choosing out of all the available operators. If you are confused about what the advent of all these different names like Tata Sky (Tata), Big TV (Reliance) and Airtel Digital TV (Bharti) means for you, then do take a look at it.</description></item><item><title>Check Out T-Mobile G1/HTC Dream/Android Emulator Online</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/04/check-out-t-mobile-g1htc-dreamandroid-emulator-online/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2008 22:51:27 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/04/check-out-t-mobile-g1htc-dreamandroid-emulator-online/</guid><description>Just came across this very cool online emulator that lets you get a first hand experience of how the Google Android based phone T-Mobile G1 (aka HTC Dream) will look and behave like. The sliding notification mechanisms look cool, few of the things aren't working but still a good thing to check out. However, I don't know if this is an official site by T-Mobile or not.
Linky: http://tmobile.modeaondemand.com/htc/g1/</description></item><item><title>Hack: Pidgin-Gtalk Connection Problems - Get Around The Corporate Firewall</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/08/hack-pidgin-gtalk-connection-problems-get-around-the-corporate-firewall/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 15:30:38 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/08/hack-pidgin-gtalk-connection-problems-get-around-the-corporate-firewall/</guid><description>I recently wrote a simple answering machine program/plugin for pidgin and someone asked me to port it to 32 bit. So I fired up pidgin within my virtual box installation at work (as I have only a 64 bit machine at home) but couldn't get it to connect. Tried all sorts of methods found over the net of changing ports etc, set port forwarding in Virtual Box NAT, even switched to using a bridged host interface but still no go.</description></item><item><title>Apology For Bad Downloads</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/05/apology-for-bad-downloads/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 16:13:19 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/05/apology-for-bad-downloads/</guid><description>Guys, for the past few days if you downloaded any &amp;ldquo;.tar.gz&amp;rdquo; packages from this site (like my splert or shantz-xwinwrap tools), then you'd have got a corrupt package. Turns out there was some issue with mime-types with my setup. I haven't been able to resolve it still but have re-upped the packages in &amp;ldquo;zip&amp;rdquo; format. Please download them again. I apologize for the inconvenience.</description></item><item><title>Shantz XWinWrap</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/03/shantz-xwinwrap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 14:41:44 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/03/shantz-xwinwrap/</guid><description>XWinWrap is a small utility written a loooong time ago that allowed you to stick most of the apps to your desktop background. What this meant was you could use an animated screensaver (like glmatrix, electric sheep, etc) or even a movie, and use it as your wallpaper. But only one version of this app was ever released, and it had a few problems, like:
Well, sticking didn't work.</description></item><item><title>Do They Really Know How To Sell Something In India?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/26/do-they-really-know-how-to-sell-something-in-india/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 14:45:46 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/26/do-they-really-know-how-to-sell-something-in-india/</guid><description>Update: UK Ad Authorities have declared iPhone ad as &amp;ldquo;misleading&amp;rdquo;. I guess then they should declare it plain fraud in India.
This is a short rant about two of the &amp;ldquo;big&amp;rdquo; products launched recently in India in the last one week and how the people behind their sales/marketing teams either try to take the Indian customer for a ride, or shaft themselves.
iPhone: The big icon. Bharti Airtel/Vodafone claimed lakhs of pre-registrations, yet no one lined up to buy it.</description></item><item><title>Splert: Shantz Pidgin Away Alerts</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/18/splert-shantz-pidgin-away-alerts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 16:55:03 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/18/splert-shantz-pidgin-away-alerts/</guid><description>This is a simple tool I wrote a few months ago to turn Pidgin, everyone’s favourite multi-client Instant Messenger (works with gtalk, msn, yahoo, aim etc), into a customized answering machine (and more) when you are away from your computer. Basically it allows you to divide up your contact list into groups based on email IDs and execute actions based on when someone from a particular group messages you while you are away.</description></item><item><title>Shantz Webcam Autolocker</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/11/shantz-webcam-autolocker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2008 17:50:54 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/11/shantz-webcam-autolocker/</guid><description>Sometimes I do some things that even I can't explain why I did &amp;lsquo;em. Did this one in one of those times as well. This is a simple (and useless) script to monitor motion in front of your PC, auto-lock it when you are away and auto-unlock it when you come back. Kinda useless cuz there is no security aspect (read face detection etc) and any kind of motion triggers the unlock.</description></item><item><title>Site Updates</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/29/site-updates-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 18:16:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/29/site-updates-2/</guid><description>Just wanted to apologize to you guys for not updating this blog frequently as work load is becoming more and more these days. But I'll try my best to update as often as possible. There are a couple of useful apps that I wrote some time ago but havent found time to add all the features that I wanted and to roll them out, maybe I'll release them with the current feature set.</description></item><item><title>A Breath Of Fresh Air: My New Ubuntu Desktop</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/21/a-breath-of-fresh-air-my-new-ubuntu-desktop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2008 18:54:53 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/21/a-breath-of-fresh-air-my-new-ubuntu-desktop/</guid><description>**UPDATE: **Surprisingly this post has found favour with “digg”ers :). Check the bottom of the post for some more info about the setup
UPDATE2: On popular demand, I've uploaded my .conkyrc. Download Conky Configuration file by clicking here and save as .conkyrc in your home folder.
After loitering around for so long, I finally got my lazy bum off the bed and installed Hardy Heron (8.04.1) onto my aging laptop. I’ve never been a sucker for eye-candy stuff, prefering to have more resources available for real work, instead of ooh-aahing over nice looking things all around my desktop.</description></item><item><title>"The Square Root of 3" - Kumar Does It Again</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/17/the-square-root-of-3-kumar-does-it-again/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2008 15:33:46 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/17/the-square-root-of-3-kumar-does-it-again/</guid><description>I watched &amp;ldquo;Harold and Kumar: Escape from Guantanamo Bay&amp;rdquo; a few days ago. Cool movie, though not as awesome as &amp;ldquo;Go to White Castle&amp;rdquo; one. But one thing that I liked was the poem that Kumar (Kal Penn) recites in an attempt to woo back her love by embarrassing himself more than he had embarrassed her (Yes, you can see such situations only in H&amp;amp;K movies ;) ). The poem is actually written by one &amp;ldquo;David Feinberg&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>A New Resource For Reverse Engineering (and more)...</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/14/a-new-resource-for-reverse-engineering-and-more/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 14:18:32 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/14/a-new-resource-for-reverse-engineering-and-more/</guid><description>My brother “Amit Goel” has started a tech blog, primarily about Reverse Engineering nuances, but he plans to write much more. Pay him a visit at Amit’s Lab and let him know what topics you want him to discuss about.</description></item><item><title>The Biggest Flaw in Gnome UI</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/07/the-biggest-flaw-in-gnome-ui/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2008 14:28:02 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/07/the-biggest-flaw-in-gnome-ui/</guid><description>Everywhere you go, any building you enter, any OS you operate, any settings window you open, one rule remains set in stone, “THE ESCAPE DOOR”. Always give an exit path, a way to make it all go away, make it look like nothing happened. But Gnome seems to think otherwise. Any settings window you open, all you see is a “close” button.
I made a few changes and then tried to “undo” them by using the following methods:</description></item><item><title>More iPhone 3G Nonsense Uncovered: No Tethering</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/06/14/more-iphone-3g-nonsense-uncovered-no-tethering/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2008 15:57:50 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/06/14/more-iphone-3g-nonsense-uncovered-no-tethering/</guid><description>iPhone 3G, the “supposedly” latest and greatest handhled, just continues to amaze me, with its ridiculousness of course. I mean first they dare to call a machine a smartphone that can’t run more than one app a time, need you to send the unit back even for a battery change, fix the glaring mistakes of its predecessor and call them “features” and make you believe that you are getting it all for cheap while covertly telling you that you need a minimum of 2 year 70$ contract to get it and need to pay through every hole for even software updates.</description></item><item><title>Google's New Favicon</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/30/googles-new-favicon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2008 19:16:21 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/30/googles-new-favicon/</guid><description>It’s amazing, isn’t it? Even a sneeze at google makes the headlines. Well, it’s not the sneeze today but the new favicon I just got. So, are you also seeing the all new, re-designed, artisticly polished “g” as the new favicon?
In other news, my Twitter-Webcam integration post has bypassed my earlier lifehacked post about Remote File Access Through E-mail by more than a few thousands, even though the time difference between the two posts is more than 3 months.</description></item><item><title>My Top 5 Comics For The Geeks</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/26/my-top-5-comics-for-the-geeks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2008 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/26/my-top-5-comics-for-the-geeks/</guid><description>If you think that all geeks do is walk around wearing thick glasses, code in unreadable languages and make weird gizmos from parts scrapped out of your junkyard, well you think wrong. We do like to have our share of fun. And what better to begin the day with a nice hot cuppa along with some geeky humour. Folks, here it is, the 5 comic strips that I love the most (in no particular order):</description></item><item><title>Ubuntu: What exactly does LTS mean?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/20/ubuntu-what-exactly-does-lts-mean/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 21:29:10 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/20/ubuntu-what-exactly-does-lts-mean/</guid><description>With the recent release of Ubuntu 8.04 (Hardy Heron), a lot of hype was generated (Overhype or well-deserved, that’s for another post). One of the main highlights of all the stories, news and reviews doing the rounds are that this is an LTS version. But many people, mostly those who are new to Ubuntu, and even a few who are already using it, are not sure what LTS really means.</description></item><item><title>The Elusive Super Phone</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/08/the-elusive-super-phone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2008 17:15:28 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/08/the-elusive-super-phone/</guid><description>HTC announce their shiny new Touch Diamond recently. Everyone ooh'ed and aah'ed while ogling at it until they realized that HTC has taken a step back (or forward towards matching Apple's iPhone crap) by removing the expansion card slot from the phone. Yes, it has 4 GB of internal storage but I'd rather have an SDHC card slot with the ever falling prices of solid state memory (an 8 GB Class 6 SDHC card is worth not more than around 60$ these days).</description></item><item><title>Http 406 Errors Galore</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/01/http-406-errors-galore/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 15:30:05 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/01/http-406-errors-galore/</guid><description>If you have ever had these errors or just want to be prepared in case they pop up somtime (and they surely will), then read on as I discuss various situations that lead to them and also their solutions.
I generally use desktop clients (mostly blogjet, but also Windows Live Writer and Scribe Fire sometimes) to blog to my WordPress based blogs. Some months ago, I started getting &amp;ldquo;Http 406: Not Acceptable&amp;rdquo; error while posting a particular post.</description></item><item><title>Page Rank 7: True Or Google Glitch?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/30/page-rank-7-true-or-google-glitch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2008 20:33:51 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/30/page-rank-7-true-or-google-glitch/</guid><description>I installed google toolbar (linux version) today in firefox and for this blog, it says that its page rank is 7. I can't believe my eyes. I suppose it's a google glitch may be (but have a wishful thinking at the back of mind that its true :-) ).
Are you getting the same result for this blog (or weird page rank results for other places that you frequent?)</description></item><item><title>Windows App Alternatives For Linux: MSPaint</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/28/windows-app-alternatives-for-linux-mspaint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2008 15:30:44 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/28/windows-app-alternatives-for-linux-mspaint/</guid><description>Some of you might know that I was in the hunt for a decent mspaint alternative recently. Note that I didn't go for GIMP / Inkscape etc because they were overkill for what I wanted to do. Many a times, I just wanted to touch up a screenshot or make a simple flow image by drawing a few boxes, use a few pointing arrows, and add some text here and there.</description></item><item><title>ImageMagick: Weaving Magic With Your Pictures</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/26/imagemagick-weaving-magic-with-your-pictures/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2008 06:23:18 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/26/imagemagick-weaving-magic-with-your-pictures/</guid><description>I’ve known about ImageMagick tools for quite some time now but never dabbled with it. A couple of weeks ago I played with it for some time (notice the new cascaded polaroid pics header above) and was amazed even more. Few of its shining features:
It has almost unlimited features to manipulate your images through its tools like convert, montage, mogrify etc and their long list of options.</description></item><item><title>5 Reasons I Like Linux (And 5 Why I Dislike It)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/19/5-reasons-i-like-linux-and-5-why-i-dislike-it/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2008 20:20:40 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/19/5-reasons-i-like-linux-and-5-why-i-dislike-it/</guid><description>Disclaimer Notes:
I wrote this because these things just came into my mind today while I was reading about the impending “Hardy Heron” release related things and saw that there is a lot of FUD being spread still. So, thought of jotting down my likes/dislikes and not making it a linux v/s windows campaign. Though at a few places, it might be necessary to compare the two just to put things into perspective.</description></item><item><title>Gmail Blocking Messages to Yahoo Groups?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/13/gmail-blocking-messages-to-yahoo-groups/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2008 16:58:36 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/13/gmail-blocking-messages-to-yahoo-groups/</guid><description>For the past couple of days I have been unable to send any mails to any of my yahoo groups through my gmail account. All my message are returned back with a &amp;ldquo;Message Rejected&amp;rdquo; failure. What I get back is a link to this support answer: Sector 5 Bounces. Anyone else seen this?</description></item><item><title>An Idea Is All You Need</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/12/an-idea-is-all-you-need-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2008 15:43:32 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/12/an-idea-is-all-you-need-2/</guid><description>Everyone wants to make a name for himself. Everyone wants to do something new and extra-ordinary. People like me (read software engineers) want to develop &amp;ldquo;something&amp;rdquo; cool. BUT, the stage where most of them go wrong is the very first one. Most of them think that the road to develop something cool starts from a particular &amp;ldquo;language&amp;rdquo; or a tool. But I beg to differ. I say the first stage is &amp;ldquo;The Idea&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Project: My WordPress Plugin shantz-wp-qotd updated to version 1.2.2</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/10/project-my-wordpress-plugin-shantz-wp-qotd-updated-to-version-122/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2008 20:33:41 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/10/project-my-wordpress-plugin-shantz-wp-qotd-updated-to-version-122/</guid><description>Updated my WordPress plugin shantz-wp-qotd to version 1.2.2 today.
Introduction: Shantz WP QOTD is a plugin to add quotes to your wordpress blog in a few easy clicks. It adds quotes to your posts and your sidebars with a multitude of options for sources and customization.
Changelog:
Version 1.2.2
Fixed a bug because of which quotes were blank some times. Thanks to Thom for reporting it.</description></item><item><title>The Why Behind "Open Source": In simple Terms</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/08/the-why-behind-open-source-in-simple-terms/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2008 14:40:43 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/08/the-why-behind-open-source-in-simple-terms/</guid><description>Many people ask me why are people crazy about Open Source, or why does it even exist. After all if your code is out there, you can't make money off it, right? Well, yes and no. Now, I ain't no open source guru, but I do my part for it. Generally my explanations are either too complex, too full of extra details or mostly just described badly for a layman that I end up on square one, i.</description></item><item><title>Migrating From PHP4 To PHP5: Solving WP-Cache (and maybe other) Issues</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/07/migrating-from-php4-to-php5-solving-wp-cache-and-maybe-other-issues/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2008 13:37:17 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/07/migrating-from-php4-to-php5-solving-wp-cache-and-maybe-other-issues/</guid><description>Situation: You are migrating your WordPress blog from PHP4 to PHP5 (intentionally or being forced to as you web host won't support PHP4 anymore). Most of the times, this is as simple as adding some simple lines to .htaccess (e.g. AddHandler application/x-httpd-php5 .php ). And you might not notice any issues. But many of you still do. The issues range from weird page layouts, to some controls not working, to some errors popping up here and there, and probably your blog not even displaying.</description></item><item><title>Twittering Away With Delhi Bloggers</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/06/twittering-away-with-delhi-bloggers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2008 14:57:24 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/06/twittering-away-with-delhi-bloggers/</guid><description>If you are twittering kinds, doesn't matter online or offline
If you blog or are interested in all things blog and blogging
If you live in Delhi, have lived there, have been there, or just connect with Delhi somehow else
If you want to meet up with your fellow twitterers and bloggers
Then you've got to be a part of the your very own City of The People With Hearts, Delhi.</description></item><item><title>Hack: Fixing The WordPress i3theme Sidebar Issue (Part II)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/06/hack-fixing-the-wordpress-i3theme-sidebar-issue-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2008 14:20:25 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/06/hack-fixing-the-wordpress-i3theme-sidebar-issue-part-ii/</guid><description>Some time back I had posted a little hack to fix an issue that users of i3theme have, i.e., their right sidebar drops to below the main content area in IE6. But it wasn't that good as it took care of only the situation when this phenomena was caused by the tag cloud widget. So, here is a little modification I did to fix the issue more properly.
Go to your wp-content/themes/folder and open the style.</description></item><item><title>Download pidgin 2.4.1 For Ubuntu Feisty Fawn (amd64/x86_64)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/04/download-pidgin-241-for-ubuntu-feisty-fawn-amd64x86_64/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2008 17:19:02 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/04/download-pidgin-241-for-ubuntu-feisty-fawn-amd64x86_64/</guid><description>pidgin is everybody's favourite IM client. Lifehacker includes it in its list of top 5 IM clients. Obviously I use it too, but one drawback of being lazy and not switching over to Gutsy Gibbon was that I was stuck with version 2.2.0 for a long time. But recently I began a new journey towards d-bus programming and chose pidgin as my companion. Found out that 2.2.0 has some serious d-bus issues on amd64 that were fixed in 2.</description></item><item><title>Wanted: A Good Paint Program For Linux</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/03/wanted-a-good-paint-program-for-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2008 12:47:23 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/03/wanted-a-good-paint-program-for-linux/</guid><description>Have been in the hunt for a good basic paint program for linux for so long. I'm running a Ubuntu Feisty Fawn (amd64) box (yeah, yeah I didn't upgrade to Gutsy because it sneaked up too quickly onto me and the impending loom of LTS goodness of Hardy was also there). Have been suggested various things so far like GPaint, Kolourpaint, tuxpaint etc but none of them cuts it.
Don't get me wrong, I love GIMP but its an overkill when I have to go through 2 menus, a dialogue box and several clicks, just to make a silly rectangle, but I don't hold anything against it cuz afterall its an &amp;ldquo;Image Manipulation&amp;rdquo; program, not a painting one.</description></item><item><title>Breaking News: Handsolo - A Revolution In The Mobile Phone Industry?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/01/breaking-news-handsolo-a-revolution-in-the-mobile-phone-industry/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 14:49:35 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/01/breaking-news-handsolo-a-revolution-in-the-mobile-phone-industry/</guid><description>Qualcomm wets it feet again in the ice-cold/boiling-hot mixture of a sea that our Mobile Phone Industry is. They decided that the all the phone makers around the globe are just churning out junk upon the unsuspecting people. Claiming to take the bull by its horns, and revolutionizing the world that whirls around it, the touted features are:
No Battery Required
Unlimited Expandable Memory
Completely Waterproof</description></item><item><title>Gawd Damnit!! South Park Episodes Go Online</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/29/gawd-damnit-south-park-episodes-go-online/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2008 20:38:55 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/29/gawd-damnit-south-park-episodes-go-online/</guid><description>Trey and Matt had talked about it a few days ago, that they were tired of downloding their own show South Park illegally. So, here it is folks. A fully revamped South Park Studios that, among other things, features full streaming of ALL the southpark episodes so far, yes that includes the latest season as well. Whats even better is that I find the quality of these even better than the ones that I downloaded earlier.</description></item><item><title>WordPress 2.5 RC3 Released: Without Even An Announcement</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/28/wordpress-25-rc3-released-without-even-an-announcement/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2008 19:31:04 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/28/wordpress-25-rc3-released-without-even-an-announcement/</guid><description>**Update: **I guess they didn't announce it because they were about to release the final thing. Yes, WordPress 2.5 final has been released and even WordPress.org has undergone a total revamp to match the release.
Yes, I just downloaded it through WordPress.org though can’t find it being mentioned anywhere on WordPress Development Blog. Did they forget to announce it or somebody over at Automattic put up the link by mistake. Anyways, if you want to get it at the earliest as well, head over to the WordPress Release Archive and look at the very bottom of the page.</description></item><item><title>Free Domain, Free Webhosting from Microsoft</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/27/free-domain-free-webhosting-from-microsoft/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2008 16:13:29 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/27/free-domain-free-webhosting-from-microsoft/</guid><description>Microsoft is doling out a lot of free stuff today. If you have a Live ID, or have the patience of 5 minutes to fill up a small form to create a new one, you can get free domain name as well as free webhosting from then for one complete year. Cool, huh? All you need to do is click here.
A word of caution: Unless you are creating a new website just for kicks, you might want to check out the terms and conditions properly because I'm not sure whether you can transfer the domain name to some other provider after the one year is over.</description></item><item><title>Windows Mobile: Missed Call Made Easy (Indian Cell Owners Rejoice)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/18/windows-mobile-missed-call-made-easy-indian-cell-owners-rejoice/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2008 15:12:34 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/18/windows-mobile-missed-call-made-easy-indian-cell-owners-rejoice/</guid><description>Perdida = Missed Call (in Spanish)
Missed Call = Ubiquitous Necessity (atleast in India)
Enter: cPerdidas -&amp;gt; A Windows Mobile program (works with WM5 as well as WM6) that will allow you to make missed calls to anyone you desire. Just config your country code, select the contact and &amp;ldquo;Hacer Perdida!&amp;rdquo; (Make the missed call) and your contact will get the missed call on his device. The only change is that the program will cut the call even before he can hear his phone ring.</description></item><item><title>Shantz Copy Basket</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/16/shantz-cp-basket/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2008 13:08:46 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/16/shantz-cp-basket/</guid><description>Introduction:
I’m sure you have copied/moved files on your computer from one place to another. And I’m sure often you have to do more than just “single-shot” copying that is copy a few files to one place, move a few to another, and copy yet some more to one more location. Well, I had to do this quite a few times (e.g. I ran out of disk space recently on a partition and had to empty out my “Movies” and “Songs” folders to move a few movies/songs each to all other partitions/disks according to the space available).</description></item><item><title>Caution: "Network Solutions", Stay As Far As Possible</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/14/caution-network-solutions-stay-as-far-as-possible/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2008 20:56:23 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/14/caution-network-solutions-stay-as-far-as-possible/</guid><description>If you had a dream of starting your own website, your online abode, and you wanted to see whether the pretty little name for your dream house is available or not, what do you do? Check its availability on one of the many domain sellers&amp;rsquo; sites. And if you picked &amp;ldquo;Network Solutions&amp;rdquo; to do the search, then you have just been scammed my dear friend.
Did you wonder, that though Network Solutions showed the domain name as available, but yet when you searched and found a cheaper registrar, the domain name was suddenly…GONE.</description></item><item><title>Chinese LionKing800 cellphone claims 1-year standby</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/13/chinese-lionking800-cellphone-claims-1-year-standby/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2008 17:30:44 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/13/chinese-lionking800-cellphone-claims-1-year-standby/</guid><description>Even though they are using a battery with 10 times the juice of a normal one, but still the claim is impressive on 2 counts acc to me:
The size of the battery &amp;ldquo;seems&amp;rdquo; to be not that big for having 10 times the mAs.
Even with this battery, 1 year of standby and 3 days of talk time is impressive.
But one term spoils it all for me, &amp;ldquo;vaporware&amp;rdquo;, anyone?</description></item><item><title>Indian Govt. vs Blackberry: Yet Another Example of Idiocy From Our "Leaders"</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/12/indian-govt-vs-blackberry-yet-another-example-of-idiocy-from-our-leaders/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2008 19:45:48 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/12/indian-govt-vs-blackberry-yet-another-example-of-idiocy-from-our-leaders/</guid><description>Just read on BGR, that RIM will have to close down its BlackBerry service in India if they don't allow our government to snoop on every little piece of data that goes through it. WTF? On an even more serious note, if they do comply, then will the same demand be made to all the ISPs? I just shudder at the mere thought of this…Quotin BGR below
It looks as if the Indian government is not content with its inability to decrypt their citizens BlackBerry e-mails, and is threatening a shutdown of Research In Motion's devices in the country as punishment.</description></item><item><title>I Heart Canon</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/10/i-heart-canon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2008 15:23:59 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/10/i-heart-canon/</guid><description>A gaping mouth was all I had when my 3 year ol&amp;rsquo; Canon Powershot S1 IS's LCD/EVF went blank all of a sudden a few months ago. Nothing could be seen, clicking the picture button resulted in blank pics. Googling about it revealed an advisory by Canon, stating that it is a known issue with the CCD image sensor. Canon impressed me by that notice when they said they will fix it for free, even for cameras out of warranty period, and will also pay to-and-fro shipping.</description></item><item><title>TIP: Automating Website Backups - Part III (Cron Made Easy)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/04/tip-automating-website-backups-part-iii-cron-made-easy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2008 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/04/tip-automating-website-backups-part-iii-cron-made-easy/</guid><description>The question that we will be answering today is: **Q2: **Cron? Using tar, making up the script file is enough command line for me. Isn’t there an easy way? Cron is a tool that can schedule any kind of tasks for you, and here we are using it to run our backup script automatically, so that we can concentrate on blogging. Now, most of us are phobic of anything that has anything to do with command line.</description></item><item><title>Games: Wormux Reporting to Action, SIR!!!</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/03/games-wormux-reporting-to-action-sir/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2008 03:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/03/games-wormux-reporting-to-action-sir/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Alpha to Bravo, over. Come in, Bravo, over.. We are under attack, over.. Send reinforcements asap. over and out&amp;rdquo;.
Well, if you dream about conversing like this, then you are better off playing something like COD4 or BF2, but if you are into a little bit less intense military warfare, and are a fan of games like worms, tanks, etc (I'm a convicted Worms World Party addict on my HTC Wizard) then you are in for countless fun-filled, sleepless nights.</description></item><item><title>Linux: Webcam Fun</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/02/linux-webcam-fun/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2008 03:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/02/linux-webcam-fun/</guid><description>If you thought that a webcam is just for getting in visual touch with your distant friends, then you could not be more wrong. There are many other uses e.g., making videos, rudimentary security systems, etc. But I didn't know that it'd be as simple as a a few keystrokes and a couple of clicks, until I stumbled across this article on Linux.com - Five fun ways to use a Linux webcam.</description></item><item><title>Idea Factory: Some Of My Latest Musings</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/01/idea-factory-some-of-my-latest-wonderings/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 03:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/01/idea-factory-some-of-my-latest-wonderings/</guid><description>jeffro2pt0 has a little contest going on his blog, giving out coupons to wpdesigners.com which lets you get atleast 12 WordPress themes for just 5$. Only thing you have to do is give a unique idea that could help improve wordpress. Now, I don’t want anymore themes (actually I’m a cheap-skate who can’t spend even 5$ for a theme, unless one of you decides to get me one ), but I got a few ideas instantly.</description></item><item><title>WordPress Must Have Plugins: Download Managers</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/29/wordpress-must-have-plugins-download-managers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Feb 2008 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/29/wordpress-must-have-plugins-download-managers/</guid><description>If you serve any kind of files for download on your WordPress blog(s), one thing you should definitly be looking out for is a download manager plugin. Post attachments are oh-so-2007. Uploading files to your server and hand-posting links everywhere is a pain in the butt. And what about your hunger for statistics?
Well, if you agree with me, then i would like to tell you about two fantastic plugins:</description></item><item><title>One Month Completed....</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/28/one-month-completed/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 04:10:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/28/one-month-completed/</guid><description>Today, this blog completes one month of its existence in this world. The achievements, although minuscule in comparison to all the biggies out there, are significant for me. It achieved the following things in just 30 days from the first post:
Front-paged at LifeHacker, HacksZine, and many others.
Over 10000 (Ten Thousand) &amp;ldquo;unique&amp;rdquo; human visitors.
Over 30000 (Thirty Thousand) page views by humans.
Over 500000 (Half Million) total hits for all website files included.</description></item><item><title>HTC Video Drivers: But This Is Not A Post About HTC</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/26/htc-video-drivers-but-this-is-not-a-post-about-htc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 11:14:36 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/26/htc-video-drivers-but-this-is-not-a-post-about-htc/</guid><description>This is a post about irresponsible/careless journalism/bloggism. For Gizmodo, getting that post about HTC’s latest press release out the door took precedence over actually **reading **the release properly and then commenting over it. The gizmodo poster’s comment is:
……but HTC's finally released a statement saying that a fix is coming. They say that the video acceleration will be supported in the future, and will be included in software upgrades for current devices…….</description></item><item><title>HollowMan Redux: Google Presents Gmail Users the Invisibility Cloak</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/25/hollowman-redux-google-presents-gmail-users-the-invisibility-cloak/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2008 18:53:20 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/25/hollowman-redux-google-presents-gmail-users-the-invisibility-cloak/</guid><description>Google gave us a nice little present today. The power to be all-seeing but yet still remaining unseen. Yes, now you can be “invisible” in your gmail chat session.
But beware, don’t fire up your gtalk, or you will again be as visible as a 100 watt bulb in a 4x4 room at night.</description></item><item><title>X-Men Are Here, Only That They Are In Your Hands</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/25/x-men-are-here-only-that-they-are-in-your-hands/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2008 14:50:23 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/25/x-men-are-here-only-that-they-are-in-your-hands/</guid><description>Who wouldn’t agree that Morph is most probably the coolest mutant (besides Wolverine of of course ). Now, it seems that the Finnish Giant Nokia has a lot of X-Men lovers as well, as they put out their latest offering to us lesser mortals. They call it “The Morph Concept”.
Featured in The Museum of Modern Art “Design and The Elastic Mind” exhibition, the Morph concept device is a bridge between highly advanced technologies and their potential benefits to end-users.</description></item><item><title>Project: shantz-wp-qotd Updated and shantz-wp-prefix-suffix released</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/24/project-shantz-wp-qotd-updated-and-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-released/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2008 09:44:24 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/24/project-shantz-wp-qotd-updated-and-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-released/</guid><description>I updated my wordpress plugin shantz-wp-qotd. (A feature rich, customizable wordpress quotes plugin) today to version 1.2.0. The new version has the following changes:
Added option to exclude pages from displaying quotes
Fixed a bug that quotes source selection checkboxes always remain checked after updating settings.
Cosmetic: Fixed a few spelling mistakes :)</description></item><item><title>Shantz WordPress Prefix Suffix</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/23/shantz-wordpress-prefix-suffix/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2008 21:38:39 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/23/shantz-wordpress-prefix-suffix/</guid><description>Shantz WP Prefix Suffix
== Description ==
Shantz WP Prefix Suffix is a light-weight and easy to use plugin which allows you to add any text and/or HTML/CSS code to your posts and/or pages as prefix (top / beginning), middle and/or suffix (bottom /end). (That includes even any new or old posts and pages and even your feed) Examples of use cases could be to include your copyright message, advertisements (like adsense, etc), permalinks, your other site links, any other custom messages.</description></item><item><title>Site Updates</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/22/site-updates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2008 05:05:04 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/22/site-updates/</guid><description>The site received a lot of new visitors yesterday as one of the small-time things that I do, received front page treatment at lifehacker. Thank you, Adam Pash, and thanks Murphy, for the original idea.</description></item><item><title>shantz-csv-to-opml</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/22/shantz-csv-to-opml/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2008 04:53:53 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/22/shantz-csv-to-opml/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION
This is a very simple script that I did for a friend. It can be used to quickly generate blogrolls.
Input: csv file with blog author names and blog links
Output: OPML file that can be imported into many blogging/blogrolling software and websites (e.g. wordpress, blogrolling.com, etc)
Usage:
shantz-csv-to-opml.pl &amp;lt;input file in csv format&amp;gt; &amp;lt;output opml filename&amp;gt; Input File Format: Each line should be like this: &amp;lt;Name of Author&amp;gt;,&amp;lt;bloglink&amp;gt;,&amp;lt;bloglink&amp;gt;... e.</description></item><item><title>Project: Retrieve Files From Remote Computer Through E-mail</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/19/project-retrieve-files-from-remote-computer-through-e-mail/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2008 17:52:16 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/19/project-retrieve-files-from-remote-computer-through-e-mail/</guid><description>I came across this post on lifehacker today (original post and solution here), which talks about a method of retrieving files from a remote computer through e-mail. Pretty archaic, I know, but again, it is a very simple method and works behind all the firewalls and stuff . But, the catch is that it is only for mac’s. Thought of creating something similar for the PC and mashed together some code during lunch time at office to make our dear old outlook remote-file-sending-capable.</description></item><item><title>Remote File Access Through E-Mail</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/19/remote-file-access-through-e-mail/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2008 17:43:30 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/19/remote-file-access-through-e-mail/</guid><description>Introduction:
This is a (proof-of-concept) outlook macro that you can use with an outlook rule to retrieve your files from your home/office PC by sending it a mail with a subject having a predefined special keyword and the body containing the names and paths of the files. The remote PC will then mail you the files on a predefined e-mail ID.
This project came into being after reading this post at lifehacker (original post and solution here).</description></item><item><title>Boring Meetings? CallJockey To The Rescue</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/19/boring-meetings-calljockey-to-the-rescue/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2008 04:43:19 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/19/boring-meetings-calljockey-to-the-rescue/</guid><description>Stuck in another boring meeting? You have a way out now, because connectivetools have released their app CallJockey, which can simulate fake incoming calls. What's more, you can select the name, phone number or one of your saved contacts from whom the fake call will appear to be coming, plus you can define the time when you want it to ring. The only limitation is that it is available only for WM5 smarphones (WM6 Standard), i.</description></item><item><title>Engineer: A New Definition</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/14/engineer-a-new-definition/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2008 17:06:12 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/14/engineer-a-new-definition/</guid><description>Came across this funny, but still thought provoking, definition of an engineer.
(Taken from “The Embedded Muse”, a useful embedded stuff related newsletter published by Jack Ganssel.)
“An engineer is a person who passes as an exacting expert on the basis of being able to turn out with prolific fortitude infinite strings of incomprehensible formulas calculated with micrometric precision from vague assumptions which are based on debatable figures taken from inconclusive experiments carried out with instruments of problematical accuracy by persons of questionable mentality and doubtful reliability for the avowed purpose of annoying and confusing a hopelessly chimerical group of esoteric fanatics referred to altogether too frequently as technicians.</description></item><item><title>SmartPhones/NextGen Telephony: News That Matters</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/14/smartphonesnextgen-telephony-news-that-matters/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2008 05:08:10 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/14/smartphonesnextgen-telephony-news-that-matters/</guid><description>Just wanted to share some pieces that generated a variety of &amp;ldquo;hmmm&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;ahaa&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;wow&amp;rdquo; from me:
China Mobile set to trial LTE:
China Mobile said it will join Vodafone Group plc and Verizon Wireless in an ongoing trial of LTE technology…….The trials &amp;ndash; which include three powerhouse network operators &amp;ndash; underscore the momentum LTE is gaining as a leading 4G technology possibility vs. WiMAX and Ultra Mobile Broadband.
&amp;ldquo;HMMM&amp;rdquo; - U go LTE!</description></item><item><title>Shantz WordPress QOTD</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/10/shantz-wordpress-qotd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 10:22:57 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/10/shantz-wordpress-qotd/</guid><description>Shantz WP QOTD is a plugin to add quotes to your wordpress blog in a few easy clicks. It adds quotes to your posts and your sidebars with a multitude of options for sources and customization.
== Description ==
There are many quotes plugins out there. This one has been started with a view to have the best of features and options, ease of use and multiple sources to get the quotes from.</description></item><item><title>Nokia + Windows Mobile = Let's Kick Some &lt;InsertWMPhoneMakerName> Butt</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/08/nokia-windows-mobile-lets-kick-some-butt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2008 05:00:58 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/08/nokia-windows-mobile-lets-kick-some-butt/</guid><description>As everyone knows, I’m an out-and-out Windows Mobile worshipper. It’s like a girlfriend, who is very difficult to manage and understand at first, but is a great source of joy if you know how to manage her. I don’t like any other phones now; the extensibility given by WM will do that to you.
I also “admire” Nokia because of the quality and reliability they provide with their phones. Having worked for them in a project (Nokia Networks/Nokia Seimens Networks actually), I know how much testing they put in before releasing something.</description></item><item><title>Tips: Configure FTP upload support for wordpress in Blogjet</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/07/tips-configure-ftp-upload-support-for-wordpress-in-blogjet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2008 14:36:27 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/07/tips-configure-ftp-upload-support-for-wordpress-in-blogjet/</guid><description>A few days ago, I had written about a wonderful blogging tool Blogjet. Now, if you host a wordpress blog, you’d be aware of the fact that for wordpress to be able to upload yor files (images, attachements in post etc) to the server, you have to make the upload directory writable by all. Now, this is a BIG security risk. Some people go to the lengths of CHMOD’ding their upload directory for a short while and after upload, restoring the apt file permissions back.</description></item><item><title>i3theme awesomeness: Cool feature for end-users/viewers</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/06/i3theme-awesomeness-cool-feature-for-end-usersviewers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2008 04:42:02 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/06/i3theme-awesomeness-cool-feature-for-end-usersviewers/</guid><description>I am just in love with this theme. I knew about the cool feature that you can click on those little green dots on the right top corner of any widget and the widget will minimize to just a bar but just now discovered another awesome feature for the viewers of the wordpress based blogs using this theme. The feature is that you, the viewer, can reorganize the widgets on the left and right sidebars according to your preference, like move the “Pages” widget towards the top for convenient navigation through all the static pages in the site.</description></item><item><title>Hack: Wordpress i3theme IE6 sidebar problem solved</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/04/hack-wordpress-i3theme-ie6-sidebar-problem-solved/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2008 14:51:21 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/04/hack-wordpress-i3theme-ie6-sidebar-problem-solved/</guid><description>The awesome i3theme that this blog uses is a treat to the eyes, except to a lot of IE6 users. The issue is that for many people viewing wordpress blogs using this theme, the right sidebar doesn't appear on the right, but **below **the middle column main area.
I didn't know this problem existed as I don't use IE but when a friend mailed to let me know, I started hunting around for the solution.</description></item><item><title>Project: ShantzTodayChanger (Windows Mobile Tool To Cycle Themes/Wallpapers Automatically)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/project-shantztodaychanger-windows-mobile-tool-to-cycle-themeswallpapers-automatically/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 19:45:07 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/project-shantztodaychanger-windows-mobile-tool-to-cycle-themeswallpapers-automatically/</guid><description>The newly launched [&amp;ldquo;Projects&amp;rdquo;] section is hereby inaugarated with a Windows Mobile Tool developed by me, called “[ShantzTodayChanger]”. This is a little tool for your Windows Mobile based phones (Compatible with WM5/WM6 but not WM2003) which will cycle ur today background or theme after a set interval of time. It has a lot of features and options that you can discover by reading the text below. And you can even use this options to achieve something other than changing wallpapers as well but that depends on your imagination.</description></item><item><title>Site Updates: More Content For You</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/site-updates-more-content-for-you/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 19:36:42 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/site-updates-more-content-for-you/</guid><description>I've added a few new sections to the blog. Do check them out. Here is a list of the new sections along with their descriptions.
[Projects]: Although I wouldn't put myself in the category of an excellent developer but I can sure type in a few lines that can compile without an error and also manage to carry out a task or two. So, this page will list some of those little things that I write to weed out a few niggles or scratch a few itches of mine.</description></item><item><title>ShantzTodayChanger</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/shantztodaychanger/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 13:41:30 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/shantztodaychanger/</guid><description>Intro:
This is a little tool for your Windows Mobile based phones (Compatible with WM5/WM6 but not WM2003) which will cycle ur today background or theme after a set interval of time. It has a lot of features and options that you can discover by reading the text below. And you can even use this options to achieve something other than changing wallpapers as well but that depends on your imagination.</description></item><item><title>Ubuntu Nuggets: Window list settings in panel</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/01/ubuntu-nuggets-window-list-settings-in-panel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 19:06:13 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/01/ubuntu-nuggets-window-list-settings-in-panel/</guid><description>I am pretty sure that all of you must be fed of that one windows taking up the whole task bar in the panel. Like this:
Well, you can change that. Plus, all you windows-to-linux converts must also be thinking of how to squeeze in a few more windows into the task bar. A &amp;ldquo;grouping of similar windows&amp;rdquo; option like windows would have been just nice. Well, that can be done too, and without any shell scripting, config file modifying, etc.</description></item><item><title>Windows Mobile 6 - Case of the Missing Calls: Solved</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/31/windows-mobile-6-case-of-the-missing-calls-solved/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2008 18:30:33 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/31/windows-mobile-6-case-of-the-missing-calls-solved/</guid><description>As the pic above says, it turned out to be quite elementary in the end. But what is &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rdquo; actually?
The Problem: Since the beginning of time (read launching of WM6), millions of WM users (ok ok, will not exaggerate from now on) have been facing a very peculiar issue. The issue is that people tell them all the time that they are avoiding those people, and not taking their calls.</description></item><item><title>WM6.1 Is Here, Loves HTC Wizard...(Really?)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/31/wm61-is-here-loves-htc-wizardreally/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2008 05:54:42 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/31/wm61-is-here-loves-htc-wizardreally/</guid><description>A user going by the remarkably simple handle &amp;ldquo;email123&amp;rdquo; announced on the xda-developers forum, that WM6.1 is here, alive and kicking. But he doesn't stop there, he says that its available &amp;ldquo;now&amp;rdquo;, that too for an HTC wizard, a 3 year old phone (which I own as well). Thats not all, he goes on to provide the proof by linking in his cooked ROM for all to download. But, here is the clincher, he claims that finally &amp;ldquo;Big Storage&amp;rdquo; is available for wizard, a feat noone has been able to achieve in the last 3 years.</description></item><item><title>All Your Base Are Belong To Us - Says Dell</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/30/all-your-base-are-belong-to-us-says-dell/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2008 18:27:55 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/30/all-your-base-are-belong-to-us-says-dell/</guid><description>Ask any laptop user about how much he liked to kick some butt in Gears of War and he would cringe and cry with agony even before you are able to say the &amp;ldquo;C&amp;rdquo; of Crysis. But not anymore. For its notebook consumers, Dell has finally come up with the perfect answer to the questions posed by these ridiculously-difficult-to-get-more-than-10-fps games. Available now is some motherly love for your laps in the form of 8800M GTX with its M1730.</description></item><item><title>BlogJet - Blog Faster, Blog Better (Now In Linux too, with a hidden bonus)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/29/blogjet-blog-faster-blog-better-now-in-linux-too-with-a-hidden-bonus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2008 15:30:27 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/29/blogjet-blog-faster-blog-better-now-in-linux-too-with-a-hidden-bonus/</guid><description>[](/img/uploads/blogjet_in_linux.png)
A quick googling for best desktop blogging client would yield just a few (read millions/gazillions) results. Having researched the subject a lot, my choices were finally limited down to BlogJet and BlogDesk, as per my feature set requirement goes (Primarily, off line editing, draft, WYSIWYG editing, categories, tagging support, pinging, trackbacks support, timestamping, past post editing, automatic image uploading) BUT there is one little problem. Both of these don’t work on Linux.</description></item><item><title>Beware of Fake Nokia N95 Cell Phones, Pirated by Chinese</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/29/beware-of-fake-nokia-n95-cell-phones-pirated-by-chinese/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2008 09:15:32 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/29/beware-of-fake-nokia-n95-cell-phones-pirated-by-chinese/</guid><description>Came across this post today, now even your N95’s aren’t safe. Make sure to check this guide to identify if your latest boy-toy is a fake or not.
Beware of Fake Nokia N95 Cell Phones, Pirated by Chinese.</description></item><item><title>Looking for a Host - For a Party that you will throw</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/28/looking-for-a-host-for-a-party-that-you-will-throw/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2008 16:31:52 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/28/looking-for-a-host-for-a-party-that-you-will-throw/</guid><description>One thing that is most difficult to choose (after a dress for your girlfriend that doesn't make her &amp;ldquo;look&amp;rdquo; fat) is choosing a webhost. A google search is going to even confuse you further. As you wade into this enormous ocean, you will be wowed by the offers given by some of these hosts, throwing away 100's of GBs (no less) of disk space and bandwidth running into terrabytes. Almost every software on earth in your one-click fantastico arsenal.</description></item><item><title>AMD (ATi) Step Up The Tempo</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/28/amd-ati-step-up-the-tempo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2008 16:01:45 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/28/amd-ati-step-up-the-tempo/</guid><description>AMD has been taking a lot of flak lately in its processor business, and a similar (albeit milder) thrashing was being given to its ATi Gfx line up as well. But they seem to be on the recover track now, with the release of the brand spanking new HD3870X2 series, some people aptly calling it &amp;ldquo;crossfire on a card&amp;rdquo;. All you gamers, please stop drooling on the screen now, and check out some benchmarks.</description></item><item><title>HTC - The best windows mobile "business unit"</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/28/htc-the-best-windows-mobile-business-unit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2008 15:26:02 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/28/htc-the-best-windows-mobile-business-unit/</guid><description>For the very post of this blog, I chose a subject that's close to my heart. Yes, its Windows Mobile. My trusted 900/1800 MHZ companion for the past couple of years is an HTC Wizard. If you have ever looked into the WinMob world, its pretty much common knowledge that HTC owns the 95% of market share of this niche little space. They are a huge organization and with huge profits and they do make jolly good phones.</description></item></channel></rss>