<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>google on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/google/</link><description>Recent content in google on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2011 20:23:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/google/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SGX 543MP2 vs Mali-400: Is iPhone 4S GPU Really Twice As Strong As SGS 2?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/10/05/sgx-543mp2-vs-mali-400-is-iphone-4s-gpu-really-twice-as-strong-as-sgs-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2011 20:23:23 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/10/05/sgx-543mp2-vs-mali-400-is-iphone-4s-gpu-really-twice-as-strong-as-sgs-2/</guid><description>Ever since Apple announced the iPhone 4S having &amp;ldquo;A5&amp;rdquo; processor, everyone has been pointing to the below image from a test run by Anandtech and saying that the iPhone 4S will be twice as strong as the Samsung Galaxy S2. I beg to differ.
While the above test doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any discrepancy, one major thing is that the SGX 543MP2 results are from an iPad 2 (a tablet) while the Mali 400 results are from a smartphone.</description></item><item><title>Deconstructing The Samsung Nexus Prime Video</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/10/05/deconstructing-the-samsung-nexus-prime-video/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2011 05:59:28 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/10/05/deconstructing-the-samsung-nexus-prime-video/</guid><description>Samsung just uploaded a teaser video to Youtube which hints at the upcoming Android phone Nexus Prime with IceCream Sandwich. It has a sideways glance at what people believe is the Nexus Prime. I&amp;rsquo;ll deconstruct the image a bit.
The things to take away from here:
The phone will have a curved display like Nexus S
It has a power button on the side (right side, since it&amp;rsquo;s marked with the power icon)</description></item><item><title>Adding Lyrics to SharkZapper for Grooveshark</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/09/23/adding-lyrics-to-sharkzapper-for-grooveshark/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2011 09:12:06 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/09/23/adding-lyrics-to-sharkzapper-for-grooveshark/</guid><description>I bet all of you know about grooveshark, the awesome music service. And sharkzapper is a cool chrome extension that puts the control and information about anything playing in your grooveshark chrome tab into a little button on the address bar. It is a very good extension but I felt that what it was missing was lyrics. Before I could comment on the extension&amp;rsquo;s chrome market page, I noticed that it has a github repository.</description></item><item><title>Chrome Script/Extension installation error: Could not read source file</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/09/19/chrome-scriptextension-installation-error-could-not-read-source-file/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2011 16:58:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/09/19/chrome-scriptextension-installation-error-could-not-read-source-file/</guid><description>This is a solution to the issue that I faced today while installing a javascript file from userscripts.org as an extension into google chrome (Yes, Chrome supports installing greasemonkey javascripts as extensions). I had already installed this script once into my browser earlier but when I tried installing it again today, it started giving me a weird error &amp;ldquo;Could not read source file&amp;rdquo;. I tried all possible means, like putting it on a different server, installing from local disk, changing versions, deleting all cache, etc but still the issue persisted.</description></item><item><title>Google Music Beta Latest APK version 3.0.1 for Android</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/05/27/google-music-latest-apk-android-3-0-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 03:57:10 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/05/27/google-music-latest-apk-android-3-0-1/</guid><description>Google just released the latest version of its Music app that ties into its cloud player service Music Beta. This brings the version upto 3.0.1 and adds a lot of fixes, crashes a lot less and now even works on Samsung Galaxy S with Gingerbread which was broken earlier. If you are outside the US and not able to download the app from the market, then download it from here:http://www.multiupload.com/KIM5LQDL0K</description></item><item><title>Use Encrypted Google Search As Default in Chrome</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/05/12/use-encrypted-google-search-as-default-in-chrome/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 04:26:21 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/05/12/use-encrypted-google-search-as-default-in-chrome/</guid><description>Google just launched an encrypted search portal which is a Godsend for people on public networks since there is a lot that can be gleaned from your search queries. For doing your protected searches, however, you have to go to a different portal which I linked to above. Now, the omnibar (the address bar in Google Chrome) also serves as a search box but searches on the normal google portal by default.</description></item><item><title>Google to abandon Android. Spin off separate company</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/04/01/google-to-abandon-android-spin-off-separate-company/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 07:03:06 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/04/01/google-to-abandon-android-spin-off-separate-company/</guid><description>Now, this is mind blowing. I&amp;rsquo;ve just talked to a pretty reliable source within the Android ranks of Google that Google is going to distance itself legally from Android and spin it off in a separate company. The source said that the move can happen very soon and may be announced at Google I/O conference in May. Although details are sketchy and only very few high profile folks know about it within Google, my source says that the probable reason is increasing worries about legal aspects of Android with respect to Patents and IP law suits.</description></item><item><title>ZDNet Fail. Answer is Stop Tech Blogging</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/11/19/zdnet-fail-answer-is-stop-tech-blogging/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2010 15:45:04 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/11/19/zdnet-fail-answer-is-stop-tech-blogging/</guid><description>Just read this article over at zdnet. What it basically says is condensed in these two points:
Android is a failure for Google because it is open and carriers/OEMs are stripping off google search from it and putting replacements like baidu/Bing. (BTW, half the people say Android is fail because it is not open and the other half say it is fail because it is open. Which one is it, please decide ;) )</description></item><item><title>Is Android Open Source Or Not?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/25/android-open-source-or-not/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 11:31:06 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/25/android-open-source-or-not/</guid><description>Is Android really open source or not? That is the question being asked by almost everyone. A lot of people, especially those influenced by RDF or those who are in the news industry with no idea about OS and open source but were asked by their boss to get a scoop on this pronto, tend to bring up a few keywords and then twist them around in the way they see fit to make sure it says Android isn&amp;rsquo;t open.</description></item><item><title>Solving The Android Permissions And Malware Puzzle</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/13/android-permissions-malware/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2010 19:44:59 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/13/android-permissions-malware/</guid><description>There has been a spate of security reports recently about Android apps being malware or suspicious. Most of these were found baseless but at least one was indeed correct (e.g. The Russian Trojan app). We also know that Android has a very good security model but even then, the rest of the reports also makes one think and focus on why an apps requires the permissions that it states it needs?</description></item><item><title>Android vs iPhone: Security Models</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/25/android-vs-iphone-security-models/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2010 22:02:49 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/25/android-vs-iphone-security-models/</guid><description>Android and iPhone OS (iOS) have been at loggerheads for quite some time now. This is a take on which has a better security model to protect its users. I thought of writing it up because there have been a lot of discussions around me lately about which platform is more secure and I keep repeating the same points over and over at every one of them, so thought that in future I&amp;rsquo;ll just point them to this page :P</description></item><item><title>Android Froyo And Nexus One: Everything We Know</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/05/23/android-froyo-nexus-one/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2010 17:44:18 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/05/23/android-froyo-nexus-one/</guid><description>This is an effort from my side to consolidate everything about Android Froyo with respect to Nexus One. It is mainly concentrated towards listing the features/fixes that we have seen in Froyo that weren&amp;rsquo;t announced in Google I/O, things that work with nexus one, things that don&amp;rsquo;t and possible fixes/workarounds known, what the announced features actually feel like in real use etc.** Will keep updating this post as I get more info, get more fixes, etc.</description></item><item><title>Comments In Google Reader Shared Items Are Here</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/12/google-reader-shared-items-comments/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2009 05:00:22 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/12/google-reader-shared-items-comments/</guid><description>Since quite some time, Google Reader has included the feature to share interesting items with your friends who also use Google Reader. Some time back they also added the option to &amp;ldquo;Share with a Note&amp;rdquo; to add your take to the shared piece. But I always thought there was no way to share back by comments (or see my friends' take) about that particular article. One way could have been to post the comments on the original site of the article but that had the drawbacks that:</description></item><item><title>Call For Google Adsense Maths Class Charity Fund</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/23/call-for-google-adsense-maths-class-charity-fund/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2008 08:25:36 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/23/call-for-google-adsense-maths-class-charity-fund/</guid><description>I hereby call for setting up a charity fund so that we can donate some money to get the poor ol’ Google Adsense some Mathematics/Algebra 101 classes because apparantly it thinks that 0.63 + 0.07 = 0.69.</description></item><item><title>Project: Shantz-WP-Prefix-Suffix Updated to 1.1.0</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/20/project-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-to-110/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 04:08:17 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/20/project-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-to-110/</guid><description>Well, its not just prefix suffix any more, because I added an option to add things in the middle of the posts as well. I got this idea because people told me that this was one of the most sought after option as advertisements (e.g. google adsense, adbrite, etc) give maximum click through rate when placed smack dab in the middle of the content. What’s more is that it is configurable and you can choose how many paragraphs and/or words should be skipped from the start of the post before you add whatever you want, be it text, css, html, php or javascript.</description></item><item><title>Google Adsense : Conflict of Interests?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/07/google-adsense-conflict-of-interests/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2008 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/07/google-adsense-conflict-of-interests/</guid><description>“Google Adsense” has been caught in a conflict of interests with its parent company “Google”. Google piad 140k to teh cause of “Say No to Prop 8” but on the other hand people reported that Google Adsense delivered a substantially huge amount of “Say Yes to Prop 8” advertisements all over the internet, even on sites which are completely out of context with this matter. Not only is this conflicting with the interests of the parent company but also with the “Terms of Use” put forward by Adsense that ads should not have any kind of intolerance or advocacy towards an individual or a group.</description></item><item><title>Google Releases Android Source Code</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/21/google-releases-android-source-code/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2008 17:57:52 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/21/google-releases-android-source-code/</guid><description>FOSS (Free and Open Source Software) community rejoices today as google finally lived upto their promise of releasing the android source code. Now, the things that is left to be evaluated is that how much of it is actually true, or whether there are some binary blobs still in there. Moreover, it remains to be seen that how much this converts into a “community” project instead of being ruled by Google with an iron hand.</description></item><item><title>Android Devices Trickling In A Few Days Early?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/20/android-devices-trickling-in-a-few-days-early/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2008 19:32:35 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/20/android-devices-trickling-in-a-few-days-early/</guid><description>There is still a day left for the first Android based Device, T-Mobile G1, to come out into the hands of general public but I was in a for a small surprise as I went through my Google Analytics report for the last week. It had a mysterious number of 2 sitting at the bottom of my “Unique Visitors by Operating Systems” filter report. The “mysterious” part coming from the fact that the left most column displayed “Android”.</description></item><item><title>Firefox Incognito / Private Browsing Mode - Part II</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/11/firefox-incognito-private-browsing-mode-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2008 16:59:33 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/11/firefox-incognito-private-browsing-mode-part-ii/</guid><description>A few people (e.g. Varun) told me my previous post differed from the way how google chrome / Microsoft IE8 handle Incognito (Private Browsing) mode. The main consideration was that while chrome/IE8 don&amp;rsquo;t write anything to disk at all, the firefox method is an after-effect, i.e., writing to disk and then clearing it up while closing the window. Well, true but nothing is non-rectificable :). So this is a post about a method that one can use to go &amp;ldquo;really&amp;rdquo; undercover with firefox.</description></item><item><title>Firefox Incognito Mode Is Here: Move Over Chrome/IE8</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/10/firefox-incognito-mode-is-here-move-over-chromeie8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2008 17:49:41 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/10/firefox-incognito-mode-is-here-move-over-chromeie8/</guid><description>Update: Part 2 of this post is now up here to allay some of the drawbacks that were pointed out.
There has been so much hype over the “Incognito” (or Private Browsing) mode of Google Chrome / Microsoft IE8, with many internet users screeming Hallelujiah. But I don’t understand what the hoopla is all about. This mode has always been there in Mozilla firefox as well. You just need to devote less than one minute (yes, you read that right, less than one minute) to set it up.</description></item><item><title>Hack: Pidgin-Gtalk Connection Problems - Get Around The Corporate Firewall</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/08/hack-pidgin-gtalk-connection-problems-get-around-the-corporate-firewall/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 15:30:38 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/08/hack-pidgin-gtalk-connection-problems-get-around-the-corporate-firewall/</guid><description>I recently wrote a simple answering machine program/plugin for pidgin and someone asked me to port it to 32 bit. So I fired up pidgin within my virtual box installation at work (as I have only a 64 bit machine at home) but couldn&amp;rsquo;t get it to connect. Tried all sorts of methods found over the net of changing ports etc, set port forwarding in Virtual Box NAT, even switched to using a bridged host interface but still no go.</description></item><item><title>Google's New Favicon</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/30/googles-new-favicon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2008 19:16:21 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/30/googles-new-favicon/</guid><description>It’s amazing, isn’t it? Even a sneeze at google makes the headlines. Well, it’s not the sneeze today but the new favicon I just got. So, are you also seeing the all new, re-designed, artisticly polished “g” as the new favicon?
In other news, my Twitter-Webcam integration post has bypassed my earlier lifehacked post about Remote File Access Through E-mail by more than a few thousands, even though the time difference between the two posts is more than 3 months.</description></item><item><title>Page Rank 7: True Or Google Glitch?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/30/page-rank-7-true-or-google-glitch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2008 20:33:51 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/30/page-rank-7-true-or-google-glitch/</guid><description>I installed google toolbar (linux version) today in firefox and for this blog, it says that its page rank is 7. I can&amp;rsquo;t believe my eyes. I suppose it&amp;rsquo;s a google glitch may be (but have a wishful thinking at the back of mind that its true :-) ).
Are you getting the same result for this blog (or weird page rank results for other places that you frequent?)</description></item><item><title>HollowMan Redux: Google Presents Gmail Users the Invisibility Cloak</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/25/hollowman-redux-google-presents-gmail-users-the-invisibility-cloak/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2008 18:53:20 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/25/hollowman-redux-google-presents-gmail-users-the-invisibility-cloak/</guid><description>Google gave us a nice little present today. The power to be all-seeing but yet still remaining unseen. Yes, now you can be “invisible” in your gmail chat session.
But beware, don’t fire up your gtalk, or you will again be as visible as a 100 watt bulb in a 4x4 room at night.</description></item><item><title>SmartPhones/NextGen Telephony: News That Matters</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/14/smartphonesnextgen-telephony-news-that-matters/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2008 05:08:10 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/14/smartphonesnextgen-telephony-news-that-matters/</guid><description>Just wanted to share some pieces that generated a variety of &amp;ldquo;hmmm&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;ahaa&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;wow&amp;rdquo; from me:
China Mobile set to trial LTE:
China Mobile said it will join Vodafone Group plc and Verizon Wireless in an ongoing trial of LTE technology…….The trials &amp;ndash; which include three powerhouse network operators &amp;ndash; underscore the momentum LTE is gaining as a leading 4G technology possibility vs. WiMAX and Ultra Mobile Broadband.
&amp;ldquo;HMMM&amp;rdquo; - U go LTE!</description></item><item><title>Looking for a Host - For a Party that you will throw</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/28/looking-for-a-host-for-a-party-that-you-will-throw/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2008 16:31:52 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/28/looking-for-a-host-for-a-party-that-you-will-throw/</guid><description>One thing that is most difficult to choose (after a dress for your girlfriend that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make her &amp;ldquo;look&amp;rdquo; fat) is choosing a webhost. A google search is going to even confuse you further. As you wade into this enormous ocean, you will be wowed by the offers given by some of these hosts, throwing away 100&amp;rsquo;s of GBs (no less) of disk space and bandwidth running into terrabytes. Almost every software on earth in your one-click fantastico arsenal.</description></item></channel></rss>