<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Google on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/google/</link><description>Recent content in Google on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2011 20:23:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/google/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SGX 543MP2 vs Mali-400: Is iPhone 4S GPU Really Twice As Strong As SGS 2?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/10/05/sgx-543mp2-vs-mali-400-is-iphone-4s-gpu-really-twice-as-strong-as-sgs-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2011 20:23:23 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/10/05/sgx-543mp2-vs-mali-400-is-iphone-4s-gpu-really-twice-as-strong-as-sgs-2/</guid><description>Ever since Apple announced the iPhone 4S having &amp;ldquo;A5&amp;rdquo; processor, everyone has been pointing to the below image from a test run by Anandtech and saying that the iPhone 4S will be twice as strong as the Samsung Galaxy S2. I beg to differ.
While the above test doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any discrepancy, one major thing is that the SGX 543MP2 results are from an iPad 2 (a tablet) while the Mali 400 results are from a smartphone.</description><content>&lt;p>Ever since Apple announced the iPhone 4S having &amp;ldquo;A5&amp;rdquo; processor, everyone has been pointing to the below image from a test run by Anandtech and saying that the iPhone 4S will be twice as strong as the Samsung Galaxy S2. I beg to differ.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/2011/10/anandtech-gpu-comparison-sgx543mp2-mali400-300x238.png" />
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>While the above test doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any discrepancy, one major thing is that the SGX 543MP2 results are from an iPad 2 (a tablet) while the Mali 400 results are from a smartphone. Thus, we can&amp;rsquo;t readily take this to directly and accurately predict the comparison results for iPhone 4S because there are other things to consider:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Mali-400 lags behing SGX543MP2 in &amp;ldquo;offscreen&amp;rdquo; tests which are done for resolutions greater than native SGS2 resolution (SGS 2 resolution is 800x480 while test is done at 720p) and brute triangle pushing. Samsung didn&amp;rsquo;t have to optimize their GPU implementation for this because SGS2 was never going to run a game at 720p resolution and would also need to push lesser triangles for similar detail. Hence they could easily make this trade-off to get lesser power consumption and heat generation&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Mali-400 goes hand in hand with SGX543MP2 in all other tests as seen on glbenchmark.com&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>It is naive to think that the same SGX543MP2 implementation as iPad 2 will be present in iPhone 4S. Even if iPhone 4S is slated to have &amp;ldquo;A5&amp;rdquo;, a lot depends on the actual clock speeds (CPU and GPU), graphics memory, etc. Apple will do similar trade offs like Samsung (and Apple has already done this with A4 in iPad 1 vs iPhone 4) and the real results would be available only then.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>So, the end result is that we will have the real comparison only when iPhone 4S is out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PS: Not that the results matter anyways :P since firstly, the comparisons should now be moving to upcoming Nexus Prime and not SGS2 and secondly, the raw power of these GPUs won&amp;rsquo;t determine much since they cater to two completely different OSs and would have a lot of software and ecosystem dependencies on the user-perceived outcome.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Deconstructing The Samsung Nexus Prime Video</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/10/05/deconstructing-the-samsung-nexus-prime-video/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2011 05:59:28 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/10/05/deconstructing-the-samsung-nexus-prime-video/</guid><description>Samsung just uploaded a teaser video to Youtube which hints at the upcoming Android phone Nexus Prime with IceCream Sandwich. It has a sideways glance at what people believe is the Nexus Prime. I&amp;rsquo;ll deconstruct the image a bit.
The things to take away from here:
The phone will have a curved display like Nexus S
It has a power button on the side (right side, since it&amp;rsquo;s marked with the power icon)</description><content>&lt;p>Samsung just uploaded a &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oM9RO-GAKjE">teaser video&lt;/a> to Youtube which hints at the upcoming Android phone &lt;strong>Nexus Prime&lt;/strong> with IceCream Sandwich. It has a sideways glance at what people believe is the Nexus Prime. I&amp;rsquo;ll deconstruct the image a bit.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/2011/10/samsung-nexus-prime-leak-1-300x158.jpg" />
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/2011/10/samsung-nexus-prime-leak-2-300x158.jpg" />
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>The things to take away from here:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The phone will have a curved display like Nexus S&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>It has a power button on the side (right side, since it&amp;rsquo;s marked with the power icon)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The interesting thing however is the 3 dots on the left side&lt;/strong>. People claim that it could be related to camera or volume controls or even speaker grills. But I think that they are for dock connection. Anyone who has owned a Nexus One has seen the same 3 gold dots on the bottom used for dock connection. I believe that on Nexus Prime they have been moved to the side mainly because Prime has (or is supposed to have) a 16:9 screen and hence the optimal placement in a dock would be horizontal and hence the sideways placement.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Let me know what you think :)&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Adding Lyrics to SharkZapper for Grooveshark</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/09/23/adding-lyrics-to-sharkzapper-for-grooveshark/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2011 09:12:06 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/09/23/adding-lyrics-to-sharkzapper-for-grooveshark/</guid><description>I bet all of you know about grooveshark, the awesome music service. And sharkzapper is a cool chrome extension that puts the control and information about anything playing in your grooveshark chrome tab into a little button on the address bar. It is a very good extension but I felt that what it was missing was lyrics. Before I could comment on the extension&amp;rsquo;s chrome market page, I noticed that it has a github repository.</description><content>&lt;p>I bet all of you know about grooveshark, the awesome music service. And sharkzapper is a cool chrome extension that puts the control and information about anything playing in your grooveshark chrome tab into a little button on the address bar. It is a very good extension but I felt that what it was missing was lyrics. Before I could comment on the extension&amp;rsquo;s chrome market page, I noticed that it has a github repository. &amp;ldquo;Open Source&amp;rdquo;, oh joy. So, I forked the repository and after some hacking around, I&amp;rsquo;ve now added support for automatic searching and fetching of the currently playing song into the sharkzapper popup window and it updates itself whenever the song changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What was even cooler that I learnt a bit about using YQL in the process :)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve sent in a pull request to the author of the extension to the original author of the extension to merge this code. In the meanwhile, if you would like to try this out, you can hit up my &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://github.com/shantanugoel/sharkzapper">github repository&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>, download the code and install into chrome by enabling developer mode and choosing &amp;ldquo;Load unpacked extension&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Happy listening :)&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Chrome Script/Extension installation error: Could not read source file</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/09/19/chrome-scriptextension-installation-error-could-not-read-source-file/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2011 16:58:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/09/19/chrome-scriptextension-installation-error-could-not-read-source-file/</guid><description>This is a solution to the issue that I faced today while installing a javascript file from userscripts.org as an extension into google chrome (Yes, Chrome supports installing greasemonkey javascripts as extensions). I had already installed this script once into my browser earlier but when I tried installing it again today, it started giving me a weird error &amp;ldquo;Could not read source file&amp;rdquo;. I tried all possible means, like putting it on a different server, installing from local disk, changing versions, deleting all cache, etc but still the issue persisted.</description><content>&lt;p>This is a solution to the issue that I faced today while installing a javascript file from userscripts.org as an extension into google chrome (Yes, Chrome supports installing greasemonkey javascripts as extensions). I had already installed this script once into my browser earlier but when I tried installing it again today, it started giving me a weird error &amp;ldquo;Could not read source file&amp;rdquo;. I tried all possible means, like putting it on a different server, installing from local disk, changing versions, deleting all cache, etc but still the issue persisted.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally looking into the source code of the chromium browser svn repository, I got a clue. What google chrome does when you install a script as installation is that it first downloads the script, then it calls a function ConvertUserScriptToExtension to convert the script into a google chrome compatible script and then installs it. Now, since I had already installed this script once, I found that the script was already existing in my downloads directory, so while downloading chrome renames it to &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->(1).js (i.e., appends a number to it to distinguish from the original file). But it seems like that the path sent to the conversion function still uses the original name/path and it somehow finds that the older file is not the downloaded one but also doesn&amp;rsquo;t know which is the current downloaded one and hence fails with an error &amp;ldquo;Could not read source file&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Solution: Pretty simple. Just delete the original file present in your download directory and then try installing the script and it will install fine :)&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Google Music Beta Latest APK version 3.0.1 for Android</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/05/27/google-music-latest-apk-android-3-0-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 03:57:10 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/05/27/google-music-latest-apk-android-3-0-1/</guid><description>Google just released the latest version of its Music app that ties into its cloud player service Music Beta. This brings the version upto 3.0.1 and adds a lot of fixes, crashes a lot less and now even works on Samsung Galaxy S with Gingerbread which was broken earlier. If you are outside the US and not able to download the app from the market, then download it from here:http://www.multiupload.com/KIM5LQDL0K</description><content>&lt;p>Google just released the latest version of its Music app  that ties into its cloud player service Music Beta. This brings the version upto 3.0.1 and adds a lot of fixes, crashes a lot less and now even works on Samsung Galaxy S with Gingerbread which was broken earlier. If you are outside the US and not able to download the app from the market, then download it from here:&lt;a href="http://www.multiupload.com/KIM5LQDL0K">http://www.multiupload.com/KIM5LQDL0K&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I just tried it on my Nexus One with Stock Gingerbread (2.3.4) and it works awesome. Picked up my music from the Google account immediately and even recognizes the third party equalizers like MusicFx&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to say Thanks ;)&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Use Encrypted Google Search As Default in Chrome</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/05/12/use-encrypted-google-search-as-default-in-chrome/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 04:26:21 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/05/12/use-encrypted-google-search-as-default-in-chrome/</guid><description>Google just launched an encrypted search portal which is a Godsend for people on public networks since there is a lot that can be gleaned from your search queries. For doing your protected searches, however, you have to go to a different portal which I linked to above. Now, the omnibar (the address bar in Google Chrome) also serves as a search box but searches on the normal google portal by default.</description><content>&lt;p>Google just launched an &lt;a href="https://encrypted.google.com/">encrypted search portal&lt;/a> which is a Godsend for people on public networks since there is a lot that can be gleaned from your search queries. For doing your protected searches, however, you have to go to a different portal which I linked to above. Now, the omnibar (the address bar in Google Chrome) also serves as a search box but searches on the normal google portal by default. Here is a simple, few seconds process to switch it over to encrypted search.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the wrench/tool icon at the top of Google Chrome and go to Options.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On the &amp;ldquo;Basics&amp;rdquo; tab, go to the &amp;ldquo;Search&amp;rdquo; item and click on &amp;ldquo;Manage Search Engines&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Go to the very bottom of the new page that opens and you will see three empty boxes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>For the first box (leftmost), give any nickname for the engine. I gave &amp;ldquo;EncryptedGoogle&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>For second box, give a keyword that invokes the new search engine. I gave &amp;ldquo;encrypted.google.com&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>For last box, give the url for the search engine. This should be&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;code>https://encrypted.google.com/search?{google:RLZ}{google:acceptedSuggestion}{google:originalQueryForSuggestion}sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie={inputEncoding}&amp;amp;q=%s&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="7">
&lt;li>Press Enter and the engine will be added to the list. Then hover over the engine row and click on &amp;ldquo;Make as default&amp;rdquo;. And you are done.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Happy safe searching :)&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Google to abandon Android. Spin off separate company</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/04/01/google-to-abandon-android-spin-off-separate-company/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 07:03:06 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/04/01/google-to-abandon-android-spin-off-separate-company/</guid><description>Now, this is mind blowing. I&amp;rsquo;ve just talked to a pretty reliable source within the Android ranks of Google that Google is going to distance itself legally from Android and spin it off in a separate company. The source said that the move can happen very soon and may be announced at Google I/O conference in May. Although details are sketchy and only very few high profile folks know about it within Google, my source says that the probable reason is increasing worries about legal aspects of Android with respect to Patents and IP law suits.</description><content>&lt;p>Now, this is mind blowing. I&amp;rsquo;ve just talked to a pretty reliable source within the Android ranks of Google that Google is going to distance itself &lt;strong>legally&lt;/strong> from Android and spin it off in a separate company. The source said that the move can happen very soon and may be announced at Google I/O conference in May. Although details are sketchy and only very few high profile folks know about it within Google, my source says that the probable reason is increasing worries about legal aspects of Android with respect to Patents and IP law suits. Google also doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to be held responsible by any of the OEMs using Android when they are targeted by these law suits. So, they arrived at this decision &lt;strong>to create a win-win situation where the new company will still be handed over instructions from MountainView through back channels but liabilities of the company are going to be very limited because they will show zero or no earnings at all.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I can see everyone from Cupertino to Redmond running helter skelter by this move from Google as they will lose one major weapon in their armory in their &amp;ldquo;Take no prisoners&amp;rdquo; war against Android&amp;rsquo;s rapid growth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll keep you guys updated as I get more details on this.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update&lt;/strong>: Yes, it is true&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;..that all of you saw straight through my pathetic attempt at an april fools joke :P&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>ZDNet Fail. Answer is Stop Tech Blogging</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/11/19/zdnet-fail-answer-is-stop-tech-blogging/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2010 15:45:04 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/11/19/zdnet-fail-answer-is-stop-tech-blogging/</guid><description>Just read this article over at zdnet. What it basically says is condensed in these two points:
Android is a failure for Google because it is open and carriers/OEMs are stripping off google search from it and putting replacements like baidu/Bing. (BTW, half the people say Android is fail because it is not open and the other half say it is fail because it is open. Which one is it, please decide ;) )</description><content>&lt;p>Just read this &lt;a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/android-fail-the-answer-is-a-google-phone/7822">article&lt;/a> over at zdnet. What it basically says is condensed in these two points:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Android is a failure for Google because it is open and carriers/OEMs are stripping off google search from it and putting replacements like baidu/Bing. (BTW, half the people say Android is fail because it is not open and the other half say it is fail because it is open. Which one is it, please decide ;) )&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The solution is a Google Phone with google branding, sold unlocked at full price.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Let me answer 2nd point first. Dana Blankenhorn, thanks for that nice blast from the past advice. Google already did it with Nexus One, like, one year ago duh..&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, on to the first point. Even if lot of people are stripping off Google search, they still have a big share of the mobile search market. They didn&amp;rsquo;t create Android solely to earn from it directly. It was more of a way to ensure that they still have an avenue for mobile revenue which would have otherwise been completely lost (iPhone). Another thing here is that if they didn&amp;rsquo;t keep it open enough for other players, it might have not got such widespread adoption or they might have been killed in US/EU under antitrust laws.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, all I can say to Dana and ZDNet is &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-&amp;gt; kthxbi :P&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Is Android Open Source Or Not?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/25/android-open-source-or-not/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 11:31:06 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/25/android-open-source-or-not/</guid><description>Is Android really open source or not? That is the question being asked by almost everyone. A lot of people, especially those influenced by RDF or those who are in the news industry with no idea about OS and open source but were asked by their boss to get a scoop on this pronto, tend to bring up a few keywords and then twist them around in the way they see fit to make sure it says Android isn&amp;rsquo;t open.</description><content>&lt;p>Is Android really open source or not? That is the question being asked by almost everyone. A lot of people, especially those influenced by &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reality_distortion_field">RDF&lt;/a> or those who are in the news industry with no idea about OS and open source but were asked by their boss to get a scoop on this pronto, tend to bring up a few keywords and then twist them around in the way they see fit to make sure it says Android isn&amp;rsquo;t open. They don&amp;rsquo;t need to be correct, they only need the article to &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>sound correct&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo; by picking up sentences out of context or putting quotes only from people who agree with them. This will convince their boss and 99% of their readers who have no idea about all these things either. But the boss is happy he got a story and associated clicks. Readers are happy because they got the points to float around in their next forum flame war. They don&amp;rsquo;t have to read when someone corrects them. They have made their points and rest is all someone making noises like a rat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lot out of the rest of the people, who are indeed informed, make the mistake of thinking that &amp;ldquo;Open Source = GPL&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Open Source = Free Software&amp;rdquo;, which is not true. Open source is similar to free software but is one that choses to keep more options open. In short, Free Software Movement, as the one evangelized by FSF, is a subset of open source that tries to achieve freedom of software by restriction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please also note that many people including Steve Jobs confuse people more by interchanging between open and open source. An android phone that you get may not be open, the android market may be open, etc but this discussion is purely about open-source.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyways, with asbestos underwear on, I write this post to speak my mind about this matter by talking about various points thrown up by the above mentioned classes. Since this is going to be a long post, I&amp;rsquo;ll mention here the things it is going to cover:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Allegations against Android&amp;rsquo;s open-source nature. Are they true?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Does OSI Foundation (&lt;a href="http://www.opensource.org">Open source Initiative&lt;/a>) think that Android is open source?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Android and open source in layman terms&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Takeaways/conclusion&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update&lt;/strong>: Updated the article as per Tony and Kasper&amp;rsquo;s comments below. Thanks Kasper and Tony for your valuable inputs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="android-and-open-source-allegations-and-answers">Android and Open Source: Allegations and Answers&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allegation&lt;/strong>: Google does a lot of development in private for few months and then releases the code to public.
&lt;strong>Answer&lt;/strong>: Almost every open source project I know does this. Do you think every person who works on an open source project pushes his code to the mainline 10 times when re writes a 10 line code? No. He completes the feature, tests it and then pushes it out. Individuals might do it sooner, companies might do it later but everyone pushes out their code when they feel things are fairly ready. So, Google choses to do the &amp;ldquo;push&amp;rdquo; every few months when they think their new feature set is ready. This, of course, is more influenced by the fact that they need to be competitive in the aggressive mobile market and hence not let the competitors know about the exact features but still it is well within the limits of open source. And they are doing it before/with the binary release as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also to be noted here is the fact that the &amp;ldquo;code dump&amp;rdquo; is done only for major releases. Minor fixes and even features keep trickling into the code base every now and then and these allow others to make fixes as well. e.g. Cyanogen was able to bring &amp;ldquo;802.11n&amp;rdquo; capability and was able to include various fixes including one for wi-fi sleep policies before they actually made into an OTA update for any phone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allegation&lt;/strong>: Only google employees can check in code to mainline.
&lt;strong>Answer&lt;/strong>: Every open source project has only a select few folks who can check in code. Most of the open source projects start with only their founders having commit access. They may or may not give commit accesses to anyone else. Check out various open source projects on sourceforge, googlecode, etc and you will find this. Most of the projects that do choose to give commit access to others, start doing it after some time when they feel the project is mature enough and they are confident enough in someone else. Android is just a hatchling, around 2 years old. It has begun making strides only now so Google may even choose to take the latter path but I can understand if Google wants to keep this as their control point because of the hustle and bustle of the mobile OS world which is much more rapid and cut throat than the desktop OS and this does not make them closed. Not only that, but seeing how everyone in the mobile world is so trigger happy with suing everyone else, it creates a legal issue for them as they would be the ones to answer if someone else brings this upon them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allegation&lt;/strong>: Google only accepts their own code into official android and nobody else&amp;rsquo;s.
&lt;strong>Answer&lt;/strong>: This one is hilarious. Obviously, anyone who says this hasn&amp;rsquo;t actually been to review.android.com. Just go their and check whether any merged changes have non-google, non-android email ids. Anyone can upload their patches there but the accepted ones are fairly low. This problem is present in every popular open source project, even the Linux kernel. But is more pronounced in the case of android because Google&amp;rsquo;s android team is much smaller than the number of persons working on other projects and there is red tape of a big company involved. If you want to get your patch in, just like the kernel, you need to engage with them. Talk to them in the relevant bug report, comment the code properly, give them a reason to not avoid your patch. But yes, the process is still very slow and it is eons faster to just contribute to a fork like cyanogenmod. I do hope that google does get better in this regard soon though.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allegation&lt;/strong>: It is not possible to make a full android build from the public code tree of android.
&lt;strong>Answer&lt;/strong>: BS. Cyanogen does just fine with his full AOSP builds. People argue that Google does not release the modem/baseband code but they idiotically fail to realize that the baseband code is not part of Android at all. It is the IP of the baseband manufacturer and is specific to each hardware. Android is just the code that runs on apps hardware. Google does not indeed release the code of their built in google apps (gtalk/gmail etc) though but they are already working towards that and these apps will not be a part of the base Android system anymore. These would be standalone apps and even now you don&amp;rsquo;t need them to make a fully working android build.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allegation&lt;/strong>: &amp;ldquo;Android&amp;rdquo; is a registered trademark and is held by Google.
&lt;strong>Answer&lt;/strong>: Linus holds the trademark for &amp;ldquo;Linux&amp;rdquo;, Mozilla foundation holds the trademark for &amp;ldquo;Firefox&amp;rdquo;, Canonical holds the trademark for &amp;ldquo;Ubuntu&amp;rdquo;. Get the drift? Basically, it is completely possible and allowed for an open source software to be trademarked.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allegation&lt;/strong>: Google doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop the carriers/OEMs from locking down the phones, adding bloatware or custom UIs.
&lt;strong>Answer&lt;/strong>: This is an issue with carriers/OEMs and not Android. Google uses the apache software license (ASL), which is a permissive license (like MIT, BSD, etc) and hence does not stop the carriers from doing such a thing (In fact, this is the very foundation of being open, check the next passage about OSI foundation, point no. 9). Many people say they should, but if they did then they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be open anymore, would they?
Even Linus Torvalds is against making such a stipulation of not allowing locking of phones and this is the biggest reason why the Linux Kernel (and lot of other open source projects) didn&amp;rsquo;t move to FSF&amp;rsquo;s (&lt;a href="http://www.fsf.org">Free Software Foundation&lt;/a>) GPL v3. I wonder why no one calls the Linux kernel closed hmmmm&amp;hellip;
BTW, if you are so serious about unlocked/rootable phones then buy a dev phone directly from google or get one from Synapse.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="android-and-open-source-osi-foundation">Android and Open Source: OSI Foundation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The OSI foundation has a few guidelines to determine whether something is open source or not under their &lt;a href="http://www.opensource.org/osd.html">Open Source Definition&lt;/a>. Android uses the OSI compatible Apache Software License (ASL) but still let&amp;rsquo;s see whether Android comes up to all of them or not. If it is in conflict with even one of the requisites, we will call Android closed.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Allow free redistribution - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Give out un-obfuscated source code - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Allow modifications and derived works - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Allow distribution of modifications (as patches) or modified software as a whole. Can restrict the modified versions from using original name of software - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No discrimination against any person or groups - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No restriction of using the software on any device or field - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No additional license needed - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No product-specific license - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No restriction on software distributed along with original software - Check&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Technology neutral, i.e., no preference for an individual technology or user interface - Check
So, Android is true to each and every point that being open demands to it. In fact, points 9 and 10 are fundamental in making it open but alas, people less oriented with open software tend to term this as being closed (as seen in the last allegation above)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="android-and-open-source-from-a-laymans-view-point">Android and Open Source: From a layman&amp;rsquo;s view point&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Apart from the above, I would also like to share a few &amp;ldquo;layman-examples&amp;rdquo; which will let you understand for yourself why Android is open:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>You can see all the official android OS code without any restrictions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can download it, fork it, modify it without asking google&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can port it to any device without asking google&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can develop and sell your phone with Android without asking google
Now compare that with any other mobile OS you know.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="android-and-open-source-conclusion">Android and Open Source: Conclusion&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>So, the takeaways from the above wall of text are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Android is open-source&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Android is permissively open-source instead of being restrictive&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Android can do better in terms of community driven development but is perhaps held back by pace of competition and legalities involved. But, this in no way makes it non-open-source.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Let me know if you have any corrections or allegations to make :)&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Solving The Android Permissions And Malware Puzzle</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/13/android-permissions-malware/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2010 19:44:59 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/13/android-permissions-malware/</guid><description>There has been a spate of security reports recently about Android apps being malware or suspicious. Most of these were found baseless but at least one was indeed correct (e.g. The Russian Trojan app). We also know that Android has a very good security model but even then, the rest of the reports also makes one think and focus on why an apps requires the permissions that it states it needs?</description><content>&lt;p>There has been a spate of security reports recently about Android apps being malware or suspicious. Most of these were found baseless but at least one was indeed correct (e.g. The Russian Trojan app). We also know that Android has a very good &lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/26/android-vs-iphone-security-models.html">security model&lt;/a> but even then, the rest of the reports also makes one think and focus on why an apps requires the permissions that it states it needs?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We all MUST check the permissions that an app requires before installing it and then contemplate what particular feature of the app would require any mentioned permission. The problem here is two part. First is that the permissions can be cryptic. Now, I can understand most of these as I also develop Android apps but I&amp;rsquo;d fathom that a huge majority wouldn&amp;rsquo;t. A simple solution to this would be for Google to provide more details (and probably examples) for each permission. One can say that it is difficult and a UI nightmare to include too much of text into the limited space that the mobile screen gets. My suggestion here would be to keep the existing layout as it is, but when someone clicks on a requested permission, he be taken to a new page which describes the permission in detailed but simple words and also provides examples.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But this is just the first part of the current problem. The more important issue most apps are facing these days is &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>permission creep in&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo;, i.e., they request for permissions they don&amp;rsquo;t really require. This could be because either they are just adding it to their manifest file mistakenly without using them or are taking a long route for solving a problem that should ideally have been solved in a much easier way without requiring excessive permissions. This permission creep in makes even legit apps look bad. e.g. There was this recent case of a &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2010/07/29/android-wallpaper-hack/">wallpaper app&lt;/a> which was crucified by mainstream media all over the world because of the permissions it was using and then it turned out to be just that the developer&amp;rsquo;s method to solve a particular problem (providing &amp;ldquo;favorites&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;recommended&amp;rdquo; features to users) was long-winded.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->This is quite common today in Android marketplace. e.g. I tried to install the hugely famous &amp;ldquo;Chomp SMS&amp;rdquo; app today and noticed that it requires my &amp;ldquo;location&amp;rdquo; as well. Pretty weird that an SMS app needs my location and when combined with the &amp;ldquo;Internet&amp;rdquo; permission that it requires as well, it made me go &amp;ldquo;hmmm&amp;rdquo; even though it is tried and tested by a huge number of people without issues. Then I realized that it might need the internet permission for ads (since I was downloading the free version) but still a bit doubtful about location, probably that is needed for ads targeting (especially because it wanted my coarse location only, i.e., cell-triangulation location by which it can easily identify my general region or country, which is all what is needed) but I&amp;rsquo;m still not sure. Even the Android Guru &lt;a href="http://commonsware.com/blog/2010/08/12/evernote-why-you-need-think-about-permissions.html">Mark Murphy has similar reservations&lt;/a> about another popular app Evernote.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The solution? I think Google should make it mandatory for app publishers to explain in the market that why their app needs each of the permissions it requests. This should be concisely explained to the user before installation and then the user-review feature of Android marketplace can take over to determine whether the explanation given is indeed satisfactory enough or not. This would, e.g., make it immediately clear to any potential Chomp SMS users why it needs the location. I&amp;rsquo;m sure this would lead to even more sales for the good and trusted apps as people like me who were skeptical of something can put their doubts to rest. At the same time, it would quickly push the russian trojan like apps down into the oblivion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A side effect/benefit of this approach will also be that the app authors would look at the permissions that they use more cautiously and would probably try to weed out the unnecessary ones.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another idea that I have in mind is more community based. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if Google will implement the above idea or even if they do, would they make it mandatory since market already has almost a 100,000 apps without this info. BUT, if someone can take up the mantle of making a community site that documents, with the help of android users, the potential uses of all apps&amp;rsquo; permissions and also raise flags on any app having a permission without any apparent need, this would become a boon to the Android users. AppBrain, are you listening? I think this would be a good addition to your already excellent service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What are your ideas about solving the apps and permissions problems and removing the malware scare that looms upon us? Let me know in the comments..&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Android vs iPhone: Security Models</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/25/android-vs-iphone-security-models/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2010 22:02:49 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/25/android-vs-iphone-security-models/</guid><description>Android and iPhone OS (iOS) have been at loggerheads for quite some time now. This is a take on which has a better security model to protect its users. I thought of writing it up because there have been a lot of discussions around me lately about which platform is more secure and I keep repeating the same points over and over at every one of them, so thought that in future I&amp;rsquo;ll just point them to this page :P</description><content>&lt;p>Android and iPhone OS (iOS) have been at loggerheads for quite some time now. This is a take on which has a better security model to protect its users. I thought of writing it up because there have been a lot of discussions around me lately about which platform is more secure and I keep repeating the same points over and over at every one of them, so thought that in future I&amp;rsquo;ll just point them to this page :P&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Disclaimer:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A. I don&amp;rsquo;t guarantee this post to be absolutely correct as I&amp;rsquo;m no security researcher or expert but I do have some interest in this field and I&amp;rsquo;ve been a developer for some time now on different architectures and OSs especially at OS/driver level and that too in the mobile devices field, so I &amp;ldquo;might&amp;rdquo; actually be right about a few things here and there..&lt;/p>
&lt;p>B. I&amp;rsquo;m an android user myself but not of the fanboy variety. I&amp;rsquo;ll be happy to switch camps any day I get something that appeals to me better. I have love and hate points for almost all platforms available but I&amp;rsquo;m using android because &amp;ldquo;for me&amp;rdquo; it&amp;rsquo;s love points slightly outnumber the hate points.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK, on with the points then. Here is the table that I created for this showing points I considered and which side wins each. Don&amp;rsquo;t start flaming me though just by seeing the table :P I will be discussing the points as well below it.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Android
iPhone&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1. Distribution Medium Security:&lt;/strong> Apple vets every application that is put on the app store while Google&amp;rsquo;s Market Place is unrestricted. How does this affect you security wise?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**a. Approval Process: **The biggest myth is that the vetting process is what will save you from malware on app store. IT WON&amp;rsquo;T. The Apple app approval process isn&amp;rsquo;t defined anywhere but in general it just states that it checks for apps to do what they say they will do. But they don&amp;rsquo;t check the source code of the apps and static analysis of binaries can only take you so far (Heck, they have even been inept at catching a whole lot of apps that were using their disallowed private apis which can be found easily using simple tools) . So, anyone actually wanting to write a malware can do it trivially by making the malicious code to run after the app has been approved. The trigger could be time based or could even be done over the web remotely. The app could even have encrypted payloads or download new pieces of code over the web and run them. So, we can safely say that approval process is something that can&amp;rsquo;t make things secure for you that way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Result: No one wins&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**
**&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>b. Phishing:&lt;/strong> This is where App store can protect you if someone put an app claiming to be from someone that it isn&amp;rsquo;t. e.g. Someone could make an app that claims to be from &amp;ldquo;Bank of America&amp;rdquo;. In apple&amp;rsquo;s case, I&amp;rsquo;m 99.99% sure that the app won&amp;rsquo;t pass the screening but in Android&amp;rsquo;s case, there won&amp;rsquo;t be any hassles for it to reach the marketplace. It could be pulled soon after as google learns about it but still even one person&amp;rsquo;s damage here is much more than what would have happend on iPhone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Result: iPhone wins&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**
**&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2. Local Security:&lt;/strong> What about the security in the OS itself once an app is on your phone? This is an important question because 1.) As I noted above, Apple&amp;rsquo;s app screening process isn&amp;rsquo;t robust enough to catch malware 2.) People can bypass the official distribution medium easily. Android allows to install apps from other sources on most phones by just enabling an option and a huge number of people jailbreak their iPhones and get/use this capability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>a. Permissions:&lt;/strong> On Android, an app has to explicitly declare what capabilities/data of the phone it wants to access/use and the user has to explicitly give it those permissions before it is allowed to install, irrespective of from where/how this app is being installed. So, it works even if you are installing the app from your SD card and even if you have rooted your phone. On iPhone, there is no such mechanism of restricting apps. All apps are equal and can access a lot of resources unhindered without the user knowing. So, while installing a single player only game on android you can immediately be suspicious if the app is asking for internet connection or access to your contacts data but on iPhone you will not come to know about this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Result: Android wins&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**
**&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>b. Environment:&lt;/strong> On both platforms, the apps run in their own sandboxes with unique uuids&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Result: Tie&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**
**&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>3. Open vs Closed:&lt;/strong> Most of the Android code is open source while for iOS, only darwin kernel and some other things like webkit etc are open source. Now, this in itself doesn&amp;rsquo;t gurantee to make Android secure but its code does get a lot of scrutiny from open source community as well as lot of other big name companies with commercial interests in Android which allows it to find and fix more bugs and loopholes than iPhone can.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Result: Slight win for Android&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**
**&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>4. App development model:&lt;/strong> Most apps for Android are written in java while those in iPhone are written in C/Objective-C. While I&amp;rsquo;m myself a big time C lover (Majority of my coding is in C/CPP) but it is indeed a very unforgiving language where you need to be very careful with what you write and has much greater chances of exploits, .e.g, Buffer overflows, as compared to java (Interestingly, all the jailbreaks for iPhone OS have been done using such exploits and have been made available day 0/day 1 mostly.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Result: Slight win for Android&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**
**&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>5. Damage Control:&lt;/strong> What if an app actually got through everything on any of these platforms and started spreading? Both of these platforms have kill switches in the hands of Google/Apple which they can use to remove such malicious apps from the users&amp;rsquo; phones remotely.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Result: Tie&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**
**&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Summary: Well, there is no clear winner. Apple is quite good when it comes to protecting you from phishing (though that advantage goes away if you jailbreak and use alternative means to install apps) and Android has a real sound local security system (though it also has the flaw that users might not always understand why an app is requesting a certain critical permission and install it anyways). So, take your pick and let me know what you picked :) and please do tell me if I&amp;rsquo;m wrong in any of my points or missed out on something that needs to be compared.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Android Froyo And Nexus One: Everything We Know</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/05/23/android-froyo-nexus-one/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2010 17:44:18 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/05/23/android-froyo-nexus-one/</guid><description>This is an effort from my side to consolidate everything about Android Froyo with respect to Nexus One. It is mainly concentrated towards listing the features/fixes that we have seen in Froyo that weren&amp;rsquo;t announced in Google I/O, things that work with nexus one, things that don&amp;rsquo;t and possible fixes/workarounds known, what the announced features actually feel like in real use etc.** Will keep updating this post as I get more info, get more fixes, etc.</description><content>&lt;p>This is an effort from my side to consolidate everything about Android Froyo with respect to Nexus One. It is mainly concentrated towards listing the features/fixes that we have seen in Froyo that weren&amp;rsquo;t announced in Google I/O, things that work with nexus one, things that don&amp;rsquo;t and possible fixes/workarounds known, what the announced features actually feel like in real use etc.** Will keep updating this post as I get more info, get more fixes, etc. Please do let me know if I&amp;rsquo;ve missed something or there is some new development that should be updated here.**&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**UPDATED: **&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>27-MAY-2010 (Added things missing since Eclair and few other notes)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>25-MAY-2010 (Added market missing apps fix, 802.11n and other features)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>24-MAY-2010 (Added more un-announced features/fixes/changes)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>To start with, just a quick recap of things that were announced and their look/feel/working in real use (First is the announced feature and then after &amp;ldquo;:&amp;rdquo; is the effect that we see)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Feature/Fix&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Real Effects seen by us&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Remarks&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>JIT for Dalvik JVM&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Apps are quite fast, visible difference animation effects, scrolling, games etc&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>None&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Better Exchange support with calendar sync/GAL /remote wipe/account-auto-discovery/administation&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Works as advertised&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Exchange support still not upto the mark. e.g. No support for selective folder sync, subfolders are not synced automatically, no phone number/location for GAL contacts, no “move to folder”, no search, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Backup Application data/settings/history in cloud&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Yet to experience&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve enabled the settings for this but haven&amp;rsquo;t switched to another ROM yet or figured out how to test it in some other way.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Cloud Messaging to activate intents&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Works as advertised&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>very cool feature. Try out this chrome extension to send links from chrome to your phone: &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/p/chrometophone/">Chrome2Phone&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>USB Tethering and Portable Wireless Hotspot&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Works as advertised&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Real skin-saver. Works great and easily.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Javascript V8 Engine for Android Browser&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Much faster javascript execution&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Much better browsing experience noted.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>HTML5 support/Device Access (Camera/Accelerometer etc) through Browser&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Work In Progress. See Remarks&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Contrary to what many people tell you, this is still not there. HTML5 support is an ongoing thing and device access through browser would be present in Gingerbread (Next Android iteration, supposedly 3.0)&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Better Voice Input Integration&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Seems&amp;rdquo; better.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Now, I don&amp;rsquo;t have any tangible means to measure this but it seems to be working relatively better and it even seems to understand my non-US accent much better.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Flash 10.1 beta support&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Works as advertised&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Almost every flash functionality in all sites I visited work ok. Please note that you need to install Flash from market as it doesn&amp;rsquo;t come &amp;ldquo;built-in&amp;rdquo;. Just search for &amp;ldquo;Adobe&amp;rdquo; in market.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Install apps on SD card&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Not tested.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>This feature requires support from apps to integrate this and currently no apps support it. There is a command that you can run from adb shell &amp;ldquo;adb shell pm setInstallLocation 2&amp;rdquo; but it will cause &amp;ldquo;all&amp;rdquo; your apps to install to the card plus users report problems on missing apps as SD card is not available immediately at boot up.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Better global search integration for apps&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Works as advertised&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Now, apps can allow search to search within their data. Right now the official twitter app supports this and you can search your timeline from the main android search itself.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Update all apps in one click/automatic updates&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Works as advertised&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>None.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Stream music from PC to phone&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Yet to test.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>None. As pointed out by Hugo, it is not clear yet that this is supposed to be part of Froyo or GingerBread.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Improved crash reporting to developers&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Works as advertised&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Really useful to the developers as it sends complete report about the environment and stack trace etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Purchase music/apps on android market and push directly to device Over The Air&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Yet to test&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>New market website that allows this hasn&amp;rsquo;t appeared yet. As pointed out by Hugo, it is not clear yet that this is supposed to be part of Froyo or GingerBread.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Now, we move on to things that weren&amp;rsquo;t announced but we found them in the updates. This may be because these pieces were too small or specific to nexus one to have warranted a place in the Google I/O keynote.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Feature/Fix&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Remarks&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Erratic/Crazy Touchscreen behaviour fixes&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>This is about the erratic behaviour of the touchscreen that sometimes all the touches were being registered at the wrong places and one had to tap twice on the power button to fix it. So far, it seems that this has been fixed.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Multi-touch fixes&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>This seems to be a hardware problem and there are no &amp;ldquo;fixes&amp;rdquo; to it as such but there seems to be a new touchscreen API in the 2.2 Froyo SDK that google is encouraging developers to use to alleviate this issue somewhat by doing some filtering/scaling within the Android framework.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>SMS App fix&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>The messaging app had a nagging issue that many times it showed the first few words of a text message as the sender instead of the actual number/sender. This seems to be fixed now.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Capacitive Touch Button fix&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Nexus one was quite famous for its mal-functioning cap-touch buttons that didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to register the touches of a user. We had to press slightly above them most times to register a touch. This seems to be fixed now and feels much better.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Multi-Color Trackball&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>The nexus one trackball can now display multiple colors instead of just white. e.g. a nee facebook update received makes it glow blue :)&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Better Camera/Gallery Interface&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>The new camera/gallery interface is just awesome and much easier to use. Feature wise I think the new options are focus settings, zoom settings and storage location quick switch, flash on during video recording for night video capture. I must also mention that auto-flash works much better now as earlier it used to almost always fire even in quite ample light but that maybe just me.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Now, on our list are things/apps that don&amp;rsquo;t work or issues that plague the new update. We will also be listing the workarounds/fixes if known for them.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Issues&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Fix/Workaround/Remarks&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Seesmic app keeps giving &amp;ldquo;Connection error&amp;rdquo; with froyo&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Simple fix is to delete your existing account in seesmic. Setup a new account and uncheck &amp;ldquo;Secure connection&amp;rdquo; in advanced setup.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Swype doesn&amp;rsquo;t work&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Just uninstall swype and swype installer and download/install them again and it will work.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Pure Calendar doesn&amp;rsquo;t work&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>New versions have been released to make them work&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Android market doesn&amp;rsquo;t show a lot of apps&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>As of now, android market is not showing a lot of paid/copy-protected apps on the market for froyo users. There is a workaround for root users available here: &lt;a href="http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=687371">http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=687371&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Worse radio/3G performance&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Several users at modaco/xda-devs report worse performance with 3G. They say downgrading back to previous radio fixes this but try it at your own risk.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Things missing since previous versions (i.e. Eclair):&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Thanks to Marc for suggestion)&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Things missing&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>No “.com” button on the default Android keyboard&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The final part of this post is for things that were rumored to be in the Froyo update for nexus one but aren&amp;rsquo;t present:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>**Rumored Feature/fix **(Not present in Nexus One Froyo Update)&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>FM Radio Receiver&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>FM Transmitter&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s it for now. This is a huge post and I must have missed out on a lot of things for sure. So, if you remember something that I have missed or something has changed over past few days after I wrote/updated this post, please do let me know in comments.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Comments In Google Reader Shared Items Are Here</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/12/google-reader-shared-items-comments/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2009 05:00:22 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/12/google-reader-shared-items-comments/</guid><description>Since quite some time, Google Reader has included the feature to share interesting items with your friends who also use Google Reader. Some time back they also added the option to &amp;ldquo;Share with a Note&amp;rdquo; to add your take to the shared piece. But I always thought there was no way to share back by comments (or see my friends&amp;rsquo; take) about that particular article. One way could have been to post the comments on the original site of the article but that had the drawbacks that:</description><content>&lt;p>Since quite some time, &lt;strong>Google Reader&lt;/strong> has included the feature to share interesting items with your friends who also use Google Reader. Some time back they also added the option to &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>Share with a Note&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo; to add your take to the shared piece. But I always thought there was no way to share back by comments (or see my friends&amp;rsquo; take) about that particular article. One way could have been to post the comments on the original site of the article but that had the drawbacks that:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Others might not even go to the original site to check these comments&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>We might not want to make this discussion public outside of our social group&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The original site might not even allow comments&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Another way was to keep sharing the item again and again with your own notes, but that would really become a pain (as you can imagine where).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, google listened to my unspoken thoughts and from this morning onwards, we have a new commenting feature on shared items. Click on the pic below to see it. So, they have given an alternate commenting system that you can use in your friend circle to discuss any item. Really cool, I&amp;rsquo;d say. What do you think?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(PS: The people who were &amp;ldquo;predicting&amp;rdquo; a couple of months ago that Google is going to &lt;strong>shut down&lt;/strong> &lt;strong>Google Reader&lt;/strong>, well, I don&amp;rsquo;t think so. I think they are workign full steam on it to make it an essential part in their grand scheme of things to create an ecosystem, along with &lt;strong>Google Friend Connect&lt;/strong>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/2009/03/googlereadershareditemscomments.png">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/2009/03/googlereadershareditemscomments-thumb.png" alt="google-reader-shared-items-comments">&lt;/a>&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Call For Google Adsense Maths Class Charity Fund</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/23/call-for-google-adsense-maths-class-charity-fund/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2008 08:25:36 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/23/call-for-google-adsense-maths-class-charity-fund/</guid><description>I hereby call for setting up a charity fund so that we can donate some money to get the poor ol’ Google Adsense some Mathematics/Algebra 101 classes because apparantly it thinks that 0.63 + 0.07 = 0.69.</description><content>&lt;p>I hereby call for setting up a charity fund so that we can donate some money to get the poor ol’ Google Adsense some Mathematics/Algebra 101 classes because apparantly it thinks that 0.63 + 0.07 = 0.69.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/Google-AdSense-Reports-Miscalculation.png" alt="Google-AdSense-Reports-Miscalculation">&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Project: Shantz-WP-Prefix-Suffix Updated to 1.1.0</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/20/project-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-to-110/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 04:08:17 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/20/project-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-to-110/</guid><description>Well, its not just prefix suffix any more, because I added an option to add things in the middle of the posts as well. I got this idea because people told me that this was one of the most sought after option as advertisements (e.g. google adsense, adbrite, etc) give maximum click through rate when placed smack dab in the middle of the content. What’s more is that it is configurable and you can choose how many paragraphs and/or words should be skipped from the start of the post before you add whatever you want, be it text, css, html, php or javascript.</description><content>&lt;p>Well, its not just prefix suffix any more, because I added an option to add things in the middle of the posts as well. I got this idea because people told me that this was one of the most sought after option as advertisements (e.g. google adsense, adbrite, etc) give maximum click through rate when placed smack dab in the middle of the content. What’s more is that it is configurable and you can choose how many paragraphs and/or words should be skipped from the start of the post before you add whatever you want, be it text, css, html, php or javascript.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/screenshot_2D1.png">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/screenshot_2D1_thumb.jpg" alt="WordPress Plugin Shantz WP Prefix Suffic Configuration Screenshot">&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/screenshot_2D2.png">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/screenshot_2D2_thumb.jpg" alt="Wordpress Plugin Shantz Wp Prefix Suffix In Action">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And don’t forget to let me know what you think about it or if you want any new features included.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Google Adsense : Conflict of Interests?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/07/google-adsense-conflict-of-interests/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2008 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/07/google-adsense-conflict-of-interests/</guid><description>“Google Adsense” has been caught in a conflict of interests with its parent company “Google”. Google piad 140k to teh cause of “Say No to Prop 8” but on the other hand people reported that Google Adsense delivered a substantially huge amount of “Say Yes to Prop 8” advertisements all over the internet, even on sites which are completely out of context with this matter. Not only is this conflicting with the interests of the parent company but also with the “Terms of Use” put forward by Adsense that ads should not have any kind of intolerance or advocacy towards an individual or a group.</description><content>&lt;p>“Google Adsense” has been caught in a conflict of interests with its parent company “Google”. Google piad 140k to teh cause of “Say No to Prop 8” but on the other hand people reported that Google Adsense delivered a substantially huge amount of “Say Yes to Prop 8” advertisements all over the internet, even on sites which are completely out of context with this matter. Not only is this conflicting with the interests of the parent company but also with the “Terms of Use” put forward by Adsense that ads should not have any kind of intolerance or advocacy towards an individual or a group. Irate people took out their frustation on the &lt;a href="https://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=5576995&amp;amp;postID=8069138212199008176&amp;amp;isPopup=true">adsense blog&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, I just caught another conflict between google and adsense on my own blog. Basically, Google is against TLAs (text-link-ads) since they mess up the search engine rankings and even penalizes any site that sells or buys them. But look what I found in one of the ads displayed in google.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/2008/11/conflictofinterest.png">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/2008/11/conflictofinterest-thumb.png" alt="conflict-of-interest">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Looks like somebody needs to arrange a meeting between the google and adsense honchos to sort out what exactly is their stance on anything and everything.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Google Releases Android Source Code</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/21/google-releases-android-source-code/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2008 17:57:52 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/21/google-releases-android-source-code/</guid><description>FOSS (Free and Open Source Software) community rejoices today as google finally lived upto their promise of releasing the android source code. Now, the things that is left to be evaluated is that how much of it is actually true, or whether there are some binary blobs still in there. Moreover, it remains to be seen that how much this converts into a “community” project instead of being ruled by Google with an iron hand.</description><content>&lt;p>FOSS (Free and Open Source Software) community rejoices today as google finally lived upto their promise of &lt;a href="http://google-opensource.blogspot.com/2008/10/android-open-source-cell-phone.html">releasing&lt;/a> the &lt;a href="http://source.android.com/">android source code&lt;/a>. Now, the things that is left to be evaluated is that how much of it is actually true, or whether there are some binary blobs still in there. Moreover, it remains to be seen that how much this converts into a “community” project instead of being ruled by Google with an iron hand. But given the interest that Android has generated so far, and given google’s reputation as a good open source promoter, I am ready to believe that this is going to be one of the biggest landmarks that mobile FOSS industry will see. And maybe, this will finally motivate me as well to get involved in the “bigger picture” finally by contributing to a project that is more than just a few thousand lines of source. What is your opinion and expectation from this development? Let me know.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Android Devices Trickling In A Few Days Early?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/20/android-devices-trickling-in-a-few-days-early/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2008 19:32:35 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/20/android-devices-trickling-in-a-few-days-early/</guid><description>There is still a day left for the first Android based Device, T-Mobile G1, to come out into the hands of general public but I was in a for a small surprise as I went through my Google Analytics report for the last week. It had a mysterious number of 2 sitting at the bottom of my “Unique Visitors by Operating Systems” filter report. The “mysterious” part coming from the fact that the left most column displayed “Android”.</description><content>&lt;p>There is still a day left for the first Android based Device, T-Mobile G1, to come out into the hands of general public but I was in a for a small surprise as I went through my Google Analytics report for the last week. It had a mysterious number of 2 sitting at the bottom of my “Unique Visitors by Operating Systems” filter report. The “mysterious” part coming from the fact that the left most column displayed “Android”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/Operating_2DSystems_2DGoogle_20Analytics_2Dreport_2Dandroid_2Dt_2Dmobile_2Dg1.png" alt="Operating-Systems-Google Analytics-report-android-t-mobile-g1">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, the question is whether the T-Mobile G1 (aka HTC dream) is already out into a few hands (leaked to lucky googlers/HTCers/T-Mobilers?) or somebody just modified the agent string reported to my web server? (Since this is a “unique visitors” report, the 2 people have to be different and hence second option doesn’t seem likely to me)&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Firefox Incognito / Private Browsing Mode - Part II</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/11/firefox-incognito-private-browsing-mode-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2008 16:59:33 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/11/firefox-incognito-private-browsing-mode-part-ii/</guid><description>A few people (e.g. Varun) told me my previous post differed from the way how google chrome / Microsoft IE8 handle Incognito (Private Browsing) mode. The main consideration was that while chrome/IE8 don&amp;rsquo;t write anything to disk at all, the firefox method is an after-effect, i.e., writing to disk and then clearing it up while closing the window. Well, true but nothing is non-rectificable :). So this is a post about a method that one can use to go &amp;ldquo;really&amp;rdquo; undercover with firefox.</description><content>&lt;p>A few people (e.g. &lt;a href="http://paheli.net/blog/2008/09/11/security-and-usability-google-chromes-incognito-mode/">Varun&lt;/a>) told me &lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/10/firefox-incognito-mode-is-here-move-over-chromeie8.html">my previous post&lt;/a> differed from the way how google chrome / Microsoft IE8 handle Incognito (Private Browsing) mode. The main consideration was that while chrome/IE8 don&amp;rsquo;t write anything to disk at all, the firefox method is an after-effect, i.e., writing to disk and then clearing it up while closing the window. Well, true but nothing is non-rectificable :). So this is a post about a method that one can use to go &amp;ldquo;really&amp;rdquo; undercover with firefox. But before we begin, please make sure you have read Part 1 of my post, because here I&amp;rsquo;ll start from the point where we left off in the earlier post.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I began thinking on the lines of setting up a ramdisk first (and remapping the browser cache folders to the new path in this ramdisk), so that nothing gets written to the hard disk, ever, even if the browser tries very hard. Best security right? Yes, but it involved a few issues like data is still there until you reboot also a part of your ram is always blocked, etc. So I went with the approach given below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Method: Easier and privacy on-par with Chrome/IE8&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just do the following in addition to the Step 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Uncheck &amp;ldquo;Keep my history&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Uncheck &amp;ldquo;Remember what I enter in forms and the search bar&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Uncheck &amp;ldquo;Remember what I&amp;rsquo;ve downloaded&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Choose &amp;ldquo;Keep until I close firefox&amp;rdquo; for cookies&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Press advanced settings in &amp;ldquo;Private Data&amp;rdquo;, select unselect options according to your choice. For max protection, select everything.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Open a new tab, and write &amp;ldquo;about:config&amp;rdquo; (without quotes) in address bar, press enter.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Search for &amp;ldquo;browser.cache.disk.enable&amp;rdquo; and set it to false&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Search for &amp;ldquo;browser.cache.offline.enable&amp;rdquo; and set it to false&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Done. You are secure and remember, this is just a one time setup, you won&amp;rsquo;t have to do this again and again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Side Note: Usability is another concern. However, I think that is debatable and varies from user to user highly. The steps lined up in these 2 posts aren&amp;rsquo;t too hard to carry out and take around a minute to do, and is a one time effort. Now, compare this with option where you use google chrome and love its in-built incognito mode but then have to leave all the extensions and greasemonkey scripts of firefox behind which made browsing so much more accessible for you. Another path could be to use both the browsers. Anyways, I&amp;rsquo;ll not go further down this path. This is for you to decide what you feel is more usable for you :) . This is just something to say &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not impossible&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PS: If anyone is still curious about the ramdisk approach, let me know..&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Firefox Incognito Mode Is Here: Move Over Chrome/IE8</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/10/firefox-incognito-mode-is-here-move-over-chromeie8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2008 17:49:41 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/10/firefox-incognito-mode-is-here-move-over-chromeie8/</guid><description>Update: Part 2 of this post is now up here to allay some of the drawbacks that were pointed out.
There has been so much hype over the “Incognito” (or Private Browsing) mode of Google Chrome / Microsoft IE8, with many internet users screeming Hallelujiah. But I don’t understand what the hoopla is all about. This mode has always been there in Mozilla firefox as well. You just need to devote less than one minute (yes, you read that right, less than one minute) to set it up.</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update:&lt;/strong> Part 2 of this post is now up &lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/11/firefox-incognito-private-browsing-mode-part-ii.html">here&lt;/a> to allay some of the drawbacks that were pointed out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There has been so much hype over the “Incognito” (or Private Browsing) mode of Google Chrome / Microsoft IE8, with many internet users screeming Hallelujiah. But I don’t understand what the hoopla is all about. This mode has always been there in Mozilla firefox as well. You just need to devote less than one minute (yes, you read that right, less than one minute) to set it up. Well, actions are better than words, so here it goes:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Step 1.) Run the following command to start the firefox profile manager.(In Linux, press Alt+F2 and in Windows, press Win+R to bring up the run dialogue box)&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>If it says something on the lines of “cannot find command” then use full path to firefox/firefox.exe in linux/Windows respectively.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/firefox_2Dprofile_2Dmanager.jpg">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/firefox_2Dprofile_2Dmanager_thumb.jpg" alt="Firefox-profile-manager">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Step 2.) Press “Create Profile” and enter “Incognito” (or a name of your choice) as your new profile name and press “Finish”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/firefox_2Dprofile_2Dmanager2.jpg">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/firefox_2Dprofile_2Dmanager2_thumb.jpg" alt="Firefox-profile-manager2">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Step 3.) Select “Incognito” profile and press “Start Firefox”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/firefox_2Dprofile_2Dmanager3.jpg">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/firefox_2Dprofile_2Dmanager3_thumb.jpg" alt="Firefox-profile-manager3">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Step 4.) Go to Edit-&amp;gt;Preferences-&amp;gt;Privacy. Select “Always clear my private data when I close Firefox” and unselect “Ask me before clearing private data”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/firefox_2Dprivacy_2Dpreferences.jpg">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/firefox_2Dprivacy_2Dpreferences_thumb.jpg" alt="Firefox-privacy-preferences">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Step 5.) That’s it. Setup is done. Now, whenever you want to go undercover, run the following command&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Note 1: You can run incognito mode and normal mode together simultaneously.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note 2: Its advised that you put the above command in a shortcut for easy/quick access.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Isn’t that simple? Now, can you roll back that drool factor of being able to go “undercover” in google chrome or Internet Explorer 8?&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Hack: Pidgin-Gtalk Connection Problems - Get Around The Corporate Firewall</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/08/hack-pidgin-gtalk-connection-problems-get-around-the-corporate-firewall/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 15:30:38 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/08/hack-pidgin-gtalk-connection-problems-get-around-the-corporate-firewall/</guid><description>I recently wrote a simple answering machine program/plugin for pidgin and someone asked me to port it to 32 bit. So I fired up pidgin within my virtual box installation at work (as I have only a 64 bit machine at home) but couldn&amp;rsquo;t get it to connect. Tried all sorts of methods found over the net of changing ports etc, set port forwarding in Virtual Box NAT, even switched to using a bridged host interface but still no go.</description><content>&lt;p>I recently wrote a simple answering machine program/plugin for pidgin and someone asked me to port it to 32 bit. So I fired up pidgin within my virtual box installation at work (as I have only a 64 bit machine at home) but couldn&amp;rsquo;t get it to connect. Tried all sorts of methods found over the net of changing ports etc, set port forwarding in Virtual Box NAT, even switched to using a bridged host interface but still no go. On a whim, installed pidgin in the host, i.e., windows and still the same issue. Hmm, interesting.. But wait, gtalk client works, then what gives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, after a bit of snooping around, discovered that it&amp;rsquo;s a special funda that my company employs (and probably yours too) to monitor your IM conversations. The server talk.google.com was redirected to another server set up by my company that masquerades as gtalk server and tries to act as a &amp;ldquo;Man In The Middle&amp;rdquo; to hijack your connection and listen to everything while you live in the fantasy that since its an &amp;ldquo;SSL encrypted&amp;rdquo; connection, everything is secure. However, &amp;ldquo;fortunately&amp;rdquo; pidgin refuses to connect here (More details in the end)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But as they say, rules are meant to be bent and broken. Here, is a simple way 3-step procedure to circumvent around this.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Open up your gtalk account settings in pidgin and go to Advanced tab.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Check &amp;ldquo;Force old port&amp;rdquo;, uncheck &amp;ldquo;plaintext auth&amp;rdquo; and uncheck &amp;ldquo;Require SSL/TLS&amp;rdquo;. Also change &amp;ldquo;Connect port&amp;rdquo; to 443.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>main&lt;/strong> part: Go to an online nslookup service and do an nslookup for talk.google.com. Put the IP that you get in place of &amp;ldquo;talk.google.com&amp;rdquo; in the settings.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s it. Go and chat away. (or if you want to know the reasoning behind this, hit the link below)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>More Details:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Skip this if you want, only for the people who are interested, here are some details on why pidgin does not connect in this situation and how you can find out if your company is using this tactic.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>How pidgin tries to connect to gtalk servers is that first it makes a connection to talk.google.com and gets and verifies the certificate from there. Then it tries to connect to gmail.com. Now there can be various situations:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>1.
1. Its unable to complete the transaction in the first place because you didn't use the port 443, so firewall blocks it hence it can't communand tries to fallback to plaintext authorization which is not supported by google and hence it fails.
2. You chose correct settings to go around firewall but now after verifying certificate, it just keeps &amp;quot;connecting&amp;quot;. Basically, it passes through the talk.google.com phase and then tries to connect to gmail.com (don't know why) and gets stuck on this step because the company is masquerading the gtalk server but not the gmail server.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>Look for the following symptoms to see if your company is doing &amp;ldquo;something&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>1.
1. Do &amp;quot;nslookup talk.google.com&amp;quot; in your command prompt (not through web), then say you get an IP x.y.z.w. Now do &amp;quot;nslookup x.y.z.w&amp;quot; again in command prompt. Now you will get the real name of the server that is your company's. Can try this for other IM servers as well (e.g. yahoo)
2. When pidgin asks you to verify the certificate, don't take it lightly. Just fetch and see the certificate and it'll definitely be pointing to some other domain.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Enough fundas for today. Let me know if this helped you out or if you have your own techniques of finding and circumventing around such stuff.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Google's New Favicon</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/30/googles-new-favicon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2008 19:16:21 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/30/googles-new-favicon/</guid><description>It’s amazing, isn’t it? Even a sneeze at google makes the headlines. Well, it’s not the sneeze today but the new favicon I just got. So, are you also seeing the all new, re-designed, artisticly polished “g” as the new favicon?
In other news, my Twitter-Webcam integration post has bypassed my earlier lifehacked post about Remote File Access Through E-mail by more than a few thousands, even though the time difference between the two posts is more than 3 months.</description><content>&lt;p>It’s amazing, isn’t it? Even a sneeze at google makes the headlines. Well, it’s not the sneeze today but the new favicon I just got. So, are you also seeing the all new, re-designed, artisticly polished “g” as the new favicon?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/favicon.ico" alt="New Google Favicon">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In other news, my &lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/14/keep-tab-on-home-security-with-a-webcam-and-twitter.html">Twitter-Webcam integration post&lt;/a> has bypassed my earlier lifehacked post about &lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/projects/windows/remote-file-access-through-e-mail">Remote File Access Through E-mail&lt;/a> by more than a few thousands, even though the time difference between the two posts is more than 3 months. Thanks Stumble Upon :)&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Page Rank 7: True Or Google Glitch?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/30/page-rank-7-true-or-google-glitch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2008 20:33:51 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/30/page-rank-7-true-or-google-glitch/</guid><description>I installed google toolbar (linux version) today in firefox and for this blog, it says that its page rank is 7. I can&amp;rsquo;t believe my eyes. I suppose it&amp;rsquo;s a google glitch may be (but have a wishful thinking at the back of mind that its true :-) ).
Are you getting the same result for this blog (or weird page rank results for other places that you frequent?)</description><content>&lt;p>I installed google toolbar (linux version) today in firefox and for this blog, it says that its page rank is &lt;strong>7&lt;/strong>. I can&amp;rsquo;t believe my eyes. I suppose it&amp;rsquo;s a google glitch may be (but have a wishful thinking at the back of mind that its true :-) ).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Are you getting the same result for this blog (or weird page rank results for other places that you frequent?)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/tech_shantanugoel_com_pagerank_7.jpg">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/tech_shantanugoel_com_pagerank_7_thumb.jpg" alt="tech_shantanugoel_com_pagerank_7_thumb">&lt;/a>&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>HollowMan Redux: Google Presents Gmail Users the Invisibility Cloak</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/25/hollowman-redux-google-presents-gmail-users-the-invisibility-cloak/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2008 18:53:20 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/25/hollowman-redux-google-presents-gmail-users-the-invisibility-cloak/</guid><description>Google gave us a nice little present today. The power to be all-seeing but yet still remaining unseen. Yes, now you can be “invisible” in your gmail chat session.
But beware, don’t fire up your gtalk, or you will again be as visible as a 100 watt bulb in a 4x4 room at night.</description><content>&lt;p>Google gave us a nice little present today. The power to be all-seeing but yet still remaining unseen. Yes, now you can be “invisible” in your gmail chat session.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/gmail_chat_invisible_status.png" alt="Gmail_chat_invisible_status">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But beware, don’t fire up your gtalk, or you will again be as visible as a 100 watt bulb in a 4x4 room at night.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>SmartPhones/NextGen Telephony: News That Matters</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/14/smartphonesnextgen-telephony-news-that-matters/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2008 05:08:10 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/14/smartphonesnextgen-telephony-news-that-matters/</guid><description>Just wanted to share some pieces that generated a variety of &amp;ldquo;hmmm&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;ahaa&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;wow&amp;rdquo; from me:
China Mobile set to trial LTE:
China Mobile said it will join Vodafone Group plc and Verizon Wireless in an ongoing trial of LTE technology…….The trials &amp;ndash; which include three powerhouse network operators &amp;ndash; underscore the momentum LTE is gaining as a leading 4G technology possibility vs. WiMAX and Ultra Mobile Broadband.
&amp;ldquo;HMMM&amp;rdquo; - U go LTE!</description><content>&lt;p>Just wanted to share some pieces that generated a variety of &amp;ldquo;hmmm&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;ahaa&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;wow&amp;rdquo; from me:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.rcrnews.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20080213/FREE/837538685/1002/rss01">China Mobile set to trial LTE&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>China Mobile said it will join Vodafone Group plc and Verizon Wireless in an ongoing trial of LTE technology…….The trials &amp;ndash; which include three powerhouse network operators &amp;ndash; underscore the momentum LTE is gaining as a leading 4G technology possibility vs. WiMAX and Ultra Mobile Broadband.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;HMMM&amp;rdquo; - U go LTE!!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.telstra.com.au/abouttelstra/media/announcements_article.cfm?ObjectID=41758">Telstra Launches the i-mate Ultimate 8502 and 9502 in Australia&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Telstra and i-mate have today launched the i-mate™ Ultimate 8502 and i-mate™ Ultimate 9502. Telstra is the first operator to deploy these devices globally and both devices will be exclusive in Australia to Telstra customers. Building on a five-year partnership which has seen the successful launch of 10 i-mate™ devices on the Telstra network, Telstra has teamed up with i-mate™ again to release the Ultimate mobile devices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;AHA&amp;rdquo; - So, they are not vaporware after all :) !!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://android-developers.blogspot.com/2008/02/android-sdk-m5-rc14-now-available.html">Android SDK m5-rc14 now available&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>*&lt;strong>New user interface&lt;/strong> - As I mentioned when we introduced the m3 version of the Android SDK, we&amp;rsquo;re continuing to refine the UI that&amp;rsquo;s available for Android. m5-rc14 replaces the previous placeholder with a new UI, but as before, work on it is still in-progress.&lt;br>
&lt;em>&lt;strong>Layout animations&lt;/strong> - Developers can now create layout animations for their applications using the capabilities introduced in the android.view.animation package. Check out the LayoutAnimation&lt;/em>.java files in the APIDemos sample code for examples of how this works.&lt;br>
*&lt;strong>Geo-coding&lt;/strong> - android.location.Geocoder enables developers to forward and reverse geo-code (i.e. translate an address into a coordinate and vice-versa), and also search for businesses.&lt;br>
*&lt;strong>New media codecs&lt;/strong> - The MediaPlayer class has added support for the OGG Vorbis, MIDI, XMF, iMelody, RTTL/RTX, and OTA audio file formats.&lt;br>
*&lt;strong>Updated Eclipse plug-in&lt;/strong> - A new version of ADT is available and provides improvements to the Android developer experience. In particular, check out the new Android Manifest editor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;WOW&amp;rdquo; What else can I say?!!&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Looking for a Host - For a Party that you will throw</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/28/looking-for-a-host-for-a-party-that-you-will-throw/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2008 16:31:52 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/28/looking-for-a-host-for-a-party-that-you-will-throw/</guid><description>One thing that is most difficult to choose (after a dress for your girlfriend that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make her &amp;ldquo;look&amp;rdquo; fat) is choosing a webhost. A google search is going to even confuse you further. As you wade into this enormous ocean, you will be wowed by the offers given by some of these hosts, throwing away 100&amp;rsquo;s of GBs (no less) of disk space and bandwidth running into terrabytes. Almost every software on earth in your one-click fantastico arsenal.</description><content>&lt;p>One thing that is most difficult to choose (after a dress for your girlfriend that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make her &amp;ldquo;look&amp;rdquo; fat) is choosing a webhost. A google search is going to even confuse you further. As you wade into this enormous ocean, you will be wowed by the offers given by some of these hosts, throwing away 100&amp;rsquo;s of GBs (no less) of disk space and bandwidth running into terrabytes. Almost every software on earth in your one-click fantastico arsenal. (plus they promise to do your dishes after you are through with the dinner too). All this and more for a measly 3.99, 4.99, 5.99 and such price. Your jaw already touching the floor, you make a quick dash for your wallet, flip out your credit card, and sign up for that &amp;ldquo;limited time&amp;rdquo; offer for unlimited webspace before it expires. You then laugh at your friend who got a measly 100mb for the same price. But, what gives? Even a 100 GB hdd costs me close to 40-50 bucks, then how come they are able to do it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is no great Indian rope trick around it. The answer lies in just one term &amp;ldquo;oversell&amp;rdquo;. Yes, they oversell their available disk space and bandwidth to the tunes of 10s to 1000s of times, knowing that an average user will never use it up. Even if you do, then your account will be mysteriously suspended for &amp;ldquo;violating the AUP&amp;rdquo;. The AUP practically bans you from doing anything. It is a blend of the most hideous legal jargon signing on which might be equal to bequething all your savings to the host and you will never even come to know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, this post is just meant to be a word of caution for you to stay away from all those big and small names, purportedly touted as the &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; on gazillions of sites across the web, and think again. If its too good to be true, it probably is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PS: Take a look at &lt;a href="http://webhostingtalk.com">http://webhostingtalk.com&lt;/a> if you want to gather some more info or comment here, or write to me.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>