<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lifehacker on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/lifehacker/</link><description>Recent content in Lifehacker on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 May 2008 19:16:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/lifehacker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Google's New Favicon</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/30/googles-new-favicon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2008 19:16:21 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/30/googles-new-favicon/</guid><description>It’s amazing, isn’t it? Even a sneeze at google makes the headlines. Well, it’s not the sneeze today but the new favicon I just got. So, are you also seeing the all new, re-designed, artisticly polished “g” as the new favicon?
In other news, my Twitter-Webcam integration post has bypassed my earlier lifehacked post about Remote File Access Through E-mail by more than a few thousands, even though the time difference between the two posts is more than 3 months.</description></item><item><title>One Month Completed....</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/28/one-month-completed/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 04:10:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/28/one-month-completed/</guid><description>Today, this blog completes one month of its existence in this world. The achievements, although minuscule in comparison to all the biggies out there, are significant for me. It achieved the following things in just 30 days from the first post:
Front-paged at LifeHacker, HacksZine, and many others.
Over 10000 (Ten Thousand) &amp;ldquo;unique&amp;rdquo; human visitors.
Over 30000 (Thirty Thousand) page views by humans.
Over 500000 (Half Million) total hits for all website files included.</description></item><item><title>Site Updates</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/22/site-updates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2008 05:05:04 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/22/site-updates/</guid><description>The site received a lot of new visitors yesterday as one of the small-time things that I do, received front page treatment at lifehacker. Thank you, Adam Pash, and thanks Murphy, for the original idea.</description></item><item><title>Project: Retrieve Files From Remote Computer Through E-mail</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/19/project-retrieve-files-from-remote-computer-through-e-mail/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2008 17:52:16 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/19/project-retrieve-files-from-remote-computer-through-e-mail/</guid><description>I came across this post on lifehacker today (original post and solution here), which talks about a method of retrieving files from a remote computer through e-mail. Pretty archaic, I know, but again, it is a very simple method and works behind all the firewalls and stuff . But, the catch is that it is only for mac’s. Thought of creating something similar for the PC and mashed together some code during lunch time at office to make our dear old outlook remote-file-sending-capable.</description></item><item><title>Remote File Access Through E-Mail</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/19/remote-file-access-through-e-mail/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2008 17:43:30 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/19/remote-file-access-through-e-mail/</guid><description>Introduction:
This is a (proof-of-concept) outlook macro that you can use with an outlook rule to retrieve your files from your home/office PC by sending it a mail with a subject having a predefined special keyword and the body containing the names and paths of the files. The remote PC will then mail you the files on a predefined e-mail ID.
This project came into being after reading this post at lifehacker (original post and solution here).</description></item></channel></rss>