<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>windows on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/windows/</link><description>Recent content in windows on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 04:46:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bugs: What you see is not always what it is</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2012/07/23/bugs-what-you-see-is-not-always-what-it-is/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 04:46:08 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2012/07/23/bugs-what-you-see-is-not-always-what-it-is/</guid><description>Came across a neat nugget of historical information today that yet again proves that the software/hardware bug behavior that you may see on the surface might imply something totally opposite to what the problem actually is.
The &amp;ldquo;bug&amp;rdquo; existed back in the old times of the floppy drives. These drives seemed to fail very quickly on linux systems compared to MS DOS/Windows. Now, a normal observer would say linux had bad handling of the drives or was doing something messy that made these drives crap out ever so often.</description></item><item><title>The Real Threat Of Windows Phone 7</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/28/the-real-threat-of-windows-phone-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2010 19:48:34 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/28/the-real-threat-of-windows-phone-7/</guid><description>Many people say that Windows Phone 7 is a threat to iPhone because they are bringing in a super platform with a choice of multiple designs and multiple carriers with great Enterprise and gaming support and maintaining the lucrative integration that iPhone provides. Many also say that Windows Phone 7 is a threat to Android because it solves the problem of Apple's draconian policies, gives choice to customers and all this without fragmenting the OS all over the place.</description></item><item><title>[TIP] Add Directories Recursively To Perforce (P4) Depot</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/03/add-directories-recursively-to-perforce-p4-depot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2009 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/03/add-directories-recursively-to-perforce-p4-depot/</guid><description>Perforce is an excellent revision control system for the code but the GUIs (P4WIN and P4V) are too slow to be productive. Hence, I like to do most of my work through command lines. Now, the other day I needed to add a directory and all its subdirectories and files to the repository (or perforce depot). This is a trivial task through the GUI. Just drag the top level directory onto the changelist area and the GUI takes care of everything but there is no straightforward way to do this through command line, until, I discovered the &amp;ldquo;-x&amp;rdquo; option of P4.</description></item><item><title>TIP: Free Downloads For Windows Vista, XP Professional, Visual Studio 2008, MSDN And Much More</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/08/tip-free-downloads-for-windows-vista-xp-professional-visual-studio-2008-msdn-and-much-more/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2008 19:31:52 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/08/tip-free-downloads-for-windows-vista-xp-professional-visual-studio-2008-msdn-and-much-more/</guid><description>If you are a student (this works for non-students as well but I expect you to be honest ;) ), you can download a whole bunch of software for free. How? Well, all you need is to become an ACM student member, and join the MSDN AA (Microsoft Developer Network Academic Alliance) ACM Student Benefit Program.
Normally it takes around 19$ for you to become a student member but you can do it for free for a limited time by going to http://campus.</description></item><item><title>SpiderOak Promotion Code For Free Upgrade To 10 GB</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/12/spideroak-promotion-code-for-free-upgrade-to-10-gb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2008 20:58:32 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/12/spideroak-promotion-code-for-free-upgrade-to-10-gb/</guid><description>Just a small shout out to let you guys know that you can use the discount coupon code “linkup” while signing up the excellent online backup service SpiderOak to get a major bump to 10 GB from the 2 GB that they give to normal accounts.
For those who don’t know SpiderOak is a great online data backup service, with its major strengths being truly cross paltform (Mac/Linux/Windows – 32 bit as well as 64 bit), easy interface, rsync like differential backups to save time and disk space, versioned file history, web as well as client interface, unlimited number of devices, unlimited bandwidth, etc etc.</description></item><item><title>Hi BIOS! My Name Is "Linux", Or Is It?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/03/hi-bios-my-name-is-linux-or-is-it/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2008 17:44:30 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/03/hi-bios-my-name-is-linux-or-is-it/</guid><description>A couple of days ago, I read this on Matthew Garrette’s blog, where he tells us about a vendor’s BIOS trying to figure out the OS type/version and setting things around on deciding the OS it is running. The call in question was _OSI(“Linux”). He goes on to say that the action the firmware takes, on finding out if the OS is linux, was probably inaccurate and it was good that linux kernel DOES NOT identify itself as “Linux” and returns false for the _OSI(“Linux”) and instead returns true when probed for Windows.</description></item><item><title>The Biggest Flaw in Gnome UI</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/07/the-biggest-flaw-in-gnome-ui/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2008 14:28:02 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/07/the-biggest-flaw-in-gnome-ui/</guid><description>Everywhere you go, any building you enter, any OS you operate, any settings window you open, one rule remains set in stone, “THE ESCAPE DOOR”. Always give an exit path, a way to make it all go away, make it look like nothing happened. But Gnome seems to think otherwise. Any settings window you open, all you see is a “close” button.
I made a few changes and then tried to “undo” them by using the following methods:</description></item><item><title>Want To Program Smartly In C? Use GLib</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/03/smart-programming-in-c-using-glib/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2008 15:30:16 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/03/smart-programming-in-c-using-glib/</guid><description>GLib - An Introduction:
GLib is a utility library for C, which augments the standard C library in several purposeful ways to make your life that much easier while programming. GLib has the following things to offer you:
**1. Portability: **The main issue that haunts any C developer is the portability of code. One cannot rely on the standard C library for this as you may find many functions that work differently under different platforms are aren't there at all sometimes.</description></item><item><title>Windows App Alternatives For Linux: MSPaint</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/28/windows-app-alternatives-for-linux-mspaint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2008 15:30:44 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/28/windows-app-alternatives-for-linux-mspaint/</guid><description>Some of you might know that I was in the hunt for a decent mspaint alternative recently. Note that I didn't go for GIMP / Inkscape etc because they were overkill for what I wanted to do. Many a times, I just wanted to touch up a screenshot or make a simple flow image by drawing a few boxes, use a few pointing arrows, and add some text here and there.</description></item><item><title>ImageMagick: Weaving Magic With Your Pictures</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/26/imagemagick-weaving-magic-with-your-pictures/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2008 06:23:18 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/26/imagemagick-weaving-magic-with-your-pictures/</guid><description>I’ve known about ImageMagick tools for quite some time now but never dabbled with it. A couple of weeks ago I played with it for some time (notice the new cascaded polaroid pics header above) and was amazed even more. Few of its shining features:
It has almost unlimited features to manipulate your images through its tools like convert, montage, mogrify etc and their long list of options.</description></item><item><title>5 Reasons I Like Linux (And 5 Why I Dislike It)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/19/5-reasons-i-like-linux-and-5-why-i-dislike-it/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2008 20:20:40 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/19/5-reasons-i-like-linux-and-5-why-i-dislike-it/</guid><description>Disclaimer Notes:
I wrote this because these things just came into my mind today while I was reading about the impending “Hardy Heron” release related things and saw that there is a lot of FUD being spread still. So, thought of jotting down my likes/dislikes and not making it a linux v/s windows campaign. Though at a few places, it might be necessary to compare the two just to put things into perspective.</description></item><item><title>TIP: Make Those Linux Samba Shares Accessible From Windows Mobile</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/30/tip-make-those-linux-samba-shares-accessible-from-windows-mobile/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2008 10:30:12 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/30/tip-make-those-linux-samba-shares-accessible-from-windows-mobile/</guid><description>If you have ever needed to share files between your Linux and Windows computers, you have obviously used Samba, and have been quite happy with the way it seamlessly provides access to and from shared folders/files from Windows and Linux. However, many people complain that although their smb/Samba shares are accessible from Windows, they are not able to do the same with their Windows Mobile devices. e.g., using a tool called &amp;ldquo;Resco Explorer&amp;rdquo; on Windows Mobile, all they get while searching for their linux based Samba shares is the following screenshot:</description></item><item><title>Project: Shantz Copy Basket (Compatible with linux as well as windows)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/16/project-shantz-copy-basket-compatible-with-linux-as-well-as-windows/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2008 13:26:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/16/project-shantz-copy-basket-compatible-with-linux-as-well-as-windows/</guid><description>I’m sure you have copied/moved files on your computer from one place to another. And I’m sure often you have to do more than just “single-shot” copying that is copy a few files to one place, move a few to another, and copy yet some more to one more location. Well, I had to do this quite a few times (e.g. I ran out of disk space recently on a partition and had to empty out my “Movies” and “Songs” folders to move a few movies/songs each to all other partitions/disks according to the space available).</description></item><item><title>Project: Retrieve Files From Remote Computer Through E-mail</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/19/project-retrieve-files-from-remote-computer-through-e-mail/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2008 17:52:16 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/19/project-retrieve-files-from-remote-computer-through-e-mail/</guid><description>I came across this post on lifehacker today (original post and solution here), which talks about a method of retrieving files from a remote computer through e-mail. Pretty archaic, I know, but again, it is a very simple method and works behind all the firewalls and stuff . But, the catch is that it is only for mac’s. Thought of creating something similar for the PC and mashed together some code during lunch time at office to make our dear old outlook remote-file-sending-capable.</description></item><item><title>Remote File Access Through E-Mail</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/19/remote-file-access-through-e-mail/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2008 17:43:30 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/19/remote-file-access-through-e-mail/</guid><description>Introduction:
This is a (proof-of-concept) outlook macro that you can use with an outlook rule to retrieve your files from your home/office PC by sending it a mail with a subject having a predefined special keyword and the body containing the names and paths of the files. The remote PC will then mail you the files on a predefined e-mail ID.
This project came into being after reading this post at lifehacker (original post and solution here).</description></item></channel></rss>