<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Geeks on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/geeks/</link><description>Recent content in Geeks on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2008 22:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/geeks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tip: Gadgets, Deals And Stuff You Need To Know - Part II</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/06/04/tip-gadgets-deals-and-stuff-you-need-to-know-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2008 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/06/04/tip-gadgets-deals-and-stuff-you-need-to-know-part-ii/</guid><description>Last time we discussed how to select the gadget that you want to buy. This time I’ll tell you some of the things that I do to find the best price for it.
Use Price Comparison Engines: These engines will let you search for your desired products and provide a comparison of the costs at which they are available at different stores online as well as offline. Two of my favourites are Price Grabber and Froogle.</description><content>&lt;p>Last time we discussed &lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/2008/06/02/tip-gadgets-deals-and-stuff-you-need-to-know-part-i.html">how to select the gadget&lt;/a> that you want to buy. This time I’ll tell you some of the things that I do to find the best price for it.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Use Price Comparison Engines&lt;/strong>: These engines will let you search for your desired products and provide a comparison of the costs at which they are available at different stores online as well as offline. Two of my favourites are &lt;a href="http://www.pricegrabber.com/">Price Grabber&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.froogle.com/">Froogle&lt;/a>. Price Grabber has the added benefits of providing user reviews about the product as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Deal Sites&lt;/strong>: Many sites across the web aggregate the latest deals. Some are run by the site owners, e.g., &lt;a href="http://www.deals2buy.com/">Deals2Buy&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.hotdealsclub.com/">HotDealsClub&lt;/a> etc, which are mostly almost same to each other. Some are run by the community, e.g. &lt;a href="http://slickdeals.net/">slickdeals&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://fatwallet.com/">fatwallet&lt;/a>, etc.These have an added advantage that the discussion that takes place on the original discussion adds a lot of value and insight in terms of how to stack on even better deals on top of it, provides comparison to other deals, rumours about coming deals in advance, and even deals local to your state, city or a particular store as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Bargain Sites&lt;/strong>: These sites sell overstocked products at a cheap price. Some of the popular ones are &lt;a href="http://overstock.com/">Overstock&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.smartbargains.com/">Smart Bargains&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://woot.com/">W00t&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://stootsi.com/">Stootsi&lt;/a>, etc. W00t and Stootsi are a bit different in the sense that they have very limited number of products available at a time for sale (generally just 1).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Coupon Codes Sites&lt;/strong>: Many sites aggregate coupon codes for various online and offline stores that you can use with your purchase to lower the price further. However, you need to go through the terms and conditions of the coupon to make sure that it applies to your purchase, and you might also need some convincing powers to use them in some cases :) . Some of the sites are &lt;a href="http://www.wow-coupons.com/">Wow-Coupons&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.currentcodes.com/">Current Codes&lt;/a>.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Mail In Rebates&lt;/strong>: Mail In Rebates are a great way to save a lot of money and even make money on buying things. Basically what you have to do is fill in a form and send it to a given address along with proof of purchase or UPC code. And anywhere between 2–10 weeks you’ll receive a check for the said amount. So, be on the lookout for mail in rebates on manufacturers’ or sellers’ sites. But beware that mail-in-rebates don’t have 100% reliability. They might take a lot of time and might not even come. So, you better depend on them only if you are in US for more than a few weeks and keep tracking them through your mail-in-rebates’ tracking site.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Cash Back&lt;/strong>: Many sites give cash backs if you go to the seller’s site through them. An example for this is Fat Wallet.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Pricematch&lt;/strong>: This is a great weapon that most people don’t know about or don’t take into consideration. Many shops (generally brick n mortar ones) give a lowest price gaurantee and if you are getting a product at a cheaper rate some place else, they will give u a discount on the difference. e.g. Staples has a 110% price match policy, so if they sell smthing at 50$, and some other place sells it 40$, then they will give it to you for 50 – 1.1x(50–40) = 39$. But many shops will price match to offline shops online and some will consider online ones as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Use Your Mouth (and brains)&lt;/strong>: Don’t think wrong, you perverts ;). By mouth I mean “talking/conversing/convincing”. You can even negotiate prices at many places (Search for the BestBuy motto), and many times you need to convince the floor managers to allow you to stack on coupons after coupons over a product that is already being given at a discount and then get a couple of freebies as well ;).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Well, this is by no means a complete list but I’ve tried to list the most important ones atleast. If I missed out on something, or if you have your own strategies or sites you visit to get the best deals, please share it with us as well.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Tip: Gadgets, Deals And Stuff You Need To Know - Part I</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/06/02/tip-gadgets-deals-and-stuff-you-need-to-know-part-i/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2008 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/06/02/tip-gadgets-deals-and-stuff-you-need-to-know-part-i/</guid><description>If you are a gadget freak like me and can’t resist the temptations to buy the newest toy on the shelves, then you’d obviously want to eek out the maximum you can from whatever budget you have. But while doing so you have to take care of a lot of things. Here is Part I of the few things that I do get the best deals out there while making sure I’m buying the right thing from the right place.</description><content>&lt;p>If you are a gadget freak like me and can’t resist the temptations to buy the newest toy on the shelves, then you’d obviously want to eek out the maximum you can from whatever budget you have. But while doing so you have to take care of a lot of things. Here is Part I of the few things that I do get the best deals out there while making sure I’m buying the right thing from the right place.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first step to buying anything is obviously whether you are buying the right thing. The list of do’s and don’t and this regard are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Do not blindly go by the what the manufacturer’s site says. After all I’ll always say that I my product is the best.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Do not just make the decision based on the feature set. More features mean more possible points of failure, so a device with fewer features but better reliability is obviously much better than the one that promises the moon but only the “once in a blue -“ kinds.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Make sure to search for similar products from other manufacturers. Just because it comes from Apple’s stable doesn’t make it the best. (For the record, in general, I don’t like anything that comes from Cupertino)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Look for the reviews. Search for the reviews for the product you have in mind, but a big problem with this has now arisen with the advent of “paid reviews”. But of course, you can always turn towards the community. Read through all the site-based single person reviews as well but also look for forums and other communities related to the type of gadget you have in mind. e.g. – For cameras, DPReview is a good place to go, for WM smart phones, XDA-Developers is the place to be, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Is the after-sales support good? You don’t want to be locked out with a product that you can’t do anything about if something goes wrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Look also for the hidden costs of product. Many a times the base product is cheap but then it requires you to shell out a fortune in terms of required accessories to yield it’s full potential (e.g. Archos players).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Maintenance costs:e.g. Most Apple products dont have easily replaceable parts and need to be sent back to factory for even things like a new battery.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Now, the list above seems small but when put into practice it isn’t. But obviously, a geek who can handle all the latest electronic gizmos can surely handle the irks that come while chosing one, and of course, within a short while, it will become second nature to you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Are there any other things that you look for buying your new boy-toy? Do let me know. Next time, we will look at how to get the best deals for the stuff you crave.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>My Top 5 Comics For The Geeks</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/26/my-top-5-comics-for-the-geeks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2008 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/26/my-top-5-comics-for-the-geeks/</guid><description>If you think that all geeks do is walk around wearing thick glasses, code in unreadable languages and make weird gizmos from parts scrapped out of your junkyard, well you think wrong. We do like to have our share of fun. And what better to begin the day with a nice hot cuppa along with some geeky humour. Folks, here it is, the 5 comic strips that I love the most (in no particular order):</description><content>&lt;p>If you think that all geeks do is walk around wearing thick glasses, code in unreadable languages and make weird gizmos from parts scrapped out of your junkyard, well you think wrong. We do like to have our share of fun. And what better to begin the day with a nice hot cuppa along with some geeky humour. Folks, here it is, the 5 comic strips that I love the most (in no particular order):&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1. &lt;a href="http://dilbert.com/">Dilbert&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>: Our friendly neighbourhood engineer is in town. Have fun reading through his daily life&amp;rsquo;s traumas. Of course, his tragedies couldn&amp;rsquo;t be as funny without the able support of the likes of Wally, Asok, dogbert, catbert, and yeah the &amp;ldquo;pointy haired manager&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2. &lt;a href="http://xkcd.com/">XKCD&lt;/a>:&lt;/strong> Don&amp;rsquo;t know if this is the abbreviated form of something but the author calls it a webcomic of romance, sarcasm, math, and language. You&amp;rsquo;d be frowning at your monitor screen right now, trying to understand the relation between these things but you know the saying, There is the biggest order behind the biggest chaos (or something, I just made up that saying just now :-) )&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**3. &lt;a href="http://userfriendly.org/">Userfriendly&lt;/a>: **This is a story about a small ISP with your regular, average joe, sys-admins having a fun time at the expense of their unsuspecting management and, of course, about Pitr who has bigger plans for world domination than even google.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**4. &lt;a href="http://www.cad-comic.com/">Ctrl+Alt+Del&lt;/a>: **Your last resort on Windows is now your daily appetite in the form of this little story about (mis)adventures of a group of nerdy friends who just love to get into trouble, all while playing that game of Halo with one hand (and that too tied behind their backs).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>5. &lt;a href="http://www.penny-arcade.com/comic/">Penny Arcade&lt;/a>:&lt;/strong> If you are a gamer, you can&amp;rsquo;t miss this. Even &amp;ldquo;Jack Thomson&amp;rdquo; couldn&amp;rsquo;t, so you know, this one is a keeper ;-).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, go and have a nice time and yeah, don&amp;rsquo;t forget to tell me about what are your favourite tech comics.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>