<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ATi on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/ati/</link><description>Recent content in ATi on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 May 2009 17:46:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/ati/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why You Should Not Upgrade to Ubuntu Jaunty Jackalope (9.04)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/05/04/ubuntu-904-jaunty-jackalope-upgrade-graphics-problem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2009 17:46:40 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/05/04/ubuntu-904-jaunty-jackalope-upgrade-graphics-problem/</guid><description>Update: It has come to my notice that many people do not know about this (and other problems listed in comments of this post). Please digg and reddit this post so that more people can be made aware of it before they upgrade unknowingly.
You should not upgrade to Ubuntu 9.04 (aka Jaunty Jackalope), released a few weeks ago, if:
You have an older ATI graphics card (prior to R500, .</description></item><item><title>HTC Video Drivers: But This Is Not A Post About HTC</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/26/htc-video-drivers-but-this-is-not-a-post-about-htc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 11:14:36 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/26/htc-video-drivers-but-this-is-not-a-post-about-htc/</guid><description>This is a post about irresponsible/careless journalism/bloggism. For Gizmodo, getting that post about HTC’s latest press release out the door took precedence over actually **reading **the release properly and then commenting over it. The gizmodo poster’s comment is:
……but HTC&amp;rsquo;s finally released a statement saying that a fix is coming. They say that the video acceleration will be supported in the future, and will be included in software upgrades for current devices…….</description></item><item><title>AMD (ATi) Step Up The Tempo</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/28/amd-ati-step-up-the-tempo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2008 16:01:45 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/28/amd-ati-step-up-the-tempo/</guid><description>AMD has been taking a lot of flak lately in its processor business, and a similar (albeit milder) thrashing was being given to its ATi Gfx line up as well. But they seem to be on the recover track now, with the release of the brand spanking new HD3870X2 series, some people aptly calling it &amp;ldquo;crossfire on a card&amp;rdquo;. All you gamers, please stop drooling on the screen now, and check out some benchmarks.</description></item></channel></rss>