<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bash on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/bash/</link><description>Recent content in Bash on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 03:00:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/bash/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Weekend Hack: Shoutcast2Dropbox - Automatic Shoutcast Stations To Dropbox Recorder</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2015/02/16/weekend-hack-shoutcast2dropbox-automatic-shoutcast-stations-to-dropbox-recorder/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 03:00:19 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2015/02/16/weekend-hack-shoutcast2dropbox-automatic-shoutcast-stations-to-dropbox-recorder/</guid><description>So I got bored of listening to same old songs on my phone over and over and Rdio announced a streaming plan for India. With a sigh of relief I subscribed immediately and it was stellar at home with its wonderful 32 million song collection and chromecast support to boot. The experience during the commute daily was underwhelming. Couple the spotty airtel data connection with no one station covering all songs I would love and it makes for a frustrating commute with long gaps all over.</description></item><item><title>Tip: Commands To Find Out The Shell You Are Using</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/27/tip-commands-to-find-out-the-shell-you-are-using/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2009 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/27/tip-commands-to-find-out-the-shell-you-are-using/</guid><description>Many times you might not be sure about which shell you are currently using. Especially if you are not on your system and logging into someone else&amp;rsquo;s, or maybe ssh&amp;rsquo;ing into a remote server. Worry not, because here are few simple commands that you can use to find out which shell you are using currently.
Command (Note: This one is a bit unreliable as it might not work with non-bash shells or on redirection.</description></item><item><title>TIP: Switching Soundcards In Ubuntu</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/12/tip-switching-soundcards-in-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2008 18:00:47 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/12/tip-switching-soundcards-in-ubuntu/</guid><description>If you have multiple soundcards in your system and have to switch between them regularly (e.g. laptop owners like me, who use an external soundcard while being docked to groove to the highest and the lowest of frequencies through those 7.1 channels and use the in-built sound card while on the move) you would definitely be under-whelmed by the less-than-stellar performance of ubuntu in switching between the sound cards. For me at least, ubuntu (fiesty 7.</description></item></channel></rss>