<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Chrome on</title><link>/tags/chrome/</link><description>Recent content in Chrome on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 04:26:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/chrome/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Use Encrypted Google Search As Default in Chrome</title><link>/2011/05/12/use-encrypted-google-search-as-default-in-chrome/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 04:26:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2011/05/12/use-encrypted-google-search-as-default-in-chrome/</guid><description>Google just launched an encrypted search portal which is a Godsend for people on public networks since there is a lot that can be gleaned from your search queries. For doing your protected searches, however, you have to go to a different portal which I linked to above. Now, the omnibar (the address bar in Google Chrome) also serves as a search box but searches on the normal google portal by default.</description><content>&lt;p>Google just launched an &lt;a href="https://encrypted.google.com/">encrypted search portal&lt;/a> which is a Godsend for people on public networks since there is a lot that can be gleaned from your search queries. For doing your protected searches, however, you have to go to a different portal which I linked to above. Now, the omnibar (the address bar in Google Chrome) also serves as a search box but searches on the normal google portal by default. Here is a simple, few seconds process to switch it over to encrypted search.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the wrench/tool icon at the top of Google Chrome and go to Options.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On the &amp;ldquo;Basics&amp;rdquo; tab, go to the &amp;ldquo;Search&amp;rdquo; item and click on &amp;ldquo;Manage Search Engines&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Go to the very bottom of the new page that opens and you will see three empty boxes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>For the first box (leftmost), give any nickname for the engine. I gave &amp;ldquo;EncryptedGoogle&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>For second box, give a keyword that invokes the new search engine. I gave &amp;ldquo;encrypted.google.com&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>For last box, give the url for the search engine. This should be&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;code>https://encrypted.google.com/search?{google:RLZ}{google:acceptedSuggestion}{google:originalQueryForSuggestion}sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie={inputEncoding}&amp;amp;q=%s&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="7">
&lt;li>Press Enter and the engine will be added to the list. Then hover over the engine row and click on &amp;ldquo;Make as default&amp;rdquo;. And you are done.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Happy safe searching :)&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Firefox Incognito / Private Browsing Mode - Part II</title><link>/2008/09/11/firefox-incognito-private-browsing-mode-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2008 16:59:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/09/11/firefox-incognito-private-browsing-mode-part-ii/</guid><description>A few people (e.g. Varun) told me my previous post differed from the way how google chrome / Microsoft IE8 handle Incognito (Private Browsing) mode. The main consideration was that while chrome/IE8 don&amp;rsquo;t write anything to disk at all, the firefox method is an after-effect, i.e., writing to disk and then clearing it up while closing the window. Well, true but nothing is non-rectificable :). So this is a post about a method that one can use to go &amp;ldquo;really&amp;rdquo; undercover with firefox.</description><content>&lt;p>A few people (e.g. &lt;a href="http://paheli.net/blog/2008/09/11/security-and-usability-google-chromes-incognito-mode/">Varun&lt;/a>) told me &lt;a href="/2008/09/10/firefox-incognito-mode-is-here-move-over-chromeie8.html">my previous post&lt;/a> differed from the way how google chrome / Microsoft IE8 handle Incognito (Private Browsing) mode. The main consideration was that while chrome/IE8 don&amp;rsquo;t write anything to disk at all, the firefox method is an after-effect, i.e., writing to disk and then clearing it up while closing the window. Well, true but nothing is non-rectificable :). So this is a post about a method that one can use to go &amp;ldquo;really&amp;rdquo; undercover with firefox. But before we begin, please make sure you have read Part 1 of my post, because here I&amp;rsquo;ll start from the point where we left off in the earlier post.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I began thinking on the lines of setting up a ramdisk first (and remapping the browser cache folders to the new path in this ramdisk), so that nothing gets written to the hard disk, ever, even if the browser tries very hard. Best security right? Yes, but it involved a few issues like data is still there until you reboot also a part of your ram is always blocked, etc. So I went with the approach given below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Method: Easier and privacy on-par with Chrome/IE8&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just do the following in addition to the Step 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Uncheck &amp;ldquo;Keep my history&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Uncheck &amp;ldquo;Remember what I enter in forms and the search bar&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Uncheck &amp;ldquo;Remember what I&amp;rsquo;ve downloaded&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Choose &amp;ldquo;Keep until I close firefox&amp;rdquo; for cookies&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Press advanced settings in &amp;ldquo;Private Data&amp;rdquo;, select unselect options according to your choice. For max protection, select everything.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Open a new tab, and write &amp;ldquo;about:config&amp;rdquo; (without quotes) in address bar, press enter.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Search for &amp;ldquo;browser.cache.disk.enable&amp;rdquo; and set it to false&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Search for &amp;ldquo;browser.cache.offline.enable&amp;rdquo; and set it to false&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Done. You are secure and remember, this is just a one time setup, you won&amp;rsquo;t have to do this again and again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Side Note: Usability is another concern. However, I think that is debatable and varies from user to user highly. The steps lined up in these 2 posts aren&amp;rsquo;t too hard to carry out and take around a minute to do, and is a one time effort. Now, compare this with option where you use google chrome and love its in-built incognito mode but then have to leave all the extensions and greasemonkey scripts of firefox behind which made browsing so much more accessible for you. Another path could be to use both the browsers. Anyways, I&amp;rsquo;ll not go further down this path. This is for you to decide what you feel is more usable for you :) . This is just something to say &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not impossible&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PS: If anyone is still curious about the ramdisk approach, let me know..&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Firefox Incognito Mode Is Here: Move Over Chrome/IE8</title><link>/2008/09/10/firefox-incognito-mode-is-here-move-over-chromeie8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2008 17:49:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/09/10/firefox-incognito-mode-is-here-move-over-chromeie8/</guid><description>Update: Part 2 of this post is now up here to allay some of the drawbacks that were pointed out.
There has been so much hype over the “Incognito” (or Private Browsing) mode of Google Chrome / Microsoft IE8, with many internet users screeming Hallelujiah. But I don’t understand what the hoopla is all about. This mode has always been there in Mozilla firefox as well. You just need to devote less than one minute (yes, you read that right, less than one minute) to set it up.</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update:&lt;/strong> Part 2 of this post is now up &lt;a href="/2008/09/11/firefox-incognito-private-browsing-mode-part-ii.html">here&lt;/a> to allay some of the drawbacks that were pointed out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There has been so much hype over the “Incognito” (or Private Browsing) mode of Google Chrome / Microsoft IE8, with many internet users screeming Hallelujiah. But I don’t understand what the hoopla is all about. This mode has always been there in Mozilla firefox as well. You just need to devote less than one minute (yes, you read that right, less than one minute) to set it up. Well, actions are better than words, so here it goes:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Step 1.) Run the following command to start the firefox profile manager.(In Linux, press Alt+F2 and in Windows, press Win+R to bring up the run dialogue box)&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>If it says something on the lines of “cannot find command” then use full path to firefox/firefox.exe in linux/Windows respectively.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/img/uploads/firefox_2Dprofile_2Dmanager.jpg">&lt;img src="/img/uploads/firefox_2Dprofile_2Dmanager_thumb.jpg" alt="Firefox-profile-manager">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Step 2.) Press “Create Profile” and enter “Incognito” (or a name of your choice) as your new profile name and press “Finish”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/img/uploads/firefox_2Dprofile_2Dmanager2.jpg">&lt;img src="/img/uploads/firefox_2Dprofile_2Dmanager2_thumb.jpg" alt="Firefox-profile-manager2">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Step 3.) Select “Incognito” profile and press “Start Firefox”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/img/uploads/firefox_2Dprofile_2Dmanager3.jpg">&lt;img src="/img/uploads/firefox_2Dprofile_2Dmanager3_thumb.jpg" alt="Firefox-profile-manager3">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Step 4.) Go to Edit-&amp;gt;Preferences-&amp;gt;Privacy. Select “Always clear my private data when I close Firefox” and unselect “Ask me before clearing private data”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/img/uploads/firefox_2Dprivacy_2Dpreferences.jpg">&lt;img src="/img/uploads/firefox_2Dprivacy_2Dpreferences_thumb.jpg" alt="Firefox-privacy-preferences">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Step 5.) That’s it. Setup is done. Now, whenever you want to go undercover, run the following command&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Note 1: You can run incognito mode and normal mode together simultaneously.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note 2: Its advised that you put the above command in a shortcut for easy/quick access.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Isn’t that simple? Now, can you roll back that drool factor of being able to go “undercover” in google chrome or Internet Explorer 8?&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>