<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Opera on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/opera/</link><description>Recent content in Opera on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 08:17:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/opera/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Opera Web Server In A Browser: Bad Idea</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/06/17/opera-web-server-browser-bad-idea/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 08:17:04 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/06/17/opera-web-server-browser-bad-idea/</guid><description>Today, the whole word is going gaga over &amp;ldquo;Opera Unite&amp;rdquo;, the new technology in Opera 10 which will make your web browser a web server as well (and not just that, it will make a whole lot of “sharing” options available). Well, I’m not so excited about it. Technology wise, it is really cool but what they don’t realize is that this is like giving motorized chain-saw or a swiss army knife in the hands of a two-year old.</description><content>&lt;p>Today, the whole word is going gaga over &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://unite.opera.com/">Opera Unite&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo;, the new technology in Opera 10 which will make your web browser a web server as well (and not just that, it will make a whole lot of “sharing” options available). Well, I’m not so excited about it. Technology wise, it is really cool but what they don’t realize is that this is like giving motorized chain-saw or a swiss army knife in the hands of a two-year old. Seriously, majority of the people around the world who get themselves into all sorts of shit while just plain surfing the net, now got a whole new array of avenues where they can be exploited upon. For people who do need a webserver, there are plenty of straight-forward point and click options available. I hope they atleast have options to completely turn it off and even better, keep it turned off by default.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>