<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Boycott Novell on</title><link>/tags/boycott-novell/</link><description>Recent content in Boycott Novell on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2008 09:38:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/boycott-novell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Boycott Novell Protestors Manhandled By National Free Software Conference 2008 Organizers</title><link>/2008/11/16/boycott-novell-protestors-manhandled-by-national-free-software-conference-2008-organizers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2008 09:38:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/11/16/boycott-novell-protestors-manhandled-by-national-free-software-conference-2008-organizers/</guid><description>This is a really sad day. Not only the organizers of National Conference On Free Software 2008 taking place at CUSAT seem to be utterly misguided when they decided to let Novell be on-board as their main sponsor, they even took the extreme step of bringing in police to silence the lone voices of the Boycott Novell protestors. They seem to be treading on the toes of not just free software but free speech as well, which is against the very ethics of the conference they are holding.</description><content>&lt;p>This is a really sad day. Not only the organizers of National Conference On Free Software 2008 taking place at CUSAT seem to be utterly misguided when they decided to let Novell be on-board as their main sponsor, they even took the extreme step of bringing in police to silence the lone voices of the Boycott Novell protestors. They seem to be treading on the toes of not just free software but free speech as well, which is against the very ethics of the conference they are holding. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure whether the conference organizers took this step on their own or in cahoots with Novell-Microsoft &amp;ldquo;gang&amp;rdquo; but whatever happened was unfortunate. You can see the pictures on &lt;a href="http://playingwithsid.blogspot.com/2008/11/boycott-novell-protesters-man-handled.html">Arky&amp;rsquo;s Blog&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is not something we should just sit and watch and should raise our voice against it. Please &lt;a href="http://digg.com/linux_unix/Boycott_Novell_Protestors_Manhandled_at_Free_Software_Conf">digg this post&lt;/a>, forward this link to your friends, write about it on your own blogs and spread the word.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>