<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>android wi-fi sleep policy on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/android-wi-fi-sleep-policy/</link><description>Recent content in android wi-fi sleep policy on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2010 05:27:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/android-wi-fi-sleep-policy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Android App: Wi-Fi Keep Alive updates</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/09/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive-updates/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2010 05:27:27 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/09/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive-updates/</guid><description>I pushed out a couple of updates to my android app Wi-Fi Keep alive a few weeks ago (mainly related to fixing the resolution and colors of the widget icons) taking the latest version to 1.4.4. This is just to let you know that it will take a while (a few weeks) more to get the pending updates and requests in to the program. I have been pretty ill for the last few weeks and have only just got back up out of the bed and now my development machine has also gone for a toss.</description></item><item><title>Android App Wi-Fi Keep Alive updated to 1.4.1</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/22/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive-updated-1-4-0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2010 16:58:07 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/22/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive-updated-1-4-0/</guid><description>Update: Made a minor update for a small bug that can make wi-fi keep reconnecting in quick succession.
Pushed out a new update to my Android App Wi-Fi Keep Alive today. This update brings in another work around for the issue where the wi-fi is alive on the phone and it is also connected to the network but is somehow unable to send/receive any packets to the network. The new work around will automatically re-associate your phone with the wi-fi router if it detects such a situation.</description></item><item><title>Android App: Wi-Fi Keep Alive Updated to 1.2.0</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/03/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive-updated-to-1-2-0/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2010 22:46:36 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/03/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive-updated-to-1-2-0/</guid><description>Just finished uploading the new version 1.2.0 of my android app Wi-Fi Keep Alive to the Android market. This version has a lot of optimizations and also a few workarounds to overcome the issues few guys were facing with Android&amp;rsquo;s in-built handling of wi-fi sleep policies.
Changes done in this version:
Added workarounds to take care of sleep policies not working on some phones
Optimized the code a bit for faster operations</description></item></channel></rss>