<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>India $35 Tablet on</title><link>/tags/india-35-tablet/</link><description>Recent content in India $35 Tablet on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 18:04:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/india-35-tablet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>iWebLeaf - India's $35 Android Tablet Spawning Fake Innovators?</title><link>/posts/iwebleaf-indias-35-android-tablet-spawning-fake-innovators/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 18:04:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/iwebleaf-indias-35-android-tablet-spawning-fake-innovators/</guid><description>It was just about an year ago that we heard about the $35 Android Tablet from India which would revolutionize the education in developing countries. Mr. Kapil Sibal promoted it with utmost fervor until it was found that the BoM itself of the tablet was more than $50 and none of the guys claimed to have &amp;ldquo;invented&amp;rdquo; it even knew about its existence until a few days before the announcement. Ultimately, it was discovered that the tablet was just a rebranded chinese import which the government wanted to bring down to $35 price point by subsidizing the cost and not by somehow inventing cheaper parts.</description></item><item><title>The Great Indian $35 Tablet Hoax?</title><link>/posts/the-great-indian-35-tablet-hoax/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2010 09:59:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-great-indian-35-tablet-hoax/</guid><description>Another nail in the coffin before this Android tablet lives to fulfill the Indian kids’ dreams. Well, not exactly a nail in the coffin. The tablet might still be here, and at the price promised but the thing to note is how low the government can stoop to get bragging rights (and votes). The article elaborates how the IIT/IISC scientists weren’t even aware that such a “project” existed and they were invited to be a part of it just a month before Mr.</description></item></channel></rss>