<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nokia Morph on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/nokia-morph/</link><description>Recent content in Nokia Morph on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2008 14:50:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/nokia-morph/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>X-Men Are Here, Only That They Are In Your Hands</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/25/x-men-are-here-only-that-they-are-in-your-hands/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2008 14:50:23 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/25/x-men-are-here-only-that-they-are-in-your-hands/</guid><description>Who wouldn’t agree that Morph is most probably the coolest mutant (besides Wolverine of of course ). Now, it seems that the Finnish Giant Nokia has a lot of X-Men lovers as well, as they put out their latest offering to us lesser mortals. They call it “The Morph Concept”.
Featured in The Museum of Modern Art “Design and The Elastic Mind” exhibition, the Morph concept device is a bridge between highly advanced technologies and their potential benefits to end-users.</description><content>&lt;p>Who wouldn’t agree that Morph is most probably the coolest mutant (besides Wolverine of of course &lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/smile1.gif" alt=""> ). Now, it seems that the Finnish Giant Nokia has a lot of X-Men lovers as well, as they put out their latest offering to us lesser mortals. They call it “&lt;a href="http://www.nokia.com/A4852062">The Morph Concept&lt;/a>”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/nokia_2Dmorph_2Dconcept_2Dnano_2Dmaterials_small.jpg" alt="Nokia-morph-concept-nano-materials">&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Featured in The Museum of Modern Art “Design and The Elastic Mind” exhibition, the Morph concept device is a bridge between highly advanced technologies and their potential benefits to end-users. This device concept showcases some revolutionary leaps being explored by Nokia Research Center (NRC) in collaboration with the Cambridge Nanoscience Centre (United Kingdom) – nanoscale technologies that will potentially create a world of radically different devices that open up an entirely new spectrum of possibilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Yeah, yeah, museum-shmuseum, nanotech-shanotech. All I know is that until I see this thing up on &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->, my call is “vaporware”.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>