<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Quote of the Day on</title><link>/tags/quote-of-the-day/</link><description>Recent content in Quote of the Day on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2008 15:44:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/quote-of-the-day/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Project: "shantz-wp-qotd ", My Wordpress Plugin, Updated to 1.1.0</title><link>/posts/project-shantz-wp-qotd-my-wordpress-plugin-update-to-110/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2008 15:44:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/project-shantz-wp-qotd-my-wordpress-plugin-update-to-110/</guid><description>For the uninitiated:
I made a few additions / modifications to the code and the plugin has been updated to 1.1.0. The changes are:
Added Custom tag support for adding quotes anywhere in your posts/pages
Added Custom quote separator support and multi-line quotes support
Config Screenshots:
I recommend that you update to this new version asap, as apart from the above mentioned changes, the code is a bit more cleaner as well, which would run a bit better IMO and also help in any modification if you have in mind.</description></item><item><title>My First WordPress Plugin: Please Welcome shantz-wp-qotd</title><link>/posts/my-first-wordpress-plugin-please-welcome-shantz-wp-qotd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 11:00:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/my-first-wordpress-plugin-please-welcome-shantz-wp-qotd/</guid><description>Motivated by Ronald’s ultimate wordpress plugin tutorial at devlounge, I decided that the best way to learn something is to use it in a live project. Armed with my laptop and multiple flasks of coffee, the marathon began on Friday night. My only experience with web-related development so far had been around 8–10 years ago as a kid when, just like everybody else at that time, I was fascinated by HTML and did a “read-through” of HTML 4.</description></item><item><title>Shantz WordPress QOTD</title><link>/posts/shantz-wordpress-qotd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 10:22:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/shantz-wordpress-qotd/</guid><description>Shantz WP QOTD is a plugin to add quotes to your wordpress blog in a few easy clicks. It adds quotes to your posts and your sidebars with a multitude of options for sources and customization.
== Description ==
There are many quotes plugins out there. This one has been started with a view to have the best of features and options, ease of use and multiple sources to get the quotes from.</description></item></channel></rss>