<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>UNIX on</title><link>/tags/unix/</link><description>Recent content in UNIX on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2009 13:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/unix/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[TIP] Add Directories Recursively To Perforce (P4) Depot</title><link>/posts/add-directories-recursively-to-perforce-p4-depot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2009 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/add-directories-recursively-to-perforce-p4-depot/</guid><description>Perforce is an excellent revision control system for the code but the GUIs (P4WIN and P4V) are too slow to be productive. Hence, I like to do most of my work through command lines. Now, the other day I needed to add a directory and all its subdirectories and files to the repository (or perforce depot). This is a trivial task through the GUI. Just drag the top level directory onto the changelist area and the GUI takes care of everything but there is no straightforward way to do this through command line, until, I discovered the &amp;ldquo;-x&amp;rdquo; option of P4.</description></item><item><title>Ubuntu TIP: Automating Package Installation – apt-get to the rescue</title><link>/posts/ubuntu-tip-automating-package-installation-%e2%80%93-apt-get-to-the-rescue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2008 03:30:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ubuntu-tip-automating-package-installation-%e2%80%93-apt-get-to-the-rescue/</guid><description>Admin Note: Rahul is a long time friend of mine, and is a well known geek amongst his friends and colleagues. I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce that he will be enriching this site from time-to-time as a guest editor/author. First up is a small tid-bit of a script that he wrote to ease up his life between installations and reinstallations of everyone&amp;rsquo;s favourite OS: Ubuntu. Over to his post..
Have you ever had to reinstall your ubuntu installation, and then bear the pain of manually installing the applications you&amp;rsquo;ve come to love (i mean use :)) everyday?</description></item></channel></rss>