<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>WM6.1 on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/wm6.1/</link><description>Recent content in WM6.1 on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2008 08:43:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/wm6.1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hack:Disabling the Message Box In Oxios Memory Apps (Windows Mobile)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/15/hackdisabling-the-message-box-in-oxios-memory-apps-windows-mobile/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2008 08:43:29 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/15/hackdisabling-the-message-box-in-oxios-memory-apps-windows-mobile/</guid><description>**Update: **Modified the &amp;ldquo;Oxios Hibernate&amp;rdquo; app as well on public demand. Please redownload the below mentioned package. It now has Oxios Close as well as Oxios Hibernate.
Oxios developed a very useful tool for Windows Mobile (WM2003/5/6/6.1) called &amp;ldquo;Oxios Memory&amp;rdquo; sometime ago. On running it, it&amp;rsquo;ll flush your RAM (kind of) and recover substantial amounts of memory that can be used by the currently program. It is so good at this that many people run it regularly on their phones, and most of them want to run it in an automated mode (through a scheduler or a script).</description></item><item><title>Project: ShantzTodayChanger (Windows Mobile Tool To Cycle Themes/Wallpapers Automatically)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/project-shantztodaychanger-windows-mobile-tool-to-cycle-themeswallpapers-automatically/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 19:45:07 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/project-shantztodaychanger-windows-mobile-tool-to-cycle-themeswallpapers-automatically/</guid><description>The newly launched [&amp;ldquo;Projects&amp;rdquo;] section is hereby inaugarated with a Windows Mobile Tool developed by me, called “[ShantzTodayChanger]”. This is a little tool for your Windows Mobile based phones (Compatible with WM5/WM6 but not WM2003) which will cycle ur today background or theme after a set interval of time. It has a lot of features and options that you can discover by reading the text below. And you can even use this options to achieve something other than changing wallpapers as well but that depends on your imagination.</description></item><item><title>WM6.1 Is Here, Loves HTC Wizard...(Really?)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/31/wm61-is-here-loves-htc-wizardreally/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2008 05:54:42 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/31/wm61-is-here-loves-htc-wizardreally/</guid><description>A user going by the remarkably simple handle &amp;ldquo;email123&amp;rdquo; announced on the xda-developers forum, that WM6.1 is here, alive and kicking. But he doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop there, he says that its available &amp;ldquo;now&amp;rdquo;, that too for an HTC wizard, a 3 year old phone (which I own as well). Thats not all, he goes on to provide the proof by linking in his cooked ROM for all to download. But, here is the clincher, he claims that finally &amp;ldquo;Big Storage&amp;rdquo; is available for wizard, a feat noone has been able to achieve in the last 3 years.</description></item></channel></rss>