<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Download on</title><link>/tags/download/</link><description>Recent content in Download on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2009 18:30:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/download/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Project: Shantz XWinWrap Update to 0.3</title><link>/2009/02/16/project-shantz-xwinwrap-update-to-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2009 18:30:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/02/16/project-shantz-xwinwrap-update-to-03/</guid><description>Here is another update for the fans of XWinWrap, the tiny program that allows you to run animated wallpapers on your system. You could use screensavers, movies and what not as your desktop background. This update fixes a segfault that many users were facing, a new debug option to print some debug mesages to get some info if it is not working for you and a new hack option for giving a &amp;ldquo;desktop window&amp;rdquo; name to the program.</description><content>&lt;p>Here is another update for the fans of XWinWrap, the tiny program that allows you to run animated wallpapers on your system. You could use screensavers, movies and what not as your desktop background. This update fixes a segfault that many users were facing, a new debug option to print some debug mesages to get some info if it is not working for you and a new hack option for giving a &amp;ldquo;desktop window&amp;rdquo; name to the program. On many systems, the desktop is drawn by another program. e.g. in Ubuntu with Gnome environment, the desktop is managed by Nautilus, which creates a special window called &amp;ldquo;Desktop&amp;rdquo; and places it over your real desktop. This window name can be different in different systems. To find out what is yours, just run &amp;ldquo;xwininfo&amp;rdquo; in a terminal. Your cursor will become a &amp;ldquo;+&amp;rdquo; sign. Click anywhere on an empty area on your desktop, which will give you the window name of the transparent window, if any, that is covering your desktop. Pass this info to xwinwrap using the option &amp;ldquo;-d windowname&amp;rdquo; and it would help it to run better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As usual, 32 bit as well as 64 bit binary files are available as downloads. For users of Debian and derived operating systems (like Ubuntu, Mepis, etc), deb packages are also included for both architectures for easy installation. Source code is also available, of course.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>TIP: Free Downloads For Windows Vista, XP Professional, Visual Studio 2008, MSDN And Much More</title><link>/2008/10/08/tip-free-downloads-for-windows-vista-xp-professional-visual-studio-2008-msdn-and-much-more/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2008 19:31:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/10/08/tip-free-downloads-for-windows-vista-xp-professional-visual-studio-2008-msdn-and-much-more/</guid><description>If you are a student (this works for non-students as well but I expect you to be honest ;) ), you can download a whole bunch of software for free. How? Well, all you need is to become an ACM student member, and join the MSDN AA (Microsoft Developer Network Academic Alliance) ACM Student Benefit Program.
Normally it takes around 19$ for you to become a student member but you can do it for free for a limited time by going to http://campus.</description><content>&lt;p>If you are a student (this works for non-students as well but I expect you to be honest ;) ), you can download a whole bunch of software for free. How? Well, all you need is to become an ACM student member, and join the MSDN AA (Microsoft Developer Network Academic Alliance) ACM Student Benefit Program.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Normally it takes around 19$ for you to become a student member but you can do it for free for a limited time by going to &lt;a href="http://campus.acm.org/icpc/">http://campus.acm.org/icpc/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, the steps to get all these software for free are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Go to the above mentioned link and sign up for ACM student membership&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Once you join, create an ACM web account&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Log into My ACM, and then opt into MSDN AA ACM Student Benefit Program (Look for the link: &lt;strong>Free Software for ACM Students&lt;/strong>)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You’ll get an approval email within 24 hours after which you can log on to your MSDN AA account and download your choice of softwares.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>The Softwares that you can now download for free through this are:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Windows Vista
Windows XP Professional
Windows Server 2008
Visual Studio 2008 Professional
Visio Professional2007
Office Project Professional 2007
Access 2007
Visual Studio 2005 Team System SQL Server 2005
Expression Studio
Sharepoint Designer 2007
Virtual PC 2007
Virtual PC for Mac 7.0.2
Visual C# 2005 Express Edition
Visual C++ 2005 Express Edition
And much, much more!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me know if this helped you out or if you have any other such free deals/tips of your own.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>