<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>India on</title><link>/tags/india/</link><description>Recent content in India on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 14:45:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/india/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Do They Really Know How To Sell Something In India?</title><link>/2008/08/26/do-they-really-know-how-to-sell-something-in-india/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 14:45:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/08/26/do-they-really-know-how-to-sell-something-in-india/</guid><description>Update: UK Ad Authorities have declared iPhone ad as &amp;ldquo;misleading&amp;rdquo;. I guess then they should declare it plain fraud in India.
This is a short rant about two of the &amp;ldquo;big&amp;rdquo; products launched recently in India in the last one week and how the people behind their sales/marketing teams either try to take the Indian customer for a ride, or shaft themselves.
iPhone: The big icon. Bharti Airtel/Vodafone claimed lakhs of pre-registrations, yet no one lined up to buy it.</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="http://www.mobileburn.com/news.jsp?Id=5176">UK Ad Authorities have declared iPhone ad as &amp;ldquo;misleading&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/a> I guess then they should declare it plain fraud in India.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a short rant about two of the &amp;ldquo;big&amp;rdquo; products launched recently in India in the last one week and how the people behind their sales/marketing teams either try to take the Indian customer for a ride, or shaft themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>iPhone&lt;/strong>: The big icon. Bharti Airtel/Vodafone claimed lakhs of pre-registrations, yet no one lined up to buy it. Anyways, to the point. The ads all over the print, digital and broadcast media in India list out 3 major points in one sentence:&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>1. **A 3G Phone:** My a$$. They haven't even finalized auction details for 3G spectrum in India yet.
2. **Desktop Class Browser:** Without Flash?
3. **Push E-mail:** Oh, the one that Apple already pulled the plug on?
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Anyways, even if this were to be true, nobody would have bought it for the steep price for something that hardly even performs properly as a phone.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>BIG TV&lt;/strong>: This is the &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; big one, from the stable of none other than Reliance/Anil Dhirubhai Ambani. Ok, it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be good, very good. I checked out &lt;a href="http://bigtv.co.in">their website&lt;/a> to see how good. What do I get?&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>1. A flash only site. No fallback. Did they get it coded from a high-school flash junkie?
2. After 15 minutes of looking around clicking on 10s of links, going in circles, I'm still confused. What exactly are their packages. There are so many rates and offers floating around. Everything promising something different, but wait, not available for your region. There are so many channels, more than your current DTH, but one second, WHAT exactly are thos channels. No list? For all I care, they could be endless streams of Doordarshan and ETV regional ones. (Please repeat the question I asked in point 1 here again)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Makes me wonder, do they really want to sell anything or Anil just made this out for fun, having a roaring time watching realtime website logs seeing people getting stuck and frustrated in the maze.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Indian Govt. vs Blackberry: Yet Another Example of Idiocy From Our "Leaders"</title><link>/2008/03/12/indian-govt-vs-blackberry-yet-another-example-of-idiocy-from-our-leaders/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2008 19:45:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/03/12/indian-govt-vs-blackberry-yet-another-example-of-idiocy-from-our-leaders/</guid><description>Just read on BGR, that RIM will have to close down its BlackBerry service in India if they don&amp;rsquo;t allow our government to snoop on every little piece of data that goes through it. WTF? On an even more serious note, if they do comply, then will the same demand be made to all the ISPs? I just shudder at the mere thought of this…Quotin BGR below
It looks as if the Indian government is not content with its inability to decrypt their citizens BlackBerry e-mails, and is threatening a shutdown of Research In Motion&amp;rsquo;s devices in the country as punishment.</description><content>&lt;p>Just read on &lt;a href="http://www.boygeniusreport.com/2008/03/12/impending-blackberry-shutdown-in-india/bleName">BGR&lt;/a>, that &lt;a href="http://www.rim.com/">RIM&lt;/a> will have to close down its &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BlackBerry">BlackBerry&lt;/a> service in India if they don&amp;rsquo;t allow our government to snoop on every little piece of data that goes through it. WTF? On an even more serious note, if they do comply, then will the same demand be made to all the ISPs? I just shudder at the mere thought of this…Quotin BGR below&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It looks as if the Indian government is not content with its inability to decrypt their citizens BlackBerry e-mails, and is threatening a shutdown of Research In Motion&amp;rsquo;s devices in the country as punishment. &lt;em>Business Standard&lt;/em> reports that the Indian government desires access to RIM&amp;rsquo;s proprietary e-mail network, in order to monitor e-mails being sent and received through the country. It is reported that a meeting will take place on March 14th, involving RIM representatives, members of wireless companies within the country, and representatives of the Indian government.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;/blockquote></content></item></channel></rss>