<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>India on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/india/</link><description>Recent content in India on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 18:04:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/india/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Do They Really Know How To Sell Something In India?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/26/do-they-really-know-how-to-sell-something-in-india/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 14:45:46 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/26/do-they-really-know-how-to-sell-something-in-india/</guid><description>Update: UK Ad Authorities have declared iPhone ad as &amp;ldquo;misleading&amp;rdquo;. I guess then they should declare it plain fraud in India.
This is a short rant about two of the &amp;ldquo;big&amp;rdquo; products launched recently in India in the last one week and how the people behind their sales/marketing teams either try to take the Indian customer for a ride, or shaft themselves.
iPhone: The big icon. Bharti Airtel/Vodafone claimed lakhs of pre-registrations, yet no one lined up to buy it.</description></item><item><title>Indian Govt. vs Blackberry: Yet Another Example of Idiocy From Our "Leaders"</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/12/indian-govt-vs-blackberry-yet-another-example-of-idiocy-from-our-leaders/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2008 19:45:48 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/12/indian-govt-vs-blackberry-yet-another-example-of-idiocy-from-our-leaders/</guid><description>Just read on BGR, that RIM will have to close down its BlackBerry service in India if they don&amp;rsquo;t allow our government to snoop on every little piece of data that goes through it. WTF? On an even more serious note, if they do comply, then will the same demand be made to all the ISPs? I just shudder at the mere thought of this…Quotin BGR below
It looks as if the Indian government is not content with its inability to decrypt their citizens BlackBerry e-mails, and is threatening a shutdown of Research In Motion&amp;rsquo;s devices in the country as punishment.</description></item></channel></rss>