<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ggplot on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/ggplot/</link><description>Recent content in Ggplot on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 14:20:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/ggplot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fixing the problem of matplotlib and ggplot not showing graphs in python</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2016/06/29/fixing-the-problem-of-matplotlib-and-ggplot-not-showing-graphs-in-python/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 14:20:55 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2016/06/29/fixing-the-problem-of-matplotlib-and-ggplot-not-showing-graphs-in-python/</guid><description>While trying to make some graphs for one of my side projects recently, I came across an issue that both matplotlib and ggplot did not show up the graphs. I was able to save the graphs to an image file just fine, but if I tried to show them directly on screen while running the script, it just printed a number and exited. After tearing apart my hair for some time, I checked the backend being used by matplot lib:</description><content>&lt;p>While trying to make some graphs for one of my side projects recently, I came across an issue that both matplotlib and ggplot did not show up the graphs. I was able to save the graphs to an image file just fine, but if I tried to show them directly on screen while running the script, it just printed a number and exited. After tearing apart my hair for some time, I checked the backend being used by matplot lib:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>import matplotlib matplotlib.get_backend() &lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And there was the problem. It showed the backend being used was &amp;ldquo;agg&amp;rdquo;. Looking at the matplotlib documentation, I figured that this backend is used for rendering the graph into an image and saving it. That explained why I was able to save the images fine. But it didn&amp;rsquo;t have any interactive support. For that I had to install one of the other backends which had this support, e.g., Tkagg. So, for that what I had to do was, first install the Tk related packages using the below command:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>sudo apt-get install tcl-dev tk-dev python-tk python3-tk &lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another important step now is to reinstall matplotlib so that it detects the new backend, but also remember that if you just do a plain pip uninstall/install, it may not work because that will pick up the previous cached installation. So you have to use the &amp;ndash;no-cache-dir option like below:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>pip uninstall matplotlib pip install matplotlib --no-cache-dir &lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, the graphs work fine for both saving as image as well as showing up during runtime.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>