<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>python on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/python/</link><description>Recent content in python on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 23:46:24 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create a bit.ly like shorturl static website</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/09/17/create-bitly-clone-shorturl-static-website/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 23:46:24 +0530</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/09/17/create-bitly-clone-shorturl-static-website/</guid><description>I decided to create my own shorturl website last week for personal use and ended up developing a python project (deecubes)that can be used by anyone to do the same. This is a post to explain what/why/how about it.
Why my own shorturl website? So far I had been using sites like bit.ly or TinyURL whenever I needed to generate a shorturl (e.g. for giving to someone for easily remember, noting down on paper, putting links on resume, etc) but I had concerns that:</description></item><item><title>email-actions: An SMTP server that triggers actions from email</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/04/03/email-actions-trigger-tasks-from-email-smtp-server/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 19:20:59 +0530</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/04/03/email-actions-trigger-tasks-from-email-smtp-server/</guid><description>Releasing my project email-actions today. You install it from github or from pypi.
email-actions email-actions is a tiny SMTP server with a rules based engine to trigger any actions (notifications/commands etc) based on the emails sent to this server. Think of it like IFTTT but where input trigger is email and can be set up and run locally as well.
Why did you make email-actions Like most of my projects, email-actions is a &amp;lsquo;scratch-your-own-itch&amp;rsquo; project.</description></item><item><title>Fixing the problem of matplotlib and ggplot not showing graphs in python</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2016/06/29/fixing-the-problem-of-matplotlib-and-ggplot-not-showing-graphs-in-python/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 14:20:55 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2016/06/29/fixing-the-problem-of-matplotlib-and-ggplot-not-showing-graphs-in-python/</guid><description>While trying to make some graphs for one of my side projects recently, I came across an issue that both matplotlib and ggplot did not show up the graphs. I was able to save the graphs to an image file just fine, but if I tried to show them directly on screen while running the script, it just printed a number and exited. After tearing apart my hair for some time, I checked the backend being used by matplot lib:</description></item><item><title>Display Message on Samsung TVs in Python (Samsung MessageBox Service Exploitation)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/07/14/samsung-tv-message-box-python/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 14:07:15 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/07/14/samsung-tv-message-box-python/</guid><description>This script is the result of a weekend&amp;rsquo;s hacking to get my TV to display incoming calls/texts which I miss invariably because the phone is buried under a sofa or in a different room. Earlier I had done this using my Odroid U2 and Tasker/AutoRemote but this was limiting as this meant that I could see the notifications only when I was watching something through the Odroid. Samsung TVs, which are DLNA enabled, also include a hidden service called &amp;ldquo;Message Box&amp;rdquo; which can display different information on the TV natively irrespective of which display mode/input mode you are in.</description></item></channel></rss>