<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fraud on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/fraud/</link><description>Recent content in Fraud on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 14:45:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/fraud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Do They Really Know How To Sell Something In India?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/26/do-they-really-know-how-to-sell-something-in-india/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 14:45:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/26/do-they-really-know-how-to-sell-something-in-india/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="http://www.mobileburn.com/news.jsp?Id=5176">UK Ad Authorities have declared iPhone ad as &amp;ldquo;misleading&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/a> I guess then they should declare it plain fraud in India.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a short rant about two of the &amp;ldquo;big&amp;rdquo; products launched recently in India in the last one week and how the people behind their sales/marketing teams either try to take the Indian customer for a ride, or shaft themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>iPhone&lt;/strong>: The big icon. Bharti Airtel/Vodafone claimed lakhs of pre-registrations, yet no one lined up to buy it. Anyways, to the point. The ads all over the print, digital and broadcast media in India list out 3 major points in one sentence:&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="http://www.mobileburn.com/news.jsp?Id=5176">UK Ad Authorities have declared iPhone ad as &amp;ldquo;misleading&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/a> I guess then they should declare it plain fraud in India.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a short rant about two of the &amp;ldquo;big&amp;rdquo; products launched recently in India in the last one week and how the people behind their sales/marketing teams either try to take the Indian customer for a ride, or shaft themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>iPhone&lt;/strong>: The big icon. Bharti Airtel/Vodafone claimed lakhs of pre-registrations, yet no one lined up to buy it. Anyways, to the point. The ads all over the print, digital and broadcast media in India list out 3 major points in one sentence:&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>1. **A 3G Phone:** My a$$. They haven't even finalized auction details for 3G spectrum in India yet.
2. **Desktop Class Browser:** Without Flash?
3. **Push E-mail:** Oh, the one that Apple already pulled the plug on?
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Anyways, even if this were to be true, nobody would have bought it for the steep price for something that hardly even performs properly as a phone.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>BIG TV&lt;/strong>: This is the &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; big one, from the stable of none other than Reliance/Anil Dhirubhai Ambani. Ok, it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be good, very good. I checked out &lt;a href="http://bigtv.co.in">their website&lt;/a> to see how good. What do I get?&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>1. A flash only site. No fallback. Did they get it coded from a high-school flash junkie?
2. After 15 minutes of looking around clicking on 10s of links, going in circles, I'm still confused. What exactly are their packages. There are so many rates and offers floating around. Everything promising something different, but wait, not available for your region. There are so many channels, more than your current DTH, but one second, WHAT exactly are thos channels. No list? For all I care, they could be endless streams of Doordarshan and ETV regional ones. (Please repeat the question I asked in point 1 here again)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Makes me wonder, do they really want to sell anything or Anil just made this out for fun, having a roaring time watching realtime website logs seeing people getting stuck and frustrated in the maze.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Caution: "Network Solutions", Stay As Far As Possible</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/14/caution-network-solutions-stay-as-far-as-possible/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2008 20:56:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/14/caution-network-solutions-stay-as-far-as-possible/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you had a dream of starting your own website, your online abode, and you wanted to see whether the pretty little name for your dream house is available or not, what do you do? Check its availability on one of the many domain sellers&amp;rsquo; sites. And if you picked &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://www.networksolutions.com/">Network Solutions&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo; to do the search, then you have just been scammed my dear friend.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Did you wonder, that though Network Solutions showed the domain name as available, but yet when you searched and found a cheaper registrar, the domain name was suddenly…&lt;strong>GONE&lt;/strong>..What about the second one you had searched for at NetSol? Gone. Third One? Gone. Now, what is the probability of all 3 names being registered within 5 minutes of you searching for them? Probably one in a billion. No, its one in one (100%) if you searched on Network Solutions, as a &lt;a href="http://blog.twilightfairy.in/">friend&lt;/a> of mine found out the hard way.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>If you had a dream of starting your own website, your online abode, and you wanted to see whether the pretty little name for your dream house is available or not, what do you do? Check its availability on one of the many domain sellers&amp;rsquo; sites. And if you picked &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://www.networksolutions.com/">Network Solutions&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo; to do the search, then you have just been scammed my dear friend.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Did you wonder, that though Network Solutions showed the domain name as available, but yet when you searched and found a cheaper registrar, the domain name was suddenly…&lt;strong>GONE&lt;/strong>..What about the second one you had searched for at NetSol? Gone. Third One? Gone. Now, what is the probability of all 3 names being registered within 5 minutes of you searching for them? Probably one in a billion. No, its one in one (100%) if you searched on Network Solutions, as a &lt;a href="http://blog.twilightfairy.in/">friend&lt;/a> of mine found out the hard way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Donning the detective cap, if you do a whois for all those domains, they will undoubtedly be registered with Network Solutions. And you are now in there clutches, to buy it for their exhorbitant prices, almost 4-5 times the normal prices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Actually, its not that bad as of now, because NetSol doesn&amp;rsquo;t really &amp;ldquo;buy&amp;rdquo; all those domain names (otherwise it&amp;rsquo;ll take less than a day for them to go bankrupt). They register it with ICANN but are allowed to cancel it within 5 days so they don&amp;rsquo;t have to pay any money. This clause was made to protect registrars from Credit Card fraud, but NetSol is using it to create their own fraud. As now, they can block the site for 5 days for free and people panic and buy it from them for their higher prices. They say that they do it to &amp;ldquo;protect&amp;rdquo; their customers. Hell, all they are protecting is the customers from buying it from their &amp;ldquo;cheaper&amp;rdquo; competitors as NetSol will sell it to anyone who pays and not just the guy who searched for it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, if you have become a victim of this and can wait for 5 days, then do that instead of paying through your nose. I call for a boycott of all services of Network Solutions and not just the domain whois, so that they can learn a lesson.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>