<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Adsense Privacy Policy Generator on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/adsense-privacy-policy-generator/</link><description>Recent content in Adsense Privacy Policy Generator on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 17:35:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/adsense-privacy-policy-generator/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Save Your Adsense Account: Put Up That Privacy Policy</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/04/save-your-adsense-account-put-up-that-privacy-policy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 17:35:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/04/save-your-adsense-account-put-up-that-privacy-policy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Google is known to be pretty strict with making sure that all Adsense publishers remain conformant to their policies. I’m not very old in this game but had read and heard enough (about google shutting down Adsense accounts without even warning) that I made sure to read their terms and conditions thoroughly. What got my attention was the very last line in the &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/adsense/support/bin/answer.py?hl=en&amp;amp;answer=48182">policy&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hi,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During a recent review of your account we noticed that you are currently displaying Google ads on [domain name removed] but do not have a privacy policy posted which discloses how the site uses third party advertising companies.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>Google is known to be pretty strict with making sure that all Adsense publishers remain conformant to their policies. I’m not very old in this game but had read and heard enough (about google shutting down Adsense accounts without even warning) that I made sure to read their terms and conditions thoroughly. What got my attention was the very last line in the &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/adsense/support/bin/answer.py?hl=en&amp;amp;answer=48182">policy&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hi,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During a recent review of your account we noticed that you are currently displaying Google ads on [domain name removed] but do not have a privacy policy posted which discloses how the site uses third party advertising companies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As stated in our program policies, sites displaying Google ads should include a privacy policy that informs visitors of the use of cookies and/or web beacons to serve ads. You can find more information about this requirement here: &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/adsense/support/bin/answer.py?answer=100557">http://www.google.com/adsense/support/bin/answer.py?answer=100557&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To ensure that your site is in compliance with this policy, please create a privacy policy page and link to it from any pages which display Google ads. You can find some privacy policy examples and tips here: &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/adsense/support/bin/answer.py?answer=100557">http://www.google.com/adsense/support/bin/answer.py?answer=100557&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once you have taken the necessary corrective action, please reply to this email so that we can follow up accordingly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We appreciate your cooperation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sincerely,
The Google AdSense Team&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now why I wrote this post was that though almost every site I visit has adsense ads, but only a very miniscule fraction of them is abiding with this condition. Maybe they don’t know this because on my search, I came to know that this clause was added to google’s policy around March this year. I don’t know how much fuss is google is going to create over this but I’d rather be safe than sorry. Especially when it takes only a few minutes to create your privacy policy. To create yours with a few clicks, I came across a simple online template here: &lt;a href="http://www.serprank.com/privacy-policy-generator/index.php">Adsense Privacy Policy Generator&lt;/a>. I too used it (with a few modifications) to create my own &lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/privacy/">privacy policy&lt;/a>. You are free to use it to create your own.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>