<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Twitter on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/twitter/</link><description>Recent content in Twitter on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 21:19:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/twitter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Project: Shantz Pidgin Away Alerts (splert) Updated to 0.03</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/03/project-shantz-pidgin-away-alerts-splert-updated-to-003/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 21:19:08 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/03/project-shantz-pidgin-away-alerts-splert-updated-to-003/</guid><description>I updated my project splert to version 0.03 today.For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know splert is a tool that lets you convert the multi-client instant messenger pidgin (connects to gtalk, msn, yahoo, jabber, etc) into a full blown answering machine and much more.
The main changes are:
Now you can use other 3rd party twitter bots with it to get updates through twitter since the official twitter bot is down since a long time and there are no chances of coming back soon.</description><content>&lt;p>I updated my project splert to version 0.03 today.For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know splert is a tool that lets you convert the multi-client instant messenger pidgin (connects to gtalk, msn, yahoo, jabber, etc) into a full blown answering machine and much more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main changes are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Now you can use other 3rd party twitter bots with it to get updates through twitter since the official twitter bot is down since a long time and there are no chances of coming back soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can also use it even when you are not &amp;ldquo;away&amp;rdquo; by specifying the status when you want it to work. (e.g. any, available, unavailable, invisible, etc. Use splert -h to see all available status types). As an example, you can use this to selectively talk to people when you are busy.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>(As usual, binary files as well as 32 bit and 64 bit ubuntu/debian deb packages are available)&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Project: Splert - A Custom Answering Machine And More for IMs</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/18/project-splert-a-custom-answering-machine-and-more-for-ims/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 17:00:09 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/18/project-splert-a-custom-answering-machine-and-more-for-ims/</guid><description>Update Aug 25 2008: Updated to v0.02 and also added 32 bit package. Hit the link given below to download.
You must have heard of (or used) the auto-reply features given by today&amp;rsquo;s instant messengers that are sent to the ones messaging you while you are not at your desk. But those are one-size-fits-all kind of messages. So, I wrote this simple tool a few months ago to turn Pidgin, everyone’s favourite multi-client Instant Messenger (works with gtalk, msn, yahoo, aim etc), into a customized answering machine (and more) when you are away from your computer.</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update Aug 25 2008&lt;/strong>: Updated to v0.02 and also added 32 bit package. Hit the link given below to download.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You must have heard of (or used) the auto-reply features given by today&amp;rsquo;s instant messengers that are sent to the ones messaging you while you are not at your desk. But those are one-size-fits-all kind of messages. So, I wrote this simple tool a few months ago to turn Pidgin, everyone’s favourite multi-client Instant Messenger (works with gtalk, msn, yahoo, aim etc), into a &lt;strong>customized answering machine (and more)&lt;/strong> when you are away from your computer. Basically it allows you to divide up your contact list into groups based on email IDs and execute actions based on when someone from a particular group messages you while you are away. e.g. For general friends, you can keep a message like “Will talk to you later when I come back”, or if someone from office IMs you, it’ll send them your phone number “Call me at XXXXXX if urgent”. And if you boss is the one pinging you, you could direct the message towards your twitter account so that you get it as an SMS on your phone immediately.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Splert: Shantz Pidgin Away Alerts</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/18/splert-shantz-pidgin-away-alerts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 16:55:03 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/18/splert-shantz-pidgin-away-alerts/</guid><description>This is a simple tool I wrote a few months ago to turn Pidgin, everyone’s favourite multi-client Instant Messenger (works with gtalk, msn, yahoo, aim etc), into a customized answering machine (and more) when you are away from your computer. Basically it allows you to divide up your contact list into groups based on email IDs and execute actions based on when someone from a particular group messages you while you are away.</description><content>&lt;p>This is a simple tool I wrote a few months ago to turn Pidgin, everyone’s favourite multi-client Instant Messenger (works with gtalk, msn, yahoo, aim etc), into a &lt;strong>customized answering machine (and more)&lt;/strong> when you are away from your computer. Basically it allows you to divide up your contact list into groups based on email IDs and execute actions based on when someone from a particular group messages you while you are away. e.g. For general friends, you can keep a message like “Will talk to you later when I come back”, or if someone from office IMs you, it’ll send them your phone number “Call me at XXXXXX if urgent”. And if you boss is the one pinging you, you could direct the message towards your twitter account so that you get it as an SMS on your phone immediately.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Time is short, so here are the details:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Features:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Group based rule execution, each group can contain any number of email IDs&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Custom replies for each group.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Integrates with twitter and will forward the message to your twitter account (or send a direct message to some other account) if you so desire. (Temporarily disabled since Twitter has blocked their IM bot)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Runs as a separate process over d-bus instead of running as a pidgin plugin, so much lesser chances of crashing.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Prerequisites:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Pidgin &amp;gt; 2.4.1&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Linux&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Download:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Usage:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Unzip the attached package anywhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Either install using the deb package or just copy the splert binary and config.txt to a folder of your choice&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Modify the “config.txt” file according to your needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Run splert. (or run splert -h for checking out the available options though you wouldn’t need them most of the times)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Config File:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Config file fields and formats are explained fully in the sample config file included in the attached file. However, here is a very basic sample configuration:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>[Friends]
user = &lt;a href="mailto:foo@foo.com">foo@foo.com&lt;/a>
message = &amp;ldquo;Not Here. Will talk to you later&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[VIP]
user = &lt;a href="mailto:boss@boss.com">boss@boss.com&lt;/a>
message = &amp;ldquo;Got your message. Will Contact you asap&amp;rdquo;
twitter = 1
twitterto = my2ndtwitteracct&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>ChangeLog:&lt;/strong>
0.03 - Oct04 2008 -&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Added option to specify twitter bot id (e.g. &lt;a href="mailto:twitterspy@jabber.org">twitterspy@jabber.org&lt;/a>) using option &amp;ldquo;-t/-twitterbot&amp;rdquo;. However, you need to do any &amp;ldquo;extra&amp;rdquo; stuff manually. e.g. logging in using twlogin command with twitterspy.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added option to specify the status when you want to send messages instead of just when being away. Use &amp;ldquo;-s/&amp;ndash;status&amp;rdquo; option to do this.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>0.02 - Aug25 2008 -&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Fixed bug where response was not sent for 1st message received&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added 32 bit package&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>0.01 - Aug15 2008 - Initial Version&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please let me know if you like it or found some issues with it. Also, let me know if you would like me to add any features to it.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Google's New Favicon</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/30/googles-new-favicon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2008 19:16:21 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/30/googles-new-favicon/</guid><description>It’s amazing, isn’t it? Even a sneeze at google makes the headlines. Well, it’s not the sneeze today but the new favicon I just got. So, are you also seeing the all new, re-designed, artisticly polished “g” as the new favicon?
In other news, my Twitter-Webcam integration post has bypassed my earlier lifehacked post about Remote File Access Through E-mail by more than a few thousands, even though the time difference between the two posts is more than 3 months.</description><content>&lt;p>It’s amazing, isn’t it? Even a sneeze at google makes the headlines. Well, it’s not the sneeze today but the new favicon I just got. So, are you also seeing the all new, re-designed, artisticly polished “g” as the new favicon?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/favicon.ico" alt="New Google Favicon">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In other news, my &lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/14/keep-tab-on-home-security-with-a-webcam-and-twitter.html">Twitter-Webcam integration post&lt;/a> has bypassed my earlier lifehacked post about &lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/projects/windows/remote-file-access-through-e-mail">Remote File Access Through E-mail&lt;/a> by more than a few thousands, even though the time difference between the two posts is more than 3 months. Thanks Stumble Upon :)&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Keep Tab On Home Security With A Webcam And Twitter</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/14/keep-tab-on-home-security-with-a-webcam-and-twitter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2008 04:00:13 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/14/keep-tab-on-home-security-with-a-webcam-and-twitter/</guid><description>Worried about someone breaking into your house in your absence? Or just need to keep a tab on who enters your room while you are away? Well, all you need is a webcam, a linux PC/laptop and a twitter account. And you are set for real time updates through twitter about all that goes on at your abode behind your back (can even receive a text message/sms on your phone). Keep reading for the very simple setup you need.</description><content>&lt;p>Worried about someone breaking into your house in your absence? Or just need to keep a tab on who enters your room while you are away? Well, all you need is a webcam, a linux PC/laptop and a twitter account. And you are set for real time updates through twitter about all that goes on at your abode behind your back (can even receive a text message/sms on your phone). Keep reading for the very simple setup you need.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1.) Download and install &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://www.lavrsen.dk/twiki/bin/view/Motion/DownloadFiles">motion&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo; on your computer. For ubuntu users, this is as simple as running&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>2.) Setup your motion configuration file. (Usually at /etc/motion/motion.conf). There are quite a lot of options available. You might want to tweak it a lot according to ur needs later on but the most important ones that you can begin with are (leave the rest untouched for now):&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2a.) Add/edit the option &amp;ldquo;target_dir&amp;rdquo; to point to the directory where you want to save the images of the event when motion is detected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2b.) Add/edit the option &amp;ldquo;locate&amp;rdquo; and set it to &amp;ldquo;on&amp;rdquo; so that you get a nice square box around the detected moving object/person.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2c.) Add/edit the option &amp;ldquo;webcam_port&amp;rdquo; and set it to, say, &amp;ldquo;8000&amp;rdquo;. Motion includes a mini http server so now, you can use it to view the actual images of the happening when you get the update and check for false alarms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3.) Now, comes the most important part, about getting the update.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>motion has an option called &amp;ldquo;on_motion_detected&amp;rdquo; and here you can specify any command or program that you want to run when motion is detected. To get the update on your twitter account, use one of the following three methods with this option.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3a.) Using curl. If you have curl installed in your system, then you can use the following value for the on_motion_detected option:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>3b.) Using wget. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have curl, you can even use wget for this. Use the following value:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>3c.) Using my perl script. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have curl as well as wget, you can even use my perl script (attached below) for this. The value will now be:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;ol start="4">
&lt;li>Now connect your webcam and start motion (Just type &amp;ldquo;motion&amp;rdquo; on command line and press enter). Wait for someone to break in, or just roam around in front of the camera yourself and have fun as you receive a message on your phone about the &amp;ldquo;motion&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>PS: For receiving a text message on your phone, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to turn on the &amp;ldquo;Device Updates&amp;rdquo; option in your twitter account, otherwise you need to open the twitter web page to check the status.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The script: &lt;a href="http://tech.shantanugoel.com/resources/downloads/twitter.pl">Twitter Updating Perl Script&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me know if you put this to some other exciting uses or have any questions about the method described above.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Twittering Away With Delhi Bloggers</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/06/twittering-away-with-delhi-bloggers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2008 14:57:24 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/06/twittering-away-with-delhi-bloggers/</guid><description>If you are twittering kinds, doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter online or offline
If you blog or are interested in all things blog and blogging
If you live in Delhi, have lived there, have been there, or just connect with Delhi somehow else
If you want to meet up with your fellow twitterers and bloggers
Then you&amp;rsquo;ve got to be a part of the your very own City of The People With Hearts, Delhi.</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/tweetup_logo_73x73_bigger.jpg" alt="Tweetup_logo_73x73_bigger">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you are twittering kinds, doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter online or offline&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you blog or are interested in all things blog and blogging&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you live in Delhi, have lived there, have been there, or just connect with Delhi somehow else&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you want to meet up with your fellow twitterers and bloggers&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Then you&amp;rsquo;ve got to be a part of the your very own City of The People With Hearts, Delhi. How, you ask? It&amp;rsquo;s as simple as pointing your mice and keyboards towards &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/delhitweetup">Delhi Tweetup&lt;/a> to get the latest on every scoop about blogging, twittering and blogging and twittering in Delhi (and outside as well).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And if you want to be a little bit more involved, you can also join the &lt;a href="http://groups.yahoo.com/group/delhibloggers">Delhi Bloggers&amp;rsquo; Yahoo Group&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>