<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tinker on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/categories/tinker/</link><description>Recent content in Tinker on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 02:25:17 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/categories/tinker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fixing the Raspberrypi 4 Ethernet disconnection problem</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2020/01/19/raspberry-pi-4b-ethernet-lan-disconnect/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 02:25:17 +0530</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2020/01/19/raspberry-pi-4b-ethernet-lan-disconnect/</guid><description>I added a Raspberry Pi 4B recently in my ever expanding homelab. To get the best network with the new gigabit ethernet port on the raspi, and still save power, I added a PoE hat to it so I could power the raspi as well as provide it data through the ethernet port. Everything worked fine except that I ocassionaly got into situations where the raspi stopped responding suddenly. Initially I thought that it&amp;rsquo;s crashing due to some issues and used to just restart it manually.</description></item><item><title>Practical Reverse Engineering Tutorials Part 2: Protostar Stack4</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/12/04/practical-reverse-engineering-tutorial-2-protostar-stack4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 21:04:24 +0530</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/12/04/practical-reverse-engineering-tutorial-2-protostar-stack4/</guid><description>About the challenge In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll go through the Protostar stack4 challenge. This would be a bit similar to the stack0 challenge that we already tackled earlier, but it will think about an interesting way to get alternate code to execute instead of just modifying data.
Pre-requisite: Make sure you&amp;rsquo;ve completed the Part 1 of the Practical Reverse Engineering Tutorials series. It&amp;rsquo;d also be great if you can try stack1-stack3 challenges on your own as they are similar to stack0.</description></item><item><title>Practical Reverse Engineering Tutorials Part 1: Introduction &amp; Protostar Stack 0</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/11/16/practical-reverse-engineering-tutorial-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 08:46:24 +0530</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/11/16/practical-reverse-engineering-tutorial-1/</guid><description>What is this about? This article is the 1st part of the Practical Reverse Engineering Tutorials series. This series is geared towards a structured, but almost completely practical, approach to learn Reverse Engineering. Many of the existing articles/books take a long winded approach to teach RE which is prefixed with a lot of theory before the reader can get their hands dirty. This series will take a different approach of picking up various challenges in the order of increasing difficulty and help the reader in exploring ways how to break them.</description></item><item><title>email-actions: An SMTP server that triggers actions from email</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/04/03/email-actions-trigger-tasks-from-email-smtp-server/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 19:20:59 +0530</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/04/03/email-actions-trigger-tasks-from-email-smtp-server/</guid><description>Releasing my project email-actions today. You install it from github or from pypi.
email-actions email-actions is a tiny SMTP server with a rules based engine to trigger any actions (notifications/commands etc) based on the emails sent to this server. Think of it like IFTTT but where input trigger is email and can be set up and run locally as well.
Why did you make email-actions Like most of my projects, email-actions is a &amp;lsquo;scratch-your-own-itch&amp;rsquo; project.</description></item><item><title>Bypass ISP DNS hijack by changing DNS port on Ubiquiti USG router</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/03/13/bypass-isp-dns-hijack-ubiquiti-ubnt-usg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 16:46:24 +0530</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/03/13/bypass-isp-dns-hijack-ubiquiti-ubnt-usg/</guid><description>The Background We talked earlier about how certain ISPs block websites by using DNS hijack methods and I had recommended using DNSCrypt to bypass it. Well, as part of my home network overhaul, I moved over from the consumer grade (but still decent enough) Asus router over to Ubiquiti stack which, among other things, lead me to use their &amp;ldquo;Unify Security Gateway (USG)&amp;rdquo; as the router. Now, this router is pretty decent and is running Ubiquiti&amp;rsquo;s EdgeOS (derived from Vyatta OS, which in turn is based on linux/debian).</description></item><item><title>ACT Fibernet blocks sites using deep packet inspection</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/01/24/act-fibernet-deep-packet-inspection-blocking-sites/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 16:04:28 +0530</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/01/24/act-fibernet-deep-packet-inspection-blocking-sites/</guid><description>ISPs in India have been blocking websites since many years. It&amp;rsquo;s often done without much sense to it. The goveernment/telecom bodies and courts sometimes tell the ISPs to block content instead of telling the same to the websites that host the content. Sometimes, the orders are to block certain urls and ISPs are over-enthusiastic in implementing the orders and block complete websites. It&amp;rsquo;s all frustrating but it becomes enraging when you find out that the ISPs are messing with your traffic in a less than ethical way to implement this.</description></item><item><title>Indian ISP ACT Fibernet blocks bit.ly. Does DNS Hijacking</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2016/09/17/indian-isp-act-fibernet-blocks-bit-ly-does-dns-hijacking/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 17:14:43 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2016/09/17/indian-isp-act-fibernet-blocks-bit-ly-does-dns-hijacking/</guid><description>TLDR;
Indian ISP ACT Fibernet (aka Beam Telecom) hijacks its users&amp;rsquo; DNS requests (even when using public DNS servers like Google or OpenDNS) and blocks websites through this method. This has huge implications beyond website blocking and you can&amp;rsquo;t rely on anything that you are browsing anymore though there are ways available to make yourself safe.
Aside: Indian ISPs are blocking benign/collateral damage sites now like bit.</description></item><item><title>NTP Driver For ESP8266</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2015/03/01/ntp-driver-for-esp8266/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 08:02:22 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2015/03/01/ntp-driver-for-esp8266/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m building a smartwatch project based around the new IoT posterkid on the block, ESP8266. Apart from the usual &amp;ldquo;smart&amp;rdquo; stuff, it does still need to display correct time :) and hence, the need for an ntp driver/client. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find anyone working on that yet, so wrote up a quick and dirty implementation here:
NTP Implementation for ESP8266
ESP8266 Smartwatch NTP Demo It still has a lot of stuff left to be done to make it good enough for the smartwatch project but it works.</description></item><item><title>Weekend Hack: Shoutcast2Dropbox - Automatic Shoutcast Stations To Dropbox Recorder</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2015/02/16/weekend-hack-shoutcast2dropbox-automatic-shoutcast-stations-to-dropbox-recorder/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 03:00:19 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2015/02/16/weekend-hack-shoutcast2dropbox-automatic-shoutcast-stations-to-dropbox-recorder/</guid><description>So I got bored of listening to same old songs on my phone over and over and Rdio announced a streaming plan for India. With a sigh of relief I subscribed immediately and it was stellar at home with its wonderful 32 million song collection and chromecast support to boot. The experience during the commute daily was underwhelming. Couple the spotty airtel data connection with no one station covering all songs I would love and it makes for a frustrating commute with long gaps all over.</description></item><item><title>Browser controlled Raspberry Pi Camera Car</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2014/08/03/browser-controlled-raspberry-pi-camera-car/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2014 15:33:12 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2014/08/03/browser-controlled-raspberry-pi-camera-car/</guid><description>Spent this weekend building a remote controlled car with a live camera feed with a Raspberry Pi doing the communication and brains duty. Pretty nice real time movement control and camera pan/tilt control through websockets with a live stream feeding back to any browser directly from the car through mjpg-streamer
(PS: Video is at the bottom of the post. Browser/video on TV courtesy ChromeCast. Casted my Nexus 5 screen to the TV simultaneously while controlling the car :) )</description></item><item><title>Converting A Toy RC Car Into An Autonomous Fun Car The Indian Way</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2014/07/23/converting-a-toy-rc-car-into-an-autonomous-fun-car-the-indian-way/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 17:05:12 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2014/07/23/converting-a-toy-rc-car-into-an-autonomous-fun-car-the-indian-way/</guid><description>Dangerous is a mind which is left grounded at home for days. Being stuck at home and having a few pieces of joy around made me do this over the weekend.
Ingredients:
An old Toy RC car broken out of shape by my 4 year old
DAGU Mini Driver
Screw Driver/Batteries/Tape/Glue/Rubber bands/Old gift cards
Half an hour of coding
Output:</description></item><item><title>[Xposed Mod] Bypass Exchange Security Policy for Nexus and other AOSP devices</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/10/14/xposed-mod-bypass-exchange-security-policy-for-nexus-4-android-4-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 14:13:10 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/10/14/xposed-mod-bypass-exchange-security-policy-for-nexus-4-android-4-3/</guid><description>Exchange Security Bypass Xposed Mode for Nexus 4/5/7 and other AOSP based devices (Android 4.3 / 4.4)
Update: This has now been tested to work successfully on all stock or nearly stock JellyBean (4.3) and KitKat (4.4) ROMs on Nexus 4 / Nexus 5 / Nexus 7. Other AOSP ROMs like CM11 should work as well.
This mod should be used along with Xposed ( http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=1574401 ). Xposed is this awesome framework developed by rovo89 which allows you to carry out mods to your device without changing any files (well except one &amp;ldquo;app_process&amp;rdquo; as part of the xposed installer).</description></item><item><title>Display Message on Samsung TVs in Python (Samsung MessageBox Service Exploitation)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/07/14/samsung-tv-message-box-python/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 14:07:15 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/07/14/samsung-tv-message-box-python/</guid><description>This script is the result of a weekend&amp;rsquo;s hacking to get my TV to display incoming calls/texts which I miss invariably because the phone is buried under a sofa or in a different room. Earlier I had done this using my Odroid U2 and Tasker/AutoRemote but this was limiting as this meant that I could see the notifications only when I was watching something through the Odroid. Samsung TVs, which are DLNA enabled, also include a hidden service called &amp;ldquo;Message Box&amp;rdquo; which can display different information on the TV natively irrespective of which display mode/input mode you are in.</description></item><item><title>Fixing The Static Noise, Clicks And Pops with Turtlebeach Earforce PX5</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/03/03/fixing-the-static-noise-clicks-and-pops-with-turtlebeach-earforce-px5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 18:27:17 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/03/03/fixing-the-static-noise-clicks-and-pops-with-turtlebeach-earforce-px5/</guid><description>So I got this beautiful piece of headset a few days ago, called the EarForce PX5 by TurtleBeach. It&amp;rsquo;s claim to fame being an awesome virtual surround sound headset which also does the double duty of providing game audio as well as voice chat over the same headset. I preferred this over the Sony PS3 Elite headset as the PX5 is more generic and can work across multiple devices since it uses the regular bluetooth for A2DP and voice chat and the wireless transmitter has standard optical/RCA inputs and outputs.</description></item><item><title>Fixing the DS3/Sixaxis Controller Not Working in PSN Store Issue</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/01/13/fixing-the-ds3sixaxis-controller-not-working-in-psn-store-issue/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2013 19:55:44 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/01/13/fixing-the-ds3sixaxis-controller-not-working-in-psn-store-issue/</guid><description>So, my wife got me a new slim PS3 today to replace my old YLOD&amp;rsquo;ed phat (Yes, Awesome wife I know. And slim PS3 cuz I hate the looks of the new superslim). But, I digress. The issue at hand is that everything worked fine when I unwrapped it, hooked it up to the power and TV and switched it on. However, once I started the PSN store (or what is now called Sony Entertainment Network Store), nothing worked.</description></item><item><title>Chrome Script/Extension installation error: Could not read source file</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/09/19/chrome-scriptextension-installation-error-could-not-read-source-file/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2011 16:58:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/09/19/chrome-scriptextension-installation-error-could-not-read-source-file/</guid><description>This is a solution to the issue that I faced today while installing a javascript file from userscripts.org as an extension into google chrome (Yes, Chrome supports installing greasemonkey javascripts as extensions). I had already installed this script once into my browser earlier but when I tried installing it again today, it started giving me a weird error &amp;ldquo;Could not read source file&amp;rdquo;. I tried all possible means, like putting it on a different server, installing from local disk, changing versions, deleting all cache, etc but still the issue persisted.</description></item><item><title>Use Encrypted Google Search As Default in Chrome</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/05/12/use-encrypted-google-search-as-default-in-chrome/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 04:26:21 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/05/12/use-encrypted-google-search-as-default-in-chrome/</guid><description>Google just launched an encrypted search portal which is a Godsend for people on public networks since there is a lot that can be gleaned from your search queries. For doing your protected searches, however, you have to go to a different portal which I linked to above. Now, the omnibar (the address bar in Google Chrome) also serves as a search box but searches on the normal google portal by default.</description></item><item><title>What does caret (^) in an apt-get command mean?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/23/apt-get-caret/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2010 18:03:06 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/23/apt-get-caret/</guid><description>If you have come across a tutorial or just someone on a forum who tells you to install something in Debian/Ubuntu that involves using apt-get, it is ok for you but when they tell you that you need to use a caret symbol (^) at the end, that&amp;rsquo;s where you become curious. What is even more weird is that when you search for the name of the package that the given command seems to install cannot be found using apt-cache search.</description></item><item><title>Setup Call Recording With Android App Tasker On Nexus One</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/24/setup-call-recording-android-app-tasker-nexus-one/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2010 10:01:16 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/24/setup-call-recording-android-app-tasker-nexus-one/</guid><description>I wanted to record calls on my Android phone (Nexus one). The easy way would have been to download an app but I like tinkering. And given that I recently bought Tasker, android’s very own swiss knife, I thought I should give it a run. After just an hour I was able to create my very own call recorder (some time went into trial and error with things as this was my first major task with tasker and also some things didn’t work with nexus one, which I will note below).</description></item><item><title>Android Dev Tip: App Not Showing on X10 Mini Marketplace</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/07/android-dev-tip-app-not-showing-on-x10-mini-marketplace/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2010 21:18:06 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/07/android-dev-tip-app-not-showing-on-x10-mini-marketplace/</guid><description>Many Android Developers (and users) get confused that why a certain app isn&amp;rsquo;t showing up on the new Xperia X10 Mini (and few other) phones. This happens even if they support all android versions and have published their apps for all countries, so that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the issue. I came across this as well when few people mentioned that they couldn&amp;rsquo;t find my app Wi-Fi Keep Alive in the X10 mini marketplace.</description></item><item><title>SSH Tunneling On Android</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/02/ssh-tunneling-android/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2010 10:53:36 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/02/ssh-tunneling-android/</guid><description>If you want to have a secure browsing environment or just want to access your home network securely without exposing extra services to the internet and without the mess that comes with setting up and maintaining a VPN server, ssh tunneling is your rescuer. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you how to setup an ssh tunnel to your home network easily. Also look for some bonus tips at the end ;)</description></item><item><title>Firefly / sqlite error "unable to open database file" Solution</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/26/firefly-sqlite-error-unable-to-open-database-file-solution/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2010 18:11:40 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/26/firefly-sqlite-error-unable-to-open-database-file-solution/</guid><description>Recently I came across a weird error while trying to run firefly itunes server (mt-daapd) on my router (Asus wl-500w). It had something to do with sqlite and gave a vague message &amp;ldquo;Unable to open database file&amp;rdquo;. After going bonkers for a short time, I solved it and this is how.
One of my hard disks crashed recently and unfortunately it was the one I had connected to my router to serve media to me all over the house (through PS3/laptop) or when I travel (through laptop/phone).</description></item><item><title>Cannot Change Channel Problem With Asus WL-500W</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/13/cannot-change-channel-problem-with-asus-wl-500w/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 12:16:44 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/13/cannot-change-channel-problem-with-asus-wl-500w/</guid><description>Recently I found an issue with my asus wl-500w wi-fi router that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to change the channel on which it was transmitting. I moved to a new location which was totally jam-packed with other wi-fi networks using same channel as mine which was hampeing my connection. I tried for umpteen number of times. Changing the channel through the web configuration did not give any error but I found that it was still transmitting at channel 1.</description></item><item><title>Mute (or Answer) Skype Calls with BT Headset Button in Linux</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/08/mute-answer-skype-calls-bluetooth-headset-button-in-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2010 18:31:55 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/08/mute-answer-skype-calls-bluetooth-headset-button-in-linux/</guid><description>Skype on linux works great but the problem that I faced was that it does not handle the buttons on the bluetooth headsets. My wife uses skype to call into her work related conference calls and was pretty frustrated that she had to keep sitting in front of my laptop (her laptop didn&amp;rsquo;t allow to install skype) just to switch mute on and off. So, I whipped up this little trick to do so.</description></item><item><title>Integrate JDownloader with Flashgot</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/04/14/jdownloader-flashgot-integrate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2010 16:21:41 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/04/14/jdownloader-flashgot-integrate/</guid><description>This is just a short post to to document how I got JDownloader to integrate with Flashgot. JDownloader doesn&amp;rsquo;t have an installer but a zip file that you just download and extract somewhere on your PC and start using it. Somehow, the Flashgot extension of Firefox is not able to detect it automatically and I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what parameters to use to add it manually to its list. Latest versions of JDownloader ask you whether you want to install Flashgot or not.</description></item><item><title>Automatic Login For Beam Cable</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/04/14/beam-cable-automatic-login/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2010 04:33:37 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/04/14/beam-cable-automatic-login/</guid><description>This article will tell you a simple way to login automatically to beam cable (Beam-Telecom) internet connection instead of using the web login manually. Not only that, I’ll also tell you how to do this auto-login through your router if you have one with a custom linux firmware. I took a beam cable connection a few days ago. The price is excellent and speeds are good but the only thing that bothered me was the web based login.</description></item><item><title>Continuous Monitoring With Tail Fails</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/12/23/continuous-monitor-tail-fails/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2009 18:10:44 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/12/23/continuous-monitor-tail-fails/</guid><description>If you can&amp;rsquo;t get tail command to continuously monitor a file, then read on. I was working on a script yesterday, a part of which depended on continuous monitoring of a text file. I had used our trusty old &amp;ldquo;tail&amp;rdquo; command for this but while testing by manually putting in some data into the file, it was failing but curiously it was working fine when used in actual scenario. Befuddled, I did a simple test.</description></item><item><title>grub and knetworkmanager problems in Kubuntu Karmic</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/11/08/grub-knetworkmanager-kubuntu-karmic/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2009 12:08:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/11/08/grub-knetworkmanager-kubuntu-karmic/</guid><description>I generally move from LTS to LTS releases of Ubuntu but reluctantly had to update my system to Karmic when my old HDD gave in. I also thought of trying out Kubuntu (KDE based) this time as I had heard that its doing a lot of interesting things (Akonadi/Nepomuk etc) and that with 4.3.1 it is stable as well. The installation went fine, all over within less than half an hour and then the problems started.</description></item><item><title>Making Frets On Fire Work With Pulse Aludio - pasuspender</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/08/23/make-frets-on-fire-work-pulse-audio-pasuspender/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2009 18:18:45 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/08/23/make-frets-on-fire-work-pulse-audio-pasuspender/</guid><description>I recently got hold of a Guitar Hero controller for my PS3 but the game still had some time to come so I tried it out on my laptop with Frets on Fire (rather FoFix). But when I started it, it was crashing with some weird error about not being able to open mixer devices. Searching on the google, I came to know this is happening because of Pulse Audio as this application needs direct access to the sound devices and finally I came upon **pasuspender.</description></item><item><title>Easiest Way to Shutdown Asus WL-500W</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/07/10/shutdown-asus-wl-500-w/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2009 23:19:12 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/07/10/shutdown-asus-wl-500-w/</guid><description>If you are a proud owner of an Asus WL-500W wireless router (or maybe another one of the same series like wl-500g, wl-500gp, etc), then you know that this router has a very useful USB port with which you might have attached your external hard disk and have already offloaded all your downloding tasks to it, or maybe using it for various other purposes. Whatever maybe the reason, the main point is that because of this hard disk, now we cannot just turn off the power of the router any more.</description></item><item><title>Microtek UPS Problems (And A Solution)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/05/10/microtek-ups-problems-solution/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2009 15:35:02 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/05/10/microtek-ups-problems-solution/</guid><description>I got myself a Microtek 800VA UPS (MDP800+) a couple of weeks ago to save my PS3 from the frequent power outages that we are seeing in Hyderabad but the purpose was rather lost when I found that it worked fine only till the mains power was on. As soon as there was an outage, it couldn’t stop the PS3 from an abrupt shut down. I ran around the pathetic Microtek customer service for days and they finally sent an “engineer” down to my place (after a week) to diagnose the issue and he couldn’t say anything more than that the UPS is meant for a PC and nothing else.</description></item><item><title>TIP: Perforce - Sync Files In A Label Without Deleting Previous Files</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/27/p4perforce-sync-files-label-without-deleting-previous/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2009 14:00:50 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/27/p4perforce-sync-files-label-without-deleting-previous/</guid><description>If you have used perforce, you&amp;rsquo;d have definitely come across a situation where you wanted to sync files belonging to two different labels, but as soon as you sync the second label, the files from the first label get deleted. P4 help suggests the following ways to achieve this:
p4 sync @label1,label2
or something like
`p4 sync @label1,@label2``
But I&amp;rsquo;ve found that depending on the perforce version you are using, the above commands might not work.</description></item><item><title>Shutdown Script For Asus WL-500W With Oleg Firmware</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/09/shutdown-script-asus-wl-500w-oleg-firmware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 13:30:04 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/09/shutdown-script-asus-wl-500w-oleg-firmware/</guid><description>If you have an Asus WL-500W, the DIYers&amp;rsquo; favourite wireless router, and have installed the Oleg custom firmware on it, then you would have set up a shutdown script for it, that allows your router to shut down gracefully. This is especially important if you have a USB hard disk attached to it. There are many such scripts available in Oleg&amp;rsquo;s firmware that you can tweak. All of these reside in &amp;ldquo;/usr/local/sbin/&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>[TIP] Add Directories Recursively To Perforce (P4) Depot</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/03/add-directories-recursively-to-perforce-p4-depot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2009 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/03/add-directories-recursively-to-perforce-p4-depot/</guid><description>Perforce is an excellent revision control system for the code but the GUIs (P4WIN and P4V) are too slow to be productive. Hence, I like to do most of my work through command lines. Now, the other day I needed to add a directory and all its subdirectories and files to the repository (or perforce depot). This is a trivial task through the GUI. Just drag the top level directory onto the changelist area and the GUI takes care of everything but there is no straightforward way to do this through command line, until, I discovered the &amp;ldquo;-x&amp;rdquo; option of P4.</description></item><item><title>Secure Access To Your DSL Modem's Telnet (telnet / ssh)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/25/secure-access-dsl-modems-telnet-ssh/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2009 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/25/secure-access-dsl-modems-telnet-ssh/</guid><description>I have one of those crappy DSL modems that all these ISPs give to you with the connection. My ISP is Airtel and the modem that I have is Beetel 110-BXi (They also have other models like 220-BX and 220 BXi). One thing common among all these modems is that they do not provide secure access like Secure Shell (ssh) as all they provide is ftp/telnet/http etc which are all clear text protocols.</description></item><item><title>[TIP] Install Twonky on Asus WL-500W with stock firmware</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/23/tip-install-twonky-on-asus-wl-500w-with-stock-firmware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2009 06:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/23/tip-install-twonky-on-asus-wl-500w-with-stock-firmware/</guid><description>Asus WL-500W is a greate wi-fi router with lots of features, one of them being able to use it as a media server to serve movies/songs over your network from a hard disk connected directly to it through USB. But the media server that is included in the official firmware leaves a lot to be desired. If you are a fan of twonky, all you would have heard so far would have been that to use it on your router, you&amp;rsquo;d have to change your firmware over to a non-official one.</description></item><item><title>[TIP] Ubuntu 1 MB /tmp Partition Problem</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/10/tip-ubuntu-1-mb-tmp-partition-problem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2009 00:30:31 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/10/tip-ubuntu-1-mb-tmp-partition-problem/</guid><description>Recently someone asked me about an issue he was facing with his Ubuntu Hardy Heron installation. Many of the applications, that he regularly used, were misbehaving. e.g., he couldn&amp;rsquo;t play flash videos in firefox, downloads were failing, installation of new applications were failing, etc. Everything was giving errors of not enough disk space even though he had quite a few GBs left on his drive. A few of the error messages pointed out that there wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough space in /tmp.</description></item><item><title>[Ubuntu TIP] Solved: Totem Cannot Detect UPnP Media Server</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/31/ubuntu-tip-solved-totem-cannot-detect-upnp-media-server/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 17:46:28 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/31/ubuntu-tip-solved-totem-cannot-detect-upnp-media-server/</guid><description>First a bit of background. A UPnP media server can serve your media files (video / audio / pictures) over the network to any compatible player. Some of the most known examples of these media servers are MediaTomb, TVersity, ushare, etc. In linux, few players can play media off these servers natively, but many require a plugin / library called &amp;ldquo;coherence&amp;rdquo;. e.g. the default media players (Totem and RhythmBox) can detect and play media from media servers once you install coherence (&amp;ldquo;sudo apt-get install python-coherence&amp;rdquo;).</description></item><item><title>Tip: Commands To Find Out The Shell You Are Using</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/27/tip-commands-to-find-out-the-shell-you-are-using/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2009 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/27/tip-commands-to-find-out-the-shell-you-are-using/</guid><description>Many times you might not be sure about which shell you are currently using. Especially if you are not on your system and logging into someone else&amp;rsquo;s, or maybe ssh&amp;rsquo;ing into a remote server. Worry not, because here are few simple commands that you can use to find out which shell you are using currently.
Command (Note: This one is a bit unreliable as it might not work with non-bash shells or on redirection.</description></item><item><title>[TIP] Asus WL-500W Hacks:How To Reset Web Admin Password</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/23/tip-asus-wl-500w-hackshow-to-reset-web-admin-password/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2009 22:41:31 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/23/tip-asus-wl-500w-hackshow-to-reset-web-admin-password/</guid><description>Most of you must be knowing by now that I bought the amazing Asus WL-500W router a few days back. This router builds on the great lineage it has in its predecessors, the WL-500g, WL-500g Deluxe, WL-500gP, WL-500gP v2 etc, and shines ahead with being much more than a router, rather a complete headless linux PC. Anyways, to the point. In most routers/modems, if you forget the password to your web-administration gui (which generally resides as 192.</description></item><item><title>Kill Lotus Notes And Restart Without Rebooting</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/23/kill-lotus-notes-and-restart-without-rebooting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2008 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/23/kill-lotus-notes-and-restart-without-rebooting/</guid><description>A friend called me today and happened to mention his biggest gripe about Lotus Notes, that it hangs ever so often (ok that’s acceptable), but the clincher is that if you kill it through the task manager it will not allow you to restart and relogin until you reboot your PC. Now, that is a serious problem and a hit to productivity. But the omniscient angel I am, I had the solution ready (because till a couple of years ago, I was also haunted by this very issue every day).</description></item><item><title>TIP: Free Downloads For Windows Vista, XP Professional, Visual Studio 2008, MSDN And Much More</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/08/tip-free-downloads-for-windows-vista-xp-professional-visual-studio-2008-msdn-and-much-more/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2008 19:31:52 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/08/tip-free-downloads-for-windows-vista-xp-professional-visual-studio-2008-msdn-and-much-more/</guid><description>If you are a student (this works for non-students as well but I expect you to be honest ;) ), you can download a whole bunch of software for free. How? Well, all you need is to become an ACM student member, and join the MSDN AA (Microsoft Developer Network Academic Alliance) ACM Student Benefit Program.
Normally it takes around 19$ for you to become a student member but you can do it for free for a limited time by going to http://campus.</description></item><item><title>TIP: A Post For Pidgin Plugin Developers</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/23/tip-a-post-for-pidgin-plugin-developers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 15:30:32 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/23/tip-a-post-for-pidgin-plugin-developers/</guid><description>Recently I wrote a small autoreply-answering-machine app for pidgin with a simple premise. Send custom automatic replies to different people when they message you and came across a strange bug. It never sent the reply when you received the first message from someone. I was using the &amp;ldquo;ReceivedImMessage&amp;rdquo; signal over d-bus (or &amp;ldquo;received-im-message&amp;rdquo; for the plugin writers). What I found initially looked to be a gross and basic error by pidgin developers, but later found that it is indeed a good design and thought that I&amp;rsquo;ll make a post about it for the benefit of fellow pidgin plugin/app developers.</description></item><item><title>Dropbox Online Storage Public/Shared Folders: A Word Of Caution</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/16/dropbox-online-storage-publicshared-folders-a-word-of-caution/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 14:26:50 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/16/dropbox-online-storage-publicshared-folders-a-word-of-caution/</guid><description>Update: In a thread about this post at Dropbox forums, it was brought to my notice that Dropbox has now changed its terms to remove the objectionable clause.
If you use dropbox (A popular online storage service with free 2 GB space), and use (or intend to use) its public or shared folders feature, then you must know something about the EULA (End Users&amp;rsquo; LIcense Agreement). Yes, the one that you clicked &amp;ldquo;I Agree&amp;rdquo; on, without even reading one word of.</description></item><item><title>SpiderOak Promotion Code For Free Upgrade To 10 GB</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/12/spideroak-promotion-code-for-free-upgrade-to-10-gb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2008 20:58:32 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/12/spideroak-promotion-code-for-free-upgrade-to-10-gb/</guid><description>Just a small shout out to let you guys know that you can use the discount coupon code “linkup” while signing up the excellent online backup service SpiderOak to get a major bump to 10 GB from the 2 GB that they give to normal accounts.
For those who don’t know SpiderOak is a great online data backup service, with its major strengths being truly cross paltform (Mac/Linux/Windows – 32 bit as well as 64 bit), easy interface, rsync like differential backups to save time and disk space, versioned file history, web as well as client interface, unlimited number of devices, unlimited bandwidth, etc etc.</description></item><item><title>Firefox Incognito / Private Browsing Mode - Part II</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/11/firefox-incognito-private-browsing-mode-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2008 16:59:33 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/11/firefox-incognito-private-browsing-mode-part-ii/</guid><description>A few people (e.g. Varun) told me my previous post differed from the way how google chrome / Microsoft IE8 handle Incognito (Private Browsing) mode. The main consideration was that while chrome/IE8 don&amp;rsquo;t write anything to disk at all, the firefox method is an after-effect, i.e., writing to disk and then clearing it up while closing the window. Well, true but nothing is non-rectificable :). So this is a post about a method that one can use to go &amp;ldquo;really&amp;rdquo; undercover with firefox.</description></item><item><title>Firefox Incognito Mode Is Here: Move Over Chrome/IE8</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/10/firefox-incognito-mode-is-here-move-over-chromeie8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2008 17:49:41 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/10/firefox-incognito-mode-is-here-move-over-chromeie8/</guid><description>Update: Part 2 of this post is now up here to allay some of the drawbacks that were pointed out.
There has been so much hype over the “Incognito” (or Private Browsing) mode of Google Chrome / Microsoft IE8, with many internet users screeming Hallelujiah. But I don’t understand what the hoopla is all about. This mode has always been there in Mozilla firefox as well. You just need to devote less than one minute (yes, you read that right, less than one minute) to set it up.</description></item><item><title>Fixing The WordPress Drain Hole Pugin v2.1.3</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/10/fixing-the-wordpress-drain-hole-pugin-v213/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2008 17:36:27 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/10/fixing-the-wordpress-drain-hole-pugin-v213/</guid><description>If you use the awesome download manager plugin &amp;ldquo;Drain Hole&amp;rdquo; for your WordPress blog (A short review here), and upgraded to the latest version 2.1.3, you must have noticed that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t scan and add new files to the download repositories now. Well, this is a quick and short post to tell you how to fix it in less than a minute.
Steps:
Go to your wordpress folder and then navigate to wp-content/plugins/drain-hole/models.</description></item><item><title>Tip: Gadgets, Deals And Stuff You Need To Know - Part III</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/06/10/tip-gadgets-deals-and-stuff-you-need-to-know-part-iii/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2008 13:05:35 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/06/10/tip-gadgets-deals-and-stuff-you-need-to-know-part-iii/</guid><description>This is the last part in this series. So far we’ve seen how to select the gadget and how to get the best price for it. This time we’ll fill in the last remaining piece of the puzzle, the minor tit-bits that go a long way in preventing a lot of heart-burn. Don’t worry this is a short one.
This last piece is to make sure that the place that you decided upon to buy your gadget, is OK in all respects, i.</description></item><item><title>Tip: Gadgets, Deals And Stuff You Need To Know - Part II</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/06/04/tip-gadgets-deals-and-stuff-you-need-to-know-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2008 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/06/04/tip-gadgets-deals-and-stuff-you-need-to-know-part-ii/</guid><description>Last time we discussed how to select the gadget that you want to buy. This time I’ll tell you some of the things that I do to find the best price for it.
Use Price Comparison Engines: These engines will let you search for your desired products and provide a comparison of the costs at which they are available at different stores online as well as offline. Two of my favourites are Price Grabber and Froogle.</description></item><item><title>Tip: Gadgets, Deals And Stuff You Need To Know - Part I</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/06/02/tip-gadgets-deals-and-stuff-you-need-to-know-part-i/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2008 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/06/02/tip-gadgets-deals-and-stuff-you-need-to-know-part-i/</guid><description>If you are a gadget freak like me and can’t resist the temptations to buy the newest toy on the shelves, then you’d obviously want to eek out the maximum you can from whatever budget you have. But while doing so you have to take care of a lot of things. Here is Part I of the few things that I do get the best deals out there while making sure I’m buying the right thing from the right place.</description></item><item><title>TIP: Viewing Any PDF Online, Without A PDF Reader And For Free</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/23/tip-viewing-any-pdf-online-without-a-pdf-reader-and-for-free/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2008 21:42:54 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/23/tip-viewing-any-pdf-online-without-a-pdf-reader-and-for-free/</guid><description>Just a small tip. If you want to view a pdf and you don’t have adobe acrobat (or any other pdf reader) installed, e.g., you are sitting in a cyber cage or at a friend’s place, you can still view it. Only thing you have to do is, just prefix the url to the online pdf with &amp;ldquo;http://www.scribd.com/vacuum?url=&amp;rdquo; and you’ll see a nice web interface rendering your pdf without having to install anything on your PC.</description></item><item><title>Fill Your Password To Invite Your Buddies - Not So Fast!!</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/16/fill-your-password-to-invite-your-buddies-not-so-fast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2008 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/16/fill-your-password-to-invite-your-buddies-not-so-fast/</guid><description>For the past many years, I’ve seen a trend that has been on a meteoric rise. Whatever new service you sign on for on the internet (especially the web2.0–oh-so-cool-you-have-to-tell-everyone-about-it ones), it gives you an option to fill in your e-mail ID and password and makes a generous offer of letting all your friends know about your new avatar and let them all join in the fun. Most of the people around me, it seems, don’t think twice before gladly accepting the offer, as is made apparent from the increasing amount of automated mails I’m getting with subjects like “Hey, don’t be left out!</description></item><item><title>Keep Tab On Home Security With A Webcam And Twitter</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/14/keep-tab-on-home-security-with-a-webcam-and-twitter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2008 04:00:13 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/14/keep-tab-on-home-security-with-a-webcam-and-twitter/</guid><description>Worried about someone breaking into your house in your absence? Or just need to keep a tab on who enters your room while you are away? Well, all you need is a webcam, a linux PC/laptop and a twitter account. And you are set for real time updates through twitter about all that goes on at your abode behind your back (can even receive a text message/sms on your phone). Keep reading for the very simple setup you need.</description></item><item><title>Fun With Webcam In Linux</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/12/fun-with-webcam-in-linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2008 03:57:47 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/12/fun-with-webcam-in-linux/</guid><description>Did you know that instead of installing special software to view your webcam video, you can simply use mplayer for the same purpose, and with a lot of fine control. e.g. try running the following command with your webcam attached to your computer.
And you can use mencoder to capture and encode video from your webcam:
mencoder tv:// -tv driver=v4l2:width=60:height=40:fps=60:device=/dev/video0 -nosound -ovc lavc -lavcopts vcodec=mjpeg -o test.avi Have fun playing with the huge number of options available.</description></item><item><title>Tip: Getting Your Webcam To Work In Ubuntu</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/10/tip-getting-your-webcam-to-work-in-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2008 19:17:42 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/10/tip-getting-your-webcam-to-work-in-ubuntu/</guid><description>I have an old noname cheapo webcam, that I dusted out of my junk (why? More on that in a post coming soon). I hoped that it would work in my Ubuntu setup out of the box like most of my other hardware. I connected it to my laptop&amp;rsquo;s usb port. dmesg gave the following output:
[21328.211333] usb 1-1: new full speed USB device using ohci_hcd and address 2 [21328.319698] usb 1-1: configuration #1 chosen from 1 choice [21328.</description></item><item><title>Hack:Disabling the Message Box In Oxios Memory Apps (Windows Mobile)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/15/hackdisabling-the-message-box-in-oxios-memory-apps-windows-mobile/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2008 08:43:29 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/15/hackdisabling-the-message-box-in-oxios-memory-apps-windows-mobile/</guid><description>**Update: **Modified the &amp;ldquo;Oxios Hibernate&amp;rdquo; app as well on public demand. Please redownload the below mentioned package. It now has Oxios Close as well as Oxios Hibernate.
Oxios developed a very useful tool for Windows Mobile (WM2003/5/6/6.1) called &amp;ldquo;Oxios Memory&amp;rdquo; sometime ago. On running it, it&amp;rsquo;ll flush your RAM (kind of) and recover substantial amounts of memory that can be used by the currently program. It is so good at this that many people run it regularly on their phones, and most of them want to run it in an automated mode (through a scheduler or a script).</description></item><item><title>TIP: Make Those Linux Samba Shares Accessible From Windows Mobile</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/30/tip-make-those-linux-samba-shares-accessible-from-windows-mobile/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2008 10:30:12 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/30/tip-make-those-linux-samba-shares-accessible-from-windows-mobile/</guid><description>If you have ever needed to share files between your Linux and Windows computers, you have obviously used Samba, and have been quite happy with the way it seamlessly provides access to and from shared folders/files from Windows and Linux. However, many people complain that although their smb/Samba shares are accessible from Windows, they are not able to do the same with their Windows Mobile devices. e.g., using a tool called &amp;ldquo;Resco Explorer&amp;rdquo; on Windows Mobile, all they get while searching for their linux based Samba shares is the following screenshot:</description></item><item><title>Ubuntu TIP: Extending Nautilus, Scripting Your Way To UI Bliss</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/09/ubuntu-tip-extending-nautilus-scripting-your-way-to-ui-bliss/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2008 16:10:18 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/09/ubuntu-tip-extending-nautilus-scripting-your-way-to-ui-bliss/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m back from my vacation and this is a smallish post before we return to our regular programming (I&amp;rsquo;m full of puns ).
Rahul (my friend and guest author on this blog) introduced me to an old-but-useful trick a few days ago that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about. It&amp;rsquo;s about customizing nautilus to display a context menu that has a few of your chosen scripts to weave their magic on the selected object.</description></item><item><title>Ubuntu TIP: Automating Package Installation – apt-get to the rescue</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/06/ubuntu-tip-automating-package-installation-apt-get-to-the-rescue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2008 03:30:20 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/06/ubuntu-tip-automating-package-installation-apt-get-to-the-rescue/</guid><description>Admin Note: Rahul is a long time friend of mine, and is a well known geek amongst his friends and colleagues. I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce that he will be enriching this site from time-to-time as a guest editor/author. First up is a small tid-bit of a script that he wrote to ease up his life between installations and reinstallations of everyone&amp;rsquo;s favourite OS: Ubuntu. Over to his post..
Have you ever had to reinstall your ubuntu installation, and then bear the pain of manually installing the applications you&amp;rsquo;ve come to love (i mean use :)) everyday?</description></item><item><title> TIP: Automating Website Backups - Part IIb (Reducing Backup Size Contd.)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/28/tip-automating-website-backups-part-iib-reducing-backup-size-contd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/28/tip-automating-website-backups-part-iib-reducing-backup-size-contd/</guid><description>Last time, I had told you about how to reduce the backup size. Well, this is a short note further developing on the approaches discussed there. Basically, telling tar to backup only those files which have changed. For this, Linux has a command “find” which I am very fond of. You can give it a option “-newer” followed by a f”filename” and it will return the names of the files that are newer than filename.</description></item><item><title>TIP: Move Your WordPress Blog, And Leave The Trash Behind</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/27/tip-move-your-wordpress-blog-and-leave-the-trash-behind/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2008 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/27/tip-move-your-wordpress-blog-and-leave-the-trash-behind/</guid><description>If you are moving your blog, or just want to start afresh, you would definitely use some way to import your old content into the new place, instead of manually copying and pasting everything. Generally this means saving your database and importing into the new place. But:
You have seen WordPress importing your/others&amp;rsquo; blogs from other services automatically. Wasn&amp;rsquo;t that quick and easy.
Your databse has become overly full of so much trash over the years and you would like to trim out all the fat and take just the meat (the posts, pages, comments, tags, custom fields etc)</description></item><item><title>TIP: WordPress Posts Scheduling - Back To The Future (or Blast From The Past?)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/26/tip-wordpress-posts-scheduling-back-to-the-future-or-blast-from-the-past/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/26/tip-wordpress-posts-scheduling-back-to-the-future-or-blast-from-the-past/</guid><description>If you are like me (I mean underpaid, overworked, coding zombie), then the only time you find for blogging is weekends. To keep your readers happy and satisfied through the week, the only options you have are burning the midnight electricity (what? You still use oil? :P) or paying up your son/nephew/wife/etc to push the publish button regularly for the drafts you wrote on weekend. Right? WRONG….
Matt and his AutoMattic team took care of bonded labour like us, and had the good heart to put in the capability of scheduling posts in WordPress (More commonly known as “future posting”).</description></item><item><title>TIP: Automating Website Backups - Part II (Reducing Backup Size)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/24/tip-automating-website-backups-part-ii-reducing-backup-size/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2008 21:43:13 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/24/tip-automating-website-backups-part-ii-reducing-backup-size/</guid><description>Last week I had written a short guide on “Automating Website Backups”. I received some good comments/suggestions about it from Jasvinder through e-mail about other aspects that should be addressed. So, thought of doing a few follow ups to that post. This is done in more of a FAQ fashion, so as to answer some of the questions that may arise after reading the first post. Each post will answer one of the questions listed below in detail</description></item><item><title>TIP: Automating Website Backups</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/17/tip-automating-website-backups/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2008 09:19:50 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/17/tip-automating-website-backups/</guid><description>What can go wrong with your wonderfully running website / blog? Everything..
Your online abode is so difficult to keep secured. It can get hacked, you may install something wrong, a wrong configuration can wreak havoc, the server hard disk might crash, natural calamities, and what not. Your best option to secure yourself against all this is summarized in just one word “BACKUP”.
Now, a backup involves two most important things: “Database Backup” and “Files Backup”.</description></item><item><title>TIP: Switching Soundcards In Ubuntu</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/12/tip-switching-soundcards-in-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2008 18:00:47 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/12/tip-switching-soundcards-in-ubuntu/</guid><description>If you have multiple soundcards in your system and have to switch between them regularly (e.g. laptop owners like me, who use an external soundcard while being docked to groove to the highest and the lowest of frequencies through those 7.1 channels and use the in-built sound card while on the move) you would definitely be under-whelmed by the less-than-stellar performance of ubuntu in switching between the sound cards. For me at least, ubuntu (fiesty 7.</description></item><item><title>Tips: Configure FTP upload support for wordpress in Blogjet</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/07/tips-configure-ftp-upload-support-for-wordpress-in-blogjet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2008 14:36:27 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/07/tips-configure-ftp-upload-support-for-wordpress-in-blogjet/</guid><description>A few days ago, I had written about a wonderful blogging tool Blogjet. Now, if you host a wordpress blog, you’d be aware of the fact that for wordpress to be able to upload yor files (images, attachements in post etc) to the server, you have to make the upload directory writable by all. Now, this is a BIG security risk. Some people go to the lengths of CHMOD’ding their upload directory for a short while and after upload, restoring the apt file permissions back.</description></item></channel></rss>