<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>protostar on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/protostar/</link><description>Recent content in protostar on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 21:04:24 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/protostar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Practical Reverse Engineering Tutorials Part 2: Protostar Stack4</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/12/04/practical-reverse-engineering-tutorial-2-protostar-stack4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 21:04:24 +0530</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/12/04/practical-reverse-engineering-tutorial-2-protostar-stack4/</guid><description>About the challenge In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll go through the Protostar stack4 challenge. This would be a bit similar to the stack0 challenge that we already tackled earlier, but it will think about an interesting way to get alternate code to execute instead of just modifying data.
Pre-requisite: Make sure you&amp;rsquo;ve completed the Part 1 of the Practical Reverse Engineering Tutorials series. It&amp;rsquo;d also be great if you can try stack1-stack3 challenges on your own as they are similar to stack0.</description></item><item><title>Practical Reverse Engineering Tutorials Part 1: Introduction &amp; Protostar Stack 0</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/11/16/practical-reverse-engineering-tutorial-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 08:46:24 +0530</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/11/16/practical-reverse-engineering-tutorial-1/</guid><description>What is this about? This article is the 1st part of the Practical Reverse Engineering Tutorials series. This series is geared towards a structured, but almost completely practical, approach to learn Reverse Engineering. Many of the existing articles/books take a long winded approach to teach RE which is prefixed with a lot of theory before the reader can get their hands dirty. This series will take a different approach of picking up various challenges in the order of increasing difficulty and help the reader in exploring ways how to break them.</description></item></channel></rss>