<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Smartphone on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/smartphone/</link><description>Recent content in Smartphone on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2010 04:10:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/smartphone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A short Tablet/Smartphone survey for a project</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/11/15/short-tablet-smartphone-survey-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2010 04:10:06 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/11/15/short-tablet-smartphone-survey-project/</guid><description>I need a bit of your help in filling out a short survey that I need for a small project of mine that I&amp;rsquo;m doing with a friend. It will take maximum of only 2-3 minutes of your time. Please fill it out below. If you are facing any problems with the survey or have any queries/suggestions etc, please use this contact form to send them to us.
Much Thanks!! :)</description></item><item><title>The Elusive Super Phone</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/08/the-elusive-super-phone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2008 17:15:28 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/08/the-elusive-super-phone/</guid><description>HTC announce their shiny new Touch Diamond recently. Everyone ooh&amp;rsquo;ed and aah&amp;rsquo;ed while ogling at it until they realized that HTC has taken a step back (or forward towards matching Apple&amp;rsquo;s iPhone crap) by removing the expansion card slot from the phone. Yes, it has 4 GB of internal storage but I&amp;rsquo;d rather have an SDHC card slot with the ever falling prices of solid state memory (an 8 GB Class 6 SDHC card is worth not more than around 60$ these days).</description></item><item><title>Boring Meetings? CallJockey To The Rescue</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/19/boring-meetings-calljockey-to-the-rescue/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2008 04:43:19 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/19/boring-meetings-calljockey-to-the-rescue/</guid><description>Stuck in another boring meeting? You have a way out now, because connectivetools have released their app CallJockey, which can simulate fake incoming calls. What&amp;rsquo;s more, you can select the name, phone number or one of your saved contacts from whom the fake call will appear to be coming, plus you can define the time when you want it to ring. The only limitation is that it is available only for WM5 smarphones (WM6 Standard), i.</description></item><item><title>ShantzTodayChanger</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/shantztodaychanger/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 13:41:30 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/shantztodaychanger/</guid><description>Intro:
This is a little tool for your Windows Mobile based phones (Compatible with WM5/WM6 but not WM2003) which will cycle ur today background or theme after a set interval of time. It has a lot of features and options that you can discover by reading the text below. And you can even use this options to achieve something other than changing wallpapers as well but that depends on your imagination.</description></item><item><title>Beware of Fake Nokia N95 Cell Phones, Pirated by Chinese</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/29/beware-of-fake-nokia-n95-cell-phones-pirated-by-chinese/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2008 09:15:32 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/29/beware-of-fake-nokia-n95-cell-phones-pirated-by-chinese/</guid><description>Came across this post today, now even your N95’s aren’t safe. Make sure to check this guide to identify if your latest boy-toy is a fake or not.
Beware of Fake Nokia N95 Cell Phones, Pirated by Chinese.</description></item></channel></rss>