<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Plugin on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/plugin/</link><description>Recent content in Plugin on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2008 12:48:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/plugin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Project: My WordPress Plugin "Shantz WP Prefix Suffix" Updated to 1.0.4</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/15/project-my-wordpress-plugin-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-to-104/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2008 12:48:42 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/15/project-my-wordpress-plugin-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-to-104/</guid><description>For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know Shantz-WP-Prefix-Suffix is a WordPress plugin that allows you to add any text and/or HTML/CSS/PHP/Javascript code to the top or bottom of your posts (e.g. see my site links at top of each post and the copyright link and permalink at the bottom of each) I&amp;rsquo;ve updated it to version 1.0.4 which allows you to add PHP code to the top or bottom of your posts now.</description></item><item><title>Fixing The WordPress Drain Hole Pugin v2.1.3</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/10/fixing-the-wordpress-drain-hole-pugin-v213/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2008 17:36:27 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/10/fixing-the-wordpress-drain-hole-pugin-v213/</guid><description>If you use the awesome download manager plugin &amp;ldquo;Drain Hole&amp;rdquo; for your WordPress blog (A short review here), and upgraded to the latest version 2.1.3, you must have noticed that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t scan and add new files to the download repositories now. Well, this is a quick and short post to tell you how to fix it in less than a minute.
Steps:
Go to your wordpress folder and then navigate to wp-content/plugins/drain-hole/models.</description></item><item><title>Project: My WordPress Plugin shantz-wp-qotd updated to version 1.2.2</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/10/project-my-wordpress-plugin-shantz-wp-qotd-updated-to-version-122/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2008 20:33:41 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/10/project-my-wordpress-plugin-shantz-wp-qotd-updated-to-version-122/</guid><description>Updated my WordPress plugin shantz-wp-qotd to version 1.2.2 today.
Introduction: Shantz WP QOTD is a plugin to add quotes to your wordpress blog in a few easy clicks. It adds quotes to your posts and your sidebars with a multitude of options for sources and customization.
Changelog:
Version 1.2.2
Fixed a bug because of which quotes were blank some times. Thanks to Thom for reporting it.</description></item><item><title>HACK: Fixing The Code Syntax Highlighter WordPress Plugins To Work With WYSIWYG</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/23/hack-fixing-the-code-syntax-highlighter-wordpress-plugins-to-work-with-wysiwyg/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2008 17:18:22 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/23/hack-fixing-the-code-syntax-highlighter-wordpress-plugins-to-work-with-wysiwyg/</guid><description>There are many code syntax highlighter plugins available for WordPress (e.g. iG Syntax Highlighter, WP-Syntax, etc) but almost all of them have a problem. They want you to write the code in &amp;ldquo;HTML editing mode&amp;rdquo;. If you use any kind of WYSIWYG or visual editors (like built in TinyMCE or offline clients&amp;rsquo; similar modes), there is a grave problem. Your code becomes garbled. e.g.:
If you intend to write:
It might turn out as:</description></item><item><title>WordPress Must Have Plugins: Download Managers</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/29/wordpress-must-have-plugins-download-managers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Feb 2008 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/29/wordpress-must-have-plugins-download-managers/</guid><description>If you serve any kind of files for download on your WordPress blog(s), one thing you should definitly be looking out for is a download manager plugin. Post attachments are oh-so-2007. Uploading files to your server and hand-posting links everywhere is a pain in the butt. And what about your hunger for statistics?
Well, if you agree with me, then i would like to tell you about two fantastic plugins:</description></item><item><title>Project: "shantz-wp-qotd ", My Wordpress Plugin, Updated to 1.1.0</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/17/project-shantz-wp-qotd-my-wordpress-plugin-update-to-110/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2008 15:44:18 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/17/project-shantz-wp-qotd-my-wordpress-plugin-update-to-110/</guid><description>For the uninitiated:
I made a few additions / modifications to the code and the plugin has been updated to 1.1.0. The changes are:
Added Custom tag support for adding quotes anywhere in your posts/pages
Added Custom quote separator support and multi-line quotes support
Config Screenshots:
I recommend that you update to this new version asap, as apart from the above mentioned changes, the code is a bit more cleaner as well, which would run a bit better IMO and also help in any modification if you have in mind.</description></item><item><title>Shantz WordPress QOTD</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/10/shantz-wordpress-qotd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 10:22:57 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/10/shantz-wordpress-qotd/</guid><description>Shantz WP QOTD is a plugin to add quotes to your wordpress blog in a few easy clicks. It adds quotes to your posts and your sidebars with a multitude of options for sources and customization.
== Description ==
There are many quotes plugins out there. This one has been started with a view to have the best of features and options, ease of use and multiple sources to get the quotes from.</description></item></channel></rss>