<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nokia on</title><link>/tags/nokia/</link><description>Recent content in Nokia on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2008 14:50:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/nokia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>X-Men Are Here, Only That They Are In Your Hands</title><link>/2008/02/25/x-men-are-here-only-that-they-are-in-your-hands/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2008 14:50:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/02/25/x-men-are-here-only-that-they-are-in-your-hands/</guid><description>Who wouldn’t agree that Morph is most probably the coolest mutant (besides Wolverine of of course ). Now, it seems that the Finnish Giant Nokia has a lot of X-Men lovers as well, as they put out their latest offering to us lesser mortals. They call it “The Morph Concept”.
Featured in The Museum of Modern Art “Design and The Elastic Mind” exhibition, the Morph concept device is a bridge between highly advanced technologies and their potential benefits to end-users.</description><content>&lt;p>Who wouldn’t agree that Morph is most probably the coolest mutant (besides Wolverine of of course &lt;img src="/img/uploads/smile1.gif" alt=""> ). Now, it seems that the Finnish Giant Nokia has a lot of X-Men lovers as well, as they put out their latest offering to us lesser mortals. They call it “&lt;a href="http://www.nokia.com/A4852062">The Morph Concept&lt;/a>”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/img/uploads/nokia_2Dmorph_2Dconcept_2Dnano_2Dmaterials_small.jpg" alt="Nokia-morph-concept-nano-materials">&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Featured in The Museum of Modern Art “Design and The Elastic Mind” exhibition, the Morph concept device is a bridge between highly advanced technologies and their potential benefits to end-users. This device concept showcases some revolutionary leaps being explored by Nokia Research Center (NRC) in collaboration with the Cambridge Nanoscience Centre (United Kingdom) – nanoscale technologies that will potentially create a world of radically different devices that open up an entirely new spectrum of possibilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Yeah, yeah, museum-shmuseum, nanotech-shanotech. All I know is that until I see this thing up on &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->, my call is “vaporware”.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Nokia + Windows Mobile = Let's Kick Some &lt;InsertWMPhoneMakerName> Butt</title><link>/2008/02/08/nokia-windows-mobile-lets-kick-some-butt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2008 05:00:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/02/08/nokia-windows-mobile-lets-kick-some-butt/</guid><description>As everyone knows, I’m an out-and-out Windows Mobile worshipper. It’s like a girlfriend, who is very difficult to manage and understand at first, but is a great source of joy if you know how to manage her. I don’t like any other phones now; the extensibility given by WM will do that to you.
I also “admire” Nokia because of the quality and reliability they provide with their phones. Having worked for them in a project (Nokia Networks/Nokia Seimens Networks actually), I know how much testing they put in before releasing something.</description><content>&lt;p>As everyone knows, I’m an out-and-out Windows Mobile worshipper. It’s like a girlfriend, who is very difficult to manage and understand at first, but is a great source of joy if you know how to manage her. I don’t like any other phones now; the extensibility given by WM will do that to you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also “admire” Nokia because of the quality and reliability they provide with their phones. Having worked for them in a project (Nokia Networks/Nokia Seimens Networks actually), I know how much testing they put in before releasing something. That coupled with the recent &lt;a href="/2008/01/28/htc-the-best-windows-mobile-business-unit.html">crap-doings&lt;/a> by even the largest of the WM Phone companies like HTC, have made me try to look elsewhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, if this &lt;a href="http://www.itwire.com/content/view/16510/127/">news&lt;/a> comes true, then we are in for a treat, as the two giants might just come together to give us a sweet little toy for our “smart” cravings &lt;img src="/img/uploads/smile3.gif" alt="">. Read the news and let us know how you feel about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PS: Don’t even mention iPhone/iPod/iTouch or any other iCrap.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Beware of Fake Nokia N95 Cell Phones, Pirated by Chinese</title><link>/2008/01/29/beware-of-fake-nokia-n95-cell-phones-pirated-by-chinese/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2008 09:15:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/01/29/beware-of-fake-nokia-n95-cell-phones-pirated-by-chinese/</guid><description>Came across this post today, now even your N95’s aren’t safe. Make sure to check this guide to identify if your latest boy-toy is a fake or not.
Beware of Fake Nokia N95 Cell Phones, Pirated by Chinese.</description><content>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Came across this post today, now even your N95’s aren’t safe. Make sure to check this guide to identify if your latest boy-toy is a fake or not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://news.ronatvan.com/2008/01/29/beware-of-fake-nokia-n95-cell-phones-pirated-by-chinese/">Beware of Fake Nokia N95 Cell Phones, Pirated by Chinese&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>