<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>blog on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/blog/</link><description>Recent content in blog on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 16:25:46 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Migrating my hugo blog from Gitlab/AWS S3 to Github Pages with Actions</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2020/01/05/migrate-hugo-blog-gitlab-s3-github-pages-actions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 16:25:46 +0530</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2020/01/05/migrate-hugo-blog-gitlab-s3-github-pages-actions/</guid><description>Until Now - The State of the union This blog is generated using hugo, an awesome static site generator. So far, the workflow I used to deploy it was:
Push commit to the source repository on GitLab GitLab CI kicks off on receiving the push CI downloads latest version of hugo and generates the static site Runs aws-cli to sync the new files to AWS S3 S3 serves the static site Cloudflare provides: DNS services (so I can use https://shantanugoel.</description></item><item><title>WordCamp India Is Here</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/14/wordcamp-india/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2009 20:51:48 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/14/wordcamp-india/</guid><description>Just a little piece of news to all the bloggers, and especially WordPressers (did I just coin a new term?), out there. WordCamp is coming to India. And what&amp;rsquo;s more, Matt is going to be there. (Yes, THE Matt. Oh My, you just don&amp;rsquo;t believe me, do you. Fanboys, it is time to rejoice as I assure you this is THE Matt Mullenweg). It&amp;rsquo;s going to be held on the 21st and 22nd of this Feb at Adobe, Noida (who are the main sponsors for this event).</description></item><item><title>Slow Updates And A Small Nugget Post</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/13/slow-updates-and-a-small-nugget-post/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2009 04:47:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/13/slow-updates-and-a-small-nugget-post/</guid><description>Many readers of this blog have written to me for the slow updates. I apologize for the same. I’ve been swamped by loads of work for quite some time now and haven’t been able to write anything here or update any of my projects, though I have loads of new hacks and tricks that I would write once I’m free and lots in store for most of the projects as well in form of bug fixes and new features.</description></item><item><title>Site Updates</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/29/site-updates-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 18:16:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/29/site-updates-2/</guid><description>Just wanted to apologize to you guys for not updating this blog frequently as work load is becoming more and more these days. But I&amp;rsquo;ll try my best to update as often as possible. There are a couple of useful apps that I wrote some time ago but havent found time to add all the features that I wanted and to roll them out, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll release them with the current feature set.</description></item><item><title>Twittering Away With Delhi Bloggers</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/06/twittering-away-with-delhi-bloggers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2008 14:57:24 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/06/twittering-away-with-delhi-bloggers/</guid><description>If you are twittering kinds, doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter online or offline
If you blog or are interested in all things blog and blogging
If you live in Delhi, have lived there, have been there, or just connect with Delhi somehow else
If you want to meet up with your fellow twitterers and bloggers
Then you&amp;rsquo;ve got to be a part of the your very own City of The People With Hearts, Delhi.</description></item><item><title>One Month Completed....</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/28/one-month-completed/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 04:10:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/28/one-month-completed/</guid><description>Today, this blog completes one month of its existence in this world. The achievements, although minuscule in comparison to all the biggies out there, are significant for me. It achieved the following things in just 30 days from the first post:
Front-paged at LifeHacker, HacksZine, and many others.
Over 10000 (Ten Thousand) &amp;ldquo;unique&amp;rdquo; human visitors.
Over 30000 (Thirty Thousand) page views by humans.
Over 500000 (Half Million) total hits for all website files included.</description></item><item><title>shantz-csv-to-opml</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/22/shantz-csv-to-opml/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2008 04:53:53 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/22/shantz-csv-to-opml/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION
This is a very simple script that I did for a friend. It can be used to quickly generate blogrolls.
Input: csv file with blog author names and blog links
Output: OPML file that can be imported into many blogging/blogrolling software and websites (e.g. wordpress, blogrolling.com, etc)
Usage:
shantz-csv-to-opml.pl &amp;lt;input file in csv format&amp;gt; &amp;lt;output opml filename&amp;gt; Input File Format: Each line should be like this: &amp;lt;Name of Author&amp;gt;,&amp;lt;bloglink&amp;gt;,&amp;lt;bloglink&amp;gt;... e.</description></item><item><title>Project: "shantz-wp-qotd ", My Wordpress Plugin, Updated to 1.1.0</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/17/project-shantz-wp-qotd-my-wordpress-plugin-update-to-110/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2008 15:44:18 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/17/project-shantz-wp-qotd-my-wordpress-plugin-update-to-110/</guid><description>For the uninitiated:
I made a few additions / modifications to the code and the plugin has been updated to 1.1.0. The changes are:
Added Custom tag support for adding quotes anywhere in your posts/pages
Added Custom quote separator support and multi-line quotes support
Config Screenshots:
I recommend that you update to this new version asap, as apart from the above mentioned changes, the code is a bit more cleaner as well, which would run a bit better IMO and also help in any modification if you have in mind.</description></item><item><title>My First WordPress Plugin: Please Welcome shantz-wp-qotd</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/10/my-first-wordpress-plugin-please-welcome-shantz-wp-qotd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 11:00:27 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/10/my-first-wordpress-plugin-please-welcome-shantz-wp-qotd/</guid><description>Motivated by Ronald’s ultimate wordpress plugin tutorial at devlounge, I decided that the best way to learn something is to use it in a live project. Armed with my laptop and multiple flasks of coffee, the marathon began on Friday night. My only experience with web-related development so far had been around 8–10 years ago as a kid when, just like everybody else at that time, I was fascinated by HTML and did a “read-through” of HTML 4.</description></item><item><title>Site Updates: More Content For You</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/site-updates-more-content-for-you/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 19:36:42 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/site-updates-more-content-for-you/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve added a few new sections to the blog. Do check them out. Here is a list of the new sections along with their descriptions.
[Projects]: Although I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t put myself in the category of an excellent developer but I can sure type in a few lines that can compile without an error and also manage to carry out a task or two. So, this page will list some of those little things that I write to weed out a few niggles or scratch a few itches of mine.</description></item><item><title>BlogJet - Blog Faster, Blog Better (Now In Linux too, with a hidden bonus)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/29/blogjet-blog-faster-blog-better-now-in-linux-too-with-a-hidden-bonus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2008 15:30:27 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/29/blogjet-blog-faster-blog-better-now-in-linux-too-with-a-hidden-bonus/</guid><description>A quick googling for best desktop blogging client would yield just a few (read millions/gazillions) results. Having researched the subject a lot, my choices were finally limited down to BlogJet and BlogDesk, as per my feature set requirement goes (Primarily, off line editing, draft, WYSIWYG editing, categories, tagging support, pinging, trackbacks support, timestamping, past post editing, automatic image uploading) BUT there is one little problem. Both of these don’t work on Linux.</description></item></channel></rss>