<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on</title><link>/tags/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 16:25:46 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Migrating my hugo blog from Gitlab/AWS S3 to Github Pages with Actions</title><link>/2020/01/05/migrate-hugo-blog-gitlab-s3-github-pages-actions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 16:25:46 +0530</pubDate><guid>/2020/01/05/migrate-hugo-blog-gitlab-s3-github-pages-actions/</guid><description>Until Now - The State of the union This blog is generated using hugo, an awesome static site generator. So far, the workflow I used to deploy it was:
Push commit to the source repository on GitLab GitLab CI kicks off on receiving the push CI downloads latest version of hugo and generates the static site Runs aws-cli to sync the new files to AWS S3 S3 serves the static site Cloudflare provides: DNS services (so I can use https://shantanugoel.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="until-now---the-state-of-the-union">Until Now - The State of the union&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This blog is generated using hugo, an awesome static site generator. So far, the workflow I used to deploy it was:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Push commit to the source repository on GitLab&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GitLab CI kicks off on receiving the push
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>CI downloads latest version of hugo and generates the static site&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Runs aws-cli to sync the new files to AWS S3&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>S3 serves the static site&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cloudflare provides:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>DNS services (so I can use &lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com">https://shantanugoel.com&lt;/a> without having to prefix it with a &lt;code>www&lt;/code>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>CDN/Caching services for resilience and keeping S3 bills low for data transfer&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="why-what-broke-the-camels-back">Why? What broke the camel&amp;rsquo;s back&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I was mostly happy with this setup with a couple of niggles at the back of my mind, vis. a vis.:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>aws s3 sync was finicky sometimes and sometimes, albeit rarely, the sync didn&amp;rsquo;t complete&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It took a long time to deploy a new update. Whenever I made a new post, it took around 5 minutes or more to appear due to issues stemming from GitLab CI taking time but mostly due to the time spent in s3 sync.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I also wanted to reduce the moving parts. I could have used GitLab pages but they&amp;rsquo;ve proved unreliable whenever I tried to use them&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When the files ran into 10s of thousands, if I did lot of updates, I started running into incurring some cost due to S3 API usage. Especially because it was hard to upload only changed files. I tried few methods with hashes etc and it could be improved further but still I wanted to get rid of this issue.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Finally, the last push was announcement of &lt;a href="https://github.com/features/actions">GitHub Actions&lt;/a>. I had the itch, as usual, to try out the new and shiny, and so here we are.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="what-all-i-need-is-everything">What? All I need is everything&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>So, what I wanted to do was replace the source storage (GitLab to GitHub), CI (GitLab to GitHub Actions) and site host (AWS S3 to GitHub Pages). I kept Cloudflare&amp;rsquo;s DNS and CDN services as is because they are awesome, and I still want to continue to use the naked domain without &lt;code>www&lt;/code>.
Another thing I wanted while going this way was to keep the source repository and pages repository on GitHub separate because I want to be able to keep drafts in GitHub without having them available publicly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ll see in the next section how all this was put together.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-lets-get-our-hands-dirty-shall-we">How? Let&amp;rsquo;s get our hands dirty, shall we!&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The migration turned out to be pretty simple. This is how my setup looks like now:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Made a private source repository at GitHub, let&amp;rsquo;s call this &lt;code>shantanugoel.com-source&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>This repository will be used to contain the website&amp;rsquo;s source&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Made another public repository which will contain our published site, e.g. &lt;a href="https://github.com/shantanugoel/shantanugoel.com">https://github.com/shantanugoel/shantanugoel.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Go to the settings section of this repository (e.g. &lt;a href="https://github.com/shantanugoel/shantanugoel.com/settings/">https://github.com/shantanugoel/shantanugoel.com/settings/&lt;/a> ) and set it to serve GitHub pages from the master branch&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Go to the Deploy Keys section of this repository (e.g. &lt;a href="https://github.com/shantanugoel/shantanugoel.com/settings/keys">https://github.com/shantanugoel/shantanugoel.com/settings/keys&lt;/a> ) and generate a deploy key with write access to the repository. Copy this key somewhere as you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to see this again.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Go to your source repository&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code>Secrets&lt;/code> section (e.g. &lt;a href="https://github.com/shantanugoel/shantanugoel.com-source/settings/secrets">https://github.com/shantanugoel/shantanugoel.com-source/settings/secrets&lt;/a> ), and click on &amp;ldquo;Add a new secret&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Add a new secret named &lt;code>ACTIONS_DEPLOY_KEY&lt;/code> and set its value to the key that you copied in previous step.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This secret will be used in the action workflow that you&amp;rsquo;ll create in the next step.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Added a GitHub Action workflow specification to the repository at this location relative to root of repository &lt;code>.github/workflows/deploy.yml&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The filename can be anything ending in &lt;code>.yml&lt;/code> and written in YAML, but the directory path needs to be exactly as above.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The contents of the file are below. I&amp;rsquo;ve used comments in the contents to explain their usage.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-yaml" data-lang="yaml">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#75715e"># Names can be anything as per your choice in the file&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">name&lt;/span>: &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">CI&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#75715e"># This action runs whenever somec hange is pushed to the master branch of this repository&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">on&lt;/span>:
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">push&lt;/span>:
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">branches&lt;/span>:
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> - &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">master&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">jobs&lt;/span>:
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">build-deploy&lt;/span>:
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">runs-on&lt;/span>: &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">ubuntu-18.04&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">steps&lt;/span>:
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#75715e"># This action is provided by Github. It checksout the repository along with submodules&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#75715e"># for the hugo theme I use&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> - &lt;span style="color:#f92672">uses&lt;/span>: &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">actions/checkout@v1&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">with&lt;/span>:
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">submodules&lt;/span>: &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">true&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#75715e"># This action downloads the latest hugu&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> - &lt;span style="color:#f92672">name&lt;/span>: &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">Setup Hugo&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">uses&lt;/span>: &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">peaceiris/actions-hugo@v2&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">with&lt;/span>:
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">hugo-version&lt;/span>: &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#39;latest&amp;#39;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#75715e"># Run hugo to generate the site and minify css/js etc&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> - &lt;span style="color:#f92672">name&lt;/span>: &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">Build&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">run&lt;/span>: &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">hugo --minify&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#75715e"># Publish the website to the designated github pages repository&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#75715e"># ACTIONS_DEPLOY_KEY uses our deploy key to publish since the action in source repository&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#75715e"># does not have access permissions to other repositories by default&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#75715e"># EXTERNAL_REPOSITORY param is used to specify the github pages repository, otherwise by default&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#75715e"># this action publishes to current repository itself&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#75715e"># PUBLISH_BRANCH specifies the branch which is set to serve GitHub Pages&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#75715e"># PUBLISH_DIR is the dir where hugo generates the site contents&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> - &lt;span style="color:#f92672">name&lt;/span>: &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">Deploy&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">uses&lt;/span>: &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">peaceiris/actions-gh-pages@v2&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">env&lt;/span>:
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">ACTIONS_DEPLOY_KEY&lt;/span>: &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">${{ secrets.ACTIONS_DEPLOY_KEY }}&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">EXTERNAL_REPOSITORY&lt;/span>: &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">shantanugoel/shantanugoel.com&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">PUBLISH_BRANCH&lt;/span>: &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">master&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">PUBLISH_DIR&lt;/span>: &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">./public&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Now, anytime you commit and push a change to your source repository, it will be live on your destination within a minute or so.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item><item><title>WordCamp India Is Here</title><link>/2009/02/14/wordcamp-india/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2009 20:51:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/02/14/wordcamp-india/</guid><description>Just a little piece of news to all the bloggers, and especially WordPressers (did I just coin a new term?), out there. WordCamp is coming to India. And what&amp;rsquo;s more, Matt is going to be there. (Yes, THE Matt. Oh My, you just don&amp;rsquo;t believe me, do you. Fanboys, it is time to rejoice as I assure you this is THE Matt Mullenweg). It&amp;rsquo;s going to be held on the 21st and 22nd of this Feb at Adobe, Noida (who are the main sponsors for this event).</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://wci.eventbrite.com/">&lt;img src="/img/uploads/wordcamp-india-registration.gif" alt="WordCamp India">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just a little piece of news to all the bloggers, and especially WordPressers (did I just coin a new term?), out there. WordCamp is coming to India. And what&amp;rsquo;s more, Matt is going to be there. (Yes, THE Matt. Oh My, you just don&amp;rsquo;t believe me, do you. Fanboys, it is time to rejoice as I assure you this is THE&lt;a href="http://ma.tt"> Matt Mullenweg&lt;/a>). It&amp;rsquo;s going to be held on the 21st and 22nd of this Feb at Adobe, Noida (who are the main sponsors for this event).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And there is an excellent number of events lined up already. Bollywood masala lovers, start drooling because WordCamp India is going to be a cool mix of talks, interactive discussions, code etc ranging from topics that interest the average joe blogger to the one who wants to make his empire around blogging. Many eminent personalities, besides Matt, would be gracing the occassion and none of these would be there just for the show. All of them have agreed to share their wealth of information with the participants.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, what are you waiting for? Head on to &lt;a href="http://www.delhibloggersbloc.com/">Delhi Bloggers&amp;rsquo; Blog&lt;/a> for complete details or click on the banner at the top for registration. For any other information, ring up Priyanka (9811511719), Mayank (9910786431) or Sanjay (9873707071).&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Slow Updates And A Small Nugget Post</title><link>/2009/01/13/slow-updates-and-a-small-nugget-post/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2009 04:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/01/13/slow-updates-and-a-small-nugget-post/</guid><description>Many readers of this blog have written to me for the slow updates. I apologize for the same. I’ve been swamped by loads of work for quite some time now and haven’t been able to write anything here or update any of my projects, though I have loads of new hacks and tricks that I would write once I’m free and lots in store for most of the projects as well in form of bug fixes and new features.</description><content>&lt;p>Many readers of this blog have written to me for the slow updates. I apologize for the same. I’ve been swamped by loads of work for quite some time now and haven’t been able to write anything here or update any of my projects, though I have loads of new hacks and tricks that I would write once I’m free and lots in store for most of the projects as well in form of bug fixes and new features. So, hang in there :)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meanwhile, take a look at this post ( &lt;a href="http://www.safercode.com/blog/2008/10/14/int-main-vs-void-main.html">int Main() vs void main()&lt;/a> )that I had made some time ago at another blog of mine ( &lt;a href="http://www.safercode.com/blog/">Safer Code - Secure Coding In C \ C++ And More&lt;/a> ). Why I’m telling you about this post is that it is a really important post useful for every C / C++ developer and recently it got featured on LinuxToday and Lxer, after which there is a very interesting discussion going on to discuss the various aspects related to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do check out the rest of the blog as well. It is about tit-bits of security, optimization and performance of your code and in a manner and amount that you can easily digest. What’s best is that it is delivered regularly at a slow pace that everyone can follow :). So, what are you waiting for? Add it to your feed reader or choose to get the updates through e-mail and do let me know in the comments there how you like it.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Site Updates</title><link>/2008/07/29/site-updates-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 18:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/07/29/site-updates-2/</guid><description>Just wanted to apologize to you guys for not updating this blog frequently as work load is becoming more and more these days. But I&amp;rsquo;ll try my best to update as often as possible. There are a couple of useful apps that I wrote some time ago but havent found time to add all the features that I wanted and to roll them out, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll release them with the current feature set.</description><content>&lt;p>Just wanted to apologize to you guys for not updating this blog frequently as work load is becoming more and more these days. But I&amp;rsquo;ll try my best to update as often as possible. There are a couple of useful apps that I wrote some time ago but havent found time to add all the features that I wanted and to roll them out, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll release them with the current feature set.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meanwhile, today I got some time free to finally update both my blogs to WordPress 2.6 and also update all the plugins to their latest versions. Don&amp;rsquo;t notice too much on the frontend, but the admin area seems much snappier.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And as always, please let me know if there is anything specific that you want me to write about in near future.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Twittering Away With Delhi Bloggers</title><link>/2008/04/06/twittering-away-with-delhi-bloggers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2008 14:57:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/04/06/twittering-away-with-delhi-bloggers/</guid><description>If you are twittering kinds, doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter online or offline
If you blog or are interested in all things blog and blogging
If you live in Delhi, have lived there, have been there, or just connect with Delhi somehow else
If you want to meet up with your fellow twitterers and bloggers
Then you&amp;rsquo;ve got to be a part of the your very own City of The People With Hearts, Delhi.</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/img/uploads/tweetup_logo_73x73_bigger.jpg" alt="Tweetup_logo_73x73_bigger">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you are twittering kinds, doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter online or offline&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you blog or are interested in all things blog and blogging&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you live in Delhi, have lived there, have been there, or just connect with Delhi somehow else&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you want to meet up with your fellow twitterers and bloggers&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Then you&amp;rsquo;ve got to be a part of the your very own City of The People With Hearts, Delhi. How, you ask? It&amp;rsquo;s as simple as pointing your mice and keyboards towards &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/delhitweetup">Delhi Tweetup&lt;/a> to get the latest on every scoop about blogging, twittering and blogging and twittering in Delhi (and outside as well).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And if you want to be a little bit more involved, you can also join the &lt;a href="http://groups.yahoo.com/group/delhibloggers">Delhi Bloggers&amp;rsquo; Yahoo Group&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>One Month Completed....</title><link>/2008/02/28/one-month-completed/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 04:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/02/28/one-month-completed/</guid><description>Today, this blog completes one month of its existence in this world. The achievements, although minuscule in comparison to all the biggies out there, are significant for me. It achieved the following things in just 30 days from the first post:
Front-paged at LifeHacker, HacksZine, and many others.
Over 10000 (Ten Thousand) &amp;ldquo;unique&amp;rdquo; human visitors.
Over 30000 (Thirty Thousand) page views by humans.
Over 500000 (Half Million) total hits for all website files included.</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/img/uploads/trophy_small.jpg" alt="tech.shantanugoel.com completes one month">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, this blog completes one month of its existence in this world. The achievements, although minuscule in comparison to all the biggies out there, are significant for me. It achieved the following things in just 30 days from the first post:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Front-paged at &lt;a href="http://lifehacker.com/358749/retrieve-any-file-on-your-home-computer-via-email-windows-edition">LifeHacker&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://hackszine.com/blog/archive/2008/02/remote_file_access_through_ema.html">HacksZine&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="http://www.google.co.in/search?q=shantanu+goel+remote+file+access+through+e-mail+outlook&amp;amp;ie=utf-8&amp;amp;oe=utf-8&amp;amp;aq=t&amp;amp;rls=com.ubuntu:en-US:official&amp;amp;client=firefox-a">many others&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Over 10000 (Ten Thousand) &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>unique&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo; &lt;strong>&lt;em>human&lt;/em>&lt;/strong> visitors.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Over 30000 (Thirty Thousand) page views by &lt;strong>&lt;em>humans&lt;/em>&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Over 500000 (Half Million) total hits for all website files included.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Around 800 downloads of my projects&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Makes it to the first page on google for many keywords (like wm6.1 htc wizard, ubuntu two soundcards, and many others)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A &lt;a href="http://www.google.co.in/search?q=shantanu+goel">google&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="http://search.yahoo.com/search?p=shantanu+goel">yahoo&lt;/a> search for my name “shantanu goel” now gives around 6–7 links about me (4–5 from this blog) out of the first 10 results. (This changes quite dynamically though)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>But this is all because of you, the readers. Thanks a lot and keep coming. I hope I can continue writing stuff you like, because ultimately a blog is written for the people and not for search engines.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>shantz-csv-to-opml</title><link>/2008/02/22/shantz-csv-to-opml/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2008 04:53:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/02/22/shantz-csv-to-opml/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION
This is a very simple script that I did for a friend. It can be used to quickly generate blogrolls.
Input: csv file with blog author names and blog links
Output: OPML file that can be imported into many blogging/blogrolling software and websites (e.g. wordpress, blogrolling.com, etc)
Usage:
shantz-csv-to-opml.pl &amp;lt;input file in csv format&amp;gt; &amp;lt;output opml filename&amp;gt; Input File Format: Each line should be like this: &amp;lt;Name of Author&amp;gt;,&amp;lt;bloglink&amp;gt;,&amp;lt;bloglink&amp;gt;... e.</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;strong>INTRODUCTION&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a very simple script that I did for a friend. It can be used to quickly generate blogrolls.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Input: csv file with blog author names and blog links&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Output: OPML file that can be imported into many blogging/blogrolling software and websites (e.g. wordpress, blogrolling.com, etc)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Usage:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>shantz-csv-to-opml.pl &amp;lt;input file in csv format&amp;gt; &amp;lt;output opml filename&amp;gt;
Input File Format:
Each line should be like this:
&amp;lt;Name of Author&amp;gt;,&amp;lt;bloglink&amp;gt;,&amp;lt;bloglink&amp;gt;...
e.g.
Shantanu Goel, http://tech.shantanugoel.com, http://blog.shantanugoel.com
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>There can be any number of blogs for any author, if blogs are more than one, then multiple entries for that author will be made in opml file each indexed with increasing number like Shantanu Goel 1, Shantanu Goel 2, etc&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Version History:
0.1 - Initial Version&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Project: "shantz-wp-qotd ", My Wordpress Plugin, Updated to 1.1.0</title><link>/2008/02/17/project-shantz-wp-qotd-my-wordpress-plugin-update-to-110/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2008 15:44:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/02/17/project-shantz-wp-qotd-my-wordpress-plugin-update-to-110/</guid><description>For the uninitiated:
I made a few additions / modifications to the code and the plugin has been updated to 1.1.0. The changes are:
Added Custom tag support for adding quotes anywhere in your posts/pages
Added Custom quote separator support and multi-line quotes support
Config Screenshots:
I recommend that you update to this new version asap, as apart from the above mentioned changes, the code is a bit more cleaner as well, which would run a bit better IMO and also help in any modification if you have in mind.</description><content>&lt;p>For the uninitiated:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>I made a few additions / modifications to the code and the plugin has been updated to 1.1.0. The changes are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Added Custom tag support for adding quotes anywhere in your posts/pages&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Added Custom quote separator support and multi-line quotes support&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Config Screenshots:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/img/uploads/Screenshot1.png">&lt;img src="/img/uploads/Screenshot1_thumb.jpg" alt="Screenshot1">&lt;/a> &lt;a href="/img/uploads/Screenshot2.png">&lt;img src="/img/uploads/Screenshot2_thumb.jpg" alt="Screenshot2">&lt;/a> &lt;a href="/img/uploads/Screenshot3.png">&lt;img src="/img/uploads/Screenshot3_thumb.jpg" alt="Screenshot3">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I recommend that you update to this new version asap, as apart from the above mentioned changes, the code is a bit more cleaner as well, which would run a bit better IMO and also help in any modification if you have in mind.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>My First WordPress Plugin: Please Welcome shantz-wp-qotd</title><link>/2008/02/10/my-first-wordpress-plugin-please-welcome-shantz-wp-qotd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 11:00:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/02/10/my-first-wordpress-plugin-please-welcome-shantz-wp-qotd/</guid><description>Motivated by Ronald’s ultimate wordpress plugin tutorial at devlounge, I decided that the best way to learn something is to use it in a live project. Armed with my laptop and multiple flasks of coffee, the marathon began on Friday night. My only experience with web-related development so far had been around 8–10 years ago as a kid when, just like everybody else at that time, I was fascinated by HTML and did a “read-through” of HTML 4.</description><content>&lt;p>Motivated by Ronald’s ultimate wordpress plugin tutorial at &lt;a href="http://www.devlounge.net/extras/how-to-write-a-wordpress-plugin">devlounge&lt;/a>, I decided that the best way to learn something is to use it in a live project. Armed with my laptop and multiple flasks of coffee, the marathon began on Friday night. My only experience with web-related development so far had been around 8–10 years ago as a kid when, just like everybody else at that time, I was fascinated by HTML and did a “read-through” of HTML 4.0. But I have always been a believer of the theory that a C programmer can program in any language quickly without having to go through the whole manuals. Thus that night bore fruit for me, and by 5:30 in the morning I had a working “Quote of The Day” plugin at my hand with all the features I wanted it to have in its first avatar. Did a bit of polishing last night, fixed a few bugs, and created a readme, and here it is, Mr. shantz-wp-qotd “1.0”, in all its glory, ready for general consumption.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Features at a glance:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Add quotes to all your posts automatically.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Widget support - Can also have a widget in the sidebar for quotes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Customize and style your quotes with your own text and tags.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Multiple sources for quotes (paste in admin page, get from file implemented, fetch from web/rss soon to come)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Multiple patterns for quotes - Random Quote, Quote of the day (all posts display quote of the day), Quote of that day (all posts display quote for their own days)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Pattern for widget can be different&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Customization for widget can be different&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Add quotes to top or bottom of posts&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Enable/Disable the quotes without deactivating the plugin&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Coming Soon:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fetch from web/RSS support&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Custom template tag to add quote anywhere you want&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Custom quote boundary decalarator tags/Multiline quote support (Right now, each quote has to be on a new line)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Quotes Categories&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Pics support for quotes&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Anything else you want&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>File selection&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>And more…&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Site Updates: More Content For You</title><link>/2008/02/03/site-updates-more-content-for-you/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 19:36:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/02/03/site-updates-more-content-for-you/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve added a few new sections to the blog. Do check them out. Here is a list of the new sections along with their descriptions.
[Projects]: Although I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t put myself in the category of an excellent developer but I can sure type in a few lines that can compile without an error and also manage to carry out a task or two. So, this page will list some of those little things that I write to weed out a few niggles or scratch a few itches of mine.</description><content>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve added a few new sections to the blog. Do check them out. Here is a list of the new sections along with their descriptions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[Projects]: Although I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t put myself in the category of an excellent developer but I can sure type in a few lines that can compile without an error and also manage to carry out a task or two. So, this page will list some of those little things that I write to weed out a few niggles or scratch a few itches of mine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[Downloads]: This page will contain the various downloads that this blog offers for a convenient access.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[Submit News/Articles]: Like this blog? Have something to contribute? News/Views/Articles/Links that you would like us to share with the rest of the world, can be submitted using the form on this page. Due credit shall be given to you. Also, check the box at the end of the form, if you would like to be a part of the blog as a regular contributor.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>BlogJet - Blog Faster, Blog Better (Now In Linux too, with a hidden bonus)</title><link>/2008/01/29/blogjet-blog-faster-blog-better-now-in-linux-too-with-a-hidden-bonus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2008 15:30:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/01/29/blogjet-blog-faster-blog-better-now-in-linux-too-with-a-hidden-bonus/</guid><description>A quick googling for best desktop blogging client would yield just a few (read millions/gazillions) results. Having researched the subject a lot, my choices were finally limited down to BlogJet and BlogDesk, as per my feature set requirement goes (Primarily, off line editing, draft, WYSIWYG editing, categories, tagging support, pinging, trackbacks support, timestamping, past post editing, automatic image uploading) BUT there is one little problem. Both of these don’t work on Linux.</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;a href="/img/uploads/blogjet_in_linux.png">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/img/uploads/blogjet_in_linux.png">&lt;img src="/img/uploads/blogjet_in_linux_thumb1.jpg" alt="Blogjet_in_linux">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A quick googling for &lt;em>&lt;a href="http://www.google.co.in/search?q=best+desktop+blogging+client&amp;amp;ie=utf-8&amp;amp;oe=utf-8&amp;amp;aq=t&amp;amp;rls=com.ubuntu:en-US:official&amp;amp;client=firefox-a">best desktop blogging client&lt;/a>&lt;/em> would yield just a few (read millions/gazillions) results. Having researched the subject a lot, my choices were finally limited down to &lt;a href="http://www.codingrobots.com/blogjet/">BlogJet&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.blogdesk.org/en/index.htm">BlogDesk&lt;/a>, as per my feature set requirement goes (Primarily, off line editing, draft, WYSIWYG editing, categories, tagging support, pinging, trackbacks support, timestamping, past post editing, automatic image uploading) BUT there is one little problem. Both of these don’t work on Linux.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>In fact, the current crop of Linux based blog clients is at best childish, compared to these. A piece of software called &lt;a href="http://www.larryborsato.com/bleezer/">Bleezer&lt;/a> did offer a good set of features and supported linux as well, but turned out it was so crash-y, hogged up enormous amounts of ram, and had other issues that come usually packed with all java apps. But I wasn’t gonna boot into WinDUHs, just for one sole software, was I?? Sure, I wasn’t &lt;img src="/img/uploads/smile1.gif" alt="">. I tried the usual routine of trying to run them through wine but it wasn’t supported. I resorted to my faithful ol’ google, and chanced across &lt;a href="http://www.thetechandcents.com/2007/11/running-zoundry-blog-editor-under-wine.html">this little nugget&lt;/a>, with step by step instructions to achieve my goal. And it had a bonus. It told me about &lt;a href="http://www.tatanka.com.br/ies4linux/page/Main_Page">IEs4Linux&lt;/a> (IE’s For Linux). yes, you read correctly. You can run Internet Explorer on your Linux box as well. All this in under 10 minutes (Ubuntu wins again). And yeah, don’t forget to say thanks to me (and &lt;a href="http://www.thetechandcents.com/2007/11/running-zoundry-blog-editor-under-wine.html">Alex&lt;/a> as well).&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>