<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Asus WL-500gP on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/asus-wl-500gp/</link><description>Recent content in Asus WL-500gP on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 13:30:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/asus-wl-500gp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Shutdown Script For Asus WL-500W With Oleg Firmware</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/09/shutdown-script-asus-wl-500w-oleg-firmware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 13:30:04 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/09/shutdown-script-asus-wl-500w-oleg-firmware/</guid><description>If you have an Asus WL-500W, the DIYers&amp;rsquo; favourite wireless router, and have installed the Oleg custom firmware on it, then you would have set up a shutdown script for it, that allows your router to shut down gracefully. This is especially important if you have a USB hard disk attached to it. There are many such scripts available in Oleg's firmware that you can tweak. All of these reside in &amp;ldquo;/usr/local/sbin/&amp;quot;.</description></item><item><title>[TIP] Install Twonky on Asus WL-500W with stock firmware</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/23/tip-install-twonky-on-asus-wl-500w-with-stock-firmware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2009 06:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/23/tip-install-twonky-on-asus-wl-500w-with-stock-firmware/</guid><description>Asus WL-500W is a greate wi-fi router with lots of features, one of them being able to use it as a media server to serve movies/songs over your network from a hard disk connected directly to it through USB. But the media server that is included in the official firmware leaves a lot to be desired. If you are a fan of twonky, all you would have heard so far would have been that to use it on your router, you'd have to change your firmware over to a non-official one.</description></item><item><title>[TIP] Asus WL-500W Hacks:How To Reset Web Admin Password</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/23/tip-asus-wl-500w-hackshow-to-reset-web-admin-password/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2009 22:41:31 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/23/tip-asus-wl-500w-hackshow-to-reset-web-admin-password/</guid><description>Most of you must be knowing by now that I bought the amazing Asus WL-500W router a few days back. This router builds on the great lineage it has in its predecessors, the WL-500g, WL-500g Deluxe, WL-500gP, WL-500gP v2 etc, and shines ahead with being much more than a router, rather a complete headless linux PC. Anyways, to the point. In most routers/modems, if you forget the password to your web-administration gui (which generally resides as 192.</description></item></channel></rss>