<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Google Music Beta on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/google-music-beta/</link><description>Recent content in Google Music Beta on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 03:57:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/google-music-beta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Google Music Beta Latest APK version 3.0.1 for Android</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/05/27/google-music-latest-apk-android-3-0-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 03:57:10 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/05/27/google-music-latest-apk-android-3-0-1/</guid><description>Google just released the latest version of its Music app that ties into its cloud player service Music Beta. This brings the version upto 3.0.1 and adds a lot of fixes, crashes a lot less and now even works on Samsung Galaxy S with Gingerbread which was broken earlier. If you are outside the US and not able to download the app from the market, then download it from here:http://www.multiupload.com/KIM5LQDL0K</description><content>&lt;p>Google just released the latest version of its Music app  that ties into its cloud player service Music Beta. This brings the version upto 3.0.1 and adds a lot of fixes, crashes a lot less and now even works on Samsung Galaxy S with Gingerbread which was broken earlier. If you are outside the US and not able to download the app from the market, then download it from here:&lt;a href="http://www.multiupload.com/KIM5LQDL0K">http://www.multiupload.com/KIM5LQDL0K&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I just tried it on my Nexus One with Stock Gingerbread (2.3.4) and it works awesome. Picked up my music from the Google account immediately and even recognizes the third party equalizers like MusicFx&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to say Thanks ;)&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>