<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Shantz Xwinwrap on</title><link>/tags/shantz-xwinwrap/</link><description>Recent content in Shantz Xwinwrap on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2009 18:30:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/shantz-xwinwrap/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Project: Shantz XWinWrap Update to 0.3</title><link>/posts/project-shantz-xwinwrap-update-to-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2009 18:30:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/project-shantz-xwinwrap-update-to-03/</guid><description>Here is another update for the fans of XWinWrap, the tiny program that allows you to run animated wallpapers on your system. You could use screensavers, movies and what not as your desktop background. This update fixes a segfault that many users were facing, a new debug option to print some debug mesages to get some info if it is not working for you and a new hack option for giving a &amp;ldquo;desktop window&amp;rdquo; name to the program.</description></item><item><title>Project: Shantz-XwinWrap Updated to 0.02</title><link>/posts/project-shantz-xwinwrap-updated-to-002/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2008 11:03:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/project-shantz-xwinwrap-updated-to-002/</guid><description>As some of you know that I&amp;rsquo;ve taken up the development of the ultra-cool xwinwrap tool that allows you to use movies, screensavers etc as wallpapers for you linux desktops. Here is version 0.02 for you consumption that fixes a bug because of which the generated window was overlapping other windows.
The download file has plain executable binaries as well as deb packages for Ubuntu. Moreover, I&amp;rsquo;ve included both 32 bit as well as 64 bit versions.</description></item><item><title>Apology For Bad Downloads</title><link>/posts/apology-for-bad-downloads/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 16:13:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/apology-for-bad-downloads/</guid><description>Guys, for the past few days if you downloaded any &amp;ldquo;.tar.gz&amp;rdquo; packages from this site (like my splert or shantz-xwinwrap tools), then you&amp;rsquo;d have got a corrupt package. Turns out there was some issue with mime-types with my setup. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to resolve it still but have re-upped the packages in &amp;ldquo;zip&amp;rdquo; format. Please download them again. I apologize for the inconvenience.</description></item><item><title>Shantz XWinWrap: The "Moving" Wallpaper Fun Continues</title><link>/posts/shantz-xwinwrap-the-moving-wallpaper-fun-continues/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 14:46:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/shantz-xwinwrap-the-moving-wallpaper-fun-continues/</guid><description>XWinWrap is a small utility written a loooong time ago that allowed you to stick most of the apps to your desktop background (Thanks to fsckin for introducing me to it). What this meant was you could use an animated screensaver (like glmatrix, electric sheep, etc) or even a movie, and use it as your wallpaper. But only one version of this app was released, and it had a few problems, like it wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly &amp;ldquo;sticking&amp;rdquo; to the background and geometry option didn&amp;rsquo;t work as well.</description></item><item><title>Shantz XWinWrap</title><link>/posts/shantz-xwinwrap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 14:41:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/shantz-xwinwrap/</guid><description>XWinWrap is a small utility written a loooong time ago that allowed you to stick most of the apps to your desktop background. What this meant was you could use an animated screensaver (like glmatrix, electric sheep, etc) or even a movie, and use it as your wallpaper. But only one version of this app was ever released, and it had a few problems, like:
Well, sticking didn&amp;rsquo;t work. So if you did a &amp;ldquo;minimize all&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;go to desktop&amp;rdquo; kind of thing, your &amp;ldquo;wallpaper&amp;rdquo; got minimized as well.</description></item></channel></rss>