<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ganssel on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/ganssel/</link><description>Recent content in Ganssel on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2008 17:06:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/ganssel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Engineer: A New Definition</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/14/engineer-a-new-definition/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2008 17:06:12 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/14/engineer-a-new-definition/</guid><description>Came across this funny, but still thought provoking, definition of an engineer.
(Taken from “The Embedded Muse”, a useful embedded stuff related newsletter published by Jack Ganssel.)
“An engineer is a person who passes as an exacting expert on the basis of being able to turn out with prolific fortitude infinite strings of incomprehensible formulas calculated with micrometric precision from vague assumptions which are based on debatable figures taken from inconclusive experiments carried out with instruments of problematical accuracy by persons of questionable mentality and doubtful reliability for the avowed purpose of annoying and confusing a hopelessly chimerical group of esoteric fanatics referred to altogether too frequently as technicians.</description><content>&lt;p>Came across this funny, but still thought provoking, definition of an engineer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Taken from “The Embedded Muse”, a useful embedded stuff related newsletter published by &lt;a href="http://www.ganssle.com/">Jack Ganssel&lt;/a>.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“An engineer is a person who passes as an exacting expert on the basis
of being able to turn out with prolific fortitude infinite strings of
incomprehensible formulas calculated with micrometric precision from
vague assumptions which are based on debatable figures taken from
inconclusive experiments carried out with instruments of problematical
accuracy by persons of questionable mentality and doubtful reliability
for the avowed purpose of annoying and confusing a hopelessly
chimerical group of esoteric fanatics referred to altogether too
frequently as technicians.”&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>