<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Android Marketplace on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/android-marketplace/</link><description>Recent content in Android Marketplace on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 17:19:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/android-marketplace/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Carrier Billing Behind Android Paid Apps Market Jump?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/01/carrier-billing-behind-android-paid-apps-market-jump/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 17:19:51 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/01/carrier-billing-behind-android-paid-apps-market-jump/</guid><description>We heard the news today that paid apps in Android market place have been extended to 18 new countries. Could &amp;ldquo;Carrier Billing&amp;rdquo; (Allowing your service operator to add the apps&amp;rsquo; price to your cellphone bill) be the reason behind it? I think so. It was long suggested that Google Checkout and corresponding legal issues in using it across various countries was the reason behind the paid apps not being available in those countries.</description><content>&lt;p>We heard the &lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/01/android-paid-apps-india.html">news&lt;/a> today that paid apps in Android market place have been extended to 18 new countries. Could &amp;ldquo;Carrier Billing&amp;rdquo; (Allowing your service operator to add the apps&amp;rsquo; price to your cellphone bill) be the reason behind it? I think so. It was long suggested that Google Checkout and corresponding legal issues in using it across various countries was the reason behind the paid apps not being available in those countries. The, all of us developers got an email from Google on 24th of July about an updated Developers&amp;rsquo; Distribution Agreement, which basically said in clause 13.1 that &amp;ldquo;authorized carriers&amp;rdquo; had been added as an indemnified party in the apps sales.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What&amp;rsquo;s more is that the agreement had a 30 day period to be accepted (August end), and then just one month after that we got the news of so many new countries being added. Sounds mighty coincidental to me. I think it would have been much easier for google to work through the carriers to allow paid apps than burning through all that red tape for its own google checkout.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is good news, if true because carrier billing is much more convenient I think. Plus it can be used even if you do not own a credit card. Let&amp;rsquo;s hope for the best :)&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Android Paid Apps Available In India</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/01/android-paid-apps-india/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 03:40:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/01/android-paid-apps-india/</guid><description>Just got a mail from Google that paid apps are being made available in India. HOORAY!!! In addition, developers from 20 more countries can sell apps on market (Unfortunately, no India in this list) and people from 18 more countries can buy paid apps.
This is a big thing because now 32 countries out of 44 where Android has footprint can buy paid apps. This should take away one of the biggest drawbacks that Android marketplace was facing.</description><content>&lt;p>Just got a mail from Google that paid apps are being made available in India. HOORAY!!! In addition, developers from 20 more countries can sell apps on market (Unfortunately, no India in this list) and people from 18 more countries can buy paid apps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a big thing because now 32 countries out of 44 where Android has footprint can buy paid apps. This should take away one of the biggest drawbacks that Android marketplace was facing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This the list that I received:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Effective today, developers from 20 additional countries (Argentina, Australia, Belgium, Brazil, Canada, Denmark, Finland, Hong Kong, Ireland, Israel, Mexico, New Zealand, Norway, Portugal, Russia, Singapore, South Korea, Sweden, Switzerland and Taiwan) can now sell paid apps on Android Market. Over the next 2 weeks, users from 18 new countries (Argentina, Brazil, Belgium, Czech Republic, Denmark, Finland, Hong Kong, India, Ireland, Israel, Mexico, Norway, Poland, Portugal, Russia, Singapore, Sweden, and Taiwan) will be able to purchase paid apps from Android Market.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Now, let&amp;rsquo;s hope that Google allows Indian developers to sell their apps soon as well. :)&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Solving The Android Permissions And Malware Puzzle</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/13/android-permissions-malware/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2010 19:44:59 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/13/android-permissions-malware/</guid><description>There has been a spate of security reports recently about Android apps being malware or suspicious. Most of these were found baseless but at least one was indeed correct (e.g. The Russian Trojan app). We also know that Android has a very good security model but even then, the rest of the reports also makes one think and focus on why an apps requires the permissions that it states it needs?</description><content>&lt;p>There has been a spate of security reports recently about Android apps being malware or suspicious. Most of these were found baseless but at least one was indeed correct (e.g. The Russian Trojan app). We also know that Android has a very good &lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/26/android-vs-iphone-security-models.html">security model&lt;/a> but even then, the rest of the reports also makes one think and focus on why an apps requires the permissions that it states it needs?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We all MUST check the permissions that an app requires before installing it and then contemplate what particular feature of the app would require any mentioned permission. The problem here is two part. First is that the permissions can be cryptic. Now, I can understand most of these as I also develop Android apps but I&amp;rsquo;d fathom that a huge majority wouldn&amp;rsquo;t. A simple solution to this would be for Google to provide more details (and probably examples) for each permission. One can say that it is difficult and a UI nightmare to include too much of text into the limited space that the mobile screen gets. My suggestion here would be to keep the existing layout as it is, but when someone clicks on a requested permission, he be taken to a new page which describes the permission in detailed but simple words and also provides examples.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But this is just the first part of the current problem. The more important issue most apps are facing these days is &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>permission creep in&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo;, i.e., they request for permissions they don&amp;rsquo;t really require. This could be because either they are just adding it to their manifest file mistakenly without using them or are taking a long route for solving a problem that should ideally have been solved in a much easier way without requiring excessive permissions. This permission creep in makes even legit apps look bad. e.g. There was this recent case of a &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2010/07/29/android-wallpaper-hack/">wallpaper app&lt;/a> which was crucified by mainstream media all over the world because of the permissions it was using and then it turned out to be just that the developer&amp;rsquo;s method to solve a particular problem (providing &amp;ldquo;favorites&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;recommended&amp;rdquo; features to users) was long-winded.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->This is quite common today in Android marketplace. e.g. I tried to install the hugely famous &amp;ldquo;Chomp SMS&amp;rdquo; app today and noticed that it requires my &amp;ldquo;location&amp;rdquo; as well. Pretty weird that an SMS app needs my location and when combined with the &amp;ldquo;Internet&amp;rdquo; permission that it requires as well, it made me go &amp;ldquo;hmmm&amp;rdquo; even though it is tried and tested by a huge number of people without issues. Then I realized that it might need the internet permission for ads (since I was downloading the free version) but still a bit doubtful about location, probably that is needed for ads targeting (especially because it wanted my coarse location only, i.e., cell-triangulation location by which it can easily identify my general region or country, which is all what is needed) but I&amp;rsquo;m still not sure. Even the Android Guru &lt;a href="http://commonsware.com/blog/2010/08/12/evernote-why-you-need-think-about-permissions.html">Mark Murphy has similar reservations&lt;/a> about another popular app Evernote.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The solution? I think Google should make it mandatory for app publishers to explain in the market that why their app needs each of the permissions it requests. This should be concisely explained to the user before installation and then the user-review feature of Android marketplace can take over to determine whether the explanation given is indeed satisfactory enough or not. This would, e.g., make it immediately clear to any potential Chomp SMS users why it needs the location. I&amp;rsquo;m sure this would lead to even more sales for the good and trusted apps as people like me who were skeptical of something can put their doubts to rest. At the same time, it would quickly push the russian trojan like apps down into the oblivion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A side effect/benefit of this approach will also be that the app authors would look at the permissions that they use more cautiously and would probably try to weed out the unnecessary ones.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another idea that I have in mind is more community based. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if Google will implement the above idea or even if they do, would they make it mandatory since market already has almost a 100,000 apps without this info. BUT, if someone can take up the mantle of making a community site that documents, with the help of android users, the potential uses of all apps&amp;rsquo; permissions and also raise flags on any app having a permission without any apparent need, this would become a boon to the Android users. AppBrain, are you listening? I think this would be a good addition to your already excellent service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What are your ideas about solving the apps and permissions problems and removing the malware scare that looms upon us? Let me know in the comments..&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Android Dev Tip: App Not Showing on X10 Mini Marketplace</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/07/android-dev-tip-app-not-showing-on-x10-mini-marketplace/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2010 21:18:06 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/07/android-dev-tip-app-not-showing-on-x10-mini-marketplace/</guid><description>Many Android Developers (and users) get confused that why a certain app isn&amp;rsquo;t showing up on the new Xperia X10 Mini (and few other) phones. This happens even if they support all android versions and have published their apps for all countries, so that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the issue. I came across this as well when few people mentioned that they couldn&amp;rsquo;t find my app Wi-Fi Keep Alive in the X10 mini marketplace.</description><content>&lt;p>Many Android Developers (and users) get confused that why a certain app isn&amp;rsquo;t showing up on the new Xperia X10 Mini (and few other) phones. This happens even if they support all android versions and have published their apps for all countries, so that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the issue. I came across this as well when few people mentioned that they couldn&amp;rsquo;t find my app Wi-Fi Keep Alive in the X10 mini marketplace. On some digging into the android docs and the X10 mini specs, I found the issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The problem is that the X10 mini has a very small screen with only a QVGA resolution. This screen size/resolution wasn&amp;rsquo;t supported by Android until recently and the Android system might not be able to scale resources and layouts designed for other screen sizes well enough to suit the X10 mini. Hence, the Android system designers have chosen that any app which does not declare explicit support for small screens (i.e., the app dev has tested his app on small screens and made any changes, if needed, and then declared that everything works fine in the Android Manifest) then it is considered not compatible by default and hence, the Android marketplace will filter your app out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, this is a big loss. A lot of X10 minis were sold and there are lot of new low-tier and cheap Android smartphones coming out with this resolution, so it is a significant market share that you can&amp;rsquo;t afford to lose. The solution is simple. If the app does indeed work fine on small screens (or you have fixed it to work), then all you got to do is add the below mentioned line in your AndroidManifest.xml:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>&amp;lt;supports-screens android:smallScreens=&amp;quot;true&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s it. Your app should now show up fine in all screen sizes markets. Note that for all other screen sizes and resolutions, Android considers the default support as true and your app will show in those markets even if you don&amp;rsquo;t make any explicit declarations for them. You can read more about this here: &lt;a href="http://developer.android.com/guide/practices/screens_support.html">Supporting Multiple Screens in Android&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Update: **&lt;a href="http://www.blundell-apps.com/">Blundell&lt;/a> pointed out in the comments that &lt;a href="http://developer.android.com/guide/practices/screens_support.html%23defaults">Android documentation&lt;/a> says&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>This should mean that small screens should be set as supported by default if you have your minSdk &lt;strong>or&lt;/strong> targetSdk  set to anything above or equal to 4. However, in my case, my apps had minSdk as 3 but targetSdk as 7 or 8 but still they didn&amp;rsquo;t show up in X10 mini marketplace till I added the smallScreens support to true in my manifest file. If anyone has any ideas about as to why it was like this, please let me know.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>