<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Zdnet on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/zdnet/</link><description>Recent content in Zdnet on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2010 15:45:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/zdnet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ZDNet Fail. Answer is Stop Tech Blogging</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/11/19/zdnet-fail-answer-is-stop-tech-blogging/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2010 15:45:04 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/11/19/zdnet-fail-answer-is-stop-tech-blogging/</guid><description>Just read this article over at zdnet. What it basically says is condensed in these two points:
Android is a failure for Google because it is open and carriers/OEMs are stripping off google search from it and putting replacements like baidu/Bing. (BTW, half the people say Android is fail because it is not open and the other half say it is fail because it is open. Which one is it, please decide ;) )</description><content>&lt;p>Just read this &lt;a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/android-fail-the-answer-is-a-google-phone/7822">article&lt;/a> over at zdnet. What it basically says is condensed in these two points:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Android is a failure for Google because it is open and carriers/OEMs are stripping off google search from it and putting replacements like baidu/Bing. (BTW, half the people say Android is fail because it is not open and the other half say it is fail because it is open. Which one is it, please decide ;) )&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The solution is a Google Phone with google branding, sold unlocked at full price.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Let me answer 2nd point first. Dana Blankenhorn, thanks for that nice blast from the past advice. Google already did it with Nexus One, like, one year ago duh..&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, on to the first point. Even if lot of people are stripping off Google search, they still have a big share of the mobile search market. They didn&amp;rsquo;t create Android solely to earn from it directly. It was more of a way to ensure that they still have an avenue for mobile revenue which would have otherwise been completely lost (iPhone). Another thing here is that if they didn&amp;rsquo;t keep it open enough for other players, it might have not got such widespread adoption or they might have been killed in US/EU under antitrust laws.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, all I can say to Dana and ZDNet is &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-&amp;gt; kthxbi :P&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>