<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>IM on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/im/</link><description>Recent content in IM on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 15:30:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/im/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hack: Pidgin-Gtalk Connection Problems - Get Around The Corporate Firewall</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/08/hack-pidgin-gtalk-connection-problems-get-around-the-corporate-firewall/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 15:30:38 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/08/hack-pidgin-gtalk-connection-problems-get-around-the-corporate-firewall/</guid><description>I recently wrote a simple answering machine program/plugin for pidgin and someone asked me to port it to 32 bit. So I fired up pidgin within my virtual box installation at work (as I have only a 64 bit machine at home) but couldn&amp;rsquo;t get it to connect. Tried all sorts of methods found over the net of changing ports etc, set port forwarding in Virtual Box NAT, even switched to using a bridged host interface but still no go.</description><content>&lt;p>I recently wrote a simple answering machine program/plugin for pidgin and someone asked me to port it to 32 bit. So I fired up pidgin within my virtual box installation at work (as I have only a 64 bit machine at home) but couldn&amp;rsquo;t get it to connect. Tried all sorts of methods found over the net of changing ports etc, set port forwarding in Virtual Box NAT, even switched to using a bridged host interface but still no go. On a whim, installed pidgin in the host, i.e., windows and still the same issue. Hmm, interesting.. But wait, gtalk client works, then what gives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, after a bit of snooping around, discovered that it&amp;rsquo;s a special funda that my company employs (and probably yours too) to monitor your IM conversations. The server talk.google.com was redirected to another server set up by my company that masquerades as gtalk server and tries to act as a &amp;ldquo;Man In The Middle&amp;rdquo; to hijack your connection and listen to everything while you live in the fantasy that since its an &amp;ldquo;SSL encrypted&amp;rdquo; connection, everything is secure. However, &amp;ldquo;fortunately&amp;rdquo; pidgin refuses to connect here (More details in the end)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But as they say, rules are meant to be bent and broken. Here, is a simple way 3-step procedure to circumvent around this.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Open up your gtalk account settings in pidgin and go to Advanced tab.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Check &amp;ldquo;Force old port&amp;rdquo;, uncheck &amp;ldquo;plaintext auth&amp;rdquo; and uncheck &amp;ldquo;Require SSL/TLS&amp;rdquo;. Also change &amp;ldquo;Connect port&amp;rdquo; to 443.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>main&lt;/strong> part: Go to an online nslookup service and do an nslookup for talk.google.com. Put the IP that you get in place of &amp;ldquo;talk.google.com&amp;rdquo; in the settings.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s it. Go and chat away. (or if you want to know the reasoning behind this, hit the link below)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>More Details:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Skip this if you want, only for the people who are interested, here are some details on why pidgin does not connect in this situation and how you can find out if your company is using this tactic.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>How pidgin tries to connect to gtalk servers is that first it makes a connection to talk.google.com and gets and verifies the certificate from there. Then it tries to connect to gmail.com. Now there can be various situations:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>1.
1. Its unable to complete the transaction in the first place because you didn't use the port 443, so firewall blocks it hence it can't communand tries to fallback to plaintext authorization which is not supported by google and hence it fails.
2. You chose correct settings to go around firewall but now after verifying certificate, it just keeps &amp;quot;connecting&amp;quot;. Basically, it passes through the talk.google.com phase and then tries to connect to gmail.com (don't know why) and gets stuck on this step because the company is masquerading the gtalk server but not the gmail server.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>Look for the following symptoms to see if your company is doing &amp;ldquo;something&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>1.
1. Do &amp;quot;nslookup talk.google.com&amp;quot; in your command prompt (not through web), then say you get an IP x.y.z.w. Now do &amp;quot;nslookup x.y.z.w&amp;quot; again in command prompt. Now you will get the real name of the server that is your company's. Can try this for other IM servers as well (e.g. yahoo)
2. When pidgin asks you to verify the certificate, don't take it lightly. Just fetch and see the certificate and it'll definitely be pointing to some other domain.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Enough fundas for today. Let me know if this helped you out or if you have your own techniques of finding and circumventing around such stuff.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Project: Splert - A Custom Answering Machine And More for IMs</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/18/project-splert-a-custom-answering-machine-and-more-for-ims/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 17:00:09 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/18/project-splert-a-custom-answering-machine-and-more-for-ims/</guid><description>Update Aug 25 2008: Updated to v0.02 and also added 32 bit package. Hit the link given below to download.
You must have heard of (or used) the auto-reply features given by today&amp;rsquo;s instant messengers that are sent to the ones messaging you while you are not at your desk. But those are one-size-fits-all kind of messages. So, I wrote this simple tool a few months ago to turn Pidgin, everyone’s favourite multi-client Instant Messenger (works with gtalk, msn, yahoo, aim etc), into a customized answering machine (and more) when you are away from your computer.</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update Aug 25 2008&lt;/strong>: Updated to v0.02 and also added 32 bit package. Hit the link given below to download.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You must have heard of (or used) the auto-reply features given by today&amp;rsquo;s instant messengers that are sent to the ones messaging you while you are not at your desk. But those are one-size-fits-all kind of messages. So, I wrote this simple tool a few months ago to turn Pidgin, everyone’s favourite multi-client Instant Messenger (works with gtalk, msn, yahoo, aim etc), into a &lt;strong>customized answering machine (and more)&lt;/strong> when you are away from your computer. Basically it allows you to divide up your contact list into groups based on email IDs and execute actions based on when someone from a particular group messages you while you are away. e.g. For general friends, you can keep a message like “Will talk to you later when I come back”, or if someone from office IMs you, it’ll send them your phone number “Call me at XXXXXX if urgent”. And if you boss is the one pinging you, you could direct the message towards your twitter account so that you get it as an SMS on your phone immediately.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Splert: Shantz Pidgin Away Alerts</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/18/splert-shantz-pidgin-away-alerts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 16:55:03 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/18/splert-shantz-pidgin-away-alerts/</guid><description>This is a simple tool I wrote a few months ago to turn Pidgin, everyone’s favourite multi-client Instant Messenger (works with gtalk, msn, yahoo, aim etc), into a customized answering machine (and more) when you are away from your computer. Basically it allows you to divide up your contact list into groups based on email IDs and execute actions based on when someone from a particular group messages you while you are away.</description><content>&lt;p>This is a simple tool I wrote a few months ago to turn Pidgin, everyone’s favourite multi-client Instant Messenger (works with gtalk, msn, yahoo, aim etc), into a &lt;strong>customized answering machine (and more)&lt;/strong> when you are away from your computer. Basically it allows you to divide up your contact list into groups based on email IDs and execute actions based on when someone from a particular group messages you while you are away. e.g. For general friends, you can keep a message like “Will talk to you later when I come back”, or if someone from office IMs you, it’ll send them your phone number “Call me at XXXXXX if urgent”. And if you boss is the one pinging you, you could direct the message towards your twitter account so that you get it as an SMS on your phone immediately.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Time is short, so here are the details:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Features:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Group based rule execution, each group can contain any number of email IDs&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Custom replies for each group.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Integrates with twitter and will forward the message to your twitter account (or send a direct message to some other account) if you so desire. (Temporarily disabled since Twitter has blocked their IM bot)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Runs as a separate process over d-bus instead of running as a pidgin plugin, so much lesser chances of crashing.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Prerequisites:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Pidgin &amp;gt; 2.4.1&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Linux&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Download:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Usage:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Unzip the attached package anywhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Either install using the deb package or just copy the splert binary and config.txt to a folder of your choice&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Modify the “config.txt” file according to your needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Run splert. (or run splert -h for checking out the available options though you wouldn’t need them most of the times)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Config File:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Config file fields and formats are explained fully in the sample config file included in the attached file. However, here is a very basic sample configuration:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>[Friends]
user = &lt;a href="mailto:foo@foo.com">foo@foo.com&lt;/a>
message = &amp;ldquo;Not Here. Will talk to you later&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[VIP]
user = &lt;a href="mailto:boss@boss.com">boss@boss.com&lt;/a>
message = &amp;ldquo;Got your message. Will Contact you asap&amp;rdquo;
twitter = 1
twitterto = my2ndtwitteracct&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>ChangeLog:&lt;/strong>
0.03 - Oct04 2008 -&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Added option to specify twitter bot id (e.g. &lt;a href="mailto:twitterspy@jabber.org">twitterspy@jabber.org&lt;/a>) using option &amp;ldquo;-t/-twitterbot&amp;rdquo;. However, you need to do any &amp;ldquo;extra&amp;rdquo; stuff manually. e.g. logging in using twlogin command with twitterspy.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added option to specify the status when you want to send messages instead of just when being away. Use &amp;ldquo;-s/&amp;ndash;status&amp;rdquo; option to do this.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>0.02 - Aug25 2008 -&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Fixed bug where response was not sent for 1st message received&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added 32 bit package&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>0.01 - Aug15 2008 - Initial Version&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please let me know if you like it or found some issues with it. Also, let me know if you would like me to add any features to it.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Fill Your Password To Invite Your Buddies - Not So Fast!!</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/16/fill-your-password-to-invite-your-buddies-not-so-fast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2008 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/16/fill-your-password-to-invite-your-buddies-not-so-fast/</guid><description>For the past many years, I’ve seen a trend that has been on a meteoric rise. Whatever new service you sign on for on the internet (especially the web2.0–oh-so-cool-you-have-to-tell-everyone-about-it ones), it gives you an option to fill in your e-mail ID and password and makes a generous offer of letting all your friends know about your new avatar and let them all join in the fun. Most of the people around me, it seems, don’t think twice before gladly accepting the offer, as is made apparent from the increasing amount of automated mails I’m getting with subjects like “Hey, don’t be left out!</description><content>&lt;p>For the past many years, I’ve seen a trend that has been on a meteoric rise. Whatever new service you sign on for on the internet (especially the web2.0–oh-so-cool-you-have-to-tell-everyone-about-it ones), it gives you an option to fill in your e-mail ID and password and makes a generous offer of letting all your friends know about your new avatar and let them all join in the fun. Most of the people around me, it seems, don’t think twice before gladly accepting the offer, as is made apparent from the increasing amount of automated mails I’m getting with subjects like “Hey, don’t be left out! Join me on X” or “Hi SG, Why don’t you follow me on Y”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I just wanted to “remind” you all (because you already know it) how important your password is. You keep it safe from everyone, suspect even your friends of trying to hack into your e-mail, and then you give it away to an “unknown” entity with so much of ease, laying so much trust onto it that you won’t even put in your biological parents.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While many of these services are genuine, but many might not be. I’m certainly against handing out your passwords to a third-party web service until it is something like google that won’t just sell you off one fine day and run off somewhere you can’t find it. But if you are compelled to do so because of some reason, I’d recommend atleast checking out what it has to say about the data it’s collecting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me take an example of a new IM service that I recently came across. It’s called IMO (or imo or whatever) and is apparently quite popular because of its multiple IM service connections through a single interface. I thought of checking out its terms etc and making a mental image of how respectable / trustworthy I found it. I had listed the following things on the blog where I had found about this site. Listing them here again for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following are the nuggets I found:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1.&lt;/strong> They have a blogspot blog. It takes hardly a few minutes to host ur own blog on ur own domain. Maybe they have some existing google connection but yet to discover it.(I read somewhere that some of these people worked at google in the past but that’s no reason to keep your blog on such a platform)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2.&lt;/strong> Shady privacy agreement.
** 2a** They mention that not only will they save ur username and pwd but may also save ur chats/messages etc.
** 2b** They might also share info with 3rd parties (written in a manner that they can do it on their own will)
** 2c** Transparency: They might not even tell u whats going on if they so decide.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please don’t mention about the eliteness of their “advisor panel”. This is the biggest marketing gimmick that everyone pulls off. Many times the &amp;ldquo;advisors&amp;rdquo; don&amp;rsquo;t even know the &amp;ldquo;advised&amp;rdquo; company exists.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>IMP:&lt;/strong> If a site doesn’t say anything or says all goody things in its terms, that doesn’t make it clean, but if you find suspiciousness in the terms, that definitely makes a negative mark. &lt;strong>In Short, when your password is concerned, treat everyone guilty until proven innocent.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>