<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 13:35:15 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Letting go of headphones to save sanity and health</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2021/08/23/headphones/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 13:35:15 +0530</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2021/08/23/headphones/</guid><description>I love listening to music (mostly rock and metal), and I&amp;rsquo;m in meetings, A LOT. So, naturally I use headphones a lot, especially due to the video calls situation forced by the pandemic. Now, I&amp;rsquo;ve been having this uneasy feeling for a long time which is sort of like a headache but not really and it&amp;rsquo;s been gnawing at me. I attributed this to lack of sleep, stress, etc early on but then recently realized the main culprit for this is headphones that&amp;rsquo;s constantly keeping my ears busy.</description></item><item><title>Pradyumn's got a website</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2021/01/09/pradyumn-coding-website/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 13:21:55 +0530</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2021/01/09/pradyumn-coding-website/</guid><description>My 10yo (Pradyumn) got interested in coding last year. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t so sure about it in the beginning since I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to force my career choices or interests on to him. But I realized that he wanted to do it of his own accord, so I agreed to help him. But our deal was that I will introduce him a bit to the learning resources and help him out with his doubts here and there, while he will peruse all the learning material and build his things on his own without much interference/interaction with me.</description></item><item><title>A nifty window layout switcher for macOS using Hammerspoon</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2020/08/21/hammerspoon-multiscreen-window-layout-macos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 23:07:59 +0530</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2020/08/21/hammerspoon-multiscreen-window-layout-macos/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a sucker for screen real estate, and thus I use 2 32&amp;quot; 4k monitors so I can see most of my apps' windows simultaneously, instead of switching back and forth between them.
#myworkplace is pretty lean (on cables) and mean (on screen real estate). And a lot of tileception goes on (window tiling, then local tmux tiling, then 1-2 levels of remote tmux tiling) pic.twitter.com/wCqsusBfRb
&amp;mdash; Shantanu Goel (@shantanugoel) August 10, 2020 I use the awesome Rectangle app that provides shortcuts to move/resize an app window to my liking.</description></item><item><title>Bazel rules to auto generate files at compile time</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2020/05/03/bazel-rule-auto-generate-files-compile-time/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 11:02:30 +0530</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2020/05/03/bazel-rule-auto-generate-files-compile-time/</guid><description>Auto generated files in a project are pretty common. There are generally 3 scenarios for this in a project that needs auto-generated files:
An external pre-built tool generates files pre-compilation and then the generated files get checked in to the tree The tool is compiled in-tree but is again used to generate files pre-compilation and then check them into tree The tool is built during the main build step and then it also generates the needed files just in time.</description></item><item><title>Java "Object" in C++ using std::variant</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2020/04/27/java-object-cpp-std-variant/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 19:39:50 +0530</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2020/04/27/java-object-cpp-std-variant/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m going through this brilliant book, Crafting Interpreters, these days to learn more about how interpreters are built. My attempts so far have been ameturish, as I&amp;rsquo;ve never had a formal CS course, and this looked useful to upskill my toolkit. However, the book implements the interpreter in Java (at least the first part, which I am going through now) and I&amp;rsquo;m trying to follow along in C++ instead since I don&amp;rsquo;t have much experience in Java, neither an inclination to learn it.</description></item><item><title>Automatic notes backup on macOS with hammerspoon</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2020/03/20/hammerspoon-backup-joplin-notes-dotfiles-git-macos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 18:25:01 +0530</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2020/03/20/hammerspoon-backup-joplin-notes-dotfiles-git-macos/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a backup nerd and like to back-up everything I do. Not just that, I like to version them too so I can go back in time to any point. git serves as a good tool for me for versioning wherever small data/text files etc are concerned and then I back this up with remote git servers like my own git server on a raspberry pi at home, a gitlab server and a github server.</description></item><item><title>Fixing the Raspberrypi 4 Ethernet disconnection problem</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2020/01/19/raspberry-pi-4b-ethernet-lan-disconnect/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 02:25:17 +0530</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2020/01/19/raspberry-pi-4b-ethernet-lan-disconnect/</guid><description>I added a Raspberry Pi 4B recently in my ever expanding homelab. To get the best network with the new gigabit ethernet port on the raspi, and still save power, I added a PoE hat to it so I could power the raspi as well as provide it data through the ethernet port. Everything worked fine except that I ocassionaly got into situations where the raspi stopped responding suddenly. Initially I thought that it&amp;rsquo;s crashing due to some issues and used to just restart it manually.</description></item><item><title>Migrating my hugo blog from Gitlab/AWS S3 to Github Pages with Actions</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2020/01/05/migrate-hugo-blog-gitlab-s3-github-pages-actions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 16:25:46 +0530</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2020/01/05/migrate-hugo-blog-gitlab-s3-github-pages-actions/</guid><description>Until Now - The State of the union This blog is generated using hugo, an awesome static site generator. So far, the workflow I used to deploy it was:
Push commit to the source repository on GitLab GitLab CI kicks off on receiving the push CI downloads latest version of hugo and generates the static site Runs aws-cli to sync the new files to AWS S3 S3 serves the static site Cloudflare provides: DNS services (so I can use https://shantanugoel.</description></item><item><title>Integrating SDL2 with bazel on macOS</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2019/12/31/sdl2-macos-bazel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 02:01:05 +0530</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2019/12/31/sdl2-macos-bazel/</guid><description>Bazel Came across bazel build system recently at my new job and found it to be quite nice compared to my earlier mainstays CMake and Make. It&amp;rsquo;s fast and correct, just as their website says. But I also liked it because it&amp;rsquo;s explicit with very little magic. And it has a powerful query/tools system that allows you to really analyze your builds and dependencies in depth. Though examples in the wild are a bit less since it is a fairly recent entrant compared to its competitors.</description></item><item><title>Practical Reverse Engineering Tutorials Part 2: Protostar Stack4</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/12/04/practical-reverse-engineering-tutorial-2-protostar-stack4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 21:04:24 +0530</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/12/04/practical-reverse-engineering-tutorial-2-protostar-stack4/</guid><description>About the challenge In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll go through the Protostar stack4 challenge. This would be a bit similar to the stack0 challenge that we already tackled earlier, but it will think about an interesting way to get alternate code to execute instead of just modifying data.
Pre-requisite: Make sure you&amp;rsquo;ve completed the Part 1 of the Practical Reverse Engineering Tutorials series. It&amp;rsquo;d also be great if you can try stack1-stack3 challenges on your own as they are similar to stack0.</description></item><item><title>Practical Reverse Engineering Tutorials Part 1: Introduction &amp; Protostar Stack 0</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/11/16/practical-reverse-engineering-tutorial-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 08:46:24 +0530</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/11/16/practical-reverse-engineering-tutorial-1/</guid><description>What is this about? This article is the 1st part of the Practical Reverse Engineering Tutorials series. This series is geared towards a structured, but almost completely practical, approach to learn Reverse Engineering. Many of the existing articles/books take a long winded approach to teach RE which is prefixed with a lot of theory before the reader can get their hands dirty. This series will take a different approach of picking up various challenges in the order of increasing difficulty and help the reader in exploring ways how to break them.</description></item><item><title>Create a bit.ly like shorturl static website</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/09/17/create-bitly-clone-shorturl-static-website/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 23:46:24 +0530</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/09/17/create-bitly-clone-shorturl-static-website/</guid><description>I decided to create my own shorturl website last week for personal use and ended up developing a python project (deecubes)that can be used by anyone to do the same. This is a post to explain what/why/how about it.
Why my own shorturl website? So far I had been using sites like bit.ly or TinyURL whenever I needed to generate a shorturl (e.g. for giving to someone for easily remember, noting down on paper, putting links on resume, etc) but I had concerns that:</description></item><item><title>email-actions: An SMTP server that triggers actions from email</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/04/03/email-actions-trigger-tasks-from-email-smtp-server/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 19:20:59 +0530</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/04/03/email-actions-trigger-tasks-from-email-smtp-server/</guid><description>Releasing my project email-actions today. You install it from github or from pypi.
email-actions email-actions is a tiny SMTP server with a rules based engine to trigger any actions (notifications/commands etc) based on the emails sent to this server. Think of it like IFTTT but where input trigger is email and can be set up and run locally as well.
Why did you make email-actions Like most of my projects, email-actions is a &amp;lsquo;scratch-your-own-itch&amp;rsquo; project.</description></item><item><title>Bypass ISP DNS hijack by changing DNS port on Ubiquiti USG router</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/03/13/bypass-isp-dns-hijack-ubiquiti-ubnt-usg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 16:46:24 +0530</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/03/13/bypass-isp-dns-hijack-ubiquiti-ubnt-usg/</guid><description>The Background We talked earlier about how certain ISPs block websites by using DNS hijack methods and I had recommended using DNSCrypt to bypass it. Well, as part of my home network overhaul, I moved over from the consumer grade (but still decent enough) Asus router over to Ubiquiti stack which, among other things, lead me to use their &amp;ldquo;Unify Security Gateway (USG)&amp;rdquo; as the router. Now, this router is pretty decent and is running Ubiquiti&amp;rsquo;s EdgeOS (derived from Vyatta OS, which in turn is based on linux/debian).</description></item><item><title>ACT Fibernet blocks sites using deep packet inspection</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/01/24/act-fibernet-deep-packet-inspection-blocking-sites/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 16:04:28 +0530</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2017/01/24/act-fibernet-deep-packet-inspection-blocking-sites/</guid><description>ISPs in India have been blocking websites since many years. It&amp;rsquo;s often done without much sense to it. The goveernment/telecom bodies and courts sometimes tell the ISPs to block content instead of telling the same to the websites that host the content. Sometimes, the orders are to block certain urls and ISPs are over-enthusiastic in implementing the orders and block complete websites. It&amp;rsquo;s all frustrating but it becomes enraging when you find out that the ISPs are messing with your traffic in a less than ethical way to implement this.</description></item><item><title>Indian ISP ACT Fibernet blocks bit.ly. Does DNS Hijacking</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2016/09/17/indian-isp-act-fibernet-blocks-bit-ly-does-dns-hijacking/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 17:14:43 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2016/09/17/indian-isp-act-fibernet-blocks-bit-ly-does-dns-hijacking/</guid><description>TLDR;
Indian ISP ACT Fibernet (aka Beam Telecom) hijacks its users' DNS requests (even when using public DNS servers like Google or OpenDNS) and blocks websites through this method. This has huge implications beyond website blocking and you can&amp;rsquo;t rely on anything that you are browsing anymore though there are ways available to make yourself safe.
Aside: Indian ISPs are blocking benign/collateral damage sites now like bit.</description></item><item><title>Fixing the problem of matplotlib and ggplot not showing graphs in python</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2016/06/29/fixing-the-problem-of-matplotlib-and-ggplot-not-showing-graphs-in-python/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 14:20:55 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2016/06/29/fixing-the-problem-of-matplotlib-and-ggplot-not-showing-graphs-in-python/</guid><description>While trying to make some graphs for one of my side projects recently, I came across an issue that both matplotlib and ggplot did not show up the graphs. I was able to save the graphs to an image file just fine, but if I tried to show them directly on screen while running the script, it just printed a number and exited. After tearing apart my hair for some time, I checked the backend being used by matplot lib:</description></item><item><title>NTP Driver For ESP8266</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2015/03/01/ntp-driver-for-esp8266/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 08:02:22 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2015/03/01/ntp-driver-for-esp8266/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m building a smartwatch project based around the new IoT posterkid on the block, ESP8266. Apart from the usual &amp;ldquo;smart&amp;rdquo; stuff, it does still need to display correct time :) and hence, the need for an ntp driver/client. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find anyone working on that yet, so wrote up a quick and dirty implementation here:
NTP Implementation for ESP8266
ESP8266 Smartwatch NTP Demo It still has a lot of stuff left to be done to make it good enough for the smartwatch project but it works.</description></item><item><title>Weekend Hack: Shoutcast2Dropbox - Automatic Shoutcast Stations To Dropbox Recorder</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2015/02/16/weekend-hack-shoutcast2dropbox-automatic-shoutcast-stations-to-dropbox-recorder/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 03:00:19 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2015/02/16/weekend-hack-shoutcast2dropbox-automatic-shoutcast-stations-to-dropbox-recorder/</guid><description>So I got bored of listening to same old songs on my phone over and over and Rdio announced a streaming plan for India. With a sigh of relief I subscribed immediately and it was stellar at home with its wonderful 32 million song collection and chromecast support to boot. The experience during the commute daily was underwhelming. Couple the spotty airtel data connection with no one station covering all songs I would love and it makes for a frustrating commute with long gaps all over.</description></item><item><title>Browser controlled Raspberry Pi Camera Car</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2014/08/03/browser-controlled-raspberry-pi-camera-car/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2014 15:33:12 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2014/08/03/browser-controlled-raspberry-pi-camera-car/</guid><description>Spent this weekend building a remote controlled car with a live camera feed with a Raspberry Pi doing the communication and brains duty. Pretty nice real time movement control and camera pan/tilt control through websockets with a live stream feeding back to any browser directly from the car through mjpg-streamer
(PS: Video is at the bottom of the post. Browser/video on TV courtesy ChromeCast. Casted my Nexus 5 screen to the TV simultaneously while controlling the car :) )</description></item><item><title>Converting A Toy RC Car Into An Autonomous Fun Car The Indian Way</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2014/07/23/converting-a-toy-rc-car-into-an-autonomous-fun-car-the-indian-way/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 17:05:12 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2014/07/23/converting-a-toy-rc-car-into-an-autonomous-fun-car-the-indian-way/</guid><description>Dangerous is a mind which is left grounded at home for days. Being stuck at home and having a few pieces of joy around made me do this over the weekend.
Ingredients:
An old Toy RC car broken out of shape by my 4 year old
DAGU Mini Driver
Screw Driver/Batteries/Tape/Glue/Rubber bands/Old gift cards
Half an hour of coding
Output:</description></item><item><title>Patterbuzz - Your Content Your Way</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/12/07/patterbuzz-your-content-your-way/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 19:29:57 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/12/07/patterbuzz-your-content-your-way/</guid><description>My brother, Amit Goel, has founded a startup &amp;ldquo;Patterbuzz&amp;rdquo; which is aiming to disrupt the digital publishing marketplace. Read on for details about it in his words. I can assure you that you don&amp;rsquo;t want to miss out on this whether you are a publisher or a consumer :)
Welcome Offer: Download the app and register your account before 15th December and get 100 Credits FREE!! to download the content of your choice.</description></item><item><title>[Xposed Mod] Bypass Exchange Security Policy for Nexus and other AOSP devices</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/10/14/xposed-mod-bypass-exchange-security-policy-for-nexus-4-android-4-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 14:13:10 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/10/14/xposed-mod-bypass-exchange-security-policy-for-nexus-4-android-4-3/</guid><description>Exchange Security Bypass Xposed Mode for Nexus 4/5/7 and other AOSP based devices (Android 4.3 / 4.4)
Update: This has now been tested to work successfully on all stock or nearly stock JellyBean (4.3) and KitKat (4.4) ROMs on Nexus 4 / Nexus 5 / Nexus 7. Other AOSP ROMs like CM11 should work as well.
This mod should be used along with Xposed ( http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=1574401 ). Xposed is this awesome framework developed by rovo89 which allows you to carry out mods to your device without changing any files (well except one &amp;ldquo;app_process&amp;rdquo; as part of the xposed installer).</description></item><item><title>Display Message on Samsung TVs in Python (Samsung MessageBox Service Exploitation)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/07/14/samsung-tv-message-box-python/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 14:07:15 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/07/14/samsung-tv-message-box-python/</guid><description>This script is the result of a weekend&amp;rsquo;s hacking to get my TV to display incoming calls/texts which I miss invariably because the phone is buried under a sofa or in a different room. Earlier I had done this using my Odroid U2 and Tasker/AutoRemote but this was limiting as this meant that I could see the notifications only when I was watching something through the Odroid. Samsung TVs, which are DLNA enabled, also include a hidden service called &amp;ldquo;Message Box&amp;rdquo; which can display different information on the TV natively irrespective of which display mode/input mode you are in.</description></item><item><title>Fixing The Static Noise, Clicks And Pops with Turtlebeach Earforce PX5</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/03/03/fixing-the-static-noise-clicks-and-pops-with-turtlebeach-earforce-px5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 18:27:17 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/03/03/fixing-the-static-noise-clicks-and-pops-with-turtlebeach-earforce-px5/</guid><description>So I got this beautiful piece of headset a few days ago, called the EarForce PX5 by TurtleBeach. It&amp;rsquo;s claim to fame being an awesome virtual surround sound headset which also does the double duty of providing game audio as well as voice chat over the same headset. I preferred this over the Sony PS3 Elite headset as the PX5 is more generic and can work across multiple devices since it uses the regular bluetooth for A2DP and voice chat and the wireless transmitter has standard optical/RCA inputs and outputs.</description></item><item><title>The 80 Column Coding Rule</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/02/25/the-80-column-coding-rule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 18:48:21 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/02/25/the-80-column-coding-rule/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve followed the 80 column rule almost always when I code, i.e., I keep a soft limit of keeping my lines of my code limited to 80 characters max. unless breaking up the line really messes up the readability of the code.
I was asked recently why do I bother now in this age of 24&amp;quot; widescreen monitors (and above) with resolutions of 720p at the bare minimum. I could certainly afford to have more than double that limit staring back at me from the screen without overflowing.</description></item><item><title>Apple, Anti-Malware, Patents</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/02/15/apple-anti-malware-patents/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 16:55:10 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/02/15/apple-anti-malware-patents/</guid><description>Recently, there has been this trend. Blogs look for patents filed by companies and then report on each of them as if they are second coming of Jesus in technology. Especially if it is Apple who is doing the filings.
A few days ago, this new patent showed up about Apple&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;new wave approach to fighting malware&amp;rdquo; with the author giving up half-researched commentary on it.
I was intrigued by this news (if you can call it that), not because it’s something new but instead because process isolation is hardly a new concept.</description></item><item><title>Fixing the DS3/Sixaxis Controller Not Working in PSN Store Issue</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/01/13/fixing-the-ds3sixaxis-controller-not-working-in-psn-store-issue/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2013 19:55:44 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/01/13/fixing-the-ds3sixaxis-controller-not-working-in-psn-store-issue/</guid><description>So, my wife got me a new slim PS3 today to replace my old YLOD&amp;rsquo;ed phat (Yes, Awesome wife I know. And slim PS3 cuz I hate the looks of the new superslim). But, I digress. The issue at hand is that everything worked fine when I unwrapped it, hooked it up to the power and TV and switched it on. However, once I started the PSN store (or what is now called Sony Entertainment Network Store), nothing worked.</description></item><item><title>Odroid U2 Tips: Overscan, emmc Adapter, HDMI-DVI Adapter</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/01/12/odroid-u2-tips-overscan-emmc-adapter-hdmi-dvi-adapter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2013 17:56:52 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/01/12/odroid-u2-tips-overscan-emmc-adapter-hdmi-dvi-adapter/</guid><description>So I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending a few hours on getting my odroid u2 up and running and here are a few tips that I&amp;rsquo;ve come across in the process.
**Overscan: **
So, many TVs have this issue that they miss out on displaying the corners of the image put out by the Odroid U2. The phenomenon is called overscan. Now, all you have to do is select settings such as &amp;ldquo;Just Scan&amp;rdquo; or similar on your TV that allows your TV to display image coming from U2 as is.</description></item><item><title>Odroid U2 is here</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/01/12/odroid-u2-is-here/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2013 17:46:57 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2013/01/12/odroid-u2-is-here/</guid><description>So, this little baby landed up in my mailbox a couple of days ago :). The Odroid U2. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, it&amp;rsquo;s a cheap dev board based around Samsung&amp;rsquo;s Exynos 4412 SoC and supports Android as well as Ubuntu.
Odroid U2 I&amp;rsquo;ve got quite a few things planned on how to use it and will post more about my adventures with the U2 here soon.</description></item><item><title>Third Party Widgets on Android 4.2 Lock Screen</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2012/11/14/third-party-widgets-on-android-4-2-lock-screen/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2012 14:46:36 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2012/11/14/third-party-widgets-on-android-4-2-lock-screen/</guid><description>One of the features I was really looking forward to with Android 4.2 was lock screen widgets but when I got the update on my Galaxy Nexus that it only had 5 pre-defined stock widgets that could be added to the lock screen.
I headed over to the Android developers site some time later and was pleasantly surprised to see that actually 3rd party widgets can indeed be added to the lock screen.</description></item><item><title>My Tasker Night Mode Profile For Android</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2012/10/17/my-tasker-night-mode-profile-for-android/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 09:03:08 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2012/10/17/my-tasker-night-mode-profile-for-android/</guid><description>If there are two things that irritate me the most when I go to sleep, they are: Sync notifications going off and battery drained off in the morning (worst case being drained off before alarm time, making me late for work). I used to have a simple profile that turned off auto sync between 11 PM to 7 AM but it didn&amp;rsquo;t always work well because I work past 11 quite a lot and don&amp;rsquo;t usually have a fixed sleep time.</description></item><item><title>BogusApple.com: Apple Screw Up Saved By Githubber</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2012/10/01/bogusapple-com-apple-screw-up-saved-by-githubber/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 22:16:18 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2012/10/01/bogusapple-com-apple-screw-up-saved-by-githubber/</guid><description>So, I just came across a thread on apple discussion forums and it seems like that Apple has added a new feature in OS X Mountain Lion due to which it redirects a lot of web traffic to a domain called &amp;ldquo;bogusapple.com&amp;rdquo; to make sure that it is failing. Now, the problem is that Apple didn&amp;rsquo;t even register this domain. By design? To make sure that it fails? But if so, it was a very poor design decision because then anyone could have registered it and used it for benefit, like spreading malware or phishing attempts and what not.</description></item><item><title>My Android NFC Car BT Audio Setup</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2012/09/30/my-android-nfc-car-bt-audio-setup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 18:16:22 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2012/09/30/my-android-nfc-car-bt-audio-setup/</guid><description>So, my Nexus One&amp;rsquo;s battery finally lost its last legs and I picked up a new Galaxy Nexus to replace it (easy choice, since it&amp;rsquo;s a nexus device and Google sells it for a bargain at their play store). Anyways, I drift. In the mood to try out the NFC capbilities of my newly acquired gadget I thought of doing something about my car audio setup (previously consisting of a stereo line connecting the aux port of the stereo to the headphone out of Nexus one using tasker to start music when connected).</description></item><item><title>Bugs: What you see is not always what it is</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2012/07/23/bugs-what-you-see-is-not-always-what-it-is/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 04:46:08 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2012/07/23/bugs-what-you-see-is-not-always-what-it-is/</guid><description>Came across a neat nugget of historical information today that yet again proves that the software/hardware bug behavior that you may see on the surface might imply something totally opposite to what the problem actually is.
The &amp;ldquo;bug&amp;rdquo; existed back in the old times of the floppy drives. These drives seemed to fail very quickly on linux systems compared to MS DOS/Windows. Now, a normal observer would say linux had bad handling of the drives or was doing something messy that made these drives crap out ever so often.</description></item><item><title>SGX 543MP2 vs Mali-400: Is iPhone 4S GPU Really Twice As Strong As SGS 2?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/10/05/sgx-543mp2-vs-mali-400-is-iphone-4s-gpu-really-twice-as-strong-as-sgs-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2011 20:23:23 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/10/05/sgx-543mp2-vs-mali-400-is-iphone-4s-gpu-really-twice-as-strong-as-sgs-2/</guid><description>Ever since Apple announced the iPhone 4S having &amp;ldquo;A5&amp;rdquo; processor, everyone has been pointing to the below image from a test run by Anandtech and saying that the iPhone 4S will be twice as strong as the Samsung Galaxy S2. I beg to differ.
While the above test doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any discrepancy, one major thing is that the SGX 543MP2 results are from an iPad 2 (a tablet) while the Mali 400 results are from a smartphone.</description></item><item><title>Deconstructing The Samsung Nexus Prime Video</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/10/05/deconstructing-the-samsung-nexus-prime-video/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2011 05:59:28 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/10/05/deconstructing-the-samsung-nexus-prime-video/</guid><description>Samsung just uploaded a teaser video to Youtube which hints at the upcoming Android phone Nexus Prime with IceCream Sandwich. It has a sideways glance at what people believe is the Nexus Prime. I&amp;rsquo;ll deconstruct the image a bit.
The things to take away from here:
The phone will have a curved display like Nexus S
It has a power button on the side (right side, since it&amp;rsquo;s marked with the power icon)</description></item><item><title>Adding Lyrics to SharkZapper for Grooveshark</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/09/23/adding-lyrics-to-sharkzapper-for-grooveshark/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2011 09:12:06 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/09/23/adding-lyrics-to-sharkzapper-for-grooveshark/</guid><description>I bet all of you know about grooveshark, the awesome music service. And sharkzapper is a cool chrome extension that puts the control and information about anything playing in your grooveshark chrome tab into a little button on the address bar. It is a very good extension but I felt that what it was missing was lyrics. Before I could comment on the extension&amp;rsquo;s chrome market page, I noticed that it has a github repository.</description></item><item><title>Chrome Script/Extension installation error: Could not read source file</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/09/19/chrome-scriptextension-installation-error-could-not-read-source-file/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2011 16:58:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/09/19/chrome-scriptextension-installation-error-could-not-read-source-file/</guid><description>This is a solution to the issue that I faced today while installing a javascript file from userscripts.org as an extension into google chrome (Yes, Chrome supports installing greasemonkey javascripts as extensions). I had already installed this script once into my browser earlier but when I tried installing it again today, it started giving me a weird error &amp;ldquo;Could not read source file&amp;rdquo;. I tried all possible means, like putting it on a different server, installing from local disk, changing versions, deleting all cache, etc but still the issue persisted.</description></item><item><title>Swype 3.25 Beta Pre-release Parse Error Solution</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/08/23/swype-3-25-beta-pre-release-parse-error-solution/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 18:07:44 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/08/23/swype-3-25-beta-pre-release-parse-error-solution/</guid><description>Swype just released their latest beta version 3.25 for Android phones but most of the folks are facing a &amp;ldquo;parse error&amp;rdquo; while trying to update to the latest version. If you are one of such folks, there is a simple solution that I just tried and got working. Instead of updating from the swype installer, you need to update manually. Uninstall your existing swype, then uninstall the existing swype installer on your phone.</description></item><item><title>Remote Bandwidth Stats</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/08/21/remote-bandwidth-stats/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 17:44:24 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/08/21/remote-bandwidth-stats/</guid><description>This post is about my open source remote bandwidth usage stats logger project.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to log the internet bandwidth usage at my home for quite some time since I don&amp;rsquo;t really find the stats put out by my ISP to be completely accurate. But I have multiple devices at home that access the internet so it is not feasible to install a bandwidth monitor individually on all these devices as I&amp;rsquo;d still need to add up all logs and many of such devices don&amp;rsquo;t even have a way to install a monitoring software installed (e.</description></item><item><title>Featured in Chip India August 2011 Edition</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/08/01/featured-in-chip-india-august-2011-edition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 03:24:23 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/08/01/featured-in-chip-india-august-2011-edition/</guid><description>My project Kinect on PS3 got featured in this month&amp;rsquo;s Chip magazine :). They have a special gaming edition of Chip Insider which featured the project along with a 2 page interview of mine. If you buy chip, do look out for it on pages 46 and 47. I also have a scanned image of the pages below.</description></item><item><title>Huawei Ideos U8150 Review</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/06/05/huawei-ideos-u8150-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2011 15:52:19 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/06/05/huawei-ideos-u8150-review/</guid><description>Recently I received Huawei Ideos U8150 phone for review. This is an Android smartphone meant for the entry level market. I had the phone for a few weeks to put it through its paces and here are some of my thoughts about it. I am not going to expand a lot on the general Android points as we all know about it but will concentrate succinctly and to-the-point on the aspects which can make it or break it for this phone against its competition in the similar price ranges.</description></item><item><title>Google Music Beta Latest APK version 3.0.1 for Android</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/05/27/google-music-latest-apk-android-3-0-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 03:57:10 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/05/27/google-music-latest-apk-android-3-0-1/</guid><description>Google just released the latest version of its Music app that ties into its cloud player service Music Beta. This brings the version upto 3.0.1 and adds a lot of fixes, crashes a lot less and now even works on Samsung Galaxy S with Gingerbread which was broken earlier. If you are outside the US and not able to download the app from the market, then download it from here:http://www.multiupload.com/KIM5LQDL0K</description></item><item><title>Use Encrypted Google Search As Default in Chrome</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/05/12/use-encrypted-google-search-as-default-in-chrome/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 04:26:21 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/05/12/use-encrypted-google-search-as-default-in-chrome/</guid><description>Google just launched an encrypted search portal which is a Godsend for people on public networks since there is a lot that can be gleaned from your search queries. For doing your protected searches, however, you have to go to a different portal which I linked to above. Now, the omnibar (the address bar in Google Chrome) also serves as a search box but searches on the normal google portal by default.</description></item><item><title>iWebLeaf - India's $35 Android Tablet Spawning Fake Innovators?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/04/06/iwebleaf-indias-35-android-tablet-spawning-fake-innovators/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 18:04:44 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/04/06/iwebleaf-indias-35-android-tablet-spawning-fake-innovators/</guid><description>It was just about an year ago that we heard about the $35 Android Tablet from India which would revolutionize the education in developing countries. Mr. Kapil Sibal promoted it with utmost fervor until it was found that the BoM itself of the tablet was more than $50 and none of the guys claimed to have &amp;ldquo;invented&amp;rdquo; it even knew about its existence until a few days before the announcement. Ultimately, it was discovered that the tablet was just a rebranded chinese import which the government wanted to bring down to $35 price point by subsidizing the cost and not by somehow inventing cheaper parts.</description></item><item><title>Google to abandon Android. Spin off separate company</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/04/01/google-to-abandon-android-spin-off-separate-company/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 07:03:06 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/04/01/google-to-abandon-android-spin-off-separate-company/</guid><description>Now, this is mind blowing. I&amp;rsquo;ve just talked to a pretty reliable source within the Android ranks of Google that Google is going to distance itself legally from Android and spin it off in a separate company. The source said that the move can happen very soon and may be announced at Google I/O conference in May. Although details are sketchy and only very few high profile folks know about it within Google, my source says that the probable reason is increasing worries about legal aspects of Android with respect to Patents and IP law suits.</description></item><item><title>Making Kinect Work With PS3</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/03/20/making-kinect-work-with-ps3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2011 15:36:51 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/03/20/making-kinect-work-with-ps3/</guid><description>This post describes my first attempt at making Kinect work with a PS3. Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s new XBOX 360 accessory, kinect has made a powerful entry into the market, becoming the fastest selling gadget of all time. Looks like their &amp;ldquo;You are the controller&amp;rdquo; tagline is working. Of course, Sony&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;similar&amp;rdquo; accessory Move is selling well too but is far behind kinect adoption probably because nothing beats the lure of making something work with just &amp;ldquo;The Force&amp;rdquo; ;).</description></item><item><title>Ubuntu Maverick uinput Problem Solved</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/02/21/ubuntu-maverick-uinput-problem-solved/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 19:33:37 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/02/21/ubuntu-maverick-uinput-problem-solved/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with linux uinput infrastructure for one of my ideas (Details coming soon ;) ). &amp;ldquo;uinput&amp;rdquo; is basically a mechanism in linux that allows user space applications to inject input events (mouse/keyboard or anything else) into the system. But the problem I faced was that my programs were compiling and running without any errors but I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t see the effect happening, i.e., the events weren&amp;rsquo;t getting injected into the system.</description></item><item><title>PSN Ban-Wave Phishing Scam</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/02/17/psn-ban-wave-phishing-scam/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 09:25:24 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/02/17/psn-ban-wave-phishing-scam/</guid><description>**Update: **I did some more digging and the email and the links actually seem to be legitimate. Good news for many, but bad for those who actually got this email.
BEWARE!! In wake of the recent announcement of a potential Playstation Network ban wave by Sony for the people who are hacking it&amp;rsquo;s gaming console PS3, some nefarious elements seem to be using this as an opportunity to pry on your PSN passwords.</description></item><item><title>Paypal India Goes Even More Downhill. Get Your Money Out</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/01/28/paypal-india-goes-even-more-downhill-get-your-money-out/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2011 19:30:03 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/01/28/paypal-india-goes-even-more-downhill-get-your-money-out/</guid><description>Just received an email from Paypal India. The main parts are these:
With effect from 1 March 2011, you are required to comply with the requirements set out in the notification of the Reserve Bank of India governing the processing and settlement of export-related receipts facilitated by online payment gateways (&amp;ldquo;RBI Guidelines&amp;rdquo;). In order to comply with the RBI Guidelines, our user agreement in India will be amended for the following services as follows:</description></item><item><title>Android/iPhone Beware: WP7 Phones have already sold 12 million devices</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/12/04/androidiphone-beware-wp7-phones-have-already-sold-12-million-devices/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 19:16:19 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/12/04/androidiphone-beware-wp7-phones-have-already-sold-12-million-devices/</guid><description>According to TechCrunch, that is. TC has a post on its blog right now (from none other than Michael Arrington) that says Toddlers Pick iPhone Over Windows 7 Phones 10-1. The article says that this is because a toddlers' app maker&amp;rsquo;s notes that their app sold 71.5 apps per day on average on the iOS app store, while the number was 7.5 on the WP7 marketplace. Go read the article (it&amp;rsquo;s pretty short) and come back to read the below.</description></item><item><title>Ad-Free (Paid) Angry Birds For Android</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/12/02/ad-free-paid-angry-birds-android/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 13:28:52 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/12/02/ad-free-paid-angry-birds-android/</guid><description>Rovio Mobile has been pretty considerate for the Android lovers and has released their Angry Birds game for free on the Android market. Many people love it but quite a few are annoyed by it because Rovio chose to monetize it by in-game advertisements, and that too placed at awkward places which can hinder the gameplay. Many users have also reported that they are being forced to view video ads as well these days.</description></item><item><title>Review of X-Mini Capsule Happy Speakers</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/11/28/review-of-x-mini-capsule-happy-speakers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2010 16:22:18 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/11/28/review-of-x-mini-capsule-happy-speakers/</guid><description>I received a few portable speakers as review pieces from x-mini a few days ago. I tried all of them but thought of posting a review of the most interesting model out of the lot, which is the X-mini Happy. Would also be posting a review soon of one more model that I liked quite a bit which is the X-mini Max II.
In The Package</description></item><item><title>ZDNet Fail. Answer is Stop Tech Blogging</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/11/19/zdnet-fail-answer-is-stop-tech-blogging/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2010 15:45:04 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/11/19/zdnet-fail-answer-is-stop-tech-blogging/</guid><description>Just read this article over at zdnet. What it basically says is condensed in these two points:
Android is a failure for Google because it is open and carriers/OEMs are stripping off google search from it and putting replacements like baidu/Bing. (BTW, half the people say Android is fail because it is not open and the other half say it is fail because it is open. Which one is it, please decide ;) )</description></item><item><title>A short Tablet/Smartphone survey for a project</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/11/15/short-tablet-smartphone-survey-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2010 04:10:06 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/11/15/short-tablet-smartphone-survey-project/</guid><description>I need a bit of your help in filling out a short survey that I need for a small project of mine that I&amp;rsquo;m doing with a friend. It will take maximum of only 2-3 minutes of your time. Please fill it out below. If you are facing any problems with the survey or have any queries/suggestions etc, please use this contact form to send them to us.
Much Thanks!! :)</description></item><item><title>The Real Threat Of Windows Phone 7</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/28/the-real-threat-of-windows-phone-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2010 19:48:34 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/28/the-real-threat-of-windows-phone-7/</guid><description>Many people say that Windows Phone 7 is a threat to iPhone because they are bringing in a super platform with a choice of multiple designs and multiple carriers with great Enterprise and gaming support and maintaining the lucrative integration that iPhone provides. Many also say that Windows Phone 7 is a threat to Android because it solves the problem of Apple&amp;rsquo;s draconian policies, gives choice to customers and all this without fragmenting the OS all over the place.</description></item><item><title>Is Android Open Source Or Not?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/25/android-open-source-or-not/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 11:31:06 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/25/android-open-source-or-not/</guid><description>Is Android really open source or not? That is the question being asked by almost everyone. A lot of people, especially those influenced by RDF or those who are in the news industry with no idea about OS and open source but were asked by their boss to get a scoop on this pronto, tend to bring up a few keywords and then twist them around in the way they see fit to make sure it says Android isn&amp;rsquo;t open.</description></item><item><title>What does caret (^) in an apt-get command mean?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/23/apt-get-caret/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2010 18:03:06 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/23/apt-get-caret/</guid><description>If you have come across a tutorial or just someone on a forum who tells you to install something in Debian/Ubuntu that involves using apt-get, it is ok for you but when they tell you that you need to use a caret symbol (^) at the end, that&amp;rsquo;s where you become curious. What is even more weird is that when you search for the name of the package that the given command seems to install cannot be found using apt-cache search.</description></item><item><title>Android Paid Apps Now Live In India</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/05/android-paid-apps-now-live-in-india/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2010 07:35:39 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/05/android-paid-apps-now-live-in-india/</guid><description>Yes! As of today noon, paid apps are now visible on my Android Nexus One in India. Few salient points (Also, look at the end to see how to get paid apps if you are not able to see them yet):
The marketplace shows approximate prices of each app in Indian Rupees (INR) (Edit: I&amp;rsquo;ve just learned from few tweets that this is a new feature worldwide. People everywhere are now seeing approximate app costs in their local currencies.</description></item><item><title>WordPress Global Dashboard &amp; Stats Plugin Problem</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/04/wordpress-global-dashboard-stats-plugin-problem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2010 16:57:30 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/04/wordpress-global-dashboard-stats-plugin-problem/</guid><description>Seems like there is a major problem going on with WordPress.com and it&amp;rsquo;s stats plugin right now. On logging into your WordPress blog, instead of seeing the pretty charts and stats, you will see a login box instead. On logging in, it just redirects back to the same thing again (Dashboard with login page). And if you try logging into your profile over at WordPress.com, then it just redirects back to your main blog associated with your WordPress.</description></item><item><title>Carrier Billing Behind Android Paid Apps Market Jump?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/01/carrier-billing-behind-android-paid-apps-market-jump/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 17:19:51 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/01/carrier-billing-behind-android-paid-apps-market-jump/</guid><description>We heard the news today that paid apps in Android market place have been extended to 18 new countries. Could &amp;ldquo;Carrier Billing&amp;rdquo; (Allowing your service operator to add the apps' price to your cellphone bill) be the reason behind it? I think so. It was long suggested that Google Checkout and corresponding legal issues in using it across various countries was the reason behind the paid apps not being available in those countries.</description></item><item><title>Android Paid Apps Available In India</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/01/android-paid-apps-india/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 03:40:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/10/01/android-paid-apps-india/</guid><description>Just got a mail from Google that paid apps are being made available in India. HOORAY!!! In addition, developers from 20 more countries can sell apps on market (Unfortunately, no India in this list) and people from 18 more countries can buy paid apps.
This is a big thing because now 32 countries out of 44 where Android has footprint can buy paid apps. This should take away one of the biggest drawbacks that Android marketplace was facing.</description></item><item><title>Setup Call Recording With Android App Tasker On Nexus One</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/24/setup-call-recording-android-app-tasker-nexus-one/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2010 10:01:16 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/24/setup-call-recording-android-app-tasker-nexus-one/</guid><description>I wanted to record calls on my Android phone (Nexus one). The easy way would have been to download an app but I like tinkering. And given that I recently bought Tasker, android’s very own swiss knife, I thought I should give it a run. After just an hour I was able to create my very own call recorder (some time went into trial and error with things as this was my first major task with tasker and also some things didn’t work with nexus one, which I will note below).</description></item><item><title>Clearing the FUD around Ubuntu Application Review Process</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/21/clearing-the-fud-around-ubuntu-application-review-process/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2010 19:44:24 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/21/clearing-the-fud-around-ubuntu-application-review-process/</guid><description>An application review process was announced today for getting your apps into Ubuntu “extras” repository. But like most other announcements of new things, this one was met as well with as much criticism as the praise it got. A lot of the criticism is FUD though, although mostly unintentional and caused by ignorance of some facts behind it. I’ll try to address some of these concerns here to the best of my knowledge from what I’ve been reading over the past some time about this development.</description></item><item><title>The Great Indian $35 Tablet Hoax?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/13/the-great-indian-35-tablet-hoax/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2010 09:59:42 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/13/the-great-indian-35-tablet-hoax/</guid><description>Another nail in the coffin before this Android tablet lives to fulfill the Indian kids’ dreams. Well, not exactly a nail in the coffin. The tablet might still be here, and at the price promised but the thing to note is how low the government can stoop to get bragging rights (and votes). The article elaborates how the IIT/IISC scientists weren’t even aware that such a “project” existed and they were invited to be a part of it just a month before Mr.</description></item><item><title>Android App: Wi-Fi Keep Alive updates</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/09/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive-updates/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2010 05:27:27 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/09/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive-updates/</guid><description>I pushed out a couple of updates to my android app Wi-Fi Keep alive a few weeks ago (mainly related to fixing the resolution and colors of the widget icons) taking the latest version to 1.4.4. This is just to let you know that it will take a while (a few weeks) more to get the pending updates and requests in to the program. I have been pretty ill for the last few weeks and have only just got back up out of the bed and now my development machine has also gone for a toss.</description></item><item><title>Caution: Stay away from making your Android app free for a short time</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/08/caution-stay-away-from-making-your-android-app-free-for-a-short-time/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 06:18:36 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/08/caution-stay-away-from-making-your-android-app-free-for-a-short-time/</guid><description>Just read this over at the Android Developers google forum:
My app had a one-day sale on all platforms and app stores. The price went from 2.99 to free for just today, but now that the sale is over, I need to revert the price back to 2.99. The bad news is, the developer console will not let me change it! I have to pull the app until I can get this resolved.</description></item><item><title>Acer TimelineX 4820TG Mini-Review</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/06/acer-timelinex-4820tg-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2010 12:18:12 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/09/06/acer-timelinex-4820tg-review/</guid><description>This is a small review of my Acer TimelineX 4820TG that I purchased a few days ago. Now, I won’t be talking numbers (like CPU/GPU performance etc) because these things are almost same as per the component used and have been covered in various other reviews online. What I’ll concentrate more upon are the things that other reviewers don’t look at, or look at purely from numbers perspective which don’t make sense to an average buyer.</description></item><item><title>Solving The Android Permissions And Malware Puzzle</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/13/android-permissions-malware/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2010 19:44:59 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/13/android-permissions-malware/</guid><description>There has been a spate of security reports recently about Android apps being malware or suspicious. Most of these were found baseless but at least one was indeed correct (e.g. The Russian Trojan app). We also know that Android has a very good security model but even then, the rest of the reports also makes one think and focus on why an apps requires the permissions that it states it needs?</description></item><item><title>Android Dev Tip: App Not Showing on X10 Mini Marketplace</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/07/android-dev-tip-app-not-showing-on-x10-mini-marketplace/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2010 21:18:06 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/07/android-dev-tip-app-not-showing-on-x10-mini-marketplace/</guid><description>Many Android Developers (and users) get confused that why a certain app isn&amp;rsquo;t showing up on the new Xperia X10 Mini (and few other) phones. This happens even if they support all android versions and have published their apps for all countries, so that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the issue. I came across this as well when few people mentioned that they couldn&amp;rsquo;t find my app Wi-Fi Keep Alive in the X10 mini marketplace.</description></item><item><title>SSH Tunneling On Android</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/02/ssh-tunneling-android/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2010 10:53:36 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/08/02/ssh-tunneling-android/</guid><description>If you want to have a secure browsing environment or just want to access your home network securely without exposing extra services to the internet and without the mess that comes with setting up and maintaining a VPN server, ssh tunneling is your rescuer. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you how to setup an ssh tunnel to your home network easily. Also look for some bonus tips at the end ;)</description></item><item><title>Camera LED As Flashlight on Non-Rooted Android Phones</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/30/camera-led-flashlight-non-rooted-android-phones/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2010 09:31:08 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/30/camera-led-flashlight-non-rooted-android-phones/</guid><description>We all know that Android does not allow the camera LED to be controlled directly from apps and hence, you cannot use the camera LED as a Torch or Flashlight unless you are rooted. There are many flashlight apps on the Android Market Place but none of them will work for you if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a rooted phone. BUT this changed recently. I use a brilliant app called &amp;ldquo;quick settings&amp;rdquo; which keeps an icon in the notification bar and I can pull it down and change any settings without leaving other apps.</description></item><item><title>Firefly / sqlite error "unable to open database file" Solution</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/26/firefly-sqlite-error-unable-to-open-database-file-solution/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2010 18:11:40 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/26/firefly-sqlite-error-unable-to-open-database-file-solution/</guid><description>Recently I came across a weird error while trying to run firefly itunes server (mt-daapd) on my router (Asus wl-500w). It had something to do with sqlite and gave a vague message &amp;ldquo;Unable to open database file&amp;rdquo;. After going bonkers for a short time, I solved it and this is how.
One of my hard disks crashed recently and unfortunately it was the one I had connected to my router to serve media to me all over the house (through PS3/laptop) or when I travel (through laptop/phone).</description></item><item><title>Android App Wi-Fi Keep Alive updated to 1.4.1</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/22/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive-updated-1-4-0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2010 16:58:07 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/22/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive-updated-1-4-0/</guid><description>Update: Made a minor update for a small bug that can make wi-fi keep reconnecting in quick succession.
Pushed out a new update to my Android App Wi-Fi Keep Alive today. This update brings in another work around for the issue where the wi-fi is alive on the phone and it is also connected to the network but is somehow unable to send/receive any packets to the network. The new work around will automatically re-associate your phone with the wi-fi router if it detects such a situation.</description></item><item><title>Cannot Change Channel Problem With Asus WL-500W</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/13/cannot-change-channel-problem-with-asus-wl-500w/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 12:16:44 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/13/cannot-change-channel-problem-with-asus-wl-500w/</guid><description>Recently I found an issue with my asus wl-500w wi-fi router that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to change the channel on which it was transmitting. I moved to a new location which was totally jam-packed with other wi-fi networks using same channel as mine which was hampeing my connection. I tried for umpteen number of times. Changing the channel through the web configuration did not give any error but I found that it was still transmitting at channel 1.</description></item><item><title>Mute (or Answer) Skype Calls with BT Headset Button in Linux</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/08/mute-answer-skype-calls-bluetooth-headset-button-in-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2010 18:31:55 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/08/mute-answer-skype-calls-bluetooth-headset-button-in-linux/</guid><description>Skype on linux works great but the problem that I faced was that it does not handle the buttons on the bluetooth headsets. My wife uses skype to call into her work related conference calls and was pretty frustrated that she had to keep sitting in front of my laptop (her laptop didn&amp;rsquo;t allow to install skype) just to switch mute on and off. So, I whipped up this little trick to do so.</description></item><item><title>BadTokenException Error In Android Dialog</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/08/badtokenexception-android-dialog-getapplicationcontext/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2010 11:24:14 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/08/badtokenexception-android-dialog-getapplicationcontext/</guid><description>If you are creating a custom Dialog for Android, and following the Android Developers’ Creating Dialogs tutorial, then most likely you would have faced a Force Close with this exception showing up in logcat. I did too. Although I figured it out quickly, it might not be easy to find out for many, so posting it here for reference. Basically, the code given in the tutorial goes something like this:</description></item><item><title>Android App: Wi-Fi Keep Alive Updated to 1.2.0</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/03/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive-updated-to-1-2-0/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2010 22:46:36 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/03/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive-updated-to-1-2-0/</guid><description>Just finished uploading the new version 1.2.0 of my android app Wi-Fi Keep Alive to the Android market. This version has a lot of optimizations and also a few workarounds to overcome the issues few guys were facing with Android&amp;rsquo;s in-built handling of wi-fi sleep policies.
Changes done in this version:
Added workarounds to take care of sleep policies not working on some phones
Optimized the code a bit for faster operations</description></item><item><title>Android App: Wi-Fi Keep Alive</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/28/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2010 15:25:48 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/28/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive/</guid><description>I just wrote my second Android App. This again was to scratch an itch of mine but it seems to have become a bit popular already (My first app &amp;ldquo;Quick Sync Settings&amp;rdquo; did around 400 downloads in 20 days but this one has already surpassed that in less than one day). This app basically allows you to change the wi-fi sleep policy on android so that you can keep your wi-fi connected even if the phone goes to sleep (i.</description></item><item><title>Wi-Fi Keep Alive</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/28/wi-fi-keep-alive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2010 15:20:19 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/28/wi-fi-keep-alive/</guid><description>UPDATE Potential work arounds for folks having problem in sleep policies not working correctly have been put in version 1.2.0 onwards. Please redownload to test and let me know. Read below for more details.
Latest Version: 1.4.4 (See below for change log history)
Are you frustrated by your downloads getting broken or worse, switching over to slow and expensive mobile data connections like GPRS/Edge/3G when your wi-fi connection gets dropped by your Android phone when the screen goes off?</description></item><item><title>Android vs iPhone: Security Models</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/25/android-vs-iphone-security-models/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2010 22:02:49 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/25/android-vs-iphone-security-models/</guid><description>Android and iPhone OS (iOS) have been at loggerheads for quite some time now. This is a take on which has a better security model to protect its users. I thought of writing it up because there have been a lot of discussions around me lately about which platform is more secure and I keep repeating the same points over and over at every one of them, so thought that in future I&amp;rsquo;ll just point them to this page :P</description></item><item><title>How To Debug Android Widgets</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/13/how-to-debug-android-widgets/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 18:42:42 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/13/how-to-debug-android-widgets/</guid><description>For most new android app developers (like me), it is a bit puzzling how to debug the android widgets or how to put a breakpoint in an android widget code. For normal applications, it is quite simple as when you press &amp;ldquo;debug&amp;rdquo; on the eclipse toolbar, it launches the emulator (or connects to existing emulator/device), syncs your application and launches its main activity and puts the control in your hands if you have put a breakpoint.</description></item><item><title>Android App: Quickly Open Accounts &amp; Sync Settings</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/12/android-app-quickly-open-accounts-sync-settings/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2010 21:19:35 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/12/android-app-quickly-open-accounts-sync-settings/</guid><description>Just a small post to let you know that I just published a small app in the android market, which scratches an itch of mine and I thought probably it will be help others too. It basically provides a quick, one-click access to the accounts and sync settings of Android. The use case for me was that I need to enable/disable syncing for my work email while I&amp;rsquo;m at work every day as I am already in front of my office PC so don&amp;rsquo;t need to waste battery and be annoyed by mail notifications on phone but still need to keep google calendar syncing.</description></item><item><title>Quick Sync Settings</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/12/quick-sync-settings/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2010 21:14:54 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/12/quick-sync-settings/</guid><description>This is a very small android app to open the accounts and sync settings in one click. We all need to disable the sync settings of a particular account sometimes but keep all other items still syncing. For example, for most of the day I&amp;rsquo;m at work, in front of my office PC so I don&amp;rsquo;t need to keep my work email syncing which causes unnecessary drain on my battery but I do need to keep other things, like my google calendar, syncing still.</description></item><item><title>Apple is Magical: Daniel Eran Gilder is the Living Proof</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/10/apple-magical-dan-eran-gilder/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 04:49:53 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/10/apple-magical-dan-eran-gilder/</guid><description>Update: Removed the post as the person in consideration has contacted me with the explanation of what went down. I’m not sure if it is completely true or this is just as a response to this post but anyways, as I had contended in the original post that it was a stupid little thing that didn’t really warrant any attention or a post but I still did it just because I’m weird, so in the light of the developments, I think it’s best to remove the rants and focus on actual discussion.</description></item><item><title>Android Froyo And Nexus One: Everything We Know</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/05/23/android-froyo-nexus-one/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2010 17:44:18 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/05/23/android-froyo-nexus-one/</guid><description>This is an effort from my side to consolidate everything about Android Froyo with respect to Nexus One. It is mainly concentrated towards listing the features/fixes that we have seen in Froyo that weren&amp;rsquo;t announced in Google I/O, things that work with nexus one, things that don&amp;rsquo;t and possible fixes/workarounds known, what the announced features actually feel like in real use etc.** Will keep updating this post as I get more info, get more fixes, etc.</description></item><item><title>Android Froyo Update File</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/05/22/android-froyo-update/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2010 19:36:34 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/05/22/android-froyo-update/</guid><description>Just a quick post to tell you how to update your Nexus One to Android 2.2 Froyo immediately without waiting for google to send it to you OTA.
Download this file from google&amp;rsquo;s servers: http://android.clients.google.com/packages/passion/signed-passion-FRF50-from-ERE27.1e519a24.zip
After that just follow the below mentioned steps:
Put it on your SD card and rename to update.zip
Power off then hold trackball and press power again to boot into recovery</description></item><item><title>Integrate JDownloader with Flashgot</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/04/14/jdownloader-flashgot-integrate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2010 16:21:41 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/04/14/jdownloader-flashgot-integrate/</guid><description>This is just a short post to to document how I got JDownloader to integrate with Flashgot. JDownloader doesn&amp;rsquo;t have an installer but a zip file that you just download and extract somewhere on your PC and start using it. Somehow, the Flashgot extension of Firefox is not able to detect it automatically and I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what parameters to use to add it manually to its list. Latest versions of JDownloader ask you whether you want to install Flashgot or not.</description></item><item><title>Automatic Login For Beam Cable</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/04/14/beam-cable-automatic-login/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2010 04:33:37 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/04/14/beam-cable-automatic-login/</guid><description>This article will tell you a simple way to login automatically to beam cable (Beam-Telecom) internet connection instead of using the web login manually. Not only that, I’ll also tell you how to do this auto-login through your router if you have one with a custom linux firmware. I took a beam cable connection a few days ago. The price is excellent and speeds are good but the only thing that bothered me was the web based login.</description></item><item><title>Real Time Data Plotting with GNUPlot</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/12/29/real-time-plot-gnuplot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2009 11:15:51 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/12/29/real-time-plot-gnuplot/</guid><description>I wrote this script a few days ago to plot real-time / streaming data with gnuplot. The motivation was that I needed to test a piece of code for a touchscreen driver that I had written at work. The issue was that the UI wasn’t quite ready yet, so I wanted to test just the driver to be working fine. Now, the very first thought for the software to use that came to me was “gnuplot” but I found that it can’t really do this in an easy way.</description></item><item><title>RT-GNUPlot-ter</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/12/29/real-time-streaming-data-plot-gnuplot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2009 10:52:56 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/12/29/real-time-streaming-data-plot-gnuplot/</guid><description>This is a script to plot streaming / real-time data (i.e. plot the points as the data comes in) with gnuplot. The script is written in perl and works in windows as well as linux. Please read on to see the requirements, installation, usage and download link. I should also thank my colleague Rabindra Mandal, who gave me the initial idea and Thanassis Tsiodras, whose script I looked at before creating mine (though mine is quite different in nature.</description></item><item><title>Continuous Monitoring With Tail Fails</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/12/23/continuous-monitor-tail-fails/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2009 18:10:44 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/12/23/continuous-monitor-tail-fails/</guid><description>If you can&amp;rsquo;t get tail command to continuously monitor a file, then read on. I was working on a script yesterday, a part of which depended on continuous monitoring of a text file. I had used our trusty old &amp;ldquo;tail&amp;rdquo; command for this but while testing by manually putting in some data into the file, it was failing but curiously it was working fine when used in actual scenario. Befuddled, I did a simple test.</description></item><item><title>Paradise For Overclockers, Gamers and PC Enthusiasts In India</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/12/07/overclockers-pc-enthusiasts-gamers-india/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2009 18:05:27 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/12/07/overclockers-pc-enthusiasts-gamers-india/</guid><description>This is just to let you know that a few of my friends have started Overclocked, a haven for PC enthusiasts in India. Overclocked is an online store for the people who like to stretch the performance of their machines to the maximum. They store a lot of high end computer stuff that isn&amp;rsquo;t easy to find in India and that too for a reasonable price. They also assemble mean gaming machines while giving you quite a bang for your buck with gauranteed satisfaction, shipped anywhere in India, and that&amp;rsquo;s not all, they can personalize it too with a variety of custom modifications (I really like their laser engravings).</description></item><item><title>grub and knetworkmanager problems in Kubuntu Karmic</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/11/08/grub-knetworkmanager-kubuntu-karmic/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2009 12:08:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/11/08/grub-knetworkmanager-kubuntu-karmic/</guid><description>I generally move from LTS to LTS releases of Ubuntu but reluctantly had to update my system to Karmic when my old HDD gave in. I also thought of trying out Kubuntu (KDE based) this time as I had heard that its doing a lot of interesting things (Akonadi/Nepomuk etc) and that with 4.3.1 it is stable as well. The installation went fine, all over within less than half an hour and then the problems started.</description></item><item><title>Making Frets On Fire Work With Pulse Aludio - pasuspender</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/08/23/make-frets-on-fire-work-pulse-audio-pasuspender/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2009 18:18:45 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/08/23/make-frets-on-fire-work-pulse-audio-pasuspender/</guid><description>I recently got hold of a Guitar Hero controller for my PS3 but the game still had some time to come so I tried it out on my laptop with Frets on Fire (rather FoFix). But when I started it, it was crashing with some weird error about not being able to open mixer devices. Searching on the google, I came to know this is happening because of Pulse Audio as this application needs direct access to the sound devices and finally I came upon **pasuspender.</description></item><item><title>Killzone 2 Tips Tricks Tactics And Strategies : Engineer</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/08/09/killzone-2-tips-tricks-tactics-stategies-engineer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2009 16:45:04 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/08/09/killzone-2-tips-tricks-tactics-stategies-engineer/</guid><description>Killzone 2 (KZ2) is one of my most favourite games for the Playstation 3. Killzone 2 is a very different game as compared to the other run-of-the-mill FPS&amp;rsquo;s out there. Now, I might not be the best player out there but I&amp;rsquo;ve played my fair share of it. So, I thought of jotting down some quick points for the different classes, how to play them and how to make the most of them according to my opinion.</description></item><item><title>Easiest Way to Shutdown Asus WL-500W</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/07/10/shutdown-asus-wl-500-w/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2009 23:19:12 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/07/10/shutdown-asus-wl-500-w/</guid><description>If you are a proud owner of an Asus WL-500W wireless router (or maybe another one of the same series like wl-500g, wl-500gp, etc), then you know that this router has a very useful USB port with which you might have attached your external hard disk and have already offloaded all your downloding tasks to it, or maybe using it for various other purposes. Whatever maybe the reason, the main point is that because of this hard disk, now we cannot just turn off the power of the router any more.</description></item><item><title>VirtualBox High CPU Usage Problem Solved</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/07/07/virtualbox-high-cpu-usage-problem-solved/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2009 03:36:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/07/07/virtualbox-high-cpu-usage-problem-solved/</guid><description>A few days ago, I had to install Windows XP as a guest OS on my Ubuntu Hardy machine as I needed to carry out some Visual Studio work. What I noticed was that my CPU usage went through the roof (constantly at 100%) even if the guest was completely idle. Result: My laptop was shutting down within a few minutes because the CPU was heating up and its temperature going beyond 75C.</description></item><item><title>Compiling Latest FireFly (mt-daapd) for ASUS WL-500W</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/07/03/compiling-latest-firefly-mt-daapd-asus-wl-500w/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2009 10:28:32 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/07/03/compiling-latest-firefly-mt-daapd-asus-wl-500w/</guid><description>FireFly is a nice DAAP based media server that allows you to listen to your music collection anywhere using any DAAP based client like iTunes, with other players (like Winamp, Rhythmbox, VLC, etc) using plugins, or it even has its own dedicated php/flash/java based clients that can be fired up on any platform any computer giving you instant nirvana.
Many people, like me, use it on their Routers or NAS boxes to access their music anywhere without having to keep their home PC running or lugging around external drives.</description></item><item><title>Opera Web Server In A Browser: Bad Idea</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/06/17/opera-web-server-browser-bad-idea/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 08:17:04 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/06/17/opera-web-server-browser-bad-idea/</guid><description>Today, the whole word is going gaga over &amp;ldquo;Opera Unite&amp;rdquo;, the new technology in Opera 10 which will make your web browser a web server as well (and not just that, it will make a whole lot of “sharing” options available). Well, I’m not so excited about it. Technology wise, it is really cool but what they don’t realize is that this is like giving motorized chain-saw or a swiss army knife in the hands of a two-year old.</description></item><item><title>Microtek UPS Problems (And A Solution)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/05/10/microtek-ups-problems-solution/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2009 15:35:02 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/05/10/microtek-ups-problems-solution/</guid><description>I got myself a Microtek 800VA UPS (MDP800+) a couple of weeks ago to save my PS3 from the frequent power outages that we are seeing in Hyderabad but the purpose was rather lost when I found that it worked fine only till the mains power was on. As soon as there was an outage, it couldn’t stop the PS3 from an abrupt shut down. I ran around the pathetic Microtek customer service for days and they finally sent an “engineer” down to my place (after a week) to diagnose the issue and he couldn’t say anything more than that the UPS is meant for a PC and nothing else.</description></item><item><title>Why You Should Not Upgrade to Ubuntu Jaunty Jackalope (9.04)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/05/04/ubuntu-904-jaunty-jackalope-upgrade-graphics-problem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2009 17:46:40 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/05/04/ubuntu-904-jaunty-jackalope-upgrade-graphics-problem/</guid><description>Update: It has come to my notice that many people do not know about this (and other problems listed in comments of this post). Please digg and reddit this post so that more people can be made aware of it before they upgrade unknowingly.
You should not upgrade to Ubuntu 9.04 (aka Jaunty Jackalope), released a few weeks ago, if:
You have an older ATI graphics card (prior to R500, .</description></item><item><title>TIP: Perforce - Sync Files In A Label Without Deleting Previous Files</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/27/p4perforce-sync-files-label-without-deleting-previous/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2009 14:00:50 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/27/p4perforce-sync-files-label-without-deleting-previous/</guid><description>If you have used perforce, you&amp;rsquo;d have definitely come across a situation where you wanted to sync files belonging to two different labels, but as soon as you sync the second label, the files from the first label get deleted. P4 help suggests the following ways to achieve this:
p4 sync @label1,label2
or something like
`p4 sync @label1,@label2``
But I&amp;rsquo;ve found that depending on the perforce version you are using, the above commands might not work.</description></item><item><title>Project: Figlet Online - Text To ASCII Converter Tool</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/24/figlet-online-text-to-ascii-converter-tool/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2009 14:00:29 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/24/figlet-online-text-to-ascii-converter-tool/</guid><description>Figlet is a brilliant tool to convert text to amazing ASCII Art that I have used for many years. This weekend I thought of creating an online version of it, so that anyone can use it even if they can&amp;rsquo;t install it on their systems. It is pretty easy to use. The drill is just to choose the font you want (and there is a very extensive collection of more than 250 to choose from), input the text that you want to be ASCII&amp;rsquo;fied, press a button and you are done.</description></item><item><title>Figlet Online</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/22/figlet-online/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2009 14:15:54 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/22/figlet-online/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Comments In Google Reader Shared Items Are Here</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/12/google-reader-shared-items-comments/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2009 05:00:22 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/12/google-reader-shared-items-comments/</guid><description>Since quite some time, Google Reader has included the feature to share interesting items with your friends who also use Google Reader. Some time back they also added the option to &amp;ldquo;Share with a Note&amp;rdquo; to add your take to the shared piece. But I always thought there was no way to share back by comments (or see my friends' take) about that particular article. One way could have been to post the comments on the original site of the article but that had the drawbacks that:</description></item><item><title>Shutdown Script For Asus WL-500W With Oleg Firmware</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/09/shutdown-script-asus-wl-500w-oleg-firmware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 13:30:04 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/09/shutdown-script-asus-wl-500w-oleg-firmware/</guid><description>If you have an Asus WL-500W, the DIYers' favourite wireless router, and have installed the Oleg custom firmware on it, then you would have set up a shutdown script for it, that allows your router to shut down gracefully. This is especially important if you have a USB hard disk attached to it. There are many such scripts available in Oleg&amp;rsquo;s firmware that you can tweak. All of these reside in &amp;ldquo;/usr/local/sbin/&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>[TIP] Add Directories Recursively To Perforce (P4) Depot</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/03/add-directories-recursively-to-perforce-p4-depot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2009 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/03/add-directories-recursively-to-perforce-p4-depot/</guid><description>Perforce is an excellent revision control system for the code but the GUIs (P4WIN and P4V) are too slow to be productive. Hence, I like to do most of my work through command lines. Now, the other day I needed to add a directory and all its subdirectories and files to the repository (or perforce depot). This is a trivial task through the GUI. Just drag the top level directory onto the changelist area and the GUI takes care of everything but there is no straightforward way to do this through command line, until, I discovered the &amp;ldquo;-x&amp;rdquo; option of P4.</description></item><item><title>Project: My WordPress Plugin Shantz WP Prefix Suffix Updated to 1.1.4</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/02/wordpress-plugin-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-114/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2009 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/02/wordpress-plugin-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-114/</guid><description>Here comes another update, and this time it is a majorly recommended one. For those who are still living under a rock (just kidding :P), this is a plugin that allows you to add any kind of text/html/css/php/javascript code to any of your posts or pages with lots of controls over what to display, where to display, etc etc. So, you could use it as an ad-manager or a copyright notice adder (to thwart those feed scrapers) or just add some friendly messages or related posts, etc for your readers.</description></item><item><title>Secure Access To Your DSL Modem's Telnet (telnet / ssh)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/25/secure-access-dsl-modems-telnet-ssh/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2009 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/25/secure-access-dsl-modems-telnet-ssh/</guid><description>I have one of those crappy DSL modems that all these ISPs give to you with the connection. My ISP is Airtel and the modem that I have is Beetel 110-BXi (They also have other models like 220-BX and 220 BXi). One thing common among all these modems is that they do not provide secure access like Secure Shell (ssh) as all they provide is ftp/telnet/http etc which are all clear text protocols.</description></item><item><title>[TIP] Install Twonky on Asus WL-500W with stock firmware</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/23/tip-install-twonky-on-asus-wl-500w-with-stock-firmware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2009 06:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/23/tip-install-twonky-on-asus-wl-500w-with-stock-firmware/</guid><description>Asus WL-500W is a greate wi-fi router with lots of features, one of them being able to use it as a media server to serve movies/songs over your network from a hard disk connected directly to it through USB. But the media server that is included in the official firmware leaves a lot to be desired. If you are a fan of twonky, all you would have heard so far would have been that to use it on your router, you&amp;rsquo;d have to change your firmware over to a non-official one.</description></item><item><title>KillZone 2 Steel-Book Edition is here</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/20/killzone-2-steel-book-edition-is-here/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2009 21:47:04 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/20/killzone-2-steel-book-edition-is-here/</guid><description>Note: Please DIGG this post by clicking here or Reddit this post by clicking here.
I&amp;rsquo;ll be one of the proud owners of a very special steel book edition of Killzone 2 very soon. The cool part being that it&amp;rsquo;d be much before most of the rest of the world gets to even see these little babies because the official release date is still five days away. And the icing on the cake &amp;ldquo;A free classic Art Book&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Project: Shantz WordPress Prefix Suffix Updated to 1.1.2</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/19/project-shantz-wordpress-prefix-suffix-updated-to-112/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2009 18:30:15 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/19/project-shantz-wordpress-prefix-suffix-updated-to-112/</guid><description>My WordPress Plugin &amp;ldquo;Shantz Wordpress Prefix Suffix&amp;rdquo; has just been updated to version 1.1.2. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, this is a super-light and easy to use plugin that allows you to add any text or html/javascript/php code to your posts, be it the top of the posts, bottom of the posts or even in the middle. And you get a lot of options to control all this. I use it even on my site, to create links for my other blogs, adding copyright notices and even for advertisements (google adsense, chitika premium, etc).</description></item><item><title>Project: Shantz XWinWrap Update to 0.3</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/16/project-shantz-xwinwrap-update-to-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2009 18:30:03 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/16/project-shantz-xwinwrap-update-to-03/</guid><description>Here is another update for the fans of XWinWrap, the tiny program that allows you to run animated wallpapers on your system. You could use screensavers, movies and what not as your desktop background. This update fixes a segfault that many users were facing, a new debug option to print some debug mesages to get some info if it is not working for you and a new hack option for giving a &amp;ldquo;desktop window&amp;rdquo; name to the program.</description></item><item><title>WordCamp India Is Here</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/14/wordcamp-india/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2009 20:51:48 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/14/wordcamp-india/</guid><description>Just a little piece of news to all the bloggers, and especially WordPressers (did I just coin a new term?), out there. WordCamp is coming to India. And what&amp;rsquo;s more, Matt is going to be there. (Yes, THE Matt. Oh My, you just don&amp;rsquo;t believe me, do you. Fanboys, it is time to rejoice as I assure you this is THEMatt Mullenweg). It&amp;rsquo;s going to be held on the 21st and 22nd of this Feb at Adobe, Noida (who are the main sponsors for this event).</description></item><item><title>[TIP] Ubuntu 1 MB /tmp Partition Problem</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/10/tip-ubuntu-1-mb-tmp-partition-problem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2009 00:30:31 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/10/tip-ubuntu-1-mb-tmp-partition-problem/</guid><description>Recently someone asked me about an issue he was facing with his Ubuntu Hardy Heron installation. Many of the applications, that he regularly used, were misbehaving. e.g., he couldn&amp;rsquo;t play flash videos in firefox, downloads were failing, installation of new applications were failing, etc. Everything was giving errors of not enough disk space even though he had quite a few GBs left on his drive. A few of the error messages pointed out that there wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough space in /tmp.</description></item><item><title>[Ubuntu TIP] Solved: Totem Cannot Detect UPnP Media Server</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/31/ubuntu-tip-solved-totem-cannot-detect-upnp-media-server/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 17:46:28 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/31/ubuntu-tip-solved-totem-cannot-detect-upnp-media-server/</guid><description>First a bit of background. A UPnP media server can serve your media files (video / audio / pictures) over the network to any compatible player. Some of the most known examples of these media servers are MediaTomb, TVersity, ushare, etc. In linux, few players can play media off these servers natively, but many require a plugin / library called &amp;ldquo;coherence&amp;rdquo;. e.g. the default media players (Totem and RhythmBox) can detect and play media from media servers once you install coherence (&amp;ldquo;sudo apt-get install python-coherence&amp;rdquo;).</description></item><item><title>Tip: Commands To Find Out The Shell You Are Using</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/27/tip-commands-to-find-out-the-shell-you-are-using/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2009 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/27/tip-commands-to-find-out-the-shell-you-are-using/</guid><description>Many times you might not be sure about which shell you are currently using. Especially if you are not on your system and logging into someone else&amp;rsquo;s, or maybe ssh&amp;rsquo;ing into a remote server. Worry not, because here are few simple commands that you can use to find out which shell you are using currently.
Command (Note: This one is a bit unreliable as it might not work with non-bash shells or on redirection.</description></item><item><title>[TIP] Asus WL-500W Hacks:How To Reset Web Admin Password</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/23/tip-asus-wl-500w-hackshow-to-reset-web-admin-password/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2009 22:41:31 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/23/tip-asus-wl-500w-hackshow-to-reset-web-admin-password/</guid><description>Most of you must be knowing by now that I bought the amazing Asus WL-500W router a few days back. This router builds on the great lineage it has in its predecessors, the WL-500g, WL-500g Deluxe, WL-500gP, WL-500gP v2 etc, and shines ahead with being much more than a router, rather a complete headless linux PC. Anyways, to the point. In most routers/modems, if you forget the password to your web-administration gui (which generally resides as 192.</description></item><item><title>Slow Updates And A Small Nugget Post</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/13/slow-updates-and-a-small-nugget-post/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2009 04:47:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/01/13/slow-updates-and-a-small-nugget-post/</guid><description>Many readers of this blog have written to me for the slow updates. I apologize for the same. I’ve been swamped by loads of work for quite some time now and haven’t been able to write anything here or update any of my projects, though I have loads of new hacks and tricks that I would write once I’m free and lots in store for most of the projects as well in form of bug fixes and new features.</description></item><item><title>Contest: Free 20$ SiteGround Web Hosting Coupon</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/12/12/contest-free-20-siteground-web-hosting-coupon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2008 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/12/12/contest-free-20-siteground-web-hosting-coupon/</guid><description>I have a coupon to give away for the excellent SiteGround Web Hosting. This coupon will take off 20$ from anything you want to buy from them. If you have an existing website with them, then also you can use this to take off 20$ from your bill. So, what do you have to do? Just follow the 2 simple steps listed below, and I’ll choose one lucky winner at random to give it away.</description></item><item><title>The Solution To Your Problem Is Out There .... Somewhere</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/12/03/the-solution-to-your-problem-is-out-there-somewhere/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2008 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/12/03/the-solution-to-your-problem-is-out-there-somewhere/</guid><description>I got hold of a new Asus WL-500W router for me (Pics &amp;amp; specs coming up soon). The router has open source firmware so people can develop applications for it. One such app (ADOS) is that allows you to configure the router to download stuff directly to a hard disk (connected to router through USB) without the need of keeping the PC switched on. One of the app users reported the following error (Click on the pic to enlarge) that he got while using the app.</description></item><item><title>The Future Of Cell-Phones Is Here</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/23/the-future-of-cell-phones-is-here/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2008 21:00:59 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/23/the-future-of-cell-phones-is-here/</guid><description>My company had a video contest a few days ago (which yours-truly won by a handsome margin :) ). The topic was “Future of Wireless” as perceived by the employees but with the catch that it had to be done in just 10 seconds or less.
Now, everyone know that there is rarely a moment when I can think like a normal, sane person, and hence took a rather “alternative” look at what the future holds for us.</description></item><item><title>Call For Google Adsense Maths Class Charity Fund</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/23/call-for-google-adsense-maths-class-charity-fund/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2008 08:25:36 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/23/call-for-google-adsense-maths-class-charity-fund/</guid><description>I hereby call for setting up a charity fund so that we can donate some money to get the poor ol’ Google Adsense some Mathematics/Algebra 101 classes because apparantly it thinks that 0.63 + 0.07 = 0.69.</description></item><item><title>Project: Shantz-WP-Prefix-Suffix Updated to 1.1.0</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/20/project-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-to-110/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 04:08:17 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/20/project-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-to-110/</guid><description>Well, its not just prefix suffix any more, because I added an option to add things in the middle of the posts as well. I got this idea because people told me that this was one of the most sought after option as advertisements (e.g. google adsense, adbrite, etc) give maximum click through rate when placed smack dab in the middle of the content. What’s more is that it is configurable and you can choose how many paragraphs and/or words should be skipped from the start of the post before you add whatever you want, be it text, css, html, php or javascript.</description></item><item><title>Boycott Novell Protestors Manhandled By National Free Software Conference 2008 Organizers</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/16/boycott-novell-protestors-manhandled-by-national-free-software-conference-2008-organizers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2008 09:38:39 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/16/boycott-novell-protestors-manhandled-by-national-free-software-conference-2008-organizers/</guid><description>This is a really sad day. Not only the organizers of National Conference On Free Software 2008 taking place at CUSAT seem to be utterly misguided when they decided to let Novell be on-board as their main sponsor, they even took the extreme step of bringing in police to silence the lone voices of the Boycott Novell protestors. They seem to be treading on the toes of not just free software but free speech as well, which is against the very ethics of the conference they are holding.</description></item><item><title>A Treat For Google Lovers: Google Solutions Marketplace</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/10/a-treat-for-google-lovers-google-solutions-marketplace/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2008 14:30:22 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/10/a-treat-for-google-lovers-google-solutions-marketplace/</guid><description>Given the ignorant lazy bum I am, until a couple of days ago I was unaware of this magical place called “Google Solutions Marketplace”. According to Google:
Basically it is a boon for both, google product users who depend on various search, enterprise, search and apps related Google offerings, and developers who develop products and services based upon these. Google Solutions Marketplace acts as a bridge between the two to offer a one stop shop where you can buy (or even get for free, in many cases) the brilliant ideas that have been developed by many individuals and companies based on google’s services.</description></item><item><title>Google Adsense : Conflict of Interests?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/07/google-adsense-conflict-of-interests/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2008 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/07/google-adsense-conflict-of-interests/</guid><description>“Google Adsense” has been caught in a conflict of interests with its parent company “Google”. Google piad 140k to teh cause of “Say No to Prop 8” but on the other hand people reported that Google Adsense delivered a substantially huge amount of “Say Yes to Prop 8” advertisements all over the internet, even on sites which are completely out of context with this matter. Not only is this conflicting with the interests of the parent company but also with the “Terms of Use” put forward by Adsense that ads should not have any kind of intolerance or advocacy towards an individual or a group.</description></item><item><title>Creative Open Sources X-Fi Sound Card Driver…Finally</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/07/creative-open-sources-x-fi-sound-card-driverfinally/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2008 04:14:29 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/07/creative-open-sources-x-fi-sound-card-driverfinally/</guid><description>Creative has finally come to its senses and turned to the open source community to raise its X-Fi series of sound cards from the ashes on the linux platform, which got burnt mostly due to the poor quality of the drivers that Creative was giving out. The announcement for releasing the source code, licensed under GPL v2, was made on their forums. For the announcement and download details, click here.</description></item><item><title>Make Money Out Of Nothing: Add Google Adsense For Search To Your 404 Page</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/06/make-money-out-of-nothing-add-google-adsense-for-search-to-your-404-page/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 14:30:28 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/06/make-money-out-of-nothing-add-google-adsense-for-search-to-your-404-page/</guid><description>A 404 page is an error page that is displayed when somebody tries to go to a link on your website that doesn’t exist. This could occur when someone linking to your website or typing in his browser address bar mistypes a url, or maybe that page has been moved or deleted by you. Lost opportunity? Maybe. But definitely not, if you follow this advise. Many people don’t have a 404 page altogether, a few implement with an inane message like “Something went wrong”, a few will try to help out the seemingly lost user by giving a few navigation options linking to home page, archives or most popular posts, etc.</description></item><item><title>Save Your Adsense Account: Put Up That Privacy Policy</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/04/save-your-adsense-account-put-up-that-privacy-policy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 17:35:58 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/11/04/save-your-adsense-account-put-up-that-privacy-policy/</guid><description>Google is known to be pretty strict with making sure that all Adsense publishers remain conformant to their policies. I’m not very old in this game but had read and heard enough (about google shutting down Adsense accounts without even warning) that I made sure to read their terms and conditions thoroughly. What got my attention was the very last line in the policy:
Now why I wrote this post was that though almost every site I visit has adsense ads, but only a very miniscule fraction of them is abiding with this condition.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Has A Problem: Software Patents Go Up In Smoke</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/31/microsoft-has-a-problem-software-patents-go-up-in-smoke/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 18:35:57 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/31/microsoft-has-a-problem-software-patents-go-up-in-smoke/</guid><description>Just read over at groklaw about a ruling made last night by the US Appeals Court. According to it, the patents granted for business practices would have to undergo specific and stringent testing procedures to check the worthiness of granting a patent to it. Essentially, they are aiming to mandate a passing of &amp;ldquo;machine-or-transformation test&amp;rdquo; as a pre-requisite for granting a patent. This means that a mere &amp;ldquo;idea in my head&amp;rdquo; doesn&amp;rsquo;t qualify for a patent until it is put into practice on a machine or can transform the state of an object for a specific purpose.</description></item><item><title>Project: My WordPress Plugin Shantz-WP-Prefix-Suffix Updated To 1.0.5</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/31/project-my-wordpress-plugin-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-to-105/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 15:48:40 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/31/project-my-wordpress-plugin-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-to-105/</guid><description>For those who are new to this plugin, Shantz WP Prefix Suffix is a light-weight and easy to use plugin which allows you to add any text, HTML/CSS/PHP/Javascript code to your posts and/or pages as prefix and/or suffix. (That includes even any new or old posts and pages and even your feed) Examples of use cases could be to include your copyright message, advertisements (like adsense, etc), permalinks, your other site links, any other custom messages.</description></item><item><title>Project: ShantzTodayChanger Is Now Open Source’d</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/30/project-shantztodaychanger-is-now-open-sourced/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2008 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/30/project-shantztodaychanger-is-now-open-sourced/</guid><description>For those who don’t know ShantzTodayChanger is a small Windows Mobile tool that allows you to cycle through your wallpapers/themes or run applications after specified intervals of time automatically and provides you a lot of tweaking options to control this.
Sometime back I formatted my laptop which I dual booted between Windows XP and Linux (Ubuntu, if you may ask). Now I installed Hardy Heron back onto thenew system within an hour but just can’t get myself motivated to “finish” the Windows install by getting and installing all the drivers after having to sit through hours pointing, clicking and rebooting to get just the base installed.</description></item><item><title>A Friend In Need Is A Good Webhost Indeed</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/27/a-friend-in-need-is-a-good-webhost-indeed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2008 10:45:09 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/27/a-friend-in-need-is-a-good-webhost-indeed/</guid><description>A webhost that puts building relationships with customers before making money is definitely a good webhost. And this works out to be good for you as well as the webhost in the end. Now, why am I saying this all which should be part of a “Doing Business 101” course. Because, in this world of unprofessional webhosting, where people lure you with fool’s gold, promising everything unlimited and cutting you off with even the slightest of deviation from their “AUP” mumbo jumbo, there still exist good webhosts which promise you very little but are good enough to deliver on them and then some more.</description></item><item><title>Kill Lotus Notes And Restart Without Rebooting</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/23/kill-lotus-notes-and-restart-without-rebooting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2008 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/23/kill-lotus-notes-and-restart-without-rebooting/</guid><description>A friend called me today and happened to mention his biggest gripe about Lotus Notes, that it hangs ever so often (ok that’s acceptable), but the clincher is that if you kill it through the task manager it will not allow you to restart and relogin until you reboot your PC. Now, that is a serious problem and a hit to productivity. But the omniscient angel I am, I had the solution ready (because till a couple of years ago, I was also haunted by this very issue every day).</description></item><item><title>Google Releases Android Source Code</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/21/google-releases-android-source-code/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2008 17:57:52 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/21/google-releases-android-source-code/</guid><description>FOSS (Free and Open Source Software) community rejoices today as google finally lived upto their promise of releasing the android source code. Now, the things that is left to be evaluated is that how much of it is actually true, or whether there are some binary blobs still in there. Moreover, it remains to be seen that how much this converts into a “community” project instead of being ruled by Google with an iron hand.</description></item><item><title>Android Devices Trickling In A Few Days Early?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/20/android-devices-trickling-in-a-few-days-early/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2008 19:32:35 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/20/android-devices-trickling-in-a-few-days-early/</guid><description>There is still a day left for the first Android based Device, T-Mobile G1, to come out into the hands of general public but I was in a for a small surprise as I went through my Google Analytics report for the last week. It had a mysterious number of 2 sitting at the bottom of my “Unique Visitors by Operating Systems” filter report. The “mysterious” part coming from the fact that the left most column displayed “Android”.</description></item><item><title>Project: Shantz-XwinWrap Updated to 0.02</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/18/project-shantz-xwinwrap-updated-to-002/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2008 11:03:48 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/18/project-shantz-xwinwrap-updated-to-002/</guid><description>As some of you know that I&amp;rsquo;ve taken up the development of the ultra-cool xwinwrap tool that allows you to use movies, screensavers etc as wallpapers for you linux desktops. Here is version 0.02 for you consumption that fixes a bug because of which the generated window was overlapping other windows.
The download file has plain executable binaries as well as deb packages for Ubuntu. Moreover, I&amp;rsquo;ve included both 32 bit as well as 64 bit versions.</description></item><item><title>Project: My WordPress Plugin "Shantz WP Prefix Suffix" Updated to 1.0.4</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/15/project-my-wordpress-plugin-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-to-104/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2008 12:48:42 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/15/project-my-wordpress-plugin-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-to-104/</guid><description>For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know Shantz-WP-Prefix-Suffix is a WordPress plugin that allows you to add any text and/or HTML/CSS/PHP/Javascript code to the top or bottom of your posts (e.g. see my site links at top of each post and the copyright link and permalink at the bottom of each) I&amp;rsquo;ve updated it to version 1.0.4 which allows you to add PHP code to the top or bottom of your posts now.</description></item><item><title>Satellite TV (DTH) In India: A Guide</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/09/satellite-tv-dth-in-india-a-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2008 17:57:57 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/09/satellite-tv-dth-in-india-a-guide/</guid><description>Amit has written a detailed Satellite TV (DTH) Guide and Comparison about the scene in India. He compares the various players that are operating right now and gives suggestions on what should one look at while choosing out of all the available operators. If you are confused about what the advent of all these different names like Tata Sky (Tata), Big TV (Reliance) and Airtel Digital TV (Bharti) means for you, then do take a look at it.</description></item><item><title>TIP: Free Downloads For Windows Vista, XP Professional, Visual Studio 2008, MSDN And Much More</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/08/tip-free-downloads-for-windows-vista-xp-professional-visual-studio-2008-msdn-and-much-more/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2008 19:31:52 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/08/tip-free-downloads-for-windows-vista-xp-professional-visual-studio-2008-msdn-and-much-more/</guid><description>If you are a student (this works for non-students as well but I expect you to be honest ;) ), you can download a whole bunch of software for free. How? Well, all you need is to become an ACM student member, and join the MSDN AA (Microsoft Developer Network Academic Alliance) ACM Student Benefit Program.
Normally it takes around 19$ for you to become a student member but you can do it for free for a limited time by going to http://campus.</description></item><item><title>Check Out T-Mobile G1/HTC Dream/Android Emulator Online</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/04/check-out-t-mobile-g1htc-dreamandroid-emulator-online/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2008 22:51:27 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/04/check-out-t-mobile-g1htc-dreamandroid-emulator-online/</guid><description>Just came across this very cool online emulator that lets you get a first hand experience of how the Google Android based phone T-Mobile G1 (aka HTC Dream) will look and behave like. The sliding notification mechanisms look cool, few of the things aren&amp;rsquo;t working but still a good thing to check out. However, I don&amp;rsquo;t know if this is an official site by T-Mobile or not.
Linky: http://tmobile.modeaondemand.com/htc/g1/</description></item><item><title>Project: Shantz Pidgin Away Alerts (splert) Updated to 0.03</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/03/project-shantz-pidgin-away-alerts-splert-updated-to-003/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 21:19:08 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/03/project-shantz-pidgin-away-alerts-splert-updated-to-003/</guid><description>I updated my project splert to version 0.03 today.For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know splert is a tool that lets you convert the multi-client instant messenger pidgin (connects to gtalk, msn, yahoo, jabber, etc) into a full blown answering machine and much more.
The main changes are:
Now you can use other 3rd party twitter bots with it to get updates through twitter since the official twitter bot is down since a long time and there are no chances of coming back soon.</description></item><item><title>TIP: A Post For Pidgin Plugin Developers</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/23/tip-a-post-for-pidgin-plugin-developers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 15:30:32 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/23/tip-a-post-for-pidgin-plugin-developers/</guid><description>Recently I wrote a small autoreply-answering-machine app for pidgin with a simple premise. Send custom automatic replies to different people when they message you and came across a strange bug. It never sent the reply when you received the first message from someone. I was using the &amp;ldquo;ReceivedImMessage&amp;rdquo; signal over d-bus (or &amp;ldquo;received-im-message&amp;rdquo; for the plugin writers). What I found initially looked to be a gross and basic error by pidgin developers, but later found that it is indeed a good design and thought that I&amp;rsquo;ll make a post about it for the benefit of fellow pidgin plugin/app developers.</description></item><item><title>Dropbox Online Storage Public/Shared Folders: A Word Of Caution</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/16/dropbox-online-storage-publicshared-folders-a-word-of-caution/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 14:26:50 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/16/dropbox-online-storage-publicshared-folders-a-word-of-caution/</guid><description>Update: In a thread about this post at Dropbox forums, it was brought to my notice that Dropbox has now changed its terms to remove the objectionable clause.
If you use dropbox (A popular online storage service with free 2 GB space), and use (or intend to use) its public or shared folders feature, then you must know something about the EULA (End Users' LIcense Agreement). Yes, the one that you clicked &amp;ldquo;I Agree&amp;rdquo; on, without even reading one word of.</description></item><item><title>SpiderOak Promotion Code For Free Upgrade To 10 GB</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/12/spideroak-promotion-code-for-free-upgrade-to-10-gb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2008 20:58:32 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/12/spideroak-promotion-code-for-free-upgrade-to-10-gb/</guid><description>Just a small shout out to let you guys know that you can use the discount coupon code “linkup” while signing up the excellent online backup service SpiderOak to get a major bump to 10 GB from the 2 GB that they give to normal accounts.
For those who don’t know SpiderOak is a great online data backup service, with its major strengths being truly cross paltform (Mac/Linux/Windows – 32 bit as well as 64 bit), easy interface, rsync like differential backups to save time and disk space, versioned file history, web as well as client interface, unlimited number of devices, unlimited bandwidth, etc etc.</description></item><item><title>Firefox Incognito / Private Browsing Mode - Part II</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/11/firefox-incognito-private-browsing-mode-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2008 16:59:33 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/11/firefox-incognito-private-browsing-mode-part-ii/</guid><description>A few people (e.g. Varun) told me my previous post differed from the way how google chrome / Microsoft IE8 handle Incognito (Private Browsing) mode. The main consideration was that while chrome/IE8 don&amp;rsquo;t write anything to disk at all, the firefox method is an after-effect, i.e., writing to disk and then clearing it up while closing the window. Well, true but nothing is non-rectificable :). So this is a post about a method that one can use to go &amp;ldquo;really&amp;rdquo; undercover with firefox.</description></item><item><title>Firefox Incognito Mode Is Here: Move Over Chrome/IE8</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/10/firefox-incognito-mode-is-here-move-over-chromeie8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2008 17:49:41 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/10/firefox-incognito-mode-is-here-move-over-chromeie8/</guid><description>Update: Part 2 of this post is now up here to allay some of the drawbacks that were pointed out.
There has been so much hype over the “Incognito” (or Private Browsing) mode of Google Chrome / Microsoft IE8, with many internet users screeming Hallelujiah. But I don’t understand what the hoopla is all about. This mode has always been there in Mozilla firefox as well. You just need to devote less than one minute (yes, you read that right, less than one minute) to set it up.</description></item><item><title>Hack: Pidgin-Gtalk Connection Problems - Get Around The Corporate Firewall</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/08/hack-pidgin-gtalk-connection-problems-get-around-the-corporate-firewall/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 15:30:38 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/08/hack-pidgin-gtalk-connection-problems-get-around-the-corporate-firewall/</guid><description>I recently wrote a simple answering machine program/plugin for pidgin and someone asked me to port it to 32 bit. So I fired up pidgin within my virtual box installation at work (as I have only a 64 bit machine at home) but couldn&amp;rsquo;t get it to connect. Tried all sorts of methods found over the net of changing ports etc, set port forwarding in Virtual Box NAT, even switched to using a bridged host interface but still no go.</description></item><item><title>Apology For Bad Downloads</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/05/apology-for-bad-downloads/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 16:13:19 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/05/apology-for-bad-downloads/</guid><description>Guys, for the past few days if you downloaded any &amp;ldquo;.tar.gz&amp;rdquo; packages from this site (like my splert or shantz-xwinwrap tools), then you&amp;rsquo;d have got a corrupt package. Turns out there was some issue with mime-types with my setup. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to resolve it still but have re-upped the packages in &amp;ldquo;zip&amp;rdquo; format. Please download them again. I apologize for the inconvenience.</description></item><item><title>Shantz XWinWrap: The "Moving" Wallpaper Fun Continues</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/03/shantz-xwinwrap-the-moving-wallpaper-fun-continues/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 14:46:02 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/03/shantz-xwinwrap-the-moving-wallpaper-fun-continues/</guid><description>XWinWrap is a small utility written a loooong time ago that allowed you to stick most of the apps to your desktop background (Thanks to fsckin for introducing me to it). What this meant was you could use an animated screensaver (like glmatrix, electric sheep, etc) or even a movie, and use it as your wallpaper. But only one version of this app was released, and it had a few problems, like it wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly &amp;ldquo;sticking&amp;rdquo; to the background and geometry option didn&amp;rsquo;t work as well.</description></item><item><title>Shantz XWinWrap</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/03/shantz-xwinwrap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 14:41:44 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/09/03/shantz-xwinwrap/</guid><description>XWinWrap is a small utility written a loooong time ago that allowed you to stick most of the apps to your desktop background. What this meant was you could use an animated screensaver (like glmatrix, electric sheep, etc) or even a movie, and use it as your wallpaper. But only one version of this app was ever released, and it had a few problems, like:
Well, sticking didn&amp;rsquo;t work.</description></item><item><title>Do They Really Know How To Sell Something In India?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/26/do-they-really-know-how-to-sell-something-in-india/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 14:45:46 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/26/do-they-really-know-how-to-sell-something-in-india/</guid><description>Update: UK Ad Authorities have declared iPhone ad as &amp;ldquo;misleading&amp;rdquo;. I guess then they should declare it plain fraud in India.
This is a short rant about two of the &amp;ldquo;big&amp;rdquo; products launched recently in India in the last one week and how the people behind their sales/marketing teams either try to take the Indian customer for a ride, or shaft themselves.
iPhone: The big icon. Bharti Airtel/Vodafone claimed lakhs of pre-registrations, yet no one lined up to buy it.</description></item><item><title>Project: Splert - A Custom Answering Machine And More for IMs</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/18/project-splert-a-custom-answering-machine-and-more-for-ims/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 17:00:09 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/18/project-splert-a-custom-answering-machine-and-more-for-ims/</guid><description>Update Aug 25 2008: Updated to v0.02 and also added 32 bit package. Hit the link given below to download.
You must have heard of (or used) the auto-reply features given by today&amp;rsquo;s instant messengers that are sent to the ones messaging you while you are not at your desk. But those are one-size-fits-all kind of messages. So, I wrote this simple tool a few months ago to turn Pidgin, everyone’s favourite multi-client Instant Messenger (works with gtalk, msn, yahoo, aim etc), into a customized answering machine (and more) when you are away from your computer.</description></item><item><title>Splert: Shantz Pidgin Away Alerts</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/18/splert-shantz-pidgin-away-alerts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 16:55:03 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/18/splert-shantz-pidgin-away-alerts/</guid><description>This is a simple tool I wrote a few months ago to turn Pidgin, everyone’s favourite multi-client Instant Messenger (works with gtalk, msn, yahoo, aim etc), into a customized answering machine (and more) when you are away from your computer. Basically it allows you to divide up your contact list into groups based on email IDs and execute actions based on when someone from a particular group messages you while you are away.</description></item><item><title>Project: Shantz Webcam Autolocker</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/11/project-shantz-webcam-autolocker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2008 17:51:31 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/11/project-shantz-webcam-autolocker/</guid><description>Sometimes I do some things that even I can&amp;rsquo;t explain why I did &amp;lsquo;em. Did this one in one of those times as well. This is a simple script to monitor motion in front of your PC, auto-lock it when you are away and auto-unlock it when you come back. Did it just because I was really bogged down by the shitload of work that I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing for the past few weeks (and even weekends as well), so wanted to take a break for a few minutes, and just chanced over my own &amp;ldquo;Home Security Using a Webcam and Twitter&amp;rdquo; post, so thought of doing something related to motion detection again.</description></item><item><title>Shantz Webcam Autolocker</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/11/shantz-webcam-autolocker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2008 17:50:54 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/11/shantz-webcam-autolocker/</guid><description>Sometimes I do some things that even I can&amp;rsquo;t explain why I did &amp;lsquo;em. Did this one in one of those times as well. This is a simple (and useless) script to monitor motion in front of your PC, auto-lock it when you are away and auto-unlock it when you come back. Kinda useless cuz there is no security aspect (read face detection etc) and any kind of motion triggers the unlock.</description></item><item><title>Fixing The WordPress Drain Hole Pugin v2.1.3</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/10/fixing-the-wordpress-drain-hole-pugin-v213/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2008 17:36:27 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/10/fixing-the-wordpress-drain-hole-pugin-v213/</guid><description>If you use the awesome download manager plugin &amp;ldquo;Drain Hole&amp;rdquo; for your WordPress blog (A short review here), and upgraded to the latest version 2.1.3, you must have noticed that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t scan and add new files to the download repositories now. Well, this is a quick and short post to tell you how to fix it in less than a minute.
Steps:
Go to your wordpress folder and then navigate to wp-content/plugins/drain-hole/models.</description></item><item><title>Hi BIOS! My Name Is "Linux", Or Is It?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/03/hi-bios-my-name-is-linux-or-is-it/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2008 17:44:30 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/03/hi-bios-my-name-is-linux-or-is-it/</guid><description>A couple of days ago, I read this on Matthew Garrette’s blog, where he tells us about a vendor’s BIOS trying to figure out the OS type/version and setting things around on deciding the OS it is running. The call in question was _OSI(“Linux”). He goes on to say that the action the firmware takes, on finding out if the OS is linux, was probably inaccurate and it was good that linux kernel DOES NOT identify itself as “Linux” and returns false for the _OSI(“Linux”) and instead returns true when probed for Windows.</description></item><item><title>Site Updates</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/29/site-updates-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 18:16:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/29/site-updates-2/</guid><description>Just wanted to apologize to you guys for not updating this blog frequently as work load is becoming more and more these days. But I&amp;rsquo;ll try my best to update as often as possible. There are a couple of useful apps that I wrote some time ago but havent found time to add all the features that I wanted and to roll them out, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll release them with the current feature set.</description></item><item><title>A Breath Of Fresh Air: My New Ubuntu Desktop</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/21/a-breath-of-fresh-air-my-new-ubuntu-desktop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2008 18:54:53 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/21/a-breath-of-fresh-air-my-new-ubuntu-desktop/</guid><description>**UPDATE: **Surprisingly this post has found favour with “digg”ers :). Check the bottom of the post for some more info about the setup
UPDATE2: On popular demand, I&amp;rsquo;ve uploaded my .conkyrc. Download Conky Configuration file by clicking here and save as .conkyrc in your home folder.
After loitering around for so long, I finally got my lazy bum off the bed and installed Hardy Heron (8.04.1) onto my aging laptop. I’ve never been a sucker for eye-candy stuff, prefering to have more resources available for real work, instead of ooh-aahing over nice looking things all around my desktop.</description></item><item><title>"The Square Root of 3" - Kumar Does It Again</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/17/the-square-root-of-3-kumar-does-it-again/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2008 15:33:46 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/17/the-square-root-of-3-kumar-does-it-again/</guid><description>I watched &amp;ldquo;Harold and Kumar: Escape from Guantanamo Bay&amp;rdquo; a few days ago. Cool movie, though not as awesome as &amp;ldquo;Go to White Castle&amp;rdquo; one. But one thing that I liked was the poem that Kumar (Kal Penn) recites in an attempt to woo back her love by embarrassing himself more than he had embarrassed her (Yes, you can see such situations only in H&amp;amp;K movies ;) ). The poem is actually written by one &amp;ldquo;David Feinberg&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>A New Resource For Reverse Engineering (and more)...</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/14/a-new-resource-for-reverse-engineering-and-more/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 14:18:32 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/14/a-new-resource-for-reverse-engineering-and-more/</guid><description>My brother “Amit Goel” has started a tech blog, primarily about Reverse Engineering nuances, but he plans to write much more. Pay him a visit at Amit’s Lab and let him know what topics you want him to discuss about.</description></item><item><title>The Biggest Flaw in Gnome UI</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/07/the-biggest-flaw-in-gnome-ui/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2008 14:28:02 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/07/07/the-biggest-flaw-in-gnome-ui/</guid><description>Everywhere you go, any building you enter, any OS you operate, any settings window you open, one rule remains set in stone, “THE ESCAPE DOOR”. Always give an exit path, a way to make it all go away, make it look like nothing happened. But Gnome seems to think otherwise. Any settings window you open, all you see is a “close” button.
I made a few changes and then tried to “undo” them by using the following methods:</description></item><item><title>My Brief History With Computers</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/06/23/my-brief-history-with-computers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2008 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/06/23/my-brief-history-with-computers/</guid><description>I’m going to be bespectacled and have been advised to reduce and limit my computer usage considerably. A bit of nostalgia set in on hearing this and I thought about my short journey so far in this wonderland of solid-state and otherwise.
**First time I touched a computer. 1989, at school in 2nd standard
**First command I typed on a computer. “dir”, 1990, 3rd standard
**First game I played on a computer.</description></item><item><title>More iPhone 3G Nonsense Uncovered: No Tethering</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/06/14/more-iphone-3g-nonsense-uncovered-no-tethering/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2008 15:57:50 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/06/14/more-iphone-3g-nonsense-uncovered-no-tethering/</guid><description>iPhone 3G, the “supposedly” latest and greatest handhled, just continues to amaze me, with its ridiculousness of course. I mean first they dare to call a machine a smartphone that can’t run more than one app a time, need you to send the unit back even for a battery change, fix the glaring mistakes of its predecessor and call them “features” and make you believe that you are getting it all for cheap while covertly telling you that you need a minimum of 2 year 70$ contract to get it and need to pay through every hole for even software updates.</description></item><item><title>Tip: Gadgets, Deals And Stuff You Need To Know - Part III</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/06/10/tip-gadgets-deals-and-stuff-you-need-to-know-part-iii/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2008 13:05:35 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/06/10/tip-gadgets-deals-and-stuff-you-need-to-know-part-iii/</guid><description>This is the last part in this series. So far we’ve seen how to select the gadget and how to get the best price for it. This time we’ll fill in the last remaining piece of the puzzle, the minor tit-bits that go a long way in preventing a lot of heart-burn. Don’t worry this is a short one.
This last piece is to make sure that the place that you decided upon to buy your gadget, is OK in all respects, i.</description></item><item><title>Tip: Gadgets, Deals And Stuff You Need To Know - Part II</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/06/04/tip-gadgets-deals-and-stuff-you-need-to-know-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2008 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/06/04/tip-gadgets-deals-and-stuff-you-need-to-know-part-ii/</guid><description>Last time we discussed how to select the gadget that you want to buy. This time I’ll tell you some of the things that I do to find the best price for it.
Use Price Comparison Engines: These engines will let you search for your desired products and provide a comparison of the costs at which they are available at different stores online as well as offline. Two of my favourites are Price Grabber and Froogle.</description></item><item><title>Tip: Gadgets, Deals And Stuff You Need To Know - Part I</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/06/02/tip-gadgets-deals-and-stuff-you-need-to-know-part-i/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2008 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/06/02/tip-gadgets-deals-and-stuff-you-need-to-know-part-i/</guid><description>If you are a gadget freak like me and can’t resist the temptations to buy the newest toy on the shelves, then you’d obviously want to eek out the maximum you can from whatever budget you have. But while doing so you have to take care of a lot of things. Here is Part I of the few things that I do get the best deals out there while making sure I’m buying the right thing from the right place.</description></item><item><title>Google's New Favicon</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/30/googles-new-favicon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2008 19:16:21 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/30/googles-new-favicon/</guid><description>It’s amazing, isn’t it? Even a sneeze at google makes the headlines. Well, it’s not the sneeze today but the new favicon I just got. So, are you also seeing the all new, re-designed, artisticly polished “g” as the new favicon?
In other news, my Twitter-Webcam integration post has bypassed my earlier lifehacked post about Remote File Access Through E-mail by more than a few thousands, even though the time difference between the two posts is more than 3 months.</description></item><item><title>My Top 5 Comics For The Geeks</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/26/my-top-5-comics-for-the-geeks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2008 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/26/my-top-5-comics-for-the-geeks/</guid><description>If you think that all geeks do is walk around wearing thick glasses, code in unreadable languages and make weird gizmos from parts scrapped out of your junkyard, well you think wrong. We do like to have our share of fun. And what better to begin the day with a nice hot cuppa along with some geeky humour. Folks, here it is, the 5 comic strips that I love the most (in no particular order):</description></item><item><title>TIP: Viewing Any PDF Online, Without A PDF Reader And For Free</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/23/tip-viewing-any-pdf-online-without-a-pdf-reader-and-for-free/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2008 21:42:54 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/23/tip-viewing-any-pdf-online-without-a-pdf-reader-and-for-free/</guid><description>Just a small tip. If you want to view a pdf and you don’t have adobe acrobat (or any other pdf reader) installed, e.g., you are sitting in a cyber cage or at a friend’s place, you can still view it. Only thing you have to do is, just prefix the url to the online pdf with &amp;ldquo;http://www.scribd.com/vacuum?url=&amp;rdquo; and you’ll see a nice web interface rendering your pdf without having to install anything on your PC.</description></item><item><title>Ubuntu: What exactly does LTS mean?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/20/ubuntu-what-exactly-does-lts-mean/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 21:29:10 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/20/ubuntu-what-exactly-does-lts-mean/</guid><description>With the recent release of Ubuntu 8.04 (Hardy Heron), a lot of hype was generated (Overhype or well-deserved, that’s for another post). One of the main highlights of all the stories, news and reviews doing the rounds are that this is an LTS version. But many people, mostly those who are new to Ubuntu, and even a few who are already using it, are not sure what LTS really means.</description></item><item><title>Fill Your Password To Invite Your Buddies - Not So Fast!!</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/16/fill-your-password-to-invite-your-buddies-not-so-fast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2008 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/16/fill-your-password-to-invite-your-buddies-not-so-fast/</guid><description>For the past many years, I’ve seen a trend that has been on a meteoric rise. Whatever new service you sign on for on the internet (especially the web2.0–oh-so-cool-you-have-to-tell-everyone-about-it ones), it gives you an option to fill in your e-mail ID and password and makes a generous offer of letting all your friends know about your new avatar and let them all join in the fun. Most of the people around me, it seems, don’t think twice before gladly accepting the offer, as is made apparent from the increasing amount of automated mails I’m getting with subjects like “Hey, don’t be left out!</description></item><item><title>Keep Tab On Home Security With A Webcam And Twitter</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/14/keep-tab-on-home-security-with-a-webcam-and-twitter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2008 04:00:13 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/14/keep-tab-on-home-security-with-a-webcam-and-twitter/</guid><description>Worried about someone breaking into your house in your absence? Or just need to keep a tab on who enters your room while you are away? Well, all you need is a webcam, a linux PC/laptop and a twitter account. And you are set for real time updates through twitter about all that goes on at your abode behind your back (can even receive a text message/sms on your phone). Keep reading for the very simple setup you need.</description></item><item><title>Fun With Webcam In Linux</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/12/fun-with-webcam-in-linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2008 03:57:47 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/12/fun-with-webcam-in-linux/</guid><description>Did you know that instead of installing special software to view your webcam video, you can simply use mplayer for the same purpose, and with a lot of fine control. e.g. try running the following command with your webcam attached to your computer.
And you can use mencoder to capture and encode video from your webcam:
mencoder tv:// -tv driver=v4l2:width=60:height=40:fps=60:device=/dev/video0 -nosound -ovc lavc -lavcopts vcodec=mjpeg -o test.avi Have fun playing with the huge number of options available.</description></item><item><title>Tip: Getting Your Webcam To Work In Ubuntu</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/10/tip-getting-your-webcam-to-work-in-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2008 19:17:42 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/10/tip-getting-your-webcam-to-work-in-ubuntu/</guid><description>I have an old noname cheapo webcam, that I dusted out of my junk (why? More on that in a post coming soon). I hoped that it would work in my Ubuntu setup out of the box like most of my other hardware. I connected it to my laptop&amp;rsquo;s usb port. dmesg gave the following output:
[21328.211333] usb 1-1: new full speed USB device using ohci_hcd and address 2 [21328.319698] usb 1-1: configuration #1 chosen from 1 choice [21328.</description></item><item><title>The Elusive Super Phone</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/08/the-elusive-super-phone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2008 17:15:28 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/08/the-elusive-super-phone/</guid><description>HTC announce their shiny new Touch Diamond recently. Everyone ooh&amp;rsquo;ed and aah&amp;rsquo;ed while ogling at it until they realized that HTC has taken a step back (or forward towards matching Apple&amp;rsquo;s iPhone crap) by removing the expansion card slot from the phone. Yes, it has 4 GB of internal storage but I&amp;rsquo;d rather have an SDHC card slot with the ever falling prices of solid state memory (an 8 GB Class 6 SDHC card is worth not more than around 60$ these days).</description></item><item><title>Want To Program Smartly In C? Use GLib</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/03/smart-programming-in-c-using-glib/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2008 15:30:16 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/03/smart-programming-in-c-using-glib/</guid><description>GLib - An Introduction:
GLib is a utility library for C, which augments the standard C library in several purposeful ways to make your life that much easier while programming. GLib has the following things to offer you:
**1. Portability: **The main issue that haunts any C developer is the portability of code. One cannot rely on the standard C library for this as you may find many functions that work differently under different platforms are aren&amp;rsquo;t there at all sometimes.</description></item><item><title>Http 406 Errors Galore</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/01/http-406-errors-galore/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 15:30:05 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/01/http-406-errors-galore/</guid><description>If you have ever had these errors or just want to be prepared in case they pop up somtime (and they surely will), then read on as I discuss various situations that lead to them and also their solutions.
I generally use desktop clients (mostly blogjet, but also Windows Live Writer and Scribe Fire sometimes) to blog to my WordPress based blogs. Some months ago, I started getting &amp;ldquo;Http 406: Not Acceptable&amp;rdquo; error while posting a particular post.</description></item><item><title>Page Rank 7: True Or Google Glitch?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/30/page-rank-7-true-or-google-glitch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2008 20:33:51 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/30/page-rank-7-true-or-google-glitch/</guid><description>I installed google toolbar (linux version) today in firefox and for this blog, it says that its page rank is 7. I can&amp;rsquo;t believe my eyes. I suppose it&amp;rsquo;s a google glitch may be (but have a wishful thinking at the back of mind that its true :-) ).
Are you getting the same result for this blog (or weird page rank results for other places that you frequent?)</description></item><item><title>Windows App Alternatives For Linux: MSPaint</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/28/windows-app-alternatives-for-linux-mspaint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2008 15:30:44 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/28/windows-app-alternatives-for-linux-mspaint/</guid><description>Some of you might know that I was in the hunt for a decent mspaint alternative recently. Note that I didn&amp;rsquo;t go for GIMP / Inkscape etc because they were overkill for what I wanted to do. Many a times, I just wanted to touch up a screenshot or make a simple flow image by drawing a few boxes, use a few pointing arrows, and add some text here and there.</description></item><item><title>ImageMagick: Weaving Magic With Your Pictures</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/26/imagemagick-weaving-magic-with-your-pictures/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2008 06:23:18 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/26/imagemagick-weaving-magic-with-your-pictures/</guid><description>I’ve known about ImageMagick tools for quite some time now but never dabbled with it. A couple of weeks ago I played with it for some time (notice the new cascaded polaroid pics header above) and was amazed even more. Few of its shining features:
It has almost unlimited features to manipulate your images through its tools like convert, montage, mogrify etc and their long list of options.</description></item><item><title>5 Reasons I Like Linux (And 5 Why I Dislike It)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/19/5-reasons-i-like-linux-and-5-why-i-dislike-it/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2008 20:20:40 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/19/5-reasons-i-like-linux-and-5-why-i-dislike-it/</guid><description>Disclaimer Notes:
I wrote this because these things just came into my mind today while I was reading about the impending “Hardy Heron” release related things and saw that there is a lot of FUD being spread still. So, thought of jotting down my likes/dislikes and not making it a linux v/s windows campaign. Though at a few places, it might be necessary to compare the two just to put things into perspective.</description></item><item><title>Hack:Disabling the Message Box In Oxios Memory Apps (Windows Mobile)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/15/hackdisabling-the-message-box-in-oxios-memory-apps-windows-mobile/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2008 08:43:29 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/15/hackdisabling-the-message-box-in-oxios-memory-apps-windows-mobile/</guid><description>**Update: **Modified the &amp;ldquo;Oxios Hibernate&amp;rdquo; app as well on public demand. Please redownload the below mentioned package. It now has Oxios Close as well as Oxios Hibernate.
Oxios developed a very useful tool for Windows Mobile (WM2003/5/6/6.1) called &amp;ldquo;Oxios Memory&amp;rdquo; sometime ago. On running it, it&amp;rsquo;ll flush your RAM (kind of) and recover substantial amounts of memory that can be used by the currently program. It is so good at this that many people run it regularly on their phones, and most of them want to run it in an automated mode (through a scheduler or a script).</description></item><item><title>Gmail Blocking Messages to Yahoo Groups?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/13/gmail-blocking-messages-to-yahoo-groups/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2008 16:58:36 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/13/gmail-blocking-messages-to-yahoo-groups/</guid><description>For the past couple of days I have been unable to send any mails to any of my yahoo groups through my gmail account. All my message are returned back with a &amp;ldquo;Message Rejected&amp;rdquo; failure. What I get back is a link to this support answer: Sector 5 Bounces. Anyone else seen this?</description></item><item><title>An Idea Is All You Need</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/12/an-idea-is-all-you-need-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2008 15:43:32 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/12/an-idea-is-all-you-need-2/</guid><description>Everyone wants to make a name for himself. Everyone wants to do something new and extra-ordinary. People like me (read software engineers) want to develop &amp;ldquo;something&amp;rdquo; cool. BUT, the stage where most of them go wrong is the very first one. Most of them think that the road to develop something cool starts from a particular &amp;ldquo;language&amp;rdquo; or a tool. But I beg to differ. I say the first stage is &amp;ldquo;The Idea&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Project: My WordPress Plugin shantz-wp-qotd updated to version 1.2.2</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/10/project-my-wordpress-plugin-shantz-wp-qotd-updated-to-version-122/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2008 20:33:41 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/10/project-my-wordpress-plugin-shantz-wp-qotd-updated-to-version-122/</guid><description>Updated my WordPress plugin shantz-wp-qotd to version 1.2.2 today.
Introduction: Shantz WP QOTD is a plugin to add quotes to your wordpress blog in a few easy clicks. It adds quotes to your posts and your sidebars with a multitude of options for sources and customization.
Changelog:
Version 1.2.2
Fixed a bug because of which quotes were blank some times. Thanks to Thom for reporting it.</description></item><item><title>The Why Behind "Open Source": In simple Terms</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/08/the-why-behind-open-source-in-simple-terms/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2008 14:40:43 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/08/the-why-behind-open-source-in-simple-terms/</guid><description>Many people ask me why are people crazy about Open Source, or why does it even exist. After all if your code is out there, you can&amp;rsquo;t make money off it, right? Well, yes and no. Now, I ain&amp;rsquo;t no open source guru, but I do my part for it. Generally my explanations are either too complex, too full of extra details or mostly just described badly for a layman that I end up on square one, i.</description></item><item><title>Migrating From PHP4 To PHP5: Solving WP-Cache (and maybe other) Issues</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/07/migrating-from-php4-to-php5-solving-wp-cache-and-maybe-other-issues/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2008 13:37:17 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/07/migrating-from-php4-to-php5-solving-wp-cache-and-maybe-other-issues/</guid><description>Situation: You are migrating your WordPress blog from PHP4 to PHP5 (intentionally or being forced to as you web host won&amp;rsquo;t support PHP4 anymore). Most of the times, this is as simple as adding some simple lines to .htaccess (e.g. AddHandler application/x-httpd-php5 .php ). And you might not notice any issues. But many of you still do. The issues range from weird page layouts, to some controls not working, to some errors popping up here and there, and probably your blog not even displaying.</description></item><item><title>Project: shantz-wp-prefix-suffix Updated to 1.0.2</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/07/project-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-to-102/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2008 03:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/07/project-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-to-102/</guid><description>Many users reported errors while activating the version 1.0.1 of my WordPress plugin shantz-wp-prefix-suffix. I tracked it down to a typo that crept into the release somehow.</description></item><item><title>Twittering Away With Delhi Bloggers</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/06/twittering-away-with-delhi-bloggers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2008 14:57:24 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/06/twittering-away-with-delhi-bloggers/</guid><description>If you are twittering kinds, doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter online or offline
If you blog or are interested in all things blog and blogging
If you live in Delhi, have lived there, have been there, or just connect with Delhi somehow else
If you want to meet up with your fellow twitterers and bloggers
Then you&amp;rsquo;ve got to be a part of the your very own City of The People With Hearts, Delhi.</description></item><item><title>Hack: Fixing The WordPress i3theme Sidebar Issue (Part II)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/06/hack-fixing-the-wordpress-i3theme-sidebar-issue-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2008 14:20:25 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/06/hack-fixing-the-wordpress-i3theme-sidebar-issue-part-ii/</guid><description>Some time back I had posted a little hack to fix an issue that users of i3theme have, i.e., their right sidebar drops to below the main content area in IE6. But it wasn&amp;rsquo;t that good as it took care of only the situation when this phenomena was caused by the tag cloud widget. So, here is a little modification I did to fix the issue more properly.
Go to your wp-content/themes/folder and open the style.</description></item><item><title>Download pidgin 2.4.1 For Ubuntu Feisty Fawn (amd64/x86_64)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/04/download-pidgin-241-for-ubuntu-feisty-fawn-amd64x86_64/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2008 17:19:02 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/04/download-pidgin-241-for-ubuntu-feisty-fawn-amd64x86_64/</guid><description>pidgin is everybody&amp;rsquo;s favourite IM client. Lifehacker includes it in its list of top 5 IM clients. Obviously I use it too, but one drawback of being lazy and not switching over to Gutsy Gibbon was that I was stuck with version 2.2.0 for a long time. But recently I began a new journey towards d-bus programming and chose pidgin as my companion. Found out that 2.2.0 has some serious d-bus issues on amd64 that were fixed in 2.</description></item><item><title>Wanted: A Good Paint Program For Linux</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/03/wanted-a-good-paint-program-for-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2008 12:47:23 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/03/wanted-a-good-paint-program-for-linux/</guid><description>Have been in the hunt for a good basic paint program for linux for so long. I&amp;rsquo;m running a Ubuntu Feisty Fawn (amd64) box (yeah, yeah I didn&amp;rsquo;t upgrade to Gutsy because it sneaked up too quickly onto me and the impending loom of LTS goodness of Hardy was also there). Have been suggested various things so far like GPaint, Kolourpaint, tuxpaint etc but none of them cuts it.
Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, I love GIMP but its an overkill when I have to go through 2 menus, a dialogue box and several clicks, just to make a silly rectangle, but I don&amp;rsquo;t hold anything against it cuz afterall its an &amp;ldquo;Image Manipulation&amp;rdquo; program, not a painting one.</description></item><item><title>Breaking News: Handsolo - A Revolution In The Mobile Phone Industry?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/01/breaking-news-handsolo-a-revolution-in-the-mobile-phone-industry/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 14:49:35 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/01/breaking-news-handsolo-a-revolution-in-the-mobile-phone-industry/</guid><description>Qualcomm wets it feet again in the ice-cold/boiling-hot mixture of a sea that our Mobile Phone Industry is. They decided that the all the phone makers around the globe are just churning out junk upon the unsuspecting people. Claiming to take the bull by its horns, and revolutionizing the world that whirls around it, the touted features are:
No Battery Required
Unlimited Expandable Memory
Completely Waterproof</description></item><item><title>TIP: Make Those Linux Samba Shares Accessible From Windows Mobile</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/30/tip-make-those-linux-samba-shares-accessible-from-windows-mobile/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2008 10:30:12 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/30/tip-make-those-linux-samba-shares-accessible-from-windows-mobile/</guid><description>If you have ever needed to share files between your Linux and Windows computers, you have obviously used Samba, and have been quite happy with the way it seamlessly provides access to and from shared folders/files from Windows and Linux. However, many people complain that although their smb/Samba shares are accessible from Windows, they are not able to do the same with their Windows Mobile devices. e.g., using a tool called &amp;ldquo;Resco Explorer&amp;rdquo; on Windows Mobile, all they get while searching for their linux based Samba shares is the following screenshot:</description></item><item><title>Gawd Damnit!! South Park Episodes Go Online</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/29/gawd-damnit-south-park-episodes-go-online/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2008 20:38:55 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/29/gawd-damnit-south-park-episodes-go-online/</guid><description>Trey and Matt had talked about it a few days ago, that they were tired of downloding their own show South Park illegally. So, here it is folks. A fully revamped South Park Studios that, among other things, features full streaming of ALL the southpark episodes so far, yes that includes the latest season as well. Whats even better is that I find the quality of these even better than the ones that I downloaded earlier.</description></item><item><title>WordPress 2.5 RC3 Released: Without Even An Announcement</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/28/wordpress-25-rc3-released-without-even-an-announcement/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2008 19:31:04 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/28/wordpress-25-rc3-released-without-even-an-announcement/</guid><description>**Update: **I guess they didn&amp;rsquo;t announce it because they were about to release the final thing. Yes, WordPress 2.5 final has been released and even WordPress.org has undergone a total revamp to match the release.
Yes, I just downloaded it through WordPress.org though can’t find it being mentioned anywhere on WordPress Development Blog. Did they forget to announce it or somebody over at Automattic put up the link by mistake. Anyways, if you want to get it at the earliest as well, head over to the WordPress Release Archive and look at the very bottom of the page.</description></item><item><title>Free Domain, Free Webhosting from Microsoft</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/27/free-domain-free-webhosting-from-microsoft/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2008 16:13:29 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/27/free-domain-free-webhosting-from-microsoft/</guid><description>Microsoft is doling out a lot of free stuff today. If you have a Live ID, or have the patience of 5 minutes to fill up a small form to create a new one, you can get free domain name as well as free webhosting from then for one complete year. Cool, huh? All you need to do is click here.
A word of caution: Unless you are creating a new website just for kicks, you might want to check out the terms and conditions properly because I&amp;rsquo;m not sure whether you can transfer the domain name to some other provider after the one year is over.</description></item><item><title>HACK: Fixing The Code Syntax Highlighter WordPress Plugins To Work With WYSIWYG</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/23/hack-fixing-the-code-syntax-highlighter-wordpress-plugins-to-work-with-wysiwyg/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2008 17:18:22 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/23/hack-fixing-the-code-syntax-highlighter-wordpress-plugins-to-work-with-wysiwyg/</guid><description>There are many code syntax highlighter plugins available for WordPress (e.g. iG Syntax Highlighter, WP-Syntax, etc) but almost all of them have a problem. They want you to write the code in &amp;ldquo;HTML editing mode&amp;rdquo;. If you use any kind of WYSIWYG or visual editors (like built in TinyMCE or offline clients' similar modes), there is a grave problem. Your code becomes garbled. e.g.:
If you intend to write:
It might turn out as:</description></item><item><title>Project: Windows Mobile Tool ShantzTodayChanger Updated to version 1.53</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/22/project-windows-mobile-tool-shantztodaychanger-updated-to-version-153/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2008 20:49:17 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/22/project-windows-mobile-tool-shantztodaychanger-updated-to-version-153/</guid><description>ShantzTodayChanger is a little tool written by me for your Windows Mobile based phones (WM5/WM6) which will cycle ur today background or theme after a set interval of time. It has a lot of features and options and you can even use it to achieve something other than changing wallpapers as well (e.g. running applications at set times) but that depends on your imagination.
Changes in this version:
1.53 - 23-March-08 -&amp;gt; RECOMMENDED UPDATE</description></item><item><title>Hack: WordPress function 'wp_list_pages' to output page description (or other custom fields) in your page lists</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/19/hack-wordpress-function-wp_list_pages-to-output-page-description-or-other-custom-fields-in-your-page-lists/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2008 03:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/19/hack-wordpress-function-wp_list_pages-to-output-page-description-or-other-custom-fields-in-your-page-lists/</guid><description>Disclaimer: I&amp;rsquo;m neither a WordPress guru nor a PHP expert. This is what it is, a dirtly little hack, otherwise I&amp;rsquo;d have called it an &amp;ldquo;enhancement&amp;rdquo; Now onto the main things.
**Aim: **You would have used wp_list_pages (or plugins like dd-list-subpages, that use it) to display a list of your pages/subpages on a particular page. e.g., I use it on my &amp;ldquo;Projects&amp;rdquo; pages hierarchy to list all the relevant projects under a particular heading.</description></item><item><title>Windows Mobile: Missed Call Made Easy (Indian Cell Owners Rejoice)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/18/windows-mobile-missed-call-made-easy-indian-cell-owners-rejoice/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2008 15:12:34 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/18/windows-mobile-missed-call-made-easy-indian-cell-owners-rejoice/</guid><description>Perdida = Missed Call (in Spanish)
Missed Call = Ubiquitous Necessity (atleast in India)
Enter: cPerdidas -&amp;gt; A Windows Mobile program (works with WM5 as well as WM6) that will allow you to make missed calls to anyone you desire. Just config your country code, select the contact and &amp;ldquo;Hacer Perdida!&amp;rdquo; (Make the missed call) and your contact will get the missed call on his device. The only change is that the program will cut the call even before he can hear his phone ring.</description></item><item><title>Project: Shantz Copy Basket (Compatible with linux as well as windows)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/16/project-shantz-copy-basket-compatible-with-linux-as-well-as-windows/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2008 13:26:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/16/project-shantz-copy-basket-compatible-with-linux-as-well-as-windows/</guid><description>I’m sure you have copied/moved files on your computer from one place to another. And I’m sure often you have to do more than just “single-shot” copying that is copy a few files to one place, move a few to another, and copy yet some more to one more location. Well, I had to do this quite a few times (e.g. I ran out of disk space recently on a partition and had to empty out my “Movies” and “Songs” folders to move a few movies/songs each to all other partitions/disks according to the space available).</description></item><item><title>Shantz Copy Basket</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/16/shantz-cp-basket/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2008 13:08:46 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/16/shantz-cp-basket/</guid><description>Introduction:
I’m sure you have copied/moved files on your computer from one place to another. And I’m sure often you have to do more than just “single-shot” copying that is copy a few files to one place, move a few to another, and copy yet some more to one more location. Well, I had to do this quite a few times (e.g. I ran out of disk space recently on a partition and had to empty out my “Movies” and “Songs” folders to move a few movies/songs each to all other partitions/disks according to the space available).</description></item><item><title>Project: shantz-wp-qotd and shantz-wp-prefix-suffix updated</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/15/project-shantz-wp-qotd-and-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2008 17:26:52 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/15/project-shantz-wp-qotd-and-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated/</guid><description>Just some news on my WordPress plugins front. shantz-wp-qotd has been updated to version 1.2.1 and shantz-wp-prefix-suffix has been updated to 1.0.1. It is just a minor update meant for people still using a WordPress version &amp;lt; 2.1. The update makes the &amp;ldquo;page exclusion&amp;rdquo; feature of both the plugins (i.e. the option to prevent the plugins from acting on &amp;ldquo;pages&amp;rdquo;) compatible with WP &amp;lt; 2.1 as well.
Go to their respective pages for downloads:</description></item><item><title>Caution: "Network Solutions", Stay As Far As Possible</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/14/caution-network-solutions-stay-as-far-as-possible/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2008 20:56:23 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/14/caution-network-solutions-stay-as-far-as-possible/</guid><description>If you had a dream of starting your own website, your online abode, and you wanted to see whether the pretty little name for your dream house is available or not, what do you do? Check its availability on one of the many domain sellers' sites. And if you picked &amp;ldquo;Network Solutions&amp;rdquo; to do the search, then you have just been scammed my dear friend.
Did you wonder, that though Network Solutions showed the domain name as available, but yet when you searched and found a cheaper registrar, the domain name was suddenly…GONE.</description></item><item><title>Chinese LionKing800 cellphone claims 1-year standby</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/13/chinese-lionking800-cellphone-claims-1-year-standby/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2008 17:30:44 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/13/chinese-lionking800-cellphone-claims-1-year-standby/</guid><description>Even though they are using a battery with 10 times the juice of a normal one, but still the claim is impressive on 2 counts acc to me:
The size of the battery &amp;ldquo;seems&amp;rdquo; to be not that big for having 10 times the mAs.
Even with this battery, 1 year of standby and 3 days of talk time is impressive.
But one term spoils it all for me, &amp;ldquo;vaporware&amp;rdquo;, anyone?</description></item><item><title>Indian Govt. vs Blackberry: Yet Another Example of Idiocy From Our "Leaders"</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/12/indian-govt-vs-blackberry-yet-another-example-of-idiocy-from-our-leaders/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2008 19:45:48 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/12/indian-govt-vs-blackberry-yet-another-example-of-idiocy-from-our-leaders/</guid><description>Just read on BGR, that RIM will have to close down its BlackBerry service in India if they don&amp;rsquo;t allow our government to snoop on every little piece of data that goes through it. WTF? On an even more serious note, if they do comply, then will the same demand be made to all the ISPs? I just shudder at the mere thought of this…Quotin BGR below
It looks as if the Indian government is not content with its inability to decrypt their citizens BlackBerry e-mails, and is threatening a shutdown of Research In Motion&amp;rsquo;s devices in the country as punishment.</description></item><item><title>I Heart Canon</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/10/i-heart-canon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2008 15:23:59 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/10/i-heart-canon/</guid><description>A gaping mouth was all I had when my 3 year ol' Canon Powershot S1 IS&amp;rsquo;s LCD/EVF went blank all of a sudden a few months ago. Nothing could be seen, clicking the picture button resulted in blank pics. Googling about it revealed an advisory by Canon, stating that it is a known issue with the CCD image sensor. Canon impressed me by that notice when they said they will fix it for free, even for cameras out of warranty period, and will also pay to-and-fro shipping.</description></item><item><title>Ubuntu TIP: Extending Nautilus, Scripting Your Way To UI Bliss</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/09/ubuntu-tip-extending-nautilus-scripting-your-way-to-ui-bliss/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2008 16:10:18 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/09/ubuntu-tip-extending-nautilus-scripting-your-way-to-ui-bliss/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m back from my vacation and this is a smallish post before we return to our regular programming (I&amp;rsquo;m full of puns ).
Rahul (my friend and guest author on this blog) introduced me to an old-but-useful trick a few days ago that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about. It&amp;rsquo;s about customizing nautilus to display a context menu that has a few of your chosen scripts to weave their magic on the selected object.</description></item><item><title>Ubuntu TIP: Automating Package Installation – apt-get to the rescue</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/06/ubuntu-tip-automating-package-installation-apt-get-to-the-rescue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2008 03:30:20 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/06/ubuntu-tip-automating-package-installation-apt-get-to-the-rescue/</guid><description>Admin Note: Rahul is a long time friend of mine, and is a well known geek amongst his friends and colleagues. I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce that he will be enriching this site from time-to-time as a guest editor/author. First up is a small tid-bit of a script that he wrote to ease up his life between installations and reinstallations of everyone&amp;rsquo;s favourite OS: Ubuntu. Over to his post..
Have you ever had to reinstall your ubuntu installation, and then bear the pain of manually installing the applications you&amp;rsquo;ve come to love (i mean use :)) everyday?</description></item><item><title>TIP: Automating Website Backups - Part III (Cron Made Easy)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/04/tip-automating-website-backups-part-iii-cron-made-easy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2008 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/04/tip-automating-website-backups-part-iii-cron-made-easy/</guid><description>The question that we will be answering today is: **Q2: **Cron? Using tar, making up the script file is enough command line for me. Isn’t there an easy way? Cron is a tool that can schedule any kind of tasks for you, and here we are using it to run our backup script automatically, so that we can concentrate on blogging. Now, most of us are phobic of anything that has anything to do with command line.</description></item><item><title>Games: Wormux Reporting to Action, SIR!!!</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/03/games-wormux-reporting-to-action-sir/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2008 03:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/03/games-wormux-reporting-to-action-sir/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Alpha to Bravo, over. Come in, Bravo, over.. We are under attack, over.. Send reinforcements asap. over and out&amp;rdquo;.
Well, if you dream about conversing like this, then you are better off playing something like COD4 or BF2, but if you are into a little bit less intense military warfare, and are a fan of games like worms, tanks, etc (I&amp;rsquo;m a convicted Worms World Party addict on my HTC Wizard) then you are in for countless fun-filled, sleepless nights.</description></item><item><title>Linux: Webcam Fun</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/02/linux-webcam-fun/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2008 03:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/02/linux-webcam-fun/</guid><description>If you thought that a webcam is just for getting in visual touch with your distant friends, then you could not be more wrong. There are many other uses e.g., making videos, rudimentary security systems, etc. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that it&amp;rsquo;d be as simple as a a few keystrokes and a couple of clicks, until I stumbled across this article on Linux.com - Five fun ways to use a Linux webcam.</description></item><item><title>Idea Factory: Some Of My Latest Musings</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/01/idea-factory-some-of-my-latest-wonderings/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 03:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/01/idea-factory-some-of-my-latest-wonderings/</guid><description>jeffro2pt0 has a little contest going on his blog, giving out coupons to wpdesigners.com which lets you get atleast 12 WordPress themes for just 5$. Only thing you have to do is give a unique idea that could help improve wordpress. Now, I don’t want anymore themes (actually I’m a cheap-skate who can’t spend even 5$ for a theme, unless one of you decides to get me one ), but I got a few ideas instantly.</description></item><item><title>WordPress Must Have Plugins: Download Managers</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/29/wordpress-must-have-plugins-download-managers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Feb 2008 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/29/wordpress-must-have-plugins-download-managers/</guid><description>If you serve any kind of files for download on your WordPress blog(s), one thing you should definitly be looking out for is a download manager plugin. Post attachments are oh-so-2007. Uploading files to your server and hand-posting links everywhere is a pain in the butt. And what about your hunger for statistics?
Well, if you agree with me, then i would like to tell you about two fantastic plugins:</description></item><item><title>One Month Completed....</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/28/one-month-completed/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 04:10:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/28/one-month-completed/</guid><description>Today, this blog completes one month of its existence in this world. The achievements, although minuscule in comparison to all the biggies out there, are significant for me. It achieved the following things in just 30 days from the first post:
Front-paged at LifeHacker, HacksZine, and many others.
Over 10000 (Ten Thousand) &amp;ldquo;unique&amp;rdquo; human visitors.
Over 30000 (Thirty Thousand) page views by humans.
Over 500000 (Half Million) total hits for all website files included.</description></item><item><title> TIP: Automating Website Backups - Part IIb (Reducing Backup Size Contd.)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/28/tip-automating-website-backups-part-iib-reducing-backup-size-contd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/28/tip-automating-website-backups-part-iib-reducing-backup-size-contd/</guid><description>Last time, I had told you about how to reduce the backup size. Well, this is a short note further developing on the approaches discussed there. Basically, telling tar to backup only those files which have changed. For this, Linux has a command “find” which I am very fond of. You can give it a option “-newer” followed by a f”filename” and it will return the names of the files that are newer than filename.</description></item><item><title>TIP: Move Your WordPress Blog, And Leave The Trash Behind</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/27/tip-move-your-wordpress-blog-and-leave-the-trash-behind/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2008 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/27/tip-move-your-wordpress-blog-and-leave-the-trash-behind/</guid><description>If you are moving your blog, or just want to start afresh, you would definitely use some way to import your old content into the new place, instead of manually copying and pasting everything. Generally this means saving your database and importing into the new place. But:
You have seen WordPress importing your/others' blogs from other services automatically. Wasn&amp;rsquo;t that quick and easy.
Your databse has become overly full of so much trash over the years and you would like to trim out all the fat and take just the meat (the posts, pages, comments, tags, custom fields etc)</description></item><item><title>HTC Video Drivers: But This Is Not A Post About HTC</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/26/htc-video-drivers-but-this-is-not-a-post-about-htc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 11:14:36 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/26/htc-video-drivers-but-this-is-not-a-post-about-htc/</guid><description>This is a post about irresponsible/careless journalism/bloggism. For Gizmodo, getting that post about HTC’s latest press release out the door took precedence over actually **reading **the release properly and then commenting over it. The gizmodo poster’s comment is:
……but HTC&amp;rsquo;s finally released a statement saying that a fix is coming. They say that the video acceleration will be supported in the future, and will be included in software upgrades for current devices…….</description></item><item><title>TIP: WordPress Posts Scheduling - Back To The Future (or Blast From The Past?)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/26/tip-wordpress-posts-scheduling-back-to-the-future-or-blast-from-the-past/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/26/tip-wordpress-posts-scheduling-back-to-the-future-or-blast-from-the-past/</guid><description>If you are like me (I mean underpaid, overworked, coding zombie), then the only time you find for blogging is weekends. To keep your readers happy and satisfied through the week, the only options you have are burning the midnight electricity (what? You still use oil? :P) or paying up your son/nephew/wife/etc to push the publish button regularly for the drafts you wrote on weekend. Right? WRONG….
Matt and his AutoMattic team took care of bonded labour like us, and had the good heart to put in the capability of scheduling posts in WordPress (More commonly known as “future posting”).</description></item><item><title>HollowMan Redux: Google Presents Gmail Users the Invisibility Cloak</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/25/hollowman-redux-google-presents-gmail-users-the-invisibility-cloak/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2008 18:53:20 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/25/hollowman-redux-google-presents-gmail-users-the-invisibility-cloak/</guid><description>Google gave us a nice little present today. The power to be all-seeing but yet still remaining unseen. Yes, now you can be “invisible” in your gmail chat session.
But beware, don’t fire up your gtalk, or you will again be as visible as a 100 watt bulb in a 4x4 room at night.</description></item><item><title>X-Men Are Here, Only That They Are In Your Hands</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/25/x-men-are-here-only-that-they-are-in-your-hands/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2008 14:50:23 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/25/x-men-are-here-only-that-they-are-in-your-hands/</guid><description>Who wouldn’t agree that Morph is most probably the coolest mutant (besides Wolverine of of course ). Now, it seems that the Finnish Giant Nokia has a lot of X-Men lovers as well, as they put out their latest offering to us lesser mortals. They call it “The Morph Concept”.
Featured in The Museum of Modern Art “Design and The Elastic Mind” exhibition, the Morph concept device is a bridge between highly advanced technologies and their potential benefits to end-users.</description></item><item><title>TIP: Automating Website Backups - Part II (Reducing Backup Size)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/24/tip-automating-website-backups-part-ii-reducing-backup-size/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2008 21:43:13 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/24/tip-automating-website-backups-part-ii-reducing-backup-size/</guid><description>Last week I had written a short guide on “Automating Website Backups”. I received some good comments/suggestions about it from Jasvinder through e-mail about other aspects that should be addressed. So, thought of doing a few follow ups to that post. This is done in more of a FAQ fashion, so as to answer some of the questions that may arise after reading the first post. Each post will answer one of the questions listed below in detail</description></item><item><title>Project: shantz-wp-qotd Updated and shantz-wp-prefix-suffix released</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/24/project-shantz-wp-qotd-updated-and-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-released/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2008 09:44:24 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/24/project-shantz-wp-qotd-updated-and-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-released/</guid><description>I updated my wordpress plugin shantz-wp-qotd. (A feature rich, customizable wordpress quotes plugin) today to version 1.2.0. The new version has the following changes:
Added option to exclude pages from displaying quotes
Fixed a bug that quotes source selection checkboxes always remain checked after updating settings.
Cosmetic: Fixed a few spelling mistakes :)</description></item><item><title>Shantz WordPress Prefix Suffix</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/23/shantz-wordpress-prefix-suffix/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2008 21:38:39 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/23/shantz-wordpress-prefix-suffix/</guid><description>Shantz WP Prefix Suffix
== Description ==
Shantz WP Prefix Suffix is a light-weight and easy to use plugin which allows you to add any text and/or HTML/CSS code to your posts and/or pages as prefix (top / beginning), middle and/or suffix (bottom /end). (That includes even any new or old posts and pages and even your feed) Examples of use cases could be to include your copyright message, advertisements (like adsense, etc), permalinks, your other site links, any other custom messages.</description></item><item><title>Site Updates</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/22/site-updates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2008 05:05:04 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/22/site-updates/</guid><description>The site received a lot of new visitors yesterday as one of the small-time things that I do, received front page treatment at lifehacker. Thank you, Adam Pash, and thanks Murphy, for the original idea.</description></item><item><title>shantz-csv-to-opml</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/22/shantz-csv-to-opml/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2008 04:53:53 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/22/shantz-csv-to-opml/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION
This is a very simple script that I did for a friend. It can be used to quickly generate blogrolls.
Input: csv file with blog author names and blog links
Output: OPML file that can be imported into many blogging/blogrolling software and websites (e.g. wordpress, blogrolling.com, etc)
Usage:
shantz-csv-to-opml.pl &amp;lt;input file in csv format&amp;gt; &amp;lt;output opml filename&amp;gt; Input File Format: Each line should be like this: &amp;lt;Name of Author&amp;gt;,&amp;lt;bloglink&amp;gt;,&amp;lt;bloglink&amp;gt;... e.</description></item><item><title>Project: Retrieve Files From Remote Computer Through E-mail</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/19/project-retrieve-files-from-remote-computer-through-e-mail/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2008 17:52:16 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/19/project-retrieve-files-from-remote-computer-through-e-mail/</guid><description>I came across this post on lifehacker today (original post and solution here), which talks about a method of retrieving files from a remote computer through e-mail. Pretty archaic, I know, but again, it is a very simple method and works behind all the firewalls and stuff . But, the catch is that it is only for mac’s. Thought of creating something similar for the PC and mashed together some code during lunch time at office to make our dear old outlook remote-file-sending-capable.</description></item><item><title>Remote File Access Through E-Mail</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/19/remote-file-access-through-e-mail/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2008 17:43:30 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/19/remote-file-access-through-e-mail/</guid><description>Introduction:
This is a (proof-of-concept) outlook macro that you can use with an outlook rule to retrieve your files from your home/office PC by sending it a mail with a subject having a predefined special keyword and the body containing the names and paths of the files. The remote PC will then mail you the files on a predefined e-mail ID.
This project came into being after reading this post at lifehacker (original post and solution here).</description></item><item><title>Boring Meetings? CallJockey To The Rescue</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/19/boring-meetings-calljockey-to-the-rescue/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2008 04:43:19 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/19/boring-meetings-calljockey-to-the-rescue/</guid><description>Stuck in another boring meeting? You have a way out now, because connectivetools have released their app CallJockey, which can simulate fake incoming calls. What&amp;rsquo;s more, you can select the name, phone number or one of your saved contacts from whom the fake call will appear to be coming, plus you can define the time when you want it to ring. The only limitation is that it is available only for WM5 smarphones (WM6 Standard), i.</description></item><item><title>Project: "shantz-wp-qotd ", My Wordpress Plugin, Updated to 1.1.0</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/17/project-shantz-wp-qotd-my-wordpress-plugin-update-to-110/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2008 15:44:18 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/17/project-shantz-wp-qotd-my-wordpress-plugin-update-to-110/</guid><description>For the uninitiated:
I made a few additions / modifications to the code and the plugin has been updated to 1.1.0. The changes are:
Added Custom tag support for adding quotes anywhere in your posts/pages
Added Custom quote separator support and multi-line quotes support
Config Screenshots:
I recommend that you update to this new version asap, as apart from the above mentioned changes, the code is a bit more cleaner as well, which would run a bit better IMO and also help in any modification if you have in mind.</description></item><item><title>TIP: Automating Website Backups</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/17/tip-automating-website-backups/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2008 09:19:50 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/17/tip-automating-website-backups/</guid><description>What can go wrong with your wonderfully running website / blog? Everything..
Your online abode is so difficult to keep secured. It can get hacked, you may install something wrong, a wrong configuration can wreak havoc, the server hard disk might crash, natural calamities, and what not. Your best option to secure yourself against all this is summarized in just one word “BACKUP”.
Now, a backup involves two most important things: “Database Backup” and “Files Backup”.</description></item><item><title>Engineer: A New Definition</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/14/engineer-a-new-definition/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2008 17:06:12 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/14/engineer-a-new-definition/</guid><description>Came across this funny, but still thought provoking, definition of an engineer.
(Taken from “The Embedded Muse”, a useful embedded stuff related newsletter published by Jack Ganssel.)
“An engineer is a person who passes as an exacting expert on the basis of being able to turn out with prolific fortitude infinite strings of incomprehensible formulas calculated with micrometric precision from vague assumptions which are based on debatable figures taken from inconclusive experiments carried out with instruments of problematical accuracy by persons of questionable mentality and doubtful reliability for the avowed purpose of annoying and confusing a hopelessly chimerical group of esoteric fanatics referred to altogether too frequently as technicians.</description></item><item><title>SmartPhones/NextGen Telephony: News That Matters</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/14/smartphonesnextgen-telephony-news-that-matters/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2008 05:08:10 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/14/smartphonesnextgen-telephony-news-that-matters/</guid><description>Just wanted to share some pieces that generated a variety of &amp;ldquo;hmmm&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;ahaa&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;wow&amp;rdquo; from me:
China Mobile set to trial LTE:
China Mobile said it will join Vodafone Group plc and Verizon Wireless in an ongoing trial of LTE technology…….The trials &amp;ndash; which include three powerhouse network operators &amp;ndash; underscore the momentum LTE is gaining as a leading 4G technology possibility vs. WiMAX and Ultra Mobile Broadband.
&amp;ldquo;HMMM&amp;rdquo; - U go LTE!</description></item><item><title>TIP: Switching Soundcards In Ubuntu</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/12/tip-switching-soundcards-in-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2008 18:00:47 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/12/tip-switching-soundcards-in-ubuntu/</guid><description>If you have multiple soundcards in your system and have to switch between them regularly (e.g. laptop owners like me, who use an external soundcard while being docked to groove to the highest and the lowest of frequencies through those 7.1 channels and use the in-built sound card while on the move) you would definitely be under-whelmed by the less-than-stellar performance of ubuntu in switching between the sound cards. For me at least, ubuntu (fiesty 7.</description></item><item><title>My First WordPress Plugin: Please Welcome shantz-wp-qotd</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/10/my-first-wordpress-plugin-please-welcome-shantz-wp-qotd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 11:00:27 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/10/my-first-wordpress-plugin-please-welcome-shantz-wp-qotd/</guid><description>Motivated by Ronald’s ultimate wordpress plugin tutorial at devlounge, I decided that the best way to learn something is to use it in a live project. Armed with my laptop and multiple flasks of coffee, the marathon began on Friday night. My only experience with web-related development so far had been around 8–10 years ago as a kid when, just like everybody else at that time, I was fascinated by HTML and did a “read-through” of HTML 4.</description></item><item><title>Shantz WordPress QOTD</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/10/shantz-wordpress-qotd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 10:22:57 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/10/shantz-wordpress-qotd/</guid><description>Shantz WP QOTD is a plugin to add quotes to your wordpress blog in a few easy clicks. It adds quotes to your posts and your sidebars with a multitude of options for sources and customization.
== Description ==
There are many quotes plugins out there. This one has been started with a view to have the best of features and options, ease of use and multiple sources to get the quotes from.</description></item><item><title>Nokia + Windows Mobile = Let's Kick Some &lt;InsertWMPhoneMakerName> Butt</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/08/nokia-windows-mobile-lets-kick-some-butt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2008 05:00:58 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/08/nokia-windows-mobile-lets-kick-some-butt/</guid><description>As everyone knows, I’m an out-and-out Windows Mobile worshipper. It’s like a girlfriend, who is very difficult to manage and understand at first, but is a great source of joy if you know how to manage her. I don’t like any other phones now; the extensibility given by WM will do that to you.
I also “admire” Nokia because of the quality and reliability they provide with their phones. Having worked for them in a project (Nokia Networks/Nokia Seimens Networks actually), I know how much testing they put in before releasing something.</description></item><item><title>Tips: Configure FTP upload support for wordpress in Blogjet</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/07/tips-configure-ftp-upload-support-for-wordpress-in-blogjet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2008 14:36:27 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/07/tips-configure-ftp-upload-support-for-wordpress-in-blogjet/</guid><description>A few days ago, I had written about a wonderful blogging tool Blogjet. Now, if you host a wordpress blog, you’d be aware of the fact that for wordpress to be able to upload yor files (images, attachements in post etc) to the server, you have to make the upload directory writable by all. Now, this is a BIG security risk. Some people go to the lengths of CHMOD’ding their upload directory for a short while and after upload, restoring the apt file permissions back.</description></item><item><title>i3theme awesomeness: Cool feature for end-users/viewers</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/06/i3theme-awesomeness-cool-feature-for-end-usersviewers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2008 04:42:02 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/06/i3theme-awesomeness-cool-feature-for-end-usersviewers/</guid><description>I am just in love with this theme. I knew about the cool feature that you can click on those little green dots on the right top corner of any widget and the widget will minimize to just a bar but just now discovered another awesome feature for the viewers of the wordpress based blogs using this theme. The feature is that you, the viewer, can reorganize the widgets on the left and right sidebars according to your preference, like move the “Pages” widget towards the top for convenient navigation through all the static pages in the site.</description></item><item><title>Hack: Wordpress i3theme IE6 sidebar problem solved</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/04/hack-wordpress-i3theme-ie6-sidebar-problem-solved/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2008 14:51:21 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/04/hack-wordpress-i3theme-ie6-sidebar-problem-solved/</guid><description>The awesome i3theme that this blog uses is a treat to the eyes, except to a lot of IE6 users. The issue is that for many people viewing wordpress blogs using this theme, the right sidebar doesn&amp;rsquo;t appear on the right, but **below **the middle column main area.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t know this problem existed as I don&amp;rsquo;t use IE but when a friend mailed to let me know, I started hunting around for the solution.</description></item><item><title>Project: ShantzTodayChanger (Windows Mobile Tool To Cycle Themes/Wallpapers Automatically)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/project-shantztodaychanger-windows-mobile-tool-to-cycle-themeswallpapers-automatically/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 19:45:07 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/project-shantztodaychanger-windows-mobile-tool-to-cycle-themeswallpapers-automatically/</guid><description>The newly launched [&amp;ldquo;Projects&amp;rdquo;] section is hereby inaugarated with a Windows Mobile Tool developed by me, called “[ShantzTodayChanger]”. This is a little tool for your Windows Mobile based phones (Compatible with WM5/WM6 but not WM2003) which will cycle ur today background or theme after a set interval of time. It has a lot of features and options that you can discover by reading the text below. And you can even use this options to achieve something other than changing wallpapers as well but that depends on your imagination.</description></item><item><title>Site Updates: More Content For You</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/site-updates-more-content-for-you/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 19:36:42 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/site-updates-more-content-for-you/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve added a few new sections to the blog. Do check them out. Here is a list of the new sections along with their descriptions.
[Projects]: Although I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t put myself in the category of an excellent developer but I can sure type in a few lines that can compile without an error and also manage to carry out a task or two. So, this page will list some of those little things that I write to weed out a few niggles or scratch a few itches of mine.</description></item><item><title>ShantzTodayChanger</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/shantztodaychanger/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 13:41:30 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/shantztodaychanger/</guid><description>Intro:
This is a little tool for your Windows Mobile based phones (Compatible with WM5/WM6 but not WM2003) which will cycle ur today background or theme after a set interval of time. It has a lot of features and options that you can discover by reading the text below. And you can even use this options to achieve something other than changing wallpapers as well but that depends on your imagination.</description></item><item><title>Ubuntu Nuggets: Window list settings in panel</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/01/ubuntu-nuggets-window-list-settings-in-panel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 19:06:13 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/01/ubuntu-nuggets-window-list-settings-in-panel/</guid><description>I am pretty sure that all of you must be fed of that one windows taking up the whole task bar in the panel. Like this:
Well, you can change that. Plus, all you windows-to-linux converts must also be thinking of how to squeeze in a few more windows into the task bar. A &amp;ldquo;grouping of similar windows&amp;rdquo; option like windows would have been just nice. Well, that can be done too, and without any shell scripting, config file modifying, etc.</description></item><item><title>Windows Mobile 6 - Case of the Missing Calls: Solved</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/31/windows-mobile-6-case-of-the-missing-calls-solved/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2008 18:30:33 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/31/windows-mobile-6-case-of-the-missing-calls-solved/</guid><description>As the pic above says, it turned out to be quite elementary in the end. But what is &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rdquo; actually?
The Problem: Since the beginning of time (read launching of WM6), millions of WM users (ok ok, will not exaggerate from now on) have been facing a very peculiar issue. The issue is that people tell them all the time that they are avoiding those people, and not taking their calls.</description></item><item><title>WM6.1 Is Here, Loves HTC Wizard...(Really?)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/31/wm61-is-here-loves-htc-wizardreally/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2008 05:54:42 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/31/wm61-is-here-loves-htc-wizardreally/</guid><description>A user going by the remarkably simple handle &amp;ldquo;email123&amp;rdquo; announced on the xda-developers forum, that WM6.1 is here, alive and kicking. But he doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop there, he says that its available &amp;ldquo;now&amp;rdquo;, that too for an HTC wizard, a 3 year old phone (which I own as well). Thats not all, he goes on to provide the proof by linking in his cooked ROM for all to download. But, here is the clincher, he claims that finally &amp;ldquo;Big Storage&amp;rdquo; is available for wizard, a feat noone has been able to achieve in the last 3 years.</description></item><item><title>All Your Base Are Belong To Us - Says Dell</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/30/all-your-base-are-belong-to-us-says-dell/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2008 18:27:55 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/30/all-your-base-are-belong-to-us-says-dell/</guid><description>Ask any laptop user about how much he liked to kick some butt in Gears of War and he would cringe and cry with agony even before you are able to say the &amp;ldquo;C&amp;rdquo; of Crysis. But not anymore. For its notebook consumers, Dell has finally come up with the perfect answer to the questions posed by these ridiculously-difficult-to-get-more-than-10-fps games. Available now is some motherly love for your laps in the form of 8800M GTX with its M1730.</description></item><item><title>BlogJet - Blog Faster, Blog Better (Now In Linux too, with a hidden bonus)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/29/blogjet-blog-faster-blog-better-now-in-linux-too-with-a-hidden-bonus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2008 15:30:27 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/29/blogjet-blog-faster-blog-better-now-in-linux-too-with-a-hidden-bonus/</guid><description>A quick googling for best desktop blogging client would yield just a few (read millions/gazillions) results. Having researched the subject a lot, my choices were finally limited down to BlogJet and BlogDesk, as per my feature set requirement goes (Primarily, off line editing, draft, WYSIWYG editing, categories, tagging support, pinging, trackbacks support, timestamping, past post editing, automatic image uploading) BUT there is one little problem. Both of these don’t work on Linux.</description></item><item><title>Beware of Fake Nokia N95 Cell Phones, Pirated by Chinese</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/29/beware-of-fake-nokia-n95-cell-phones-pirated-by-chinese/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2008 09:15:32 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/29/beware-of-fake-nokia-n95-cell-phones-pirated-by-chinese/</guid><description>Came across this post today, now even your N95’s aren’t safe. Make sure to check this guide to identify if your latest boy-toy is a fake or not.
Beware of Fake Nokia N95 Cell Phones, Pirated by Chinese.</description></item><item><title>Looking for a Host - For a Party that you will throw</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/28/looking-for-a-host-for-a-party-that-you-will-throw/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2008 16:31:52 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/28/looking-for-a-host-for-a-party-that-you-will-throw/</guid><description>One thing that is most difficult to choose (after a dress for your girlfriend that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make her &amp;ldquo;look&amp;rdquo; fat) is choosing a webhost. A google search is going to even confuse you further. As you wade into this enormous ocean, you will be wowed by the offers given by some of these hosts, throwing away 100&amp;rsquo;s of GBs (no less) of disk space and bandwidth running into terrabytes. Almost every software on earth in your one-click fantastico arsenal.</description></item><item><title>AMD (ATi) Step Up The Tempo</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/28/amd-ati-step-up-the-tempo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2008 16:01:45 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/28/amd-ati-step-up-the-tempo/</guid><description>AMD has been taking a lot of flak lately in its processor business, and a similar (albeit milder) thrashing was being given to its ATi Gfx line up as well. But they seem to be on the recover track now, with the release of the brand spanking new HD3870X2 series, some people aptly calling it &amp;ldquo;crossfire on a card&amp;rdquo;. All you gamers, please stop drooling on the screen now, and check out some benchmarks.</description></item><item><title>HTC - The best windows mobile "business unit"</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/28/htc-the-best-windows-mobile-business-unit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2008 15:26:02 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/28/htc-the-best-windows-mobile-business-unit/</guid><description>For the very post of this blog, I chose a subject that&amp;rsquo;s close to my heart. Yes, its Windows Mobile. My trusted 900/1800 MHZ companion for the past couple of years is an HTC Wizard. If you have ever looked into the WinMob world, its pretty much common knowledge that HTC owns the 95% of market share of this niche little space. They are a huge organization and with huge profits and they do make jolly good phones.</description></item></channel></rss>