<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Phone on</title><link>/tags/phone/</link><description>Recent content in Phone on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2010 19:48:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/phone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Real Threat Of Windows Phone 7</title><link>/posts/the-real-threat-of-windows-phone-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2010 19:48:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-real-threat-of-windows-phone-7/</guid><description>Many people say that Windows Phone 7 is a threat to iPhone because they are bringing in a super platform with a choice of multiple designs and multiple carriers with great Enterprise and gaming support and maintaining the lucrative integration that iPhone provides. Many also say that Windows Phone 7 is a threat to Android because it solves the problem of Apple&amp;rsquo;s draconian policies, gives choice to customers and all this without fragmenting the OS all over the place.</description></item><item><title>Android App: Wi-Fi Keep Alive Updated to 1.2.0</title><link>/posts/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive-updated-to-1-2-0/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2010 22:46:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive-updated-to-1-2-0/</guid><description>Just finished uploading the new version 1.2.0 of my android app Wi-Fi Keep Alive to the Android market. This version has a lot of optimizations and also a few workarounds to overcome the issues few guys were facing with Android&amp;rsquo;s in-built handling of wi-fi sleep policies.
Changes done in this version:
Added workarounds to take care of sleep policies not working on some phones
Optimized the code a bit for faster operations</description></item><item><title>Android App: Wi-Fi Keep Alive</title><link>/posts/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2010 15:25:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/android-app-wi-fi-keep-alive/</guid><description>I just wrote my second Android App. This again was to scratch an itch of mine but it seems to have become a bit popular already (My first app &amp;ldquo;Quick Sync Settings&amp;rdquo; did around 400 downloads in 20 days but this one has already surpassed that in less than one day). This app basically allows you to change the wi-fi sleep policy on android so that you can keep your wi-fi connected even if the phone goes to sleep (i.</description></item><item><title>The Elusive Super Phone</title><link>/posts/the-elusive-super-phone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2008 17:15:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-elusive-super-phone/</guid><description>HTC announce their shiny new Touch Diamond recently. Everyone ooh&amp;rsquo;ed and aah&amp;rsquo;ed while ogling at it until they realized that HTC has taken a step back (or forward towards matching Apple&amp;rsquo;s iPhone crap) by removing the expansion card slot from the phone. Yes, it has 4 GB of internal storage but I&amp;rsquo;d rather have an SDHC card slot with the ever falling prices of solid state memory (an 8 GB Class 6 SDHC card is worth not more than around 60$ these days).</description></item><item><title>Beware of Fake Nokia N95 Cell Phones, Pirated by Chinese</title><link>/posts/beware-of-fake-nokia-n95-cell-phones-pirated-by-chinese/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2008 09:15:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/beware-of-fake-nokia-n95-cell-phones-pirated-by-chinese/</guid><description>Came across this post today, now even your N95’s aren’t safe. Make sure to check this guide to identify if your latest boy-toy is a fake or not.
Beware of Fake Nokia N95 Cell Phones, Pirated by Chinese.</description></item><item><title>HTC - The best windows mobile "business unit"</title><link>/posts/htc-the-best-windows-mobile-business-unit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2008 15:26:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/htc-the-best-windows-mobile-business-unit/</guid><description>For the very post of this blog, I chose a subject that&amp;rsquo;s close to my heart. Yes, its Windows Mobile. My trusted 900/1800 MHZ companion for the past couple of years is an HTC Wizard. If you have ever looked into the WinMob world, its pretty much common knowledge that HTC owns the 95% of market share of this niche little space. They are a huge organization and with huge profits and they do make jolly good phones.</description></item></channel></rss>