<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on</title><link>/tags/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 17:44:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Remote Bandwidth Stats</title><link>/posts/remote-bandwidth-stats/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 17:44:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/remote-bandwidth-stats/</guid><description>This post is about my open source remote bandwidth usage stats logger project.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to log the internet bandwidth usage at my home for quite some time since I don&amp;rsquo;t really find the stats put out by my ISP to be completely accurate. But I have multiple devices at home that access the internet so it is not feasible to install a bandwidth monitor individually on all these devices as I&amp;rsquo;d still need to add up all logs and many of such devices don&amp;rsquo;t even have a way to install a monitoring software installed (e.</description></item><item><title>A short Tablet/Smartphone survey for a project</title><link>/posts/short-tablet-smartphone-survey-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2010 04:10:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/short-tablet-smartphone-survey-project/</guid><description>I need a bit of your help in filling out a short survey that I need for a small project of mine that I&amp;rsquo;m doing with a friend. It will take maximum of only 2-3 minutes of your time. Please fill it out below. If you are facing any problems with the survey or have any queries/suggestions etc, please use this contact form to send them to us.
Much Thanks!! :)</description></item><item><title>Real Time Data Plotting with GNUPlot</title><link>/posts/real-time-plot-gnuplot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2009 11:15:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/real-time-plot-gnuplot/</guid><description>I wrote this script a few days ago to plot real-time / streaming data with gnuplot. The motivation was that I needed to test a piece of code for a touchscreen driver that I had written at work. The issue was that the UI wasn’t quite ready yet, so I wanted to test just the driver to be working fine. Now, the very first thought for the software to use that came to me was “gnuplot” but I found that it can’t really do this in an easy way.</description></item><item><title>Project: Figlet Online - Text To ASCII Converter Tool</title><link>/posts/figlet-online-text-to-ascii-converter-tool/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2009 14:00:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/figlet-online-text-to-ascii-converter-tool/</guid><description>Figlet is a brilliant tool to convert text to amazing ASCII Art that I have used for many years. This weekend I thought of creating an online version of it, so that anyone can use it even if they can&amp;rsquo;t install it on their systems. It is pretty easy to use. The drill is just to choose the font you want (and there is a very extensive collection of more than 250 to choose from), input the text that you want to be ASCII&amp;rsquo;fied, press a button and you are done.</description></item><item><title>Project: Shantz WordPress Prefix Suffix Updated to 1.1.2</title><link>/posts/project-shantz-wordpress-prefix-suffix-updated-to-112/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2009 18:30:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/project-shantz-wordpress-prefix-suffix-updated-to-112/</guid><description>My WordPress Plugin &amp;ldquo;Shantz Wordpress Prefix Suffix&amp;rdquo; has just been updated to version 1.1.2. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, this is a super-light and easy to use plugin that allows you to add any text or html/javascript/php code to your posts, be it the top of the posts, bottom of the posts or even in the middle. And you get a lot of options to control all this. I use it even on my site, to create links for my other blogs, adding copyright notices and even for advertisements (google adsense, chitika premium, etc).</description></item><item><title>Project: My WordPress Plugin Shantz-WP-Prefix-Suffix Updated To 1.0.5</title><link>/posts/project-my-wordpress-plugin-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-to-105/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 15:48:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/project-my-wordpress-plugin-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-to-105/</guid><description>For those who are new to this plugin, Shantz WP Prefix Suffix is a light-weight and easy to use plugin which allows you to add any text, HTML/CSS/PHP/Javascript code to your posts and/or pages as prefix and/or suffix. (That includes even any new or old posts and pages and even your feed) Examples of use cases could be to include your copyright message, advertisements (like adsense, etc), permalinks, your other site links, any other custom messages.</description></item><item><title>Project: Shantz-XwinWrap Updated to 0.02</title><link>/posts/project-shantz-xwinwrap-updated-to-002/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2008 11:03:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/project-shantz-xwinwrap-updated-to-002/</guid><description>As some of you know that I&amp;rsquo;ve taken up the development of the ultra-cool xwinwrap tool that allows you to use movies, screensavers etc as wallpapers for you linux desktops. Here is version 0.02 for you consumption that fixes a bug because of which the generated window was overlapping other windows.
The download file has plain executable binaries as well as deb packages for Ubuntu. Moreover, I&amp;rsquo;ve included both 32 bit as well as 64 bit versions.</description></item><item><title>Project: Shantz Pidgin Away Alerts (splert) Updated to 0.03</title><link>/posts/project-shantz-pidgin-away-alerts-splert-updated-to-003/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 21:19:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/project-shantz-pidgin-away-alerts-splert-updated-to-003/</guid><description>I updated my project splert to version 0.03 today.For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know splert is a tool that lets you convert the multi-client instant messenger pidgin (connects to gtalk, msn, yahoo, jabber, etc) into a full blown answering machine and much more.
The main changes are:
Now you can use other 3rd party twitter bots with it to get updates through twitter since the official twitter bot is down since a long time and there are no chances of coming back soon.</description></item><item><title>Shantz XWinWrap: The "Moving" Wallpaper Fun Continues</title><link>/posts/shantz-xwinwrap-the-moving-wallpaper-fun-continues/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 14:46:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/shantz-xwinwrap-the-moving-wallpaper-fun-continues/</guid><description>XWinWrap is a small utility written a loooong time ago that allowed you to stick most of the apps to your desktop background (Thanks to fsckin for introducing me to it). What this meant was you could use an animated screensaver (like glmatrix, electric sheep, etc) or even a movie, and use it as your wallpaper. But only one version of this app was released, and it had a few problems, like it wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly &amp;ldquo;sticking&amp;rdquo; to the background and geometry option didn&amp;rsquo;t work as well.</description></item><item><title>Shantz XWinWrap</title><link>/posts/shantz-xwinwrap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 14:41:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/shantz-xwinwrap/</guid><description>XWinWrap is a small utility written a loooong time ago that allowed you to stick most of the apps to your desktop background. What this meant was you could use an animated screensaver (like glmatrix, electric sheep, etc) or even a movie, and use it as your wallpaper. But only one version of this app was ever released, and it had a few problems, like:
Well, sticking didn&amp;rsquo;t work. So if you did a &amp;ldquo;minimize all&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;go to desktop&amp;rdquo; kind of thing, your &amp;ldquo;wallpaper&amp;rdquo; got minimized as well.</description></item><item><title>Project: "shantz-wp-qotd ", My Wordpress Plugin, Updated to 1.1.0</title><link>/posts/project-shantz-wp-qotd-my-wordpress-plugin-update-to-110/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2008 15:44:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/project-shantz-wp-qotd-my-wordpress-plugin-update-to-110/</guid><description>For the uninitiated:
I made a few additions / modifications to the code and the plugin has been updated to 1.1.0. The changes are:
Added Custom tag support for adding quotes anywhere in your posts/pages
Added Custom quote separator support and multi-line quotes support
Config Screenshots:
I recommend that you update to this new version asap, as apart from the above mentioned changes, the code is a bit more cleaner as well, which would run a bit better IMO and also help in any modification if you have in mind.</description></item><item><title>Project: ShantzTodayChanger (Windows Mobile Tool To Cycle Themes/Wallpapers Automatically)</title><link>/posts/project-shantztodaychanger-windows-mobile-tool-to-cycle-themeswallpapers-automatically/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 19:45:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/project-shantztodaychanger-windows-mobile-tool-to-cycle-themeswallpapers-automatically/</guid><description>The newly launched [&amp;ldquo;Projects&amp;rdquo;] section is hereby inaugarated with a Windows Mobile Tool developed by me, called “[ShantzTodayChanger]”. This is a little tool for your Windows Mobile based phones (Compatible with WM5/WM6 but not WM2003) which will cycle ur today background or theme after a set interval of time. It has a lot of features and options that you can discover by reading the text below. And you can even use this options to achieve something other than changing wallpapers as well but that depends on your imagination.</description></item><item><title>Site Updates: More Content For You</title><link>/posts/site-updates-more-content-for-you/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 19:36:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/site-updates-more-content-for-you/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve added a few new sections to the blog. Do check them out. Here is a list of the new sections along with their descriptions.
[Projects]: Although I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t put myself in the category of an excellent developer but I can sure type in a few lines that can compile without an error and also manage to carry out a task or two. So, this page will list some of those little things that I write to weed out a few niggles or scratch a few itches of mine.</description></item></channel></rss>