<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Huawei Ideos U8150 Review on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/huawei-ideos-u8150-review/</link><description>Recent content in Huawei Ideos U8150 Review on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2011 15:52:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/huawei-ideos-u8150-review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Huawei Ideos U8150 Review</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/06/05/huawei-ideos-u8150-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2011 15:52:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/06/05/huawei-ideos-u8150-review/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently I received Huawei Ideos U8150 phone for review. This is an Android smartphone meant for the entry level market. I had the phone for a few weeks to put it through its paces and here are some of my thoughts about it. I am not going to expand a lot on the general Android points as we all know about it but will concentrate succinctly and to-the-point on the aspects which can make it or break it for this phone against its competition in the similar price ranges.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>Recently I received Huawei Ideos U8150 phone for review. This is an Android smartphone meant for the entry level market. I had the phone for a few weeks to put it through its paces and here are some of my thoughts about it. I am not going to expand a lot on the general Android points as we all know about it but will concentrate succinctly and to-the-point on the aspects which can make it or break it for this phone against its competition in the similar price ranges.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/huawei-ideos.gif" />
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>**Display: ** The display is average and pretty much on par with the other handsets in this range. It&amp;rsquo;s a low resolution QVGA (320x240) screen. While it&amp;rsquo;s usable but not a brilliant one and would give a sublime web browsing experience. The brightness of the display was average as well, nothing to write home about but not below the competition either.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Touchscreen: ** A good thing about this handset is that it has a capacitive touchscreen. A few entry level phones skimp out on this and put a resistive touchscreen but not so with Ideos. The screen response is pretty good.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Android Version: ** Ideos sports Android 2.2 Froyo which is again a good thing since this is the latest I have seen in any entry/mid-level and most high end phones as well. Gingerbread is still too new and I&amp;rsquo;m happy enough with Froyo. A lot of other phones are still stuck on Eclair 2.1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Camera: ** The camera is ok&amp;rsquo;ish with its 3.2 MP sensor and no LED flash. It works well for well lit subjects but is useless in dark. The quality of photos taken is average as well. Nothing extremely bad but nothing very good as well, just good enough for capturing spontaneous moments when you are not carrying your proper standalone camera with you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Connectivity: ** Ideos has 802.11n wi-fi and 7.2mbps HSDPA 3G for connectivity. wi-fi connected to my router in a snap and it also has hotspot (or wireless tethering) capability for upto 8 devices. 3G connectivity was ok. Speedtest results came out to be similar to my Nexus one over both wi-fi as well as 3G.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Built: ** Ideos is built sturdily but looks a bit tacky with its shiny back. But then again, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to find a good looking phone in entry level smartphones which performs according to it&amp;rsquo;s looks as well. I didn&amp;rsquo;t try any drop tests on it but I&amp;rsquo;d fathom it&amp;rsquo;d easily survive any short falls. The phone is also pretty light and small, easy to pocket.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Performance: ** Ideos has a Qualcomm MSM7227 processor, rated at a clock speed of 528 MHz. This processor is fairly standard in almost all the entry level devices and is good enough for daily usage and most of the apps. But most games would struggle on it. If you are buying this (or any other entry level smartphone) with the correct expectations of it performing according to it&amp;rsquo;s price range, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be disappointed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Web Browsing: ** Web browsing is mediocre on Ideos because of it&amp;rsquo;s low resolution screen, low specc&amp;rsquo;ed processor (which also results in lack of Adobe Flash). If you plan on using the browser for your web needs, don&amp;rsquo;t bet on opening any javascript heavy pages quickly and should look mostly to fill the void by using specific apps for the services you are trying to access.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Battery: ** The phone is good on the battery and it was able to last around 1.5-2 days on a single charge for medium usage even though it houses just a 1200 mAh. This is on-par, if not better, than most other phones in this range.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**GPS: ** The GPS was quick to get a fix and retained it to a good accuracy almost same as my Nexus one. Using Google maps on this phone was a breeze.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Other Notes: ** The phone bundles a free 2GB microSD card and also stereo headphones. The headphones are average at best like most other phones and you should really pair it with a cheap set of Creative IEMs that will give you a much better output while staying on a budget.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Conclusion: ** While the phone is not a powerhouse in itself, I&amp;rsquo;d rate it pretty good in it&amp;rsquo;s price segment. If I had to buy an Android smartphone on a budget around 8000 INR, it&amp;rsquo;d be a toss up between this and the Samsung Galaxy Pop S5570. So, this is a +1 recommendation from me for this phone.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>