<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Asus on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/asus/</link><description>Recent content in Asus on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 17:44:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/asus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Remote Bandwidth Stats</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/08/21/remote-bandwidth-stats/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 17:44:24 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/08/21/remote-bandwidth-stats/</guid><description>This post is about my open source remote bandwidth usage stats logger project.
I've been wanting to log the internet bandwidth usage at my home for quite some time since I don't really find the stats put out by my ISP to be completely accurate. But I have multiple devices at home that access the internet so it is not feasible to install a bandwidth monitor individually on all these devices as I'd still need to add up all logs and many of such devices don't even have a way to install a monitoring software installed (e.</description></item><item><title>Firefly / sqlite error "unable to open database file" Solution</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/26/firefly-sqlite-error-unable-to-open-database-file-solution/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2010 18:11:40 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/26/firefly-sqlite-error-unable-to-open-database-file-solution/</guid><description>Recently I came across a weird error while trying to run firefly itunes server (mt-daapd) on my router (Asus wl-500w). It had something to do with sqlite and gave a vague message &amp;ldquo;Unable to open database file&amp;rdquo;. After going bonkers for a short time, I solved it and this is how.
One of my hard disks crashed recently and unfortunately it was the one I had connected to my router to serve media to me all over the house (through PS3/laptop) or when I travel (through laptop/phone).</description></item><item><title>Cannot Change Channel Problem With Asus WL-500W</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/13/cannot-change-channel-problem-with-asus-wl-500w/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 12:16:44 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/13/cannot-change-channel-problem-with-asus-wl-500w/</guid><description>Recently I found an issue with my asus wl-500w wi-fi router that I wasn't able to change the channel on which it was transmitting. I moved to a new location which was totally jam-packed with other wi-fi networks using same channel as mine which was hampeing my connection. I tried for umpteen number of times. Changing the channel through the web configuration did not give any error but I found that it was still transmitting at channel 1.</description></item><item><title>Shutdown Script For Asus WL-500W With Oleg Firmware</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/09/shutdown-script-asus-wl-500w-oleg-firmware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 13:30:04 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/09/shutdown-script-asus-wl-500w-oleg-firmware/</guid><description>If you have an Asus WL-500W, the DIYers&amp;rsquo; favourite wireless router, and have installed the Oleg custom firmware on it, then you would have set up a shutdown script for it, that allows your router to shut down gracefully. This is especially important if you have a USB hard disk attached to it. There are many such scripts available in Oleg's firmware that you can tweak. All of these reside in &amp;ldquo;/usr/local/sbin/&amp;quot;.</description></item><item><title>The Solution To Your Problem Is Out There .... Somewhere</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/12/03/the-solution-to-your-problem-is-out-there-somewhere/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2008 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/12/03/the-solution-to-your-problem-is-out-there-somewhere/</guid><description>I got hold of a new Asus WL-500W router for me (Pics &amp;amp; specs coming up soon). The router has open source firmware so people can develop applications for it. One such app (ADOS) is that allows you to configure the router to download stuff directly to a hard disk (connected to router through USB) without the need of keeping the PC switched on. One of the app users reported the following error (Click on the pic to enlarge) that he got while using the app.</description></item></channel></rss>