<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Asus WL-500W firmware on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/asus-wl-500w-firmware/</link><description>Recent content in Asus WL-500W firmware on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 12:16:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/asus-wl-500w-firmware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cannot Change Channel Problem With Asus WL-500W</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/13/cannot-change-channel-problem-with-asus-wl-500w/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 12:16:44 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/07/13/cannot-change-channel-problem-with-asus-wl-500w/</guid><description>Recently I found an issue with my asus wl-500w wi-fi router that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to change the channel on which it was transmitting. I moved to a new location which was totally jam-packed with other wi-fi networks using same channel as mine which was hampeing my connection. I tried for umpteen number of times. Changing the channel through the web configuration did not give any error but I found that it was still transmitting at channel 1.</description></item><item><title>Shutdown Script For Asus WL-500W With Oleg Firmware</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/09/shutdown-script-asus-wl-500w-oleg-firmware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 13:30:04 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/03/09/shutdown-script-asus-wl-500w-oleg-firmware/</guid><description>If you have an Asus WL-500W, the DIYers' favourite wireless router, and have installed the Oleg custom firmware on it, then you would have set up a shutdown script for it, that allows your router to shut down gracefully. This is especially important if you have a USB hard disk attached to it. There are many such scripts available in Oleg&amp;rsquo;s firmware that you can tweak. All of these reside in &amp;ldquo;/usr/local/sbin/&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>[TIP] Install Twonky on Asus WL-500W with stock firmware</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/23/tip-install-twonky-on-asus-wl-500w-with-stock-firmware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2009 06:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/23/tip-install-twonky-on-asus-wl-500w-with-stock-firmware/</guid><description>Asus WL-500W is a greate wi-fi router with lots of features, one of them being able to use it as a media server to serve movies/songs over your network from a hard disk connected directly to it through USB. But the media server that is included in the official firmware leaves a lot to be desired. If you are a fan of twonky, all you would have heard so far would have been that to use it on your router, you&amp;rsquo;d have to change your firmware over to a non-official one.</description></item></channel></rss>