<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nexus One Flashlight Without Rooting on</title><link>/tags/nexus-one-flashlight-without-rooting/</link><description>Recent content in Nexus One Flashlight Without Rooting on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2010 09:31:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/nexus-one-flashlight-without-rooting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Camera LED As Flashlight on Non-Rooted Android Phones</title><link>/2010/07/30/camera-led-flashlight-non-rooted-android-phones/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2010 09:31:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/07/30/camera-led-flashlight-non-rooted-android-phones/</guid><description>We all know that Android does not allow the camera LED to be controlled directly from apps and hence, you cannot use the camera LED as a Torch or Flashlight unless you are rooted. There are many flashlight apps on the Android Market Place but none of them will work for you if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a rooted phone. BUT this changed recently. I use a brilliant app called &amp;ldquo;quick settings&amp;rdquo; which keeps an icon in the notification bar and I can pull it down and change any settings without leaving other apps.</description><content>&lt;p>We all know that Android does not allow the camera LED to be controlled directly from apps and hence, you cannot use the camera LED as a Torch or Flashlight unless you are rooted. There are many flashlight apps on the Android Market Place but none of them will work for you if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a rooted phone. BUT this changed recently. I use a brilliant app called &amp;ldquo;quick settings&amp;rdquo; which keeps an icon in the notification bar and I can pull it down and change any settings without leaving other apps. It has a flashlight function but so far it used to work by turning on the screen with a white screen, which was a less than ideal solution. I upgraded to the latest version a few days ago (1.9.4 p1). While messing around with the settings, I wandered across the flashlight settings which allows you to choose what kind of flashlight you want. Now, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure whether this setting was present earlier or not but I decided to give it a try and chose LED instead of screen (Screenshot below):&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/img/uploads/quick-settings-flash-android-settings.png">&lt;img src="/img/uploads/quick-settings-flash-android-settings-thumb.png" alt="Android Quick Settings Flashlight LED Settings">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once done, I went back to the main screen and pressed the flashlight icon in the top right (Screen shot below) and voila! my camera LED switched on. I&amp;rsquo;m a happy camper now as this is a life saver many times. Try this out for yourself by searching for &amp;ldquo;Quick Settings&amp;rdquo; in the market and let me know if it works on your phone too (mine is a nexus one).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/img/uploads/quick-settings-flash-android-main-screen.png">&lt;img src="/img/uploads/quick-settings-flash-android-main-screen-thumb.png" alt="Android Quick Settings">&lt;/a>&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>