<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Paypal on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/paypal/</link><description>Recent content in Paypal on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2011 19:30:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/paypal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Paypal India Goes Even More Downhill. Get Your Money Out</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/01/28/paypal-india-goes-even-more-downhill-get-your-money-out/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2011 19:30:03 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/01/28/paypal-india-goes-even-more-downhill-get-your-money-out/</guid><description>Just received an email from Paypal India. The main parts are these:
With effect from 1 March 2011, you are required to comply with the requirements set out in the notification of the Reserve Bank of India governing the processing and settlement of export-related receipts facilitated by online payment gateways (&amp;ldquo;RBI Guidelines&amp;rdquo;). In order to comply with the RBI Guidelines, our user agreement in India will be amended for the following services as follows:</description><content>&lt;p>Just received an email from Paypal India. The main parts are these:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>With effect from 1 March 2011&lt;/strong>, you are required to comply with the requirements set out in the notification of the Reserve Bank of India governing the processing and settlement of export-related receipts facilitated by online payment gateways (&amp;ldquo;RBI Guidelines&amp;rdquo;).
In order to comply with the RBI Guidelines, our user agreement in India will be amended for the following services as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Any balance in and all future payments into your PayPal account may not be used to buy goods or services and must be transferred to your bank account in India within 7 days from the receipt of confirmation from the buyer in respect of the goods or services; and&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Export-related payments for goods and services into your PayPal account may not exceed US$500 per transaction.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>So no more buying stuff. It is only useful for getting payments now (and that too &amp;lt;500$ per transaction). I don&amp;rsquo;t know what to make of this but my advice is this: &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>Get your money out of there while you still can&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo;. There is no telling what PayFoe will do next (or will be made to do by our sad Government).&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>