<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Angry Birds Without Ads on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/angry-birds-without-ads/</link><description>Recent content in Angry Birds Without Ads on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 13:28:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/angry-birds-without-ads/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ad-Free (Paid) Angry Birds For Android</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/12/02/ad-free-paid-angry-birds-android/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 13:28:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/12/02/ad-free-paid-angry-birds-android/</guid><description>&lt;p>Rovio Mobile has been pretty considerate for the Android lovers and has released their Angry Birds game for free on the Android market. Many people love it but quite a few are annoyed by it because Rovio chose to monetize it by in-game advertisements, and that too placed at awkward places which can hinder the gameplay. Many users have also reported that they are being forced to view video ads as well these days. Another drawback is that if there is no network connection (e.g. if you are in a no-signal area, roamin, in-flight, or just don&amp;rsquo;t have a data plan), then the game won&amp;rsquo;t run at all. So far all the queries about this or pleas to have a paid app have been skirted around by Rovio. But this will soon be history.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>Rovio Mobile has been pretty considerate for the Android lovers and has released their Angry Birds game for free on the Android market. Many people love it but quite a few are annoyed by it because Rovio chose to monetize it by in-game advertisements, and that too placed at awkward places which can hinder the gameplay. Many users have also reported that they are being forced to view video ads as well these days. Another drawback is that if there is no network connection (e.g. if you are in a no-signal area, roamin, in-flight, or just don&amp;rsquo;t have a data plan), then the game won&amp;rsquo;t run at all. So far all the queries about this or pleas to have a paid app have been skirted around by Rovio. But this will soon be history.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of my friends at work received an email recently from Rovio announcing the new &amp;ldquo;Seasons&amp;rdquo; edition for Christmas and Halloween levels. But that is not the important thing, something else is. Read this:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Angry Birds Seasons Available For Android&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, we bring you Angry Birds Seasons, a special edition spin-off of Angry Birds!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Season?s Greedings consists of 25 daily surprises for fans of Angry Birds to enjoy while counting down the days until Christmas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Included in the game is also the 45-level Halloween special edition, now packaged as a separate episode called Trick Or Treat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Angry Birds Seasons is available for Android devices through GetJar and Android Market.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Payment option and performance  upgrades to follow&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are still working on two things for the Angry Birds games on Android:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, we are bringing a graphically lighter option in the game, to enable better performance on older phones.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Second, we will introduce a payment system to opt-out of advertising.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Both of these upgrades will be included in later updates.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>So as you can see, Rovio is about to bring out a paid option for Android folks as well so that we can kill those pigs in peace :)&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>