<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>I-Mate Ultimate 8502 on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/i-mate-ultimate-8502/</link><description>Recent content in I-Mate Ultimate 8502 on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2008 05:08:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/i-mate-ultimate-8502/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SmartPhones/NextGen Telephony: News That Matters</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/14/smartphonesnextgen-telephony-news-that-matters/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2008 05:08:10 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/14/smartphonesnextgen-telephony-news-that-matters/</guid><description>Just wanted to share some pieces that generated a variety of &amp;ldquo;hmmm&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;ahaa&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;wow&amp;rdquo; from me:
China Mobile set to trial LTE:
China Mobile said it will join Vodafone Group plc and Verizon Wireless in an ongoing trial of LTE technology…….The trials &amp;ndash; which include three powerhouse network operators &amp;ndash; underscore the momentum LTE is gaining as a leading 4G technology possibility vs. WiMAX and Ultra Mobile Broadband.
&amp;ldquo;HMMM&amp;rdquo; - U go LTE!</description><content>&lt;p>Just wanted to share some pieces that generated a variety of &amp;ldquo;hmmm&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;ahaa&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;wow&amp;rdquo; from me:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.rcrnews.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20080213/FREE/837538685/1002/rss01">China Mobile set to trial LTE&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>China Mobile said it will join Vodafone Group plc and Verizon Wireless in an ongoing trial of LTE technology…….The trials &amp;ndash; which include three powerhouse network operators &amp;ndash; underscore the momentum LTE is gaining as a leading 4G technology possibility vs. WiMAX and Ultra Mobile Broadband.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;HMMM&amp;rdquo; - U go LTE!!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.telstra.com.au/abouttelstra/media/announcements_article.cfm?ObjectID=41758">Telstra Launches the i-mate Ultimate 8502 and 9502 in Australia&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Telstra and i-mate have today launched the i-mate™ Ultimate 8502 and i-mate™ Ultimate 9502. Telstra is the first operator to deploy these devices globally and both devices will be exclusive in Australia to Telstra customers. Building on a five-year partnership which has seen the successful launch of 10 i-mate™ devices on the Telstra network, Telstra has teamed up with i-mate™ again to release the Ultimate mobile devices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;AHA&amp;rdquo; - So, they are not vaporware after all :) !!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://android-developers.blogspot.com/2008/02/android-sdk-m5-rc14-now-available.html">Android SDK m5-rc14 now available&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>*&lt;strong>New user interface&lt;/strong> - As I mentioned when we introduced the m3 version of the Android SDK, we&amp;rsquo;re continuing to refine the UI that&amp;rsquo;s available for Android. m5-rc14 replaces the previous placeholder with a new UI, but as before, work on it is still in-progress.&lt;br>
&lt;em>&lt;strong>Layout animations&lt;/strong> - Developers can now create layout animations for their applications using the capabilities introduced in the android.view.animation package. Check out the LayoutAnimation&lt;/em>.java files in the APIDemos sample code for examples of how this works.&lt;br>
*&lt;strong>Geo-coding&lt;/strong> - android.location.Geocoder enables developers to forward and reverse geo-code (i.e. translate an address into a coordinate and vice-versa), and also search for businesses.&lt;br>
*&lt;strong>New media codecs&lt;/strong> - The MediaPlayer class has added support for the OGG Vorbis, MIDI, XMF, iMelody, RTTL/RTX, and OTA audio file formats.&lt;br>
*&lt;strong>Updated Eclipse plug-in&lt;/strong> - A new version of ADT is available and provides improvements to the Android developer experience. In particular, check out the new Android Manifest editor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;WOW&amp;rdquo; What else can I say?!!&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>