<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Computers India on</title><link>/tags/computers-india/</link><description>Recent content in Computers India on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2009 18:05:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/computers-india/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Paradise For Overclockers, Gamers and PC Enthusiasts In India</title><link>/2009/12/07/overclockers-pc-enthusiasts-gamers-india/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2009 18:05:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/12/07/overclockers-pc-enthusiasts-gamers-india/</guid><description>This is just to let you know that a few of my friends have started Overclocked, a haven for PC enthusiasts in India. Overclocked is an online store for the people who like to stretch the performance of their machines to the maximum. They store a lot of high end computer stuff that isn&amp;rsquo;t easy to find in India and that too for a reasonable price. They also assemble mean gaming machines while giving you quite a bang for your buck with gauranteed satisfaction, shipped anywhere in India, and that&amp;rsquo;s not all, they can personalize it too with a variety of custom modifications (I really like their laser engravings).</description><content>&lt;p>This is just to let you know that a few of my friends have started &lt;a href="http://www.overclocked.in">Overclocked&lt;/a>, a haven for PC enthusiasts in India. Overclocked is an online store for the people who like to stretch the performance of their machines to the maximum. They store a lot of high end computer stuff that isn&amp;rsquo;t easy to find in India and that too for a reasonable price. They also assemble mean gaming machines while giving you quite a bang for your buck with gauranteed satisfaction, shipped anywhere in India, and that&amp;rsquo;s not all, they can personalize it too with a variety of custom modifications (I really like their laser engravings).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apart from the computer hardware, they also sell a lot of games (Primarily PC but consoles as well, and that too for a cool discount from the MRP, again shipped anywhere in India). They also have a &lt;a href="http://www.overclocked.in/forums">forum&lt;/a> where people can hang out and discuss how to eek out that last bit from their PCs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do check them out. I&amp;rsquo;m sure you will like the stuff they have on offer and if you have any comments/suggestions or queries, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to contact them via their contact page or the forums. I&amp;rsquo;m sure they will be glad to listen to you. I&amp;rsquo;d say that a word of kudos will be great as these guys are doing this along with their full time professions and such places are hard to find in India :)&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>