<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PSN on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/psn/</link><description>Recent content in PSN on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 09:25:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/psn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PSN Ban-Wave Phishing Scam</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/02/17/psn-ban-wave-phishing-scam/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 09:25:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2011/02/17/psn-ban-wave-phishing-scam/</guid><description>&lt;p>**Update: **I did some more digging and the email and the links actually seem to be legitimate. Good news for many, but bad for those who actually got this email.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BEWARE!! In wake of the recent announcement of a potential Playstation Network ban wave by Sony for the people who are hacking it&amp;rsquo;s gaming console PS3, some nefarious elements seem to be using this as an opportunity to pry on your PSN passwords. Many folks are receiving emails like below:&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>**Update: **I did some more digging and the email and the links actually seem to be legitimate. Good news for many, but bad for those who actually got this email.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BEWARE!! In wake of the recent announcement of a potential Playstation Network ban wave by Sony for the people who are hacking it&amp;rsquo;s gaming console PS3, some nefarious elements seem to be using this as an opportunity to pry on your PSN passwords. Many folks are receiving emails like below:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Notice: Unauthorized circumvention devices for the PlayStation®3 system have been recently released by hackers for the PlayStation®3 system. These devices permit the use of unauthorized or pirated software. Use of such devices or software violates the terms of your &amp;ldquo;System Software License Agreement for the PlayStation®3 System&amp;rdquo; and the &amp;ldquo;Terms of Services and User Agreement&amp;rdquo; for the PlayStation®Network/Qriocity and its Community Code of Conduct provisions.   In addition, copying or playing pirated software is a violation of International Copyright Laws. A circumvention device and/or unauthorized or pirated software currently resides on your PlayStation®3 system. Immediately cease use and remove all circumvention devices and delete all unauthorized or pirated software from your PlayStation®3 system. Failure to do so will result in termination of your access to the PlayStation®Network and access to Qriocity services through your&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PlayStation®3 system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This email has been delivered from a send-only address.   Please do not reply to this message. If you have any questions, contact Consumer Services using the following link: &lt;a href="http://playstation.i">http://playstation.i&lt;/a>&amp;hellip;HvEHWTPlTnHqJPH&lt;/p>
&lt;p>LEGAL&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;PlayStation&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;PLAYSTATION&amp;rdquo;, and the &amp;ldquo;PS&amp;rdquo; Family logo are registered trademarks of Sony Computer Entertainment LLC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2011 Sony Computer Entertainment America LLC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>919 E. Hillsdale Blvd., Foster City, CA 94404&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I have intentionally removed the complete link in the email to save anyone else from falling into the trap. Basically this email (and it&amp;rsquo;s many variations) take you to a site which looks like Sony US site but it is not. So, do not put your password into it. If you have already clicked on the link, then change your psn password and remove any credit card info linked to it, immediately.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>