<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>WM5 on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/wm5/</link><description>Recent content in WM5 on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2008 08:43:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/wm5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hack:Disabling the Message Box In Oxios Memory Apps (Windows Mobile)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/15/hackdisabling-the-message-box-in-oxios-memory-apps-windows-mobile/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2008 08:43:29 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/15/hackdisabling-the-message-box-in-oxios-memory-apps-windows-mobile/</guid><description>**Update: **Modified the &amp;ldquo;Oxios Hibernate&amp;rdquo; app as well on public demand. Please redownload the below mentioned package. It now has Oxios Close as well as Oxios Hibernate.
Oxios developed a very useful tool for Windows Mobile (WM2003/5/6/6.1) called &amp;ldquo;Oxios Memory&amp;rdquo; sometime ago. On running it, it&amp;rsquo;ll flush your RAM (kind of) and recover substantial amounts of memory that can be used by the currently program. It is so good at this that many people run it regularly on their phones, and most of them want to run it in an automated mode (through a scheduler or a script).</description><content>&lt;p>**Update: **Modified the &amp;ldquo;Oxios Hibernate&amp;rdquo; app as well on public demand. Please redownload the below mentioned package. It now has Oxios Close as well as Oxios Hibernate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oxios developed a very useful tool for Windows Mobile (WM2003/5/6/6.1) called &amp;ldquo;Oxios Memory&amp;rdquo; sometime ago. On running it, it&amp;rsquo;ll flush your RAM (kind of) and recover substantial amounts of memory that can be used by the currently program. It is so good at this that many people run it regularly on their phones, and most of them want to run it in an automated mode (through a scheduler or a script). But the problem (so far) was that it generates a Message Box at the end for which the user has to press &amp;ldquo;OK&amp;rdquo; button to make it go away. There is no known way of disabling this message box and many attempts to work around it by scripting the &amp;ldquo;press OK&amp;rdquo; action have been very unreliable at best. Hence, it took it upon me today to remove this nagging problem and 5 minutes later we have a &amp;ldquo;clean&amp;rdquo; Oxios Memory.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, no more nagging prompts :)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Feel free to spread the message but please don&amp;rsquo;t hotlink to the file as it is anyways disabled. Provide a link to this page instead)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you like it, then &lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://digg.com/software/Hack_Disable_the_Message_Box_In_Oxios_Memory_Windows_Mobile">DIGG IT by clicking here&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> or choose your favourite submission engine from the links below the post :-)&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>TIP: Make Those Linux Samba Shares Accessible From Windows Mobile</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/30/tip-make-those-linux-samba-shares-accessible-from-windows-mobile/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2008 10:30:12 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/30/tip-make-those-linux-samba-shares-accessible-from-windows-mobile/</guid><description>If you have ever needed to share files between your Linux and Windows computers, you have obviously used Samba, and have been quite happy with the way it seamlessly provides access to and from shared folders/files from Windows and Linux. However, many people complain that although their smb/Samba shares are accessible from Windows, they are not able to do the same with their Windows Mobile devices. e.g., using a tool called &amp;ldquo;Resco Explorer&amp;rdquo; on Windows Mobile, all they get while searching for their linux based Samba shares is the following screenshot:</description><content>&lt;p>If you have ever needed to share files between your Linux and Windows computers, you have obviously used &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Samba_(software)">Samba&lt;/a>, and have been quite happy with the way it seamlessly provides access to and from shared folders/files from Windows and Linux. However, many people complain that although their smb/Samba shares are accessible from Windows, they are not able to do the same with their Windows Mobile devices. e.g., using a tool called &amp;ldquo;Resco Explorer&amp;rdquo; on Windows Mobile, all they get while searching for their linux based Samba shares is the following screenshot:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/1_cant_find_computer.jpg" alt="Cannot Find Computer on Network">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, there is no big magic trick to get an access to those shares, as they are already accessibly. You just need to do one more teeny little step to access them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The trick is that on Windows Mobile it will not detect your computer as having a shareable folder and will not show it, and it will thus not show a list of shared folders. So, what you need to do is enter the path to the folder you want to access. e.g.: If your computer&amp;rsquo;s name is &amp;ldquo;MyComp&amp;rdquo; and the folder you want to access is &amp;ldquo;MyFolder&amp;rdquo;, then you need to give the path &amp;ldquo;\MyComp\MyFolder&amp;rdquo; to the application on Windows Mobile from which you are trying to access your shares and it&amp;rsquo;ll connect without any problems. Of course, it&amp;rsquo;ll ask you for your username/pwd for which you need to enter your linux user name and password. Below screenshots tell you how to do this with Resco Explorer, however the same method can be used for other applications like Total Commander, Windows Mobile File Explorer, etc as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Enter Path and click share.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/2_enter_full_path.jpg" alt="Enter Full Path">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>Enter User Name / Password&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/3_enter_user_password.jpg" alt="Enter User Name And Password">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>Its done :-)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/4_its_done.jpg" alt="Access To Share Is Done">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me know if you face any issues with this.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Project: Windows Mobile Tool ShantzTodayChanger Updated to version 1.53</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/22/project-windows-mobile-tool-shantztodaychanger-updated-to-version-153/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2008 20:49:17 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/22/project-windows-mobile-tool-shantztodaychanger-updated-to-version-153/</guid><description>ShantzTodayChanger is a little tool written by me for your Windows Mobile based phones (WM5/WM6) which will cycle ur today background or theme after a set interval of time. It has a lot of features and options and you can even use it to achieve something other than changing wallpapers as well (e.g. running applications at set times) but that depends on your imagination.
Changes in this version:
1.53 - 23-March-08 -&amp;gt; RECOMMENDED UPDATE</description><content>&lt;p>ShantzTodayChanger is a little tool written by me for your Windows Mobile based phones (WM5/WM6) which will cycle ur today background or theme after a set interval of time. It has a lot of features and options and you can even use it to achieve something other than changing wallpapers as well (e.g. running applications at set times) but that depends on your imagination.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Changes in this version:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1.53 - 23-March-08 -&amp;gt; RECOMMENDED UPDATE&lt;br>
i)Theme Color Detection has been improved a lot. Should work much more accurately now.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Windows Mobile: Missed Call Made Easy (Indian Cell Owners Rejoice)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/18/windows-mobile-missed-call-made-easy-indian-cell-owners-rejoice/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2008 15:12:34 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/18/windows-mobile-missed-call-made-easy-indian-cell-owners-rejoice/</guid><description>Perdida = Missed Call (in Spanish)
Missed Call = Ubiquitous Necessity (atleast in India)
Enter: cPerdidas -&amp;gt; A Windows Mobile program (works with WM5 as well as WM6) that will allow you to make missed calls to anyone you desire. Just config your country code, select the contact and &amp;ldquo;Hacer Perdida!&amp;rdquo; (Make the missed call) and your contact will get the missed call on his device. The only change is that the program will cut the call even before he can hear his phone ring.</description><content>&lt;p>Perdida = Missed Call (in Spanish)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Missed Call = Ubiquitous Necessity (atleast in India)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Enter: &lt;a href="http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=377475">cPerdidas&lt;/a> -&amp;gt; A Windows Mobile program (works with WM5 as well as WM6) that will allow you to make missed calls to anyone you desire. Just config your country code, select the contact and &amp;ldquo;Hacer Perdida!&amp;rdquo; (Make the missed call) and your contact will get the missed call on his device. The only change is that the program will cut the call even before he can hear his phone ring. So, whenever he looks at his phone, he&amp;rsquo;ll know that you called. Hmmm, pretty useful for times when you just want to send your loved one a note that you missed them, without disturbing him/her in a meeting and, of course, without spending a penny, or waiting with your fingers clenched onto to End button tighter than a F1 driver&amp;rsquo;s fingers on the pit lane speed limiter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note: Though the original app is in spanish, it has support for adding other languages, so for English support (and easily installable cab format), look at &lt;a href="http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=377475&amp;amp;page=3">this page&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Boring Meetings? CallJockey To The Rescue</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/19/boring-meetings-calljockey-to-the-rescue/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2008 04:43:19 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/19/boring-meetings-calljockey-to-the-rescue/</guid><description>Stuck in another boring meeting? You have a way out now, because connectivetools have released their app CallJockey, which can simulate fake incoming calls. What&amp;rsquo;s more, you can select the name, phone number or one of your saved contacts from whom the fake call will appear to be coming, plus you can define the time when you want it to ring. The only limitation is that it is available only for WM5 smarphones (WM6 Standard), i.</description><content>&lt;p>Stuck in another boring meeting? You have a way out now, because connectivetools have released their app &lt;a href="http://www.connectivetools.com/calljockey.html">CallJockey&lt;/a>, which can simulate fake incoming calls. What&amp;rsquo;s more, you can select the name, phone number or one of your saved contacts from whom the fake call will appear to be coming, plus you can define the time when you want it to ring. The only limitation is that it is available only for WM5 smarphones (WM6 Standard), i.e., windows mobile phones without a touchscreen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AND, it is **FREE **but only till March 1 under a promotion they are running, so go &lt;a href="http://www.connectivetools.com/calljockey.html">get it&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/calljockey1.jpg" alt="Calljockey1"> &lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/calljockey2.jpg" alt="Calljockey2">&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Project: ShantzTodayChanger (Windows Mobile Tool To Cycle Themes/Wallpapers Automatically)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/project-shantztodaychanger-windows-mobile-tool-to-cycle-themeswallpapers-automatically/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 19:45:07 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/project-shantztodaychanger-windows-mobile-tool-to-cycle-themeswallpapers-automatically/</guid><description>The newly launched [&amp;ldquo;Projects&amp;rdquo;] section is hereby inaugarated with a Windows Mobile Tool developed by me, called “[ShantzTodayChanger]”. This is a little tool for your Windows Mobile based phones (Compatible with WM5/WM6 but not WM2003) which will cycle ur today background or theme after a set interval of time. It has a lot of features and options that you can discover by reading the text below. And you can even use this options to achieve something other than changing wallpapers as well but that depends on your imagination.</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/ShantzTodayChanger.jpg" alt="ShantzTodayChanger Config Screenshot">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The newly launched [&amp;ldquo;Projects&amp;rdquo;] section is hereby inaugarated with a Windows Mobile Tool developed by me, called “[ShantzTodayChanger]”. This is a little tool for your Windows Mobile based phones (Compatible with WM5/WM6 but not WM2003) which will cycle ur today background or theme after a set interval of time. It has a lot of features and options that you can discover by reading the text below. And you can even use this options to achieve something other than changing wallpapers as well but that depends on your imagination. !&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>ShantzTodayChanger</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/shantztodaychanger/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 13:41:30 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/shantztodaychanger/</guid><description>Intro:
This is a little tool for your Windows Mobile based phones (Compatible with WM5/WM6 but not WM2003) which will cycle ur today background or theme after a set interval of time. It has a lot of features and options that you can discover by reading the text below. And you can even use this options to achieve something other than changing wallpapers as well but that depends on your imagination.</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/ShantzTodayChanger.jpg" alt="ShantzTodayChanger Config Screenshot">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Intro:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a little tool for your Windows Mobile based phones (Compatible with WM5/WM6 but not WM2003) which will cycle ur today background or theme after a set interval of time. It has a lot of features and options that you can discover by reading the text below. And you can even use this options to achieve something other than changing wallpapers as well but that depends on your imagination. ;)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**UPDATE: **I&amp;rsquo;ve released the source code of ShantzTodayChanger since I&amp;rsquo;m not getting much time to work on it. You may download the code from the attached zip file above. I’ll still be available for questions, discussions, explanations etc about it if needed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You are free to copy, modify and redistribute it. Only thing that I ask of you are that:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You retain all credits for me and my website in the source code, final product, and other material (readme etc) intact.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Also, please provide a linkback to the original home page of shantztodaychanger if you redistribute it through some other site, otherwise I’ll be happy to host your modified versions here.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You also have to release the modified source code in its entirety.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Download:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Usage: **&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Make a folder on ur device (preferably not on storage card.) and extract all the files (mainly ShantzTodayChanger.exe, TdyChangerCfg.exe, gsgetfile.dll (might not be visible to u depending on ur explorer settings) and Readme.htm) to this folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>IMP: Do not rename any files.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Run the TdyChangerCfg.exe.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Set options through the dialog that opens and press apply button (Pressing the native WM OK button will discard all your changes)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Options:
i)Choose image type (.gif.jpg.png) or theme(.tsk) to be cycled.
ii)If the input files (images or themes) are not in the folder where exes are kept, then you can check the box (underneath the .gif option) and give the &amp;ldquo;FULL and ABSOLUTE&amp;rdquo; path of where the files are kept. You can either input the path thru keyboard or choose it graphically by pressing the button (&amp;hellip;) next to it.
iii)If you want to run a file after every cycle interval, check the corresponding box and provide the &amp;ldquo;FULL and ABSOLUTE&amp;rdquo; path of the file to be run. You can either input the path thru keyboard or choose it graphically by pressing the button (&amp;hellip;) next to it.
iv) If you want some files to be avoided during cycling, put a file mask. The program will look for this mask to appear anywhere in the name of the files and will avoid it if found. (Wildcards are not supported. Choose time option has to be checked for this to work)
v) Choose the period for which mask option has to be used. If you choose a time period and leave mask as empty, then during that time no cycling will be done. If you want to avoid some files all the time, then time period should be chosen to cover all 24 hrs of the day.
vi)enter the desired interval between cycling of images\themes.
vii)If you choose a period for the mask, another check box (Consider mask period for exe also) will be enabled. Checking this box will mean that the specified exe will be run only if an image\theme is changed during that cycle. If you dont check this, then exe will be run after every cycle even if there is no change in the image\theme.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When you want to stop the cycling, press &amp;ldquo;STOP Cycling&amp;rdquo; button.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>**Additional Notes: **&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>The GUI for configuration has not been optimized for square screen devices, so you need to make some guesswork and use hardware keyboard for input but the changer program itself will run fine.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Doesnt have to be running constantly. So saves resources when not active.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Survives soft resets as well.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Even takes care of the situation if your phone is off when the time to cycle is reached. Will cycle as soon as ur phone comes back on in this situation.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>**Planned Updates: **
i) Suggestions invited. I have a lot of updates in mind but will incorporate those only which are requested by you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Known Issues: **
i) If the mask option is selected, then in a very particular situation, the app will miss a cycle.
This can be taken care of but not in my priority list because this can be fixed only by rewriting the complete cycling code which is quite a bit. So, will fix it if I get some time from my other projects.
ii) If after maknig the configuration, you see the screen flash for a second at the right times, but the backfround doesn&amp;rsquo;t change, then do this:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Go to : Settings&amp;hellip;today&amp;hellip;.appearance&lt;/li>
&lt;li>un-check &amp;ldquo;Use this picture as background&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>start the program using &amp;ldquo;startTodayChanger.lnk&amp;rdquo; or TdyChangerCfg (Apply button)
(Thnx to CWKJ for reporting this bug and fix, and to eric for reminding me about it)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>**End Note: **
Like every software, this one is also bound to have bugs, please report it asap.
Though ShantzTodayChanger does not run continuously but sometimes some apps that close all processes automatically (like SPB backup) might clash in schedule with ShantzTodayChanger and close it when it starts to run. In such a case (which is quite unlikely), the app might not be able to set a notification for next cycle, so if u face this situation, then run the config again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Version History: **&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1.53 - 23-March-08 -&amp;gt; RECOMMENDED UPDATE
i)Theme Color Detection has been improved a lot. Should work much more accurately now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1.52 - 11-Aug-07 -&amp;gt;
i) Fixed another bug for the &amp;ldquo;time period&amp;rdquo; option.
ii) Made a little optimization in the code.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1.51 - 05-Aug-07 -&amp;gt;
i) Fixed a bug which prevented the &amp;ldquo;time period&amp;rdquo; option from working properly.
ii) Fixed a bug where wallpapers might not change if certain particular themes were installed before change cycle happens
iii) Fixed a bug where the time period option was not remembered properly by the GUI.
iv) Added option to allow user to choose whether to run the user specified file (exe\lnk) after every cycle interval only if there was a change in image\theme during that cycle.
v) Made a few small changes to the GUI to prevent users from making incorrect settings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1.50 - 29-July-07 -&amp;gt;MAJOR UPDATE
i) Added option to specify a mask to avoid files having that mask
ii) Added option to specify the time period during which the mask has to be considered
iii) Added code to ensure that if mask is empty and a period is chosen, then no rotation is done during that period.
iv) Added option to run a user specified file after every cycle interval.
v) Fixed bug where the jpg and png options were not working earlier.
vi) Clicking help button now opens help in Pocket Internet Explorer.
vii) Fixed many more subtle bugs that manifest themselves and very peculiar situations.
viii) Optimized the code a bit at a few places.
ix) Also see &amp;ldquo;Known Issues&amp;rdquo; section above.
x) Removed the &amp;ldquo;append to previous info&amp;rdquo; box as now the app remembers old info correctly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1.33 - 18-July-07 -&amp;gt;
i)Added code to select the input path graphically. It is a bit of workaround though. To select an input folder, just select any file inside it in the select folder dialog.
ii)TdyChgrCfg now shows you the previous settings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1.32 - 21-Jun-07 -&amp;gt;
i) Fixed a bug where sometimes on cycling themes, colors change but images do not change.
ii) Added a measure to avoid running multiple instances (just as a precaution)
iii)Added code to avoid losing notifications if phone is reset too early after running the program&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1.31 - 20-Jun-07 -&amp;gt;Fixed 2 bugs:
i) A notification bug where old notification is not deleted
ii) A bug where cycle interval value is not correctly read from the GUI&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1.3 - 19-Jun-07 -&amp;gt;
i)Added option to make partial changes to previously entered information.
ii)Fine-Tuned the Theme Color support algo. Now, theme colors should be almost 95% same as calculated by windows mobile while applying theme.
iii)Did some code optimization&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1.2 - 19-Jun-07 -&amp;gt;Major Update:
i)Added Theme Support. Changing of system colors as per theme is also supported (which is not done by any other program IIRC)
ii)Added option to keep input images\themes in a separate folder
iii)Provided a GUI Configuration module
iv)Provided option to choose between gif\jpg\png\tsk to be cycled.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1.11 - 12-Jun-07-&amp;gt;Fixed another bug with notification queue&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1.1 - 12-Jun-07 -&amp;gt; Fixed the bug that causes WM5/WM6 devices not to cycle wallpapers in certain conditions&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1.0 - 10-Jun-07 -&amp;gt; Initial Release&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Credits:
daxliniere/wacky.banana -&amp;gt; For asking to make the tool and their inputs
SeanFromSoCal/200mpx -&amp;gt; For their inputs&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>