<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>WM5 on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/wm5/</link><description>Recent content in WM5 on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2008 08:43:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/wm5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hack:Disabling the Message Box In Oxios Memory Apps (Windows Mobile)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/15/hackdisabling-the-message-box-in-oxios-memory-apps-windows-mobile/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2008 08:43:29 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/15/hackdisabling-the-message-box-in-oxios-memory-apps-windows-mobile/</guid><description>**Update: **Modified the &amp;ldquo;Oxios Hibernate&amp;rdquo; app as well on public demand. Please redownload the below mentioned package. It now has Oxios Close as well as Oxios Hibernate.
Oxios developed a very useful tool for Windows Mobile (WM2003/5/6/6.1) called &amp;ldquo;Oxios Memory&amp;rdquo; sometime ago. On running it, it&amp;rsquo;ll flush your RAM (kind of) and recover substantial amounts of memory that can be used by the currently program. It is so good at this that many people run it regularly on their phones, and most of them want to run it in an automated mode (through a scheduler or a script).</description></item><item><title>TIP: Make Those Linux Samba Shares Accessible From Windows Mobile</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/30/tip-make-those-linux-samba-shares-accessible-from-windows-mobile/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2008 10:30:12 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/30/tip-make-those-linux-samba-shares-accessible-from-windows-mobile/</guid><description>If you have ever needed to share files between your Linux and Windows computers, you have obviously used Samba, and have been quite happy with the way it seamlessly provides access to and from shared folders/files from Windows and Linux. However, many people complain that although their smb/Samba shares are accessible from Windows, they are not able to do the same with their Windows Mobile devices. e.g., using a tool called &amp;ldquo;Resco Explorer&amp;rdquo; on Windows Mobile, all they get while searching for their linux based Samba shares is the following screenshot:</description></item><item><title>Project: Windows Mobile Tool ShantzTodayChanger Updated to version 1.53</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/22/project-windows-mobile-tool-shantztodaychanger-updated-to-version-153/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2008 20:49:17 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/22/project-windows-mobile-tool-shantztodaychanger-updated-to-version-153/</guid><description>ShantzTodayChanger is a little tool written by me for your Windows Mobile based phones (WM5/WM6) which will cycle ur today background or theme after a set interval of time. It has a lot of features and options and you can even use it to achieve something other than changing wallpapers as well (e.g. running applications at set times) but that depends on your imagination.
Changes in this version:
1.53 - 23-March-08 -&amp;gt; RECOMMENDED UPDATE</description></item><item><title>Windows Mobile: Missed Call Made Easy (Indian Cell Owners Rejoice)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/18/windows-mobile-missed-call-made-easy-indian-cell-owners-rejoice/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2008 15:12:34 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/03/18/windows-mobile-missed-call-made-easy-indian-cell-owners-rejoice/</guid><description>Perdida = Missed Call (in Spanish)
Missed Call = Ubiquitous Necessity (atleast in India)
Enter: cPerdidas -&amp;gt; A Windows Mobile program (works with WM5 as well as WM6) that will allow you to make missed calls to anyone you desire. Just config your country code, select the contact and &amp;ldquo;Hacer Perdida!&amp;rdquo; (Make the missed call) and your contact will get the missed call on his device. The only change is that the program will cut the call even before he can hear his phone ring.</description></item><item><title>Boring Meetings? CallJockey To The Rescue</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/19/boring-meetings-calljockey-to-the-rescue/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2008 04:43:19 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/19/boring-meetings-calljockey-to-the-rescue/</guid><description>Stuck in another boring meeting? You have a way out now, because connectivetools have released their app CallJockey, which can simulate fake incoming calls. What&amp;rsquo;s more, you can select the name, phone number or one of your saved contacts from whom the fake call will appear to be coming, plus you can define the time when you want it to ring. The only limitation is that it is available only for WM5 smarphones (WM6 Standard), i.</description></item><item><title>Project: ShantzTodayChanger (Windows Mobile Tool To Cycle Themes/Wallpapers Automatically)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/project-shantztodaychanger-windows-mobile-tool-to-cycle-themeswallpapers-automatically/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 19:45:07 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/project-shantztodaychanger-windows-mobile-tool-to-cycle-themeswallpapers-automatically/</guid><description>The newly launched [&amp;ldquo;Projects&amp;rdquo;] section is hereby inaugarated with a Windows Mobile Tool developed by me, called “[ShantzTodayChanger]”. This is a little tool for your Windows Mobile based phones (Compatible with WM5/WM6 but not WM2003) which will cycle ur today background or theme after a set interval of time. It has a lot of features and options that you can discover by reading the text below. And you can even use this options to achieve something other than changing wallpapers as well but that depends on your imagination.</description></item><item><title>ShantzTodayChanger</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/shantztodaychanger/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 13:41:30 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/03/shantztodaychanger/</guid><description>Intro:
This is a little tool for your Windows Mobile based phones (Compatible with WM5/WM6 but not WM2003) which will cycle ur today background or theme after a set interval of time. It has a lot of features and options that you can discover by reading the text below. And you can even use this options to achieve something other than changing wallpapers as well but that depends on your imagination.</description></item></channel></rss>