<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>C on</title><link>/tags/c/</link><description>Recent content in C on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 18:48:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/c/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The 80 Column Coding Rule</title><link>/posts/the-80-column-coding-rule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 18:48:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-80-column-coding-rule/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve followed the 80 column rule almost always when I code, i.e., I keep a soft limit of keeping my lines of my code limited to 80 characters max. unless breaking up the line really messes up the readability of the code.
I was asked recently why do I bother now in this age of 24&amp;quot; widescreen monitors (and above) with resolutions of 720p at the bare minimum. I could certainly afford to have more than double that limit staring back at me from the screen without overflowing.</description></item><item><title>Slow Updates And A Small Nugget Post</title><link>/posts/slow-updates-and-a-small-nugget-post/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2009 04:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/slow-updates-and-a-small-nugget-post/</guid><description>Many readers of this blog have written to me for the slow updates. I apologize for the same. I’ve been swamped by loads of work for quite some time now and haven’t been able to write anything here or update any of my projects, though I have loads of new hacks and tricks that I would write once I’m free and lots in store for most of the projects as well in form of bug fixes and new features.</description></item><item><title>Want To Program Smartly In C? Use GLib</title><link>/posts/smart-programming-in-c-using-glib/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2008 15:30:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/smart-programming-in-c-using-glib/</guid><description>GLib - An Introduction:
GLib is a utility library for C, which augments the standard C library in several purposeful ways to make your life that much easier while programming. GLib has the following things to offer you:
**1. Portability: **The main issue that haunts any C developer is the portability of code. One cannot rely on the standard C library for this as you may find many functions that work differently under different platforms are aren&amp;rsquo;t there at all sometimes.</description></item></channel></rss>