<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Shantz WordPress Prefix Suffix on</title><link>/tags/shantz-wordpress-prefix-suffix/</link><description>Recent content in Shantz WordPress Prefix Suffix on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2009 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/shantz-wordpress-prefix-suffix/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Project: My WordPress Plugin Shantz WP Prefix Suffix Updated to 1.1.4</title><link>/posts/wordpress-plugin-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-114/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2009 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/wordpress-plugin-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-114/</guid><description>Here comes another update, and this time it is a majorly recommended one. For those who are still living under a rock (just kidding :P), this is a plugin that allows you to add any kind of text/html/css/php/javascript code to any of your posts or pages with lots of controls over what to display, where to display, etc etc. So, you could use it as an ad-manager or a copyright notice adder (to thwart those feed scrapers) or just add some friendly messages or related posts, etc for your readers.</description></item><item><title>Project: Shantz WordPress Prefix Suffix Updated to 1.1.2</title><link>/posts/project-shantz-wordpress-prefix-suffix-updated-to-112/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2009 18:30:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/project-shantz-wordpress-prefix-suffix-updated-to-112/</guid><description>My WordPress Plugin &amp;ldquo;Shantz Wordpress Prefix Suffix&amp;rdquo; has just been updated to version 1.1.2. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, this is a super-light and easy to use plugin that allows you to add any text or html/javascript/php code to your posts, be it the top of the posts, bottom of the posts or even in the middle. And you get a lot of options to control all this. I use it even on my site, to create links for my other blogs, adding copyright notices and even for advertisements (google adsense, chitika premium, etc).</description></item></channel></rss>