<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Code on</title><link>/tags/code/</link><description>Recent content in Code on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 18:48:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The 80 Column Coding Rule</title><link>/2013/02/25/the-80-column-coding-rule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 18:48:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/02/25/the-80-column-coding-rule/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve followed the 80 column rule almost always when I code, i.e., I keep a soft limit of keeping my lines of my code limited to 80 characters max. unless breaking up the line really messes up the readability of the code.
I was asked recently why do I bother now in this age of 24&amp;quot; widescreen monitors (and above) with resolutions of 720p at the bare minimum. I could certainly afford to have more than double that limit staring back at me from the screen without overflowing.</description><content>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve followed the 80 column rule almost always when I code, i.e., I keep a soft limit of keeping my lines of my code limited to 80 characters max. unless breaking up the line really messes up the readability of the code.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was asked recently why do I bother now in this age of 24&amp;quot; widescreen monitors (and above) with resolutions of 720p at the bare minimum. I could certainly afford to have more than double that limit staring back at me from the screen without overflowing. Then, am I just being pedantic in following this religiously? Am I not wasting precious screen real estate by doing this?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, NO. The reason I still do it is I can use that real estate for much better purposes while not breaking a sweat (and my neck) while reading long horizontal lines of code. It is still much easier to keep the code size limited horizontally within your immediate focus of vision and you can use the rest of the horizontal space for things like having a directory tree or a database of tags showing. But I keep these extras ready at the whim of a button (mapped to key combos in vim) and the most I use it for is having two (or more) files open simultaneously in vim splits to make the code easier to understand or even write. Many times, what I am reading/writing needs me to back and forth between a few files and I can keep them all open using the big screens if I limit my horizontal code size in each file.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wasn&amp;rsquo;t still able to convince the person of my self-imposed rule but maybe I&amp;rsquo;m wrong? What do you follow?&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Android Dev Tip: App Not Showing on X10 Mini Marketplace</title><link>/2010/08/07/android-dev-tip-app-not-showing-on-x10-mini-marketplace/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2010 21:18:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/08/07/android-dev-tip-app-not-showing-on-x10-mini-marketplace/</guid><description>Many Android Developers (and users) get confused that why a certain app isn&amp;rsquo;t showing up on the new Xperia X10 Mini (and few other) phones. This happens even if they support all android versions and have published their apps for all countries, so that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the issue. I came across this as well when few people mentioned that they couldn&amp;rsquo;t find my app Wi-Fi Keep Alive in the X10 mini marketplace.</description><content>&lt;p>Many Android Developers (and users) get confused that why a certain app isn&amp;rsquo;t showing up on the new Xperia X10 Mini (and few other) phones. This happens even if they support all android versions and have published their apps for all countries, so that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the issue. I came across this as well when few people mentioned that they couldn&amp;rsquo;t find my app Wi-Fi Keep Alive in the X10 mini marketplace. On some digging into the android docs and the X10 mini specs, I found the issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The problem is that the X10 mini has a very small screen with only a QVGA resolution. This screen size/resolution wasn&amp;rsquo;t supported by Android until recently and the Android system might not be able to scale resources and layouts designed for other screen sizes well enough to suit the X10 mini. Hence, the Android system designers have chosen that any app which does not declare explicit support for small screens (i.e., the app dev has tested his app on small screens and made any changes, if needed, and then declared that everything works fine in the Android Manifest) then it is considered not compatible by default and hence, the Android marketplace will filter your app out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, this is a big loss. A lot of X10 minis were sold and there are lot of new low-tier and cheap Android smartphones coming out with this resolution, so it is a significant market share that you can&amp;rsquo;t afford to lose. The solution is simple. If the app does indeed work fine on small screens (or you have fixed it to work), then all you got to do is add the below mentioned line in your AndroidManifest.xml:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>&amp;lt;supports-screens android:smallScreens=&amp;quot;true&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s it. Your app should now show up fine in all screen sizes markets. Note that for all other screen sizes and resolutions, Android considers the default support as true and your app will show in those markets even if you don&amp;rsquo;t make any explicit declarations for them. You can read more about this here: &lt;a href="http://developer.android.com/guide/practices/screens_support.html">Supporting Multiple Screens in Android&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Update: **&lt;a href="http://www.blundell-apps.com/">Blundell&lt;/a> pointed out in the comments that &lt;a href="http://developer.android.com/guide/practices/screens_support.html%23defaults">Android documentation&lt;/a> says&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>This should mean that small screens should be set as supported by default if you have your minSdk &lt;strong>or&lt;/strong> targetSdk  set to anything above or equal to 4. However, in my case, my apps had minSdk as 3 but targetSdk as 7 or 8 but still they didn&amp;rsquo;t show up in X10 mini marketplace till I added the smallScreens support to true in my manifest file. If anyone has any ideas about as to why it was like this, please let me know.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>BadTokenException Error In Android Dialog</title><link>/2010/07/08/badtokenexception-android-dialog-getapplicationcontext/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2010 11:24:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/07/08/badtokenexception-android-dialog-getapplicationcontext/</guid><description>If you are creating a custom Dialog for Android, and following the Android Developers’ Creating Dialogs tutorial, then most likely you would have faced a Force Close with this exception showing up in logcat. I did too. Although I figured it out quickly, it might not be easy to find out for many, so posting it here for reference. Basically, the code given in the tutorial goes something like this:</description><content>&lt;p>If you are creating a custom Dialog for Android, and following the &lt;a href="http://developer.android.com/guide/topics/ui/dialogs.html">Android Developers’ Creating Dialogs&lt;/a> tutorial, then most likely you would have faced a Force Close with this exception showing up in logcat. I did too. Although I figured it out quickly, it might not be easy to find out for many, so posting it here for reference. Basically, the code given in the tutorial goes something like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>Context mContext = getApplicationContext();
Dialog dialog = new Dialog(mContext);
dialog.setContentView(R.layout.custom_dialog);
dialog.setTitle(&amp;#34;Custom Dialog&amp;#34;);
TextView text = (TextView) dialog.findViewById(R.id.text);
text.setText(&amp;#34;Hello, this is a custom dialog!&amp;#34;);
ImageView image = (ImageView) dialog.findViewById(R.id.image);
image.setImageResource(R.drawable.android);
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>All looks well, but when you execute it, you will get a Force Close. The error appearing in logcat would be something like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>Uncaught handler: thread main exiting due to uncaught exception
android.view.WindowManager$BadTokenException: Unable to add window -- token null is not for an application
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>It isn’t apparent immediately that what is causing this error. The very first line in the code “Context mContext = getApplicationContext();” is the culprit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Solution:&lt;/strong> Just replace “getApplicationContext()” with “this” (i.e. “Context mContext = this;” ) and it will work fine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Explanation:&lt;/strong> As to why this is exactly an issue, I’m a bit fuzzy about it myself but this much I’m sure that the contexts that you get with getApplicationContext and this are different. On reading about this function from Android SDK help:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Return the context of the single, global Application object of the current process. This generally should only be used if you need a Context whose lifecycle is separate from the current context, that is tied to the lifetime of the process rather than the current component.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I think this would mean is that getApplicationContext returns a context which is for the application itself and not the activity, while “this” would give you the context of the activity in which you are creating the dialog. I think since it is the activity which is associated with the UI (and for whom the window has been created), using the application context would have caused the crash here.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Project: Shantz WordPress Prefix Suffix Updated to 1.1.2</title><link>/2009/02/19/project-shantz-wordpress-prefix-suffix-updated-to-112/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2009 18:30:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/02/19/project-shantz-wordpress-prefix-suffix-updated-to-112/</guid><description>My WordPress Plugin &amp;ldquo;Shantz Wordpress Prefix Suffix&amp;rdquo; has just been updated to version 1.1.2. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, this is a super-light and easy to use plugin that allows you to add any text or html/javascript/php code to your posts, be it the top of the posts, bottom of the posts or even in the middle. And you get a lot of options to control all this. I use it even on my site, to create links for my other blogs, adding copyright notices and even for advertisements (google adsense, chitika premium, etc).</description><content>&lt;p>My WordPress Plugin &amp;ldquo;Shantz Wordpress Prefix Suffix&amp;rdquo; has just been updated to version 1.1.2. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, this is a super-light and easy to use plugin that allows you to add any text or html/javascript/php code to your posts, be it the top of the posts, bottom of the posts or even in the middle. And you get a lot of options to control all this. I use it even on my site, to create links for my other blogs, adding copyright notices and even for advertisements (google adsense, chitika premium, etc).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This update brings in WordPress 2.7.1 compatibility and also another option to control the plugin order. If there are some other plugins that add content to your posts (e.g. sociable, simple tags, related posts, etc), you might notice that the text/code you append with this plugin may not occur in exactly the place you want (e.g. you might want to occur after all other plugins have posted their content). So, you can easily control this now by changing the priority value in the plugin settings. Make it higher to push the content down and lower it to add your content before anything else.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Slow Updates And A Small Nugget Post</title><link>/2009/01/13/slow-updates-and-a-small-nugget-post/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2009 04:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/01/13/slow-updates-and-a-small-nugget-post/</guid><description>Many readers of this blog have written to me for the slow updates. I apologize for the same. I’ve been swamped by loads of work for quite some time now and haven’t been able to write anything here or update any of my projects, though I have loads of new hacks and tricks that I would write once I’m free and lots in store for most of the projects as well in form of bug fixes and new features.</description><content>&lt;p>Many readers of this blog have written to me for the slow updates. I apologize for the same. I’ve been swamped by loads of work for quite some time now and haven’t been able to write anything here or update any of my projects, though I have loads of new hacks and tricks that I would write once I’m free and lots in store for most of the projects as well in form of bug fixes and new features. So, hang in there :)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meanwhile, take a look at this post ( &lt;a href="http://www.safercode.com/blog/2008/10/14/int-main-vs-void-main.html">int Main() vs void main()&lt;/a> )that I had made some time ago at another blog of mine ( &lt;a href="http://www.safercode.com/blog/">Safer Code - Secure Coding In C \ C++ And More&lt;/a> ). Why I’m telling you about this post is that it is a really important post useful for every C / C++ developer and recently it got featured on LinuxToday and Lxer, after which there is a very interesting discussion going on to discuss the various aspects related to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do check out the rest of the blog as well. It is about tit-bits of security, optimization and performance of your code and in a manner and amount that you can easily digest. What’s best is that it is delivered regularly at a slow pace that everyone can follow :). So, what are you waiting for? Add it to your feed reader or choose to get the updates through e-mail and do let me know in the comments there how you like it.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Project: My WordPress Plugin Shantz-WP-Prefix-Suffix Updated To 1.0.5</title><link>/2008/10/31/project-my-wordpress-plugin-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-to-105/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 15:48:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/10/31/project-my-wordpress-plugin-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-to-105/</guid><description>For those who are new to this plugin, Shantz WP Prefix Suffix is a light-weight and easy to use plugin which allows you to add any text, HTML/CSS/PHP/Javascript code to your posts and/or pages as prefix and/or suffix. (That includes even any new or old posts and pages and even your feed) Examples of use cases could be to include your copyright message, advertisements (like adsense, etc), permalinks, your other site links, any other custom messages.</description><content>&lt;p>For those who are new to this plugin, Shantz WP Prefix Suffix is a light-weight and easy to use plugin which allows you to add any text, HTML/CSS/PHP/Javascript code to your posts and/or pages as prefix and/or suffix. (That includes even any new or old posts and pages and even your feed)
Examples of use cases could be to include your copyright message, advertisements (like adsense, etc), permalinks, your other site links, any other custom messages. This works very fine with ad plugins like adsense-manager etc, as you don&amp;rsquo;t have to manipulate your posts or templates to add the ad code, shantz-wp-prefix-suffix will do that for you automatically for all posts and with the adsense plugin you can control whether to &amp;ldquo;display&amp;rdquo; the ad or not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Changes in this version include options to enable/disable displaying the text/code on home page and excerpts. Also a small bug was fixed that displayed the code even if it was chosen not to.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>My Brief History With Computers</title><link>/2008/06/23/my-brief-history-with-computers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2008 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/06/23/my-brief-history-with-computers/</guid><description>I’m going to be bespectacled and have been advised to reduce and limit my computer usage considerably. A bit of nostalgia set in on hearing this and I thought about my short journey so far in this wonderland of solid-state and otherwise.
**First time I touched a computer. 1989, at school in 2nd standard
**First command I typed on a computer. “dir”, 1990, 3rd standard
**First game I played on a computer.</description><content>&lt;p>I’m going to be bespectacled and have been advised to reduce and limit my computer usage considerably. A bit of nostalgia set in on hearing this and I thought about my short journey so far in this wonderland of solid-state and otherwise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**First time I touched a computer.
1989, at school in 2nd standard&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**First command I typed on a computer.
“dir”, 1990, 3rd standard&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**First game I played on a computer.
“bricks”, 1991, 4th standard&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First Colored game I played on a computer.&lt;/strong>
&amp;ldquo;Dangerous Dave&amp;rdquo;, 1991, 4th standard&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First program I wrote on a computer.&lt;/strong>
&amp;ldquo;Hello, Ankit!&amp;rdquo; in basic, 1992, 5th standard(The pre-teenage rebel in me substituted the &amp;ldquo;world&amp;rdquo; by &amp;ldquo;Ankit&amp;rdquo;. Why &amp;ldquo;Ankit&amp;rdquo;? That&amp;rsquo;s a mystery ;-) )&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First time I held a mouse.&lt;/strong>
1992, 5th standard, Windows 3.0&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First Windows Program I used&lt;/strong>
PaintBrush (MSPaint today), 1992, 5th standard&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First &amp;ldquo;3d&amp;rdquo; game I played&lt;/strong>
Wolfenstein 3D (or Wolf), 1993, 6th standard&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**First hack
**&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Remote controlling&amp;rdquo; friend&amp;rsquo;s school PC by swapping the mouse cords, 1993, 6th standard&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First movie I watched on a computer&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The wonderful world of Plants&amp;rdquo; or something similar, 1993, 6th standard&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First introduction to the internet&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>1994, 7th standard, A demo by an ISP to the whole school.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>**First site I opened on the internet
**&amp;gt; disneyland.com, 1994, 7th standard&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First commercial movie I watched on a computer&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Who Framed Roger Rabbit&amp;rdquo;, 1995, 8th standard&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>**First introduction to Linux
**&amp;gt; Suse 4.x, 1996, 9th standard&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First self-taught language learnt&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>HTML, 1997, 10th standard&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First Computer at home&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Celeron 466 MHz, 64 MB RAM, 8GB HDD, for around 60k, 1998, 11th standard&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First C program&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Hello, Shantanu!&amp;rdquo;, 1998, 11th standard (Now, do you get it?)&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>**First net connection at home
**&amp;gt; 1998, 11th standard, ISP:Glide dial up. around 250 bucks for 5 hours at 56 kbps + telephone usage charges.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**First Quake III Arena game
**&amp;gt; 2000, almost at the end of 12th standard&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First major gaming session&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>2000, QIII Arena, 11 hours straight, Tier1-Tier5, 2 days before my CET exam (Entrance test for my engineering college). For the record, I was so obsessed with QIII back then that I even had a quicky 5-minute game (DM17 map) in the 45 minute break I got during the exam as my home was quite near the exam center.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; hack&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>2001, B.E., First year. Wrote and installed a TSR onto a friend&amp;rsquo;s system to print out &amp;ldquo;U R Doomed&amp;rdquo; whenever he typed something.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First Linux self-install&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Red Hat 7.0, 2001, B.E., First year&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>**Longest Gaming Session till date
**&amp;gt; December 2001, B.E., 2nd year. Deus Ex, 26 hours with 4-5 breaks spanning from 2-15 minutes max. Finished with all the alternate endings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First major Q3 Arena lan-tournament&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Early 2002, B.E. 2nd year. At NSIT Innovision tech fest.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First Blog&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://iamhuman.blogspot.com/">http://iamhuman.blogspot.com&lt;/a>, 2004, B.E., Final year&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>**First program in the corporate world
**&amp;gt; Optimization and multi-channelization of H.264 stitching, 2004&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First real project in the corporate world&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Epsilon, the new low cost BTS (Base Transceiver Station) by Nokia, 2004&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First Laptop&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>2005, Compaq Presario R4025, AMD64 2.0 GHz, 1GB RAM, 128 MB gfx Card. US$1300&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First Windows Mobile Program&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://tech.shantanugoel.com/projects/windows-mobile/shantztodaychanger">ShantzTodayChanger&lt;/a>, 2007&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>**Finally bought first domain name
**&amp;gt;&lt;a href="http://shantanugoel.com/">http://shantanugoel.com&lt;/a>, 2008&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These “firsts” aren’t anything big in themeselves but have been an important part of my life in one or the other way making my love for computers growing at an even faster pace. So what are your nostalgic moments with your beloved machine?&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Want To Program Smartly In C? Use GLib</title><link>/2008/05/03/smart-programming-in-c-using-glib/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2008 15:30:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/05/03/smart-programming-in-c-using-glib/</guid><description>GLib - An Introduction:
GLib is a utility library for C, which augments the standard C library in several purposeful ways to make your life that much easier while programming. GLib has the following things to offer you:
**1. Portability: **The main issue that haunts any C developer is the portability of code. One cannot rely on the standard C library for this as you may find many functions that work differently under different platforms are aren&amp;rsquo;t there at all sometimes.</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;strong>GLib - An Introduction:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://library.gnome.org/devel/glib/">GLib&lt;/a> is a utility library for C, which augments the standard C library in several purposeful ways to make your life that much easier while programming. GLib has the following things to offer you:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**1. Portability: **The main issue that haunts any C developer is the portability of code. One cannot rely on the standard C library for this as you may find many functions that work differently under different platforms are aren&amp;rsquo;t there at all sometimes. GLib ensures that the all the functionality exposed by it remains consistent across platforms, so that you can rest assured that your code will work the way its supposed to work irrespective of the Operating System it&amp;rsquo;s being used for (Of course, this assumes that you have ensured about portability aspects of your non-GLib related source code). Moreover, GLib is available for a vast array of contemporary Operating Systems including GNU/Linux, Microsoft Windows and Mac OS X.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**2. Security: **Though you still need to be careful about things like freeing allocated memories properly, etc but GLib does ensure that all its functionality is secure. Moreover, GLib has a policy of ensuring that all its functions are threadsafe. This saves you from a lot of checks and balances and locks and scheduling considerations if you had written all this yourself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>3. Useful Data Types:&lt;/strong> GLib exposes a lot of data types. Some are very basic that maintain portability across OS&amp;rsquo;s and 32-bit and 64-bit systems. e.g. you can rest assured that gint32 will always be 32 bit and gint64 will always be 64 bit data types.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apart from this, it also provides a lot of derived data types e.g. singly linked lists, doubly linked lists, hash tables, stacks, queues, trees, and much more. It&amp;rsquo;d basically cover most of you data structure needs that you&amp;rsquo;d have otherwise had to implement yourselves. And it also provides helper functions that makes working with them so much more easier. If you have ever used Perl, and have wished that C programming could be a bit faster like it, you will be pleasantly surprised.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**4. Utility Functions: **GLib also provides various utility functions to ease out your manipulation of data. Some of the functions are meant as more secure and portable replacements for those provided with standard C library, while rest are meant to provide other useful functionality which you earlier had to implement in your code. Some of the major areas covered by GLib&amp;rsquo;s utility functions are String manipulation, character set manipulation and conversion (including unicode and base64), using regular expressions, file manipulation, shell functions, config file parsing (my favourite), etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>End Note:&lt;/strong> I can understand that there would be a lot of people who believe that use of GLib is dumbing down programming in C. After all, we take pride being in control of our code and this is why we love progrmming in C because we have options to do things in our own way. Yes, that is all true but there comes a time where you&amp;rsquo;d like to spend more time in developing the core functionality of your app, or focus more on giving a rapid shape to your new idea, rather than reinventing the wheel and fumbling around with writing the helper functions. So, keeping that in mind I believe GLib is wonderful piece of code that has enabled me to churn out new apps that much faster.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>An Idea Is All You Need</title><link>/2008/04/12/an-idea-is-all-you-need-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2008 15:43:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/04/12/an-idea-is-all-you-need-2/</guid><description>Everyone wants to make a name for himself. Everyone wants to do something new and extra-ordinary. People like me (read software engineers) want to develop &amp;ldquo;something&amp;rdquo; cool. BUT, the stage where most of them go wrong is the very first one. Most of them think that the road to develop something cool starts from a particular &amp;ldquo;language&amp;rdquo; or a tool. But I beg to differ. I say the first stage is &amp;ldquo;The Idea&amp;rdquo;.</description><content>&lt;p>Everyone wants to make a name for himself. Everyone wants to do something new and extra-ordinary. People like me (read software engineers) want to develop &amp;ldquo;something&amp;rdquo; cool. BUT, the stage where most of them go wrong is the very first one. Most of them think that the road to develop something cool starts from a particular &amp;ldquo;language&amp;rdquo; or a tool. But I beg to differ. I say the first stage is &amp;ldquo;The Idea&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most of my friends and others around me think that having a particular skill set is very important to develop something the world hasn&amp;rsquo;t seen till now. And for this they end up reading through piles of books, which claim to make them a master in C, C++, PHP, Python, Web 2.0 and what not. This is all OK, but the problem is, when they have gone through the books, done all the exercises, made all the samle projects, then they have a question in their minds &amp;ldquo;Now What&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What I think is that this question should have been asked in the very beginning of the journey. And it should have been answered by the occurrence of a new idea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong. I&amp;rsquo;m all for reading books, developing skill sets, learning new technologies, etc. But the only point I want to make is that all this is a &amp;ldquo;means&amp;rdquo; to give your &amp;ldquo;idea&amp;rdquo; a shape. They are not where your story begins. What if you spent a lot of time acquiring perl skills and then when (and if) you get your brilliant idea, you find out that the best way to implement it would be using C. Are you back to square one? No. Skills acquired are never a waste. &amp;ldquo;Concepts&amp;rdquo; developed can easily be applied to the new tool that you have to use.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But one more thing, its again not a hard rule that now you should just sit in your chair all day long and keep thinking. I bet its much harder to get the idea stream flowing that way. Ideas don&amp;rsquo;t have a pattern that they follow while coming into your mind. They may come to you any place unexpected (I get most of mine while bathing ;-) ).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But there is something you can do to ensure that your brain gets accustomed to recognize an idea when you do get it. So, while you are reading through that book on C programming, don&amp;rsquo;t just get engrossed in typing out the exact source code that&amp;rsquo;s fed to you. &amp;ldquo;Think&amp;rdquo; about whether is that enough? Can you make some modification to it so that it becomes more efficient? Can you tweak it a bit to do more than its already doing?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Keep your eyes open when you go around your daily chores. Think when you open your door whether wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be nice if the door could recognize you are there and open itself. There&amp;rsquo;s your idea. And while you are at it, think wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be even nicer if your home would have poured you a cool drink itself when you enter it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, tell me whether you would like to wait to think about these ideas till you read the book&amp;rsquo;s epilogue, or do you want to start thinking now?&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Project: "shantz-wp-qotd ", My Wordpress Plugin, Updated to 1.1.0</title><link>/2008/02/17/project-shantz-wp-qotd-my-wordpress-plugin-update-to-110/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2008 15:44:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/02/17/project-shantz-wp-qotd-my-wordpress-plugin-update-to-110/</guid><description>For the uninitiated:
I made a few additions / modifications to the code and the plugin has been updated to 1.1.0. The changes are:
Added Custom tag support for adding quotes anywhere in your posts/pages
Added Custom quote separator support and multi-line quotes support
Config Screenshots:
I recommend that you update to this new version asap, as apart from the above mentioned changes, the code is a bit more cleaner as well, which would run a bit better IMO and also help in any modification if you have in mind.</description><content>&lt;p>For the uninitiated:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>I made a few additions / modifications to the code and the plugin has been updated to 1.1.0. The changes are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Added Custom tag support for adding quotes anywhere in your posts/pages&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Added Custom quote separator support and multi-line quotes support&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Config Screenshots:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/img/uploads/Screenshot1.png">&lt;img src="/img/uploads/Screenshot1_thumb.jpg" alt="Screenshot1">&lt;/a> &lt;a href="/img/uploads/Screenshot2.png">&lt;img src="/img/uploads/Screenshot2_thumb.jpg" alt="Screenshot2">&lt;/a> &lt;a href="/img/uploads/Screenshot3.png">&lt;img src="/img/uploads/Screenshot3_thumb.jpg" alt="Screenshot3">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I recommend that you update to this new version asap, as apart from the above mentioned changes, the code is a bit more cleaner as well, which would run a bit better IMO and also help in any modification if you have in mind.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Site Updates: More Content For You</title><link>/2008/02/03/site-updates-more-content-for-you/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 19:36:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/02/03/site-updates-more-content-for-you/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve added a few new sections to the blog. Do check them out. Here is a list of the new sections along with their descriptions.
[Projects]: Although I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t put myself in the category of an excellent developer but I can sure type in a few lines that can compile without an error and also manage to carry out a task or two. So, this page will list some of those little things that I write to weed out a few niggles or scratch a few itches of mine.</description><content>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve added a few new sections to the blog. Do check them out. Here is a list of the new sections along with their descriptions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[Projects]: Although I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t put myself in the category of an excellent developer but I can sure type in a few lines that can compile without an error and also manage to carry out a task or two. So, this page will list some of those little things that I write to weed out a few niggles or scratch a few itches of mine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[Downloads]: This page will contain the various downloads that this blog offers for a convenient access.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[Submit News/Articles]: Like this blog? Have something to contribute? News/Views/Articles/Links that you would like us to share with the rest of the world, can be submitted using the form on this page. Due credit shall be given to you. Also, check the box at the end of the form, if you would like to be a part of the blog as a regular contributor.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>