<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>IPhone 4 on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/iphone-4/</link><description>Recent content in IPhone 4 on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 04:49:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/iphone-4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apple is Magical: Daniel Eran Gilder is the Living Proof</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/10/apple-magical-dan-eran-gilder/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 04:49:53 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2010/06/10/apple-magical-dan-eran-gilder/</guid><description>Update: Removed the post as the person in consideration has contacted me with the explanation of what went down. I’m not sure if it is completely true or this is just as a response to this post but anyways, as I had contended in the original post that it was a stupid little thing that didn’t really warrant any attention or a post but I still did it just because I’m weird, so in the light of the developments, I think it’s best to remove the rants and focus on actual discussion.</description><content>&lt;p>Update: Removed the post as the person in consideration has contacted me with the explanation of what went down. I’m not sure if it is completely true or this is just as a response to this post but anyways, as I had contended in the original post that it was a stupid little thing that didn’t really warrant any attention or a post but I still did it just because I’m weird, so in the light of the developments, I think it’s best to remove the rants and focus on actual discussion. I’ll be discussing the points put out by Dan over his blog or might make a post about them here..&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>