<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Debug Android Widgets on</title><link>/tags/debug-android-widgets/</link><description>Recent content in Debug Android Widgets on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 18:42:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/debug-android-widgets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How To Debug Android Widgets</title><link>/2010/06/13/how-to-debug-android-widgets/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 18:42:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/06/13/how-to-debug-android-widgets/</guid><description>For most new android app developers (like me), it is a bit puzzling how to debug the android widgets or how to put a breakpoint in an android widget code. For normal applications, it is quite simple as when you press &amp;ldquo;debug&amp;rdquo; on the eclipse toolbar, it launches the emulator (or connects to existing emulator/device), syncs your application and launches its main activity and puts the control in your hands if you have put a breakpoint.</description><content>&lt;p>For most new android app developers (like me), it is a bit puzzling how to debug the android widgets or how to put a breakpoint in an android widget code. For normal applications, it is quite simple as when you press &amp;ldquo;debug&amp;rdquo; on the eclipse toolbar, it launches the emulator (or connects to existing emulator/device), syncs your application and launches its main activity and puts the control in your hands if you have put a breakpoint. For widgets, it seems a bit tricky because there is no activity to be launched, so eclipse just syncs your widget&amp;rsquo;s apk and installs it and that&amp;rsquo;s it. So, is it possible or not to debug widget code? and if yes, then is it very difficult? Fortunately, it is possible and very easy to do but just slightly less intuitive and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any information about it at Android developers website and learnt it by just fumbling around for a few minutes so thought of posting here for the benefit of other newbies like me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, all you need to debug your widget code is almost same as what you do for normal applications. Just follow the below steps:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Press &amp;ldquo;debug&amp;rdquo; on the eclipse menu (or &amp;ldquo;run&amp;rdquo; it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to matter)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Once the widget apk is sync&amp;rsquo;ed and installed onto your emulator/device, switch your eclipse workspace to DDMS mode. You can either do this by pressing the &amp;ldquo;DDMS&amp;rdquo; labeled button on your top right corner or if you can&amp;rsquo;t find it, then do it by going to &amp;ldquo;Window-&amp;gt;Open Perspective-&amp;gt;DDMS&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select the process name of your widget from the list of processes shown. By default, this list appears at top left of DDMS window. (See screenshot below). If you can&amp;rsquo;t see your widget&amp;rsquo;s process name in the list, it is possible that the widget is not added to the home screen yet. So, do so.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Press the green debug button above the process list (See screenshot below)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>And that&amp;rsquo;s it. Now, if you had put a breakpoint in the code, do something that executes that piece of the code.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/img/uploads/debug-android-widget-eclipse.png">&lt;img src="/img/uploads/debug-android-widget-eclipse-thumb.png" alt="Screenshot to show how to debug android widgets in eclipse">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me know if this helped you out or if you see anything that I missed out. Happy coding :)&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>