<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Wordpress Qotd Plugin on</title><link>/tags/wordpress-qotd-plugin/</link><description>Recent content in Wordpress Qotd Plugin on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 11:00:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/wordpress-qotd-plugin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My First WordPress Plugin: Please Welcome shantz-wp-qotd</title><link>/2008/02/10/my-first-wordpress-plugin-please-welcome-shantz-wp-qotd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 11:00:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/02/10/my-first-wordpress-plugin-please-welcome-shantz-wp-qotd/</guid><description>Motivated by Ronald’s ultimate wordpress plugin tutorial at devlounge, I decided that the best way to learn something is to use it in a live project. Armed with my laptop and multiple flasks of coffee, the marathon began on Friday night. My only experience with web-related development so far had been around 8–10 years ago as a kid when, just like everybody else at that time, I was fascinated by HTML and did a “read-through” of HTML 4.</description><content>&lt;p>Motivated by Ronald’s ultimate wordpress plugin tutorial at &lt;a href="http://www.devlounge.net/extras/how-to-write-a-wordpress-plugin">devlounge&lt;/a>, I decided that the best way to learn something is to use it in a live project. Armed with my laptop and multiple flasks of coffee, the marathon began on Friday night. My only experience with web-related development so far had been around 8–10 years ago as a kid when, just like everybody else at that time, I was fascinated by HTML and did a “read-through” of HTML 4.0. But I have always been a believer of the theory that a C programmer can program in any language quickly without having to go through the whole manuals. Thus that night bore fruit for me, and by 5:30 in the morning I had a working “Quote of The Day” plugin at my hand with all the features I wanted it to have in its first avatar. Did a bit of polishing last night, fixed a few bugs, and created a readme, and here it is, Mr. shantz-wp-qotd “1.0”, in all its glory, ready for general consumption.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Features at a glance:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Add quotes to all your posts automatically.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Widget support - Can also have a widget in the sidebar for quotes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Customize and style your quotes with your own text and tags.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Multiple sources for quotes (paste in admin page, get from file implemented, fetch from web/rss soon to come)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Multiple patterns for quotes - Random Quote, Quote of the day (all posts display quote of the day), Quote of that day (all posts display quote for their own days)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Pattern for widget can be different&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Customization for widget can be different&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Add quotes to top or bottom of posts&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Enable/Disable the quotes without deactivating the plugin&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Coming Soon:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Fetch from web/RSS support&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Custom template tag to add quote anywhere you want&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Custom quote boundary decalarator tags/Multiline quote support (Right now, each quote has to be on a new line)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Quotes Categories&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Pics support for quotes&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Anything else you want&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>File selection&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>And more…&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>