<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Perl on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/perl/</link><description>Recent content in Perl on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2009 11:15:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/perl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Real Time Data Plotting with GNUPlot</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/12/29/real-time-plot-gnuplot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2009 11:15:51 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/12/29/real-time-plot-gnuplot/</guid><description>I wrote this script a few days ago to plot real-time / streaming data with gnuplot. The motivation was that I needed to test a piece of code for a touchscreen driver that I had written at work. The issue was that the UI wasn’t quite ready yet, so I wanted to test just the driver to be working fine. Now, the very first thought for the software to use that came to me was “gnuplot” but I found that it can’t really do this in an easy way.</description></item><item><title>ImageMagick: Weaving Magic With Your Pictures</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/26/imagemagick-weaving-magic-with-your-pictures/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2008 06:23:18 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/26/imagemagick-weaving-magic-with-your-pictures/</guid><description>I’ve known about ImageMagick tools for quite some time now but never dabbled with it. A couple of weeks ago I played with it for some time (notice the new cascaded polaroid pics header above) and was amazed even more. Few of its shining features:
It has almost unlimited features to manipulate your images through its tools like convert, montage, mogrify etc and their long list of options.
It is available for Windows, Linux and Mac as well.</description></item><item><title>Site Updates</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/22/site-updates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2008 05:05:04 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/22/site-updates/</guid><description>The site received a lot of new visitors yesterday as one of the small-time things that I do, received front page treatment at lifehacker. Thank you, Adam Pash, and thanks Murphy, for the original idea.</description></item></channel></rss>