<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>HTC on</title><link>/tags/htc/</link><description>Recent content in HTC on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2008 19:32:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/htc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Android Devices Trickling In A Few Days Early?</title><link>/2008/10/20/android-devices-trickling-in-a-few-days-early/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2008 19:32:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/10/20/android-devices-trickling-in-a-few-days-early/</guid><description>There is still a day left for the first Android based Device, T-Mobile G1, to come out into the hands of general public but I was in a for a small surprise as I went through my Google Analytics report for the last week. It had a mysterious number of 2 sitting at the bottom of my “Unique Visitors by Operating Systems” filter report. The “mysterious” part coming from the fact that the left most column displayed “Android”.</description><content>&lt;p>There is still a day left for the first Android based Device, T-Mobile G1, to come out into the hands of general public but I was in a for a small surprise as I went through my Google Analytics report for the last week. It had a mysterious number of 2 sitting at the bottom of my “Unique Visitors by Operating Systems” filter report. The “mysterious” part coming from the fact that the left most column displayed “Android”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/img/uploads/Operating_2DSystems_2DGoogle_20Analytics_2Dreport_2Dandroid_2Dt_2Dmobile_2Dg1.png" alt="Operating-Systems-Google Analytics-report-android-t-mobile-g1">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, the question is whether the T-Mobile G1 (aka HTC dream) is already out into a few hands (leaked to lucky googlers/HTCers/T-Mobilers?) or somebody just modified the agent string reported to my web server? (Since this is a “unique visitors” report, the 2 people have to be different and hence second option doesn’t seem likely to me)&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>The Elusive Super Phone</title><link>/2008/05/08/the-elusive-super-phone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2008 17:15:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/05/08/the-elusive-super-phone/</guid><description>HTC announce their shiny new Touch Diamond recently. Everyone ooh&amp;rsquo;ed and aah&amp;rsquo;ed while ogling at it until they realized that HTC has taken a step back (or forward towards matching Apple&amp;rsquo;s iPhone crap) by removing the expansion card slot from the phone. Yes, it has 4 GB of internal storage but I&amp;rsquo;d rather have an SDHC card slot with the ever falling prices of solid state memory (an 8 GB Class 6 SDHC card is worth not more than around 60$ these days).</description><content>&lt;p>HTC announce their shiny new Touch Diamond recently. Everyone ooh&amp;rsquo;ed and aah&amp;rsquo;ed while ogling at it until they realized that HTC has taken a step back (or forward towards matching Apple&amp;rsquo;s iPhone crap) by removing the expansion card slot from the phone. Yes, it has 4 GB of internal storage but I&amp;rsquo;d rather have an SDHC card slot with the ever falling prices of solid state memory (an 8 GB Class 6 SDHC card is worth not more than around 60$ these days). With a history of ultimate-gift-to-mankind phones like HTC Tytn, HTC Tytn II (Kaiser), iPhone, etc that excite so much on the first look and then start becoming dimmer and unwanted as the euphoria settles, we are left to wonder when will we see the real &amp;ldquo;Super Phone&amp;rdquo;. The do-it-all-be-all-end-all phone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, my prediction is (Nostradamus style) : **NEVER. **No sir, you are not going to see your dream phone any time soon, or any time at all, for that matter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why do I say that. The reasons are pretty obvious, once we take off our wishful thinking hats and don the smart thinking ones.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**1. ****A new dream every day: **Around 8-10 years ago, I wished I had a cell phone. Around 6 years ago, I wish I had one with a camera. Around 4 years ago, I wish I had a phone with Mp3 player and expandable memory. 3 years ago I wished for a smart phone. Now, I wish for&amp;hellip;. You get it. By the time something comes out, our dreams have already moved on. After all they  aren&amp;rsquo;t called &amp;ldquo;dreams&amp;rdquo; just like that ;)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**2. Where is the money: **You might be ready to give a fortune (and your first born son) for that ultimate phone, but the evil-phone-conglomerate wants much more than that. They want you to be slaves. They don&amp;rsquo;t want the world to spend a huge amount in one go and then stop. They need to mint more money and too much more frequently than you&amp;rsquo;d like to spend. This is why the strategy works. Give out a phone that has slim form factor, nice UI, wi-fi, but then make the processor crappy (Touch), then lure them with a better processor but take out the wi-fi (Touch Dual), Add the wi-fi back and slap in a keyboard too, but keep&amp;rsquo;em wanting for &lt;a href="http:///2008/01/28/htc-the-best-windows-mobile-business-unit.html">better graphics&lt;/a> (Kaiser), give &amp;rsquo;em a shiny new toy, but then lock it down in every possible (iCrap). So, you&amp;rsquo;d be stuck in the vicious circle of &amp;ldquo;upgrades&amp;rdquo; and keep the phone factory churning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, my dear fellow phone lovers, stop wasting your time waiting for that ultimate phone, and go &amp;ldquo;upgrade&amp;rdquo; at once, because &amp;ldquo;that&amp;rdquo; phone with just &amp;ldquo;that&amp;rdquo; one more feature&amp;hellip;ISN&amp;rsquo;T COMING&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>HTC Video Drivers: But This Is Not A Post About HTC</title><link>/2008/02/26/htc-video-drivers-but-this-is-not-a-post-about-htc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 11:14:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/02/26/htc-video-drivers-but-this-is-not-a-post-about-htc/</guid><description>This is a post about irresponsible/careless journalism/bloggism. For Gizmodo, getting that post about HTC’s latest press release out the door took precedence over actually **reading **the release properly and then commenting over it. The gizmodo poster’s comment is:
……but HTC&amp;rsquo;s finally released a statement saying that a fix is coming. They say that the video acceleration will be supported in the future, and will be included in software upgrades for current devices…….</description><content>&lt;p>This is a post about irresponsible/careless journalism/bloggism. For Gizmodo, getting that post about HTC’s latest press release out the door took precedence over actually **reading **the release properly and then commenting over it. The gizmodo poster’s comment is:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>……but HTC&amp;rsquo;s finally released a statement saying that a fix is coming. They say that the &lt;strong>video acceleration &lt;em>will&lt;/em> be supported in the future, and will be included in software upgrades for current devices&lt;/strong>…….&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>I’m still puzzled, after reading and rereading HTC’s (pretty short) statement 10 times over and I can’t find where it is mentioned that they will provide video acceleration for the current devices. My point is that if you don’t read it yourself, then better not release it to your readers, (or atleast refrain from commenting on it improperly, if you must be ahead in the “race”).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Read the statement below (and for actual post on Gizmodo, click &lt;a href="http://gizmodo.com/360514/htc-says-software-fix-is-coming-for-lousy-video-drivers">here&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Some of our top engineers have investigated video performance on our devices and have discovered a fix that they claim will dramatically improve performance for common on-screen tasks like scrolling and the like. Their fix would help most of our recent touch-screen products including the Touch family of devices and TYTN II / Tilt, Mogul / XV6900. The update is in testing and we hope to release it soon. However this fix is not a new video driver to utilize hardware acceleration; it is a software optimization. Video drivers are a much more complicated issue that involves companies and engineers beyond HTC alone. We do not want to lead anyone to believe they should expect these. To explain why we are not releasing video acceleration instead of the optimization I offer you our official statement&amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;HTC DOES plan to offer software upgrades that will increase feature functionality, over the air wireless speeds and other enhancements for some of the phones being criticized, but we do not anticipate including any additional support for the video acceleration issues cited in customer complaints. It is important for customers to understand that bringing this functionality to market is not a trivial driver update and requires extensive software development and time. HTC will utilize hardware video acceleration like the ATI Imageon in many upcoming products. Our users have made it clear that they expect our products to offer an improved visual experience, and we have included this feedback into planning and development of future products. To address lingering questions about HTC&amp;rsquo;s current MSM 7xxx devices, it is important to establish that a chipset like an MSM7xxx is a platform with a vast multitude of features that enable a wide range of devices with varied functionality. It is common that devices built on platforms like Qualcomm&amp;rsquo;s will not enable every feature or function. In addition to making sure the required hardware is present, unlocking extended capabilities of chipsets like the MSM 7xxx requires in-depth and time consuming software development, complicated licensing negotiations, potential intellectual property negotiations, added licensing fees, and in the case of devices that are sold through operators, the desire of the operator to include the additional functionality. To make an informed decision about which handset suits them best, consumers should look at the product specification itself instead of using the underlying chipset specifications to define what the product could potentially become.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --></content></item><item><title>Nokia + Windows Mobile = Let's Kick Some &lt;InsertWMPhoneMakerName> Butt</title><link>/2008/02/08/nokia-windows-mobile-lets-kick-some-butt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2008 05:00:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/02/08/nokia-windows-mobile-lets-kick-some-butt/</guid><description>As everyone knows, I’m an out-and-out Windows Mobile worshipper. It’s like a girlfriend, who is very difficult to manage and understand at first, but is a great source of joy if you know how to manage her. I don’t like any other phones now; the extensibility given by WM will do that to you.
I also “admire” Nokia because of the quality and reliability they provide with their phones. Having worked for them in a project (Nokia Networks/Nokia Seimens Networks actually), I know how much testing they put in before releasing something.</description><content>&lt;p>As everyone knows, I’m an out-and-out Windows Mobile worshipper. It’s like a girlfriend, who is very difficult to manage and understand at first, but is a great source of joy if you know how to manage her. I don’t like any other phones now; the extensibility given by WM will do that to you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also “admire” Nokia because of the quality and reliability they provide with their phones. Having worked for them in a project (Nokia Networks/Nokia Seimens Networks actually), I know how much testing they put in before releasing something. That coupled with the recent &lt;a href="/2008/01/28/htc-the-best-windows-mobile-business-unit.html">crap-doings&lt;/a> by even the largest of the WM Phone companies like HTC, have made me try to look elsewhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, if this &lt;a href="http://www.itwire.com/content/view/16510/127/">news&lt;/a> comes true, then we are in for a treat, as the two giants might just come together to give us a sweet little toy for our “smart” cravings &lt;img src="/img/uploads/smile3.gif" alt="">. Read the news and let us know how you feel about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PS: Don’t even mention iPhone/iPod/iTouch or any other iCrap.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>WM6.1 Is Here, Loves HTC Wizard...(Really?)</title><link>/2008/01/31/wm61-is-here-loves-htc-wizardreally/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2008 05:54:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/01/31/wm61-is-here-loves-htc-wizardreally/</guid><description>A user going by the remarkably simple handle &amp;ldquo;email123&amp;rdquo; announced on the xda-developers forum, that WM6.1 is here, alive and kicking. But he doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop there, he says that its available &amp;ldquo;now&amp;rdquo;, that too for an HTC wizard, a 3 year old phone (which I own as well). Thats not all, he goes on to provide the proof by linking in his cooked ROM for all to download. But, here is the clincher, he claims that finally &amp;ldquo;Big Storage&amp;rdquo; is available for wizard, a feat noone has been able to achieve in the last 3 years.</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;a href="/img/uploads/Screen002.jpg">&lt;img src="/img/uploads/Screen002_thumb.jpg" alt="Screen002">&lt;/a> &lt;a href="/img/uploads/Screen003.jpg">&lt;img src="/img/uploads/Screen003_thumb.jpg" alt="Screen003">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A user going by the remarkably simple handle &amp;ldquo;email123&amp;rdquo; announced on the &lt;a href="http://xda-developers.com/">xda-developers &lt;/a>forum, that WM6.1 is here, alive and kicking. But he doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop there, he says that its available &amp;ldquo;now&amp;rdquo;, that too for an HTC wizard, a 3 year old phone (which I own as well). Thats not all, he goes on to provide the proof by linking in his cooked ROM for all to download. But, here is the clincher, he claims that finally &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.google.co.in/search?hl=en&amp;amp;q=htc+big+storage+hack&amp;amp;btnG=Google+Search&amp;amp;meta=">Big Storage&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo; is available for wizard, a feat noone has been able to achieve in the last 3 years. It means that an extra 10 MB is available to you as Device Memory. It seems to get better and better for our dear old wizard. After all, old is gold.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click &lt;a href="http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=364066">here&lt;/a> to go to the thread, the link is in the first post. And do not forget to let us know if you did try out that ROM.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>HTC - The best windows mobile "business unit"</title><link>/2008/01/28/htc-the-best-windows-mobile-business-unit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2008 15:26:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/01/28/htc-the-best-windows-mobile-business-unit/</guid><description>For the very post of this blog, I chose a subject that&amp;rsquo;s close to my heart. Yes, its Windows Mobile. My trusted 900/1800 MHZ companion for the past couple of years is an HTC Wizard. If you have ever looked into the WinMob world, its pretty much common knowledge that HTC owns the 95% of market share of this niche little space. They are a huge organization and with huge profits and they do make jolly good phones.</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;a href="/img/2008/01/htc_tytn_ii.jpg">&lt;img src="/img/2008/01/htc_tytn_ii.jpg" alt="htc kaiser">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the very post of this blog, I chose a subject that&amp;rsquo;s close to my heart. Yes, its Windows Mobile. My trusted 900/1800 MHZ companion for the past couple of years is an HTC Wizard. If you have ever looked into the WinMob world, its pretty much common knowledge that HTC owns the 95% of market share of this niche little space. They are a huge organization and with huge profits and they do make jolly good phones. BUT it is not the quality of phones that helped them reach this height. Its their business plan. &amp;ldquo;Always keep the customers craving more&amp;rdquo; seems to be the motto of this taiwanese giant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each phone seems to give one extra &amp;ldquo;feature&amp;rdquo; (read UI enhancement) over the latter. With Kaiser, it seemed too good to be true, getting a one in all phone. And it indeed was. As I pointed out &lt;a href="http://forum.xda-developers.com/showpost.php?p=1767873&amp;amp;postcount=389">here&lt;/a> , it finally turned into a reality against all hopes of fellow WinMo owners, and HTC &lt;a href="http://www.engadget.com/2008/01/25/htc-further-responds-to-video-driver-issue-will-improve-future/">declared&lt;/a> that nothing is coming for the current crop. So, am writing this post just to put in my two bits to the cause of these drivers, if you can do anything about it, take a look &lt;a href="http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=351986">here&lt;/a> (and yeah, a 5000$ bounty awaits you as well)&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>