<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>HTC on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/htc/</link><description>Recent content in HTC on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2008 19:32:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/htc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Android Devices Trickling In A Few Days Early?</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/20/android-devices-trickling-in-a-few-days-early/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2008 19:32:35 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/10/20/android-devices-trickling-in-a-few-days-early/</guid><description>There is still a day left for the first Android based Device, T-Mobile G1, to come out into the hands of general public but I was in a for a small surprise as I went through my Google Analytics report for the last week. It had a mysterious number of 2 sitting at the bottom of my “Unique Visitors by Operating Systems” filter report. The “mysterious” part coming from the fact that the left most column displayed “Android”.</description></item><item><title>The Elusive Super Phone</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/08/the-elusive-super-phone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2008 17:15:28 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/08/the-elusive-super-phone/</guid><description>HTC announce their shiny new Touch Diamond recently. Everyone ooh'ed and aah'ed while ogling at it until they realized that HTC has taken a step back (or forward towards matching Apple's iPhone crap) by removing the expansion card slot from the phone. Yes, it has 4 GB of internal storage but I'd rather have an SDHC card slot with the ever falling prices of solid state memory (an 8 GB Class 6 SDHC card is worth not more than around 60$ these days).</description></item><item><title>HTC Video Drivers: But This Is Not A Post About HTC</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/26/htc-video-drivers-but-this-is-not-a-post-about-htc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 11:14:36 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/26/htc-video-drivers-but-this-is-not-a-post-about-htc/</guid><description>This is a post about irresponsible/careless journalism/bloggism. For Gizmodo, getting that post about HTC’s latest press release out the door took precedence over actually **reading **the release properly and then commenting over it. The gizmodo poster’s comment is:
……but HTC's finally released a statement saying that a fix is coming. They say that the video acceleration will be supported in the future, and will be included in software upgrades for current devices…….</description></item><item><title>Nokia + Windows Mobile = Let's Kick Some &lt;InsertWMPhoneMakerName> Butt</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/08/nokia-windows-mobile-lets-kick-some-butt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2008 05:00:58 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/02/08/nokia-windows-mobile-lets-kick-some-butt/</guid><description>As everyone knows, I’m an out-and-out Windows Mobile worshipper. It’s like a girlfriend, who is very difficult to manage and understand at first, but is a great source of joy if you know how to manage her. I don’t like any other phones now; the extensibility given by WM will do that to you.
I also “admire” Nokia because of the quality and reliability they provide with their phones. Having worked for them in a project (Nokia Networks/Nokia Seimens Networks actually), I know how much testing they put in before releasing something.</description></item><item><title>WM6.1 Is Here, Loves HTC Wizard...(Really?)</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/31/wm61-is-here-loves-htc-wizardreally/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2008 05:54:42 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/31/wm61-is-here-loves-htc-wizardreally/</guid><description>A user going by the remarkably simple handle &amp;ldquo;email123&amp;rdquo; announced on the xda-developers forum, that WM6.1 is here, alive and kicking. But he doesn't stop there, he says that its available &amp;ldquo;now&amp;rdquo;, that too for an HTC wizard, a 3 year old phone (which I own as well). Thats not all, he goes on to provide the proof by linking in his cooked ROM for all to download. But, here is the clincher, he claims that finally &amp;ldquo;Big Storage&amp;rdquo; is available for wizard, a feat noone has been able to achieve in the last 3 years.</description></item><item><title>HTC - The best windows mobile "business unit"</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/28/htc-the-best-windows-mobile-business-unit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2008 15:26:02 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/01/28/htc-the-best-windows-mobile-business-unit/</guid><description>For the very post of this blog, I chose a subject that's close to my heart. Yes, its Windows Mobile. My trusted 900/1800 MHZ companion for the past couple of years is an HTC Wizard. If you have ever looked into the WinMob world, its pretty much common knowledge that HTC owns the 95% of market share of this niche little space. They are a huge organization and with huge profits and they do make jolly good phones.</description></item></channel></rss>