<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Adsense Plugin on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/adsense-plugin/</link><description>Recent content in Adsense Plugin on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2009 18:30:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/adsense-plugin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Project: Shantz WordPress Prefix Suffix Updated to 1.1.2</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/19/project-shantz-wordpress-prefix-suffix-updated-to-112/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2009 18:30:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2009/02/19/project-shantz-wordpress-prefix-suffix-updated-to-112/</guid><description>&lt;p>My WordPress Plugin &amp;ldquo;Shantz Wordpress Prefix Suffix&amp;rdquo; has just been updated to version 1.1.2. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, this is a super-light and easy to use plugin that allows you to add any text or html/javascript/php code to your posts, be it the top of the posts, bottom of the posts or even in the middle. And you get a lot of options to control all this. I use it even on my site, to create links for my other blogs, adding copyright notices and even for advertisements (google adsense, chitika premium, etc).&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>My WordPress Plugin &amp;ldquo;Shantz Wordpress Prefix Suffix&amp;rdquo; has just been updated to version 1.1.2. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, this is a super-light and easy to use plugin that allows you to add any text or html/javascript/php code to your posts, be it the top of the posts, bottom of the posts or even in the middle. And you get a lot of options to control all this. I use it even on my site, to create links for my other blogs, adding copyright notices and even for advertisements (google adsense, chitika premium, etc).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This update brings in WordPress 2.7.1 compatibility and also another option to control the plugin order. If there are some other plugins that add content to your posts (e.g. sociable, simple tags, related posts, etc), you might notice that the text/code you append with this plugin may not occur in exactly the place you want (e.g. you might want to occur after all other plugins have posted their content). So, you can easily control this now by changing the priority value in the plugin settings. Make it higher to push the content down and lower it to add your content before anything else.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>