<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>motion detection on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/motion-detection/</link><description>Recent content in motion detection on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</managingEditor><webMaster>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2008 17:51:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/motion-detection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Project: Shantz Webcam Autolocker</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/11/project-shantz-webcam-autolocker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2008 17:51:31 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/08/11/project-shantz-webcam-autolocker/</guid><description>Sometimes I do some things that even I can&amp;rsquo;t explain why I did &amp;lsquo;em. Did this one in one of those times as well. This is a simple script to monitor motion in front of your PC, auto-lock it when you are away and auto-unlock it when you come back. Did it just because I was really bogged down by the shitload of work that I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing for the past few weeks (and even weekends as well), so wanted to take a break for a few minutes, and just chanced over my own &amp;ldquo;Home Security Using a Webcam and Twitter&amp;rdquo; post, so thought of doing something related to motion detection again.</description></item><item><title>Keep Tab On Home Security With A Webcam And Twitter</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/14/keep-tab-on-home-security-with-a-webcam-and-twitter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2008 04:00:13 +0000</pubDate><author>shantanu@shantanugoel.com (Shantanu Goel)</author><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/05/14/keep-tab-on-home-security-with-a-webcam-and-twitter/</guid><description>Worried about someone breaking into your house in your absence? Or just need to keep a tab on who enters your room while you are away? Well, all you need is a webcam, a linux PC/laptop and a twitter account. And you are set for real time updates through twitter about all that goes on at your abode behind your back (can even receive a text message/sms on your phone). Keep reading for the very simple setup you need.</description></item></channel></rss>