<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apple on</title><link>/tags/apple/</link><description>Recent content in Apple on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 16:55:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/apple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apple, Anti-Malware, Patents</title><link>/2013/02/15/apple-anti-malware-patents/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 16:55:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/02/15/apple-anti-malware-patents/</guid><description>Recently, there has been this trend. Blogs look for patents filed by companies and then report on each of them as if they are second coming of Jesus in technology. Especially if it is Apple who is doing the filings.
A few days ago, this new patent showed up about Apple&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;new wave approach to fighting malware&amp;rdquo; with the author giving up half-researched commentary on it.
I was intrigued by this news (if you can call it that), not because it’s something new but instead because process isolation is hardly a new concept.</description><content>&lt;p>Recently, there has been this trend. Blogs look for patents filed by companies and then report on each of them as if they are second coming of Jesus in technology. Especially if it is Apple who is doing the filings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few days ago, this &lt;a href="http://www.zdnet.com/apples-new-wave-anti-malware-patent-takes-a-leaf-out-of-qubes-book-7000011118/">new patent&lt;/a> showed up about Apple&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;new wave approach to fighting malware&amp;rdquo; with the author giving up half-researched commentary on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was intrigued by this news (if you can call it that), not because it’s something new but instead because process isolation is hardly a new concept. The author mentions &amp;ldquo;Qubes OS&amp;rdquo; as the one to be original inventor before Apple but in fact, it has been used for years (eg chrooting/containers in linux) and more popular recently in Android’s uid based approach. Even Qualcomm (and other SoC vendors) have stuff that helps in this space with Trustzone based isolation between processor entities at hardware level.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, I wanted to check out what’s new here (which was not immediately clear and probably no one else tried to see it because the patent link is wrong in the article and it links to some display patent, not the one in question). The correct patent is this: &lt;a href="http://www.freepatentsonline.com/RE43987.html">http://www.freepatentsonline.com/RE43987.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After going through the mangled language that any patent embodies, it is clear that “conceptually” it is similar to what has been done till now, but the approach is different. On the whole, the basic difference seems to be that linux uses chrooting, android uses separate users, Qubes adds a virtualization layer to achieve the above and Apple goes one further (not necessarily better) and makes it real/physical separate processor instead of a virtual one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, I’m still not sold on this and it doesn’t seem foolproof. (I’m not a security expert by any means, so please take the below with a tablespoon full of salt and you are free to add corrections or throw me out the window ;) ) In fact, it doesn’t seem much better than the current system but has an add-on of cost (extra physical processor, dedicated circuitry/components) and losing ease of use. Some points to be noted:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The burden is still mostly on user. The user still needs to keep all his anti-malware programs updated all the time and be alert for each indication on the system and allow/disallow things to happen in system all the time to keep it protected. This approach is not going to save the system in any way if any of the above steps falter. Which is, pretty similar to what we see today.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The approach does not mention aversion of several crucial points:&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>a. If processor P2 itself is compromised by the malware, then it is rendered useless in the scenario where P2 itself is tasked with scanning the memory/files on Memory M2 for malware. It can be made to just report “all clean” by malware as the scanning engine running on P2 is still accessible by network content in the same way it would have been on P1 in a non-dual-processor system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b. P2 is connected to the video display subsystem and this can be used to malware’s advantage to trick user into clicking on wrong areas or doing wrong things in the same way as it is today&lt;/p>
&lt;p>c. It says keypresses can be encrypted by P1 and decrypted by Network device 190 to allow P2 to not know what was pressed. But this again seems to not require the above approach. First, it requires a special network device now, not a generic one as mentioned in the patent. Second, since the network device itself needs to be configurable now for this, there is another attack vector there. This is, however, somewhat similar to what existing SoC solutions do in mobile space but that is better/feasible because the other end is a software entity and the mechanics of how it works is different.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>d. For online gaming etc, where the influx of data is huge and needs to be processed in real time, P1 takes this data directly from M2 once P2 signals availability. Not sure, how is this different then from having a single processor system without the above isolation?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>e. Several other things which I can keep typing about till my keys wear out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>TL;DR&lt;/strong>: This patent on its own may be a new idea (rather a new twist to an existing concept) but it is hardly something that can be put into practice and maybe the reason why Apple hasn’t actually produced anything with this, yet. It might become better with other ideas coupled (which Apple may have filed separate patents for but are currently unknown).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aside: Why do patents cite archaic things? Every patent gives examples of some old stuff. E.g. Even though this patent was filed in 2011, it refers to Pentium 4 as an example of processors and Quake 3 Arena as an example of online games?&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>BogusApple.com: Apple Screw Up Saved By Githubber</title><link>/2012/10/01/bogusapple-com-apple-screw-up-saved-by-githubber/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 22:16:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2012/10/01/bogusapple-com-apple-screw-up-saved-by-githubber/</guid><description>So, I just came across a thread on apple discussion forums and it seems like that Apple has added a new feature in OS X Mountain Lion due to which it redirects a lot of web traffic to a domain called &amp;ldquo;bogusapple.com&amp;rdquo; to make sure that it is failing. Now, the problem is that Apple didn&amp;rsquo;t even register this domain. By design? To make sure that it fails? But if so, it was a very poor design decision because then anyone could have registered it and used it for benefit, like spreading malware or phishing attempts and what not.</description><content>&lt;p>So, I just came across a thread on apple discussion forums and it &lt;a href="https://discussions.apple.com/thread/4380270?start=0&amp;amp;tstart=0">seems like&lt;/a> that Apple has added a new feature in OS X Mountain Lion due to which it redirects a lot of web traffic to a domain called &amp;ldquo;bogusapple.com&amp;rdquo; to make sure that it is failing. Now, the problem is that Apple didn&amp;rsquo;t even register this domain. By design? To make sure that it fails? But if so, it was a very poor design decision because then anyone could have registered it and used it for benefit, like spreading malware or phishing attempts and what not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyways, the threat is averted for now because a good natured githubber, &lt;a href="https://github.com/blog/1099-jason-salaz-is-a-githubber">Jason Salaz&lt;/a>, registered the domain name and plastered a pretty generic webpage over there which doesn&amp;rsquo;t do much (except give him a bit of web traffic boost).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After the map fiasco and then this, it looks like Apple is indeed slipping up and things are falling through the cracks. Let&amp;rsquo;s see what Tim Cook has to say about this.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>SGX 543MP2 vs Mali-400: Is iPhone 4S GPU Really Twice As Strong As SGS 2?</title><link>/2011/10/05/sgx-543mp2-vs-mali-400-is-iphone-4s-gpu-really-twice-as-strong-as-sgs-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2011 20:23:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2011/10/05/sgx-543mp2-vs-mali-400-is-iphone-4s-gpu-really-twice-as-strong-as-sgs-2/</guid><description>Ever since Apple announced the iPhone 4S having &amp;ldquo;A5&amp;rdquo; processor, everyone has been pointing to the below image from a test run by Anandtech and saying that the iPhone 4S will be twice as strong as the Samsung Galaxy S2. I beg to differ.
While the above test doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any discrepancy, one major thing is that the SGX 543MP2 results are from an iPad 2 (a tablet) while the Mali 400 results are from a smartphone.</description><content>&lt;p>Ever since Apple announced the iPhone 4S having &amp;ldquo;A5&amp;rdquo; processor, everyone has been pointing to the below image from a test run by Anandtech and saying that the iPhone 4S will be twice as strong as the Samsung Galaxy S2. I beg to differ.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="/img/2011/10/anandtech-gpu-comparison-sgx543mp2-mali400-300x238.png" />
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>While the above test doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any discrepancy, one major thing is that the SGX 543MP2 results are from an iPad 2 (a tablet) while the Mali 400 results are from a smartphone. Thus, we can&amp;rsquo;t readily take this to directly and accurately predict the comparison results for iPhone 4S because there are other things to consider:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Mali-400 lags behing SGX543MP2 in &amp;ldquo;offscreen&amp;rdquo; tests which are done for resolutions greater than native SGS2 resolution (SGS 2 resolution is 800x480 while test is done at 720p) and brute triangle pushing. Samsung didn&amp;rsquo;t have to optimize their GPU implementation for this because SGS2 was never going to run a game at 720p resolution and would also need to push lesser triangles for similar detail. Hence they could easily make this trade-off to get lesser power consumption and heat generation&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Mali-400 goes hand in hand with SGX543MP2 in all other tests as seen on glbenchmark.com&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>It is naive to think that the same SGX543MP2 implementation as iPad 2 will be present in iPhone 4S. Even if iPhone 4S is slated to have &amp;ldquo;A5&amp;rdquo;, a lot depends on the actual clock speeds (CPU and GPU), graphics memory, etc. Apple will do similar trade offs like Samsung (and Apple has already done this with A4 in iPad 1 vs iPhone 4) and the real results would be available only then.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>So, the end result is that we will have the real comparison only when iPhone 4S is out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PS: Not that the results matter anyways :P since firstly, the comparisons should now be moving to upcoming Nexus Prime and not SGS2 and secondly, the raw power of these GPUs won&amp;rsquo;t determine much since they cater to two completely different OSs and would have a lot of software and ecosystem dependencies on the user-perceived outcome.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Android vs iPhone: Security Models</title><link>/2010/06/25/android-vs-iphone-security-models/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2010 22:02:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/06/25/android-vs-iphone-security-models/</guid><description>Android and iPhone OS (iOS) have been at loggerheads for quite some time now. This is a take on which has a better security model to protect its users. I thought of writing it up because there have been a lot of discussions around me lately about which platform is more secure and I keep repeating the same points over and over at every one of them, so thought that in future I&amp;rsquo;ll just point them to this page :P</description><content>&lt;p>Android and iPhone OS (iOS) have been at loggerheads for quite some time now. This is a take on which has a better security model to protect its users. I thought of writing it up because there have been a lot of discussions around me lately about which platform is more secure and I keep repeating the same points over and over at every one of them, so thought that in future I&amp;rsquo;ll just point them to this page :P&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Disclaimer:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A. I don&amp;rsquo;t guarantee this post to be absolutely correct as I&amp;rsquo;m no security researcher or expert but I do have some interest in this field and I&amp;rsquo;ve been a developer for some time now on different architectures and OSs especially at OS/driver level and that too in the mobile devices field, so I &amp;ldquo;might&amp;rdquo; actually be right about a few things here and there..&lt;/p>
&lt;p>B. I&amp;rsquo;m an android user myself but not of the fanboy variety. I&amp;rsquo;ll be happy to switch camps any day I get something that appeals to me better. I have love and hate points for almost all platforms available but I&amp;rsquo;m using android because &amp;ldquo;for me&amp;rdquo; it&amp;rsquo;s love points slightly outnumber the hate points.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK, on with the points then. Here is the table that I created for this showing points I considered and which side wins each. Don&amp;rsquo;t start flaming me though just by seeing the table :P I will be discussing the points as well below it.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Android
iPhone&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1. Distribution Medium Security:&lt;/strong> Apple vets every application that is put on the app store while Google&amp;rsquo;s Market Place is unrestricted. How does this affect you security wise?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**a. Approval Process: **The biggest myth is that the vetting process is what will save you from malware on app store. IT WON&amp;rsquo;T. The Apple app approval process isn&amp;rsquo;t defined anywhere but in general it just states that it checks for apps to do what they say they will do. But they don&amp;rsquo;t check the source code of the apps and static analysis of binaries can only take you so far (Heck, they have even been inept at catching a whole lot of apps that were using their disallowed private apis which can be found easily using simple tools) . So, anyone actually wanting to write a malware can do it trivially by making the malicious code to run after the app has been approved. The trigger could be time based or could even be done over the web remotely. The app could even have encrypted payloads or download new pieces of code over the web and run them. So, we can safely say that approval process is something that can&amp;rsquo;t make things secure for you that way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Result: No one wins&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**
**&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>b. Phishing:&lt;/strong> This is where App store can protect you if someone put an app claiming to be from someone that it isn&amp;rsquo;t. e.g. Someone could make an app that claims to be from &amp;ldquo;Bank of America&amp;rdquo;. In apple&amp;rsquo;s case, I&amp;rsquo;m 99.99% sure that the app won&amp;rsquo;t pass the screening but in Android&amp;rsquo;s case, there won&amp;rsquo;t be any hassles for it to reach the marketplace. It could be pulled soon after as google learns about it but still even one person&amp;rsquo;s damage here is much more than what would have happend on iPhone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Result: iPhone wins&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**
**&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2. Local Security:&lt;/strong> What about the security in the OS itself once an app is on your phone? This is an important question because 1.) As I noted above, Apple&amp;rsquo;s app screening process isn&amp;rsquo;t robust enough to catch malware 2.) People can bypass the official distribution medium easily. Android allows to install apps from other sources on most phones by just enabling an option and a huge number of people jailbreak their iPhones and get/use this capability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>a. Permissions:&lt;/strong> On Android, an app has to explicitly declare what capabilities/data of the phone it wants to access/use and the user has to explicitly give it those permissions before it is allowed to install, irrespective of from where/how this app is being installed. So, it works even if you are installing the app from your SD card and even if you have rooted your phone. On iPhone, there is no such mechanism of restricting apps. All apps are equal and can access a lot of resources unhindered without the user knowing. So, while installing a single player only game on android you can immediately be suspicious if the app is asking for internet connection or access to your contacts data but on iPhone you will not come to know about this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Result: Android wins&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**
**&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>b. Environment:&lt;/strong> On both platforms, the apps run in their own sandboxes with unique uuids&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Result: Tie&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**
**&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>3. Open vs Closed:&lt;/strong> Most of the Android code is open source while for iOS, only darwin kernel and some other things like webkit etc are open source. Now, this in itself doesn&amp;rsquo;t gurantee to make Android secure but its code does get a lot of scrutiny from open source community as well as lot of other big name companies with commercial interests in Android which allows it to find and fix more bugs and loopholes than iPhone can.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Result: Slight win for Android&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**
**&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>4. App development model:&lt;/strong> Most apps for Android are written in java while those in iPhone are written in C/Objective-C. While I&amp;rsquo;m myself a big time C lover (Majority of my coding is in C/CPP) but it is indeed a very unforgiving language where you need to be very careful with what you write and has much greater chances of exploits, .e.g, Buffer overflows, as compared to java (Interestingly, all the jailbreaks for iPhone OS have been done using such exploits and have been made available day 0/day 1 mostly.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Result: Slight win for Android&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**
**&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>5. Damage Control:&lt;/strong> What if an app actually got through everything on any of these platforms and started spreading? Both of these platforms have kill switches in the hands of Google/Apple which they can use to remove such malicious apps from the users&amp;rsquo; phones remotely.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Result: Tie&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**
**&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Summary: Well, there is no clear winner. Apple is quite good when it comes to protecting you from phishing (though that advantage goes away if you jailbreak and use alternative means to install apps) and Android has a real sound local security system (though it also has the flaw that users might not always understand why an app is requesting a certain critical permission and install it anyways). So, take your pick and let me know what you picked :) and please do tell me if I&amp;rsquo;m wrong in any of my points or missed out on something that needs to be compared.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Apple is Magical: Daniel Eran Gilder is the Living Proof</title><link>/2010/06/10/apple-magical-dan-eran-gilder/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 04:49:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/06/10/apple-magical-dan-eran-gilder/</guid><description>Update: Removed the post as the person in consideration has contacted me with the explanation of what went down. I’m not sure if it is completely true or this is just as a response to this post but anyways, as I had contended in the original post that it was a stupid little thing that didn’t really warrant any attention or a post but I still did it just because I’m weird, so in the light of the developments, I think it’s best to remove the rants and focus on actual discussion.</description><content>&lt;p>Update: Removed the post as the person in consideration has contacted me with the explanation of what went down. I’m not sure if it is completely true or this is just as a response to this post but anyways, as I had contended in the original post that it was a stupid little thing that didn’t really warrant any attention or a post but I still did it just because I’m weird, so in the light of the developments, I think it’s best to remove the rants and focus on actual discussion. I’ll be discussing the points put out by Dan over his blog or might make a post about them here..&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Do They Really Know How To Sell Something In India?</title><link>/2008/08/26/do-they-really-know-how-to-sell-something-in-india/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 14:45:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/08/26/do-they-really-know-how-to-sell-something-in-india/</guid><description>Update: UK Ad Authorities have declared iPhone ad as &amp;ldquo;misleading&amp;rdquo;. I guess then they should declare it plain fraud in India.
This is a short rant about two of the &amp;ldquo;big&amp;rdquo; products launched recently in India in the last one week and how the people behind their sales/marketing teams either try to take the Indian customer for a ride, or shaft themselves.
iPhone: The big icon. Bharti Airtel/Vodafone claimed lakhs of pre-registrations, yet no one lined up to buy it.</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="http://www.mobileburn.com/news.jsp?Id=5176">UK Ad Authorities have declared iPhone ad as &amp;ldquo;misleading&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/a> I guess then they should declare it plain fraud in India.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a short rant about two of the &amp;ldquo;big&amp;rdquo; products launched recently in India in the last one week and how the people behind their sales/marketing teams either try to take the Indian customer for a ride, or shaft themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>iPhone&lt;/strong>: The big icon. Bharti Airtel/Vodafone claimed lakhs of pre-registrations, yet no one lined up to buy it. Anyways, to the point. The ads all over the print, digital and broadcast media in India list out 3 major points in one sentence:&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>1. **A 3G Phone:** My a$$. They haven't even finalized auction details for 3G spectrum in India yet.
2. **Desktop Class Browser:** Without Flash?
3. **Push E-mail:** Oh, the one that Apple already pulled the plug on?
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Anyways, even if this were to be true, nobody would have bought it for the steep price for something that hardly even performs properly as a phone.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>BIG TV&lt;/strong>: This is the &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; big one, from the stable of none other than Reliance/Anil Dhirubhai Ambani. Ok, it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be good, very good. I checked out &lt;a href="http://bigtv.co.in">their website&lt;/a> to see how good. What do I get?&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>1. A flash only site. No fallback. Did they get it coded from a high-school flash junkie?
2. After 15 minutes of looking around clicking on 10s of links, going in circles, I'm still confused. What exactly are their packages. There are so many rates and offers floating around. Everything promising something different, but wait, not available for your region. There are so many channels, more than your current DTH, but one second, WHAT exactly are thos channels. No list? For all I care, they could be endless streams of Doordarshan and ETV regional ones. (Please repeat the question I asked in point 1 here again)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Makes me wonder, do they really want to sell anything or Anil just made this out for fun, having a roaring time watching realtime website logs seeing people getting stuck and frustrated in the maze.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>More iPhone 3G Nonsense Uncovered: No Tethering</title><link>/2008/06/14/more-iphone-3g-nonsense-uncovered-no-tethering/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2008 15:57:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/06/14/more-iphone-3g-nonsense-uncovered-no-tethering/</guid><description>iPhone 3G, the “supposedly” latest and greatest handhled, just continues to amaze me, with its ridiculousness of course. I mean first they dare to call a machine a smartphone that can’t run more than one app a time, need you to send the unit back even for a battery change, fix the glaring mistakes of its predecessor and call them “features” and make you believe that you are getting it all for cheap while covertly telling you that you need a minimum of 2 year 70$ contract to get it and need to pay through every hole for even software updates.</description><content>&lt;p>iPhone 3G, the “supposedly” latest and greatest handhled, just continues to amaze me, with its ridiculousness of course. I mean first they dare to call a machine a smartphone that can’t run more than one app a time, need you to send the unit back even for a battery change, fix the glaring mistakes of its predecessor and call them “features” and make you believe that you are getting it all for cheap while covertly telling you that you need a minimum of 2 year 70$ contract to get it and need to pay through every hole for even software updates. And then they don’t stop this, just out is the information that you can’t tether the “data transfer powerhouse” to your laptops/PCs/Macs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>HSDPA/HSUPA my a**. I mean what good is a “3G” device that doesn’t even let you use the potential of the hyper-speeds by connecting to your bigger machines or even doing video calls. Oh right, I forgot, now you can check your e-mail at 50 messages per minute, WOOHOO!!, I’m so l33t.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So far the only good things I’ve noticed about the new release are:The MobileMe aka “sync-with-anything-anywhere” service, which although paid (obviously, its Apple we are talking about here), is still interesting. And the new SDK 2.0 that promises the 3rd party devs the same access to the phone as Apple’s devs, seems to be a step in the right direction though it remains to be seen how much of this is actually followed up on by Apple.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, what do you feel is &lt;strong>THE&lt;/strong> revolutionary thing about this new Cupertino offering? And of course, chime in with your gripes as well.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Tip: Gadgets, Deals And Stuff You Need To Know - Part I</title><link>/2008/06/02/tip-gadgets-deals-and-stuff-you-need-to-know-part-i/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2008 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/06/02/tip-gadgets-deals-and-stuff-you-need-to-know-part-i/</guid><description>If you are a gadget freak like me and can’t resist the temptations to buy the newest toy on the shelves, then you’d obviously want to eek out the maximum you can from whatever budget you have. But while doing so you have to take care of a lot of things. Here is Part I of the few things that I do get the best deals out there while making sure I’m buying the right thing from the right place.</description><content>&lt;p>If you are a gadget freak like me and can’t resist the temptations to buy the newest toy on the shelves, then you’d obviously want to eek out the maximum you can from whatever budget you have. But while doing so you have to take care of a lot of things. Here is Part I of the few things that I do get the best deals out there while making sure I’m buying the right thing from the right place.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first step to buying anything is obviously whether you are buying the right thing. The list of do’s and don’t and this regard are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Do not blindly go by the what the manufacturer’s site says. After all I’ll always say that I my product is the best.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Do not just make the decision based on the feature set. More features mean more possible points of failure, so a device with fewer features but better reliability is obviously much better than the one that promises the moon but only the “once in a blue -“ kinds.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Make sure to search for similar products from other manufacturers. Just because it comes from Apple’s stable doesn’t make it the best. (For the record, in general, I don’t like anything that comes from Cupertino)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Look for the reviews. Search for the reviews for the product you have in mind, but a big problem with this has now arisen with the advent of “paid reviews”. But of course, you can always turn towards the community. Read through all the site-based single person reviews as well but also look for forums and other communities related to the type of gadget you have in mind. e.g. – For cameras, DPReview is a good place to go, for WM smart phones, XDA-Developers is the place to be, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Is the after-sales support good? You don’t want to be locked out with a product that you can’t do anything about if something goes wrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Look also for the hidden costs of product. Many a times the base product is cheap but then it requires you to shell out a fortune in terms of required accessories to yield it’s full potential (e.g. Archos players).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Maintenance costs:e.g. Most Apple products dont have easily replaceable parts and need to be sent back to factory for even things like a new battery.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Now, the list above seems small but when put into practice it isn’t. But obviously, a geek who can handle all the latest electronic gizmos can surely handle the irks that come while chosing one, and of course, within a short while, it will become second nature to you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Are there any other things that you look for buying your new boy-toy? Do let me know. Next time, we will look at how to get the best deals for the stuff you crave.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>The Elusive Super Phone</title><link>/2008/05/08/the-elusive-super-phone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2008 17:15:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/05/08/the-elusive-super-phone/</guid><description>HTC announce their shiny new Touch Diamond recently. Everyone ooh&amp;rsquo;ed and aah&amp;rsquo;ed while ogling at it until they realized that HTC has taken a step back (or forward towards matching Apple&amp;rsquo;s iPhone crap) by removing the expansion card slot from the phone. Yes, it has 4 GB of internal storage but I&amp;rsquo;d rather have an SDHC card slot with the ever falling prices of solid state memory (an 8 GB Class 6 SDHC card is worth not more than around 60$ these days).</description><content>&lt;p>HTC announce their shiny new Touch Diamond recently. Everyone ooh&amp;rsquo;ed and aah&amp;rsquo;ed while ogling at it until they realized that HTC has taken a step back (or forward towards matching Apple&amp;rsquo;s iPhone crap) by removing the expansion card slot from the phone. Yes, it has 4 GB of internal storage but I&amp;rsquo;d rather have an SDHC card slot with the ever falling prices of solid state memory (an 8 GB Class 6 SDHC card is worth not more than around 60$ these days). With a history of ultimate-gift-to-mankind phones like HTC Tytn, HTC Tytn II (Kaiser), iPhone, etc that excite so much on the first look and then start becoming dimmer and unwanted as the euphoria settles, we are left to wonder when will we see the real &amp;ldquo;Super Phone&amp;rdquo;. The do-it-all-be-all-end-all phone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, my prediction is (Nostradamus style) : **NEVER. **No sir, you are not going to see your dream phone any time soon, or any time at all, for that matter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why do I say that. The reasons are pretty obvious, once we take off our wishful thinking hats and don the smart thinking ones.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**1. ****A new dream every day: **Around 8-10 years ago, I wished I had a cell phone. Around 6 years ago, I wish I had one with a camera. Around 4 years ago, I wish I had a phone with Mp3 player and expandable memory. 3 years ago I wished for a smart phone. Now, I wish for&amp;hellip;. You get it. By the time something comes out, our dreams have already moved on. After all they  aren&amp;rsquo;t called &amp;ldquo;dreams&amp;rdquo; just like that ;)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**2. Where is the money: **You might be ready to give a fortune (and your first born son) for that ultimate phone, but the evil-phone-conglomerate wants much more than that. They want you to be slaves. They don&amp;rsquo;t want the world to spend a huge amount in one go and then stop. They need to mint more money and too much more frequently than you&amp;rsquo;d like to spend. This is why the strategy works. Give out a phone that has slim form factor, nice UI, wi-fi, but then make the processor crappy (Touch), then lure them with a better processor but take out the wi-fi (Touch Dual), Add the wi-fi back and slap in a keyboard too, but keep&amp;rsquo;em wanting for &lt;a href="http:///2008/01/28/htc-the-best-windows-mobile-business-unit.html">better graphics&lt;/a> (Kaiser), give &amp;rsquo;em a shiny new toy, but then lock it down in every possible (iCrap). So, you&amp;rsquo;d be stuck in the vicious circle of &amp;ldquo;upgrades&amp;rdquo; and keep the phone factory churning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, my dear fellow phone lovers, stop wasting your time waiting for that ultimate phone, and go &amp;ldquo;upgrade&amp;rdquo; at once, because &amp;ldquo;that&amp;rdquo; phone with just &amp;ldquo;that&amp;rdquo; one more feature&amp;hellip;ISN&amp;rsquo;T COMING&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>