<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mtpaint on Shantanu Vs The World</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/tags/mtpaint/</link><description>Recent content in Mtpaint on Shantanu Vs The World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2008 15:30:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shantanugoel.com/tags/mtpaint/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Windows App Alternatives For Linux: MSPaint</title><link>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/28/windows-app-alternatives-for-linux-mspaint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2008 15:30:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/28/windows-app-alternatives-for-linux-mspaint/</guid><description>&lt;p>Some of you might know that I was in the hunt for a decent mspaint alternative &lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/03/wanted-a-good-paint-program-for-linux.html">recently&lt;/a>. Note that I didn&amp;rsquo;t go for GIMP / Inkscape etc because they were overkill for what I wanted to do. Many a times, I just wanted to touch up a screenshot or make a simple flow image by drawing a few boxes, use a few pointing arrows, and add some text here and there. All this could be done with the previous mentioned programs as well but took a bit more steps than I wanted (stroking the selections / paths for lines, boxes, circles, and even then, no arrows). I didn&amp;rsquo;t find an adequate replacement at the time but got it now, so thought of writing about it. Basically I came across 4 apps: tuxpaint, gpaint, kolourpaint and mtpaint. Won&amp;rsquo;t discuss tuxpaint here cuz I found it a little too kiddish.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>Some of you might know that I was in the hunt for a decent mspaint alternative &lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/2008/04/03/wanted-a-good-paint-program-for-linux.html">recently&lt;/a>. Note that I didn&amp;rsquo;t go for GIMP / Inkscape etc because they were overkill for what I wanted to do. Many a times, I just wanted to touch up a screenshot or make a simple flow image by drawing a few boxes, use a few pointing arrows, and add some text here and there. All this could be done with the previous mentioned programs as well but took a bit more steps than I wanted (stroking the selections / paths for lines, boxes, circles, and even then, no arrows). I didn&amp;rsquo;t find an adequate replacement at the time but got it now, so thought of writing about it. Basically I came across 4 apps: tuxpaint, gpaint, kolourpaint and mtpaint. Won&amp;rsquo;t discuss tuxpaint here cuz I found it a little too kiddish.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>gpaint: (Available in Ubuntu repositories) gpaint is a very simplistic program that has a mspaint look and feel but feels a bit lacking. It can do basic procedures like basic shape selections, lines, boxes but that&amp;rsquo;s it. No polygon selections, brush, color picker, etc, and yeah no arrows. Moreover, it saves only in pngs.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/gpaint.png">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/gpaint-thumb.png" alt="gpaint screenshot">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>kolourpaint: (Available in Ubuntu Repositories) kolourpaint is very close to mspaint. Infact it does a bit more than mspaint. It has all the things that I mentioned as missing in gpaint, plus has basic image manipulation effects as well. I liked it quite a bit, but it had 2 drawbacks for me, still no arrows, and it depends on KDE/Qt libraries.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/kolourpaint.png">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/kolourpaint-thumb.png" alt="kolourpaint screenshot">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>mtpaint: (Available in Ubuntu Repositories from Gutsy onwards. Rest of the folks can search for a package on net, or find a suitable package or source &lt;a href="http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=155874&amp;amp;package_id=173703">here&lt;/a>) This is the software that got me most excited. It is actually a kind of lower-intermediate package that lies somewhere between mspaint and a very basic, poor man&amp;rsquo;s GIMP. It has all the features ok kolourpaint, (plus arrows at last :-) ), a small smattering of basic effects (gaussian, edge detection, blur, embossing), can work with gifs also (handles transparency and animation quite well). So, this is the one I would be sticking to for now.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/mtpaint.png">&lt;img src="https://shantanugoel.com/img/uploads/mtpaint-thumb.png" alt="mtpaint screenshot">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am using mtpaint now for my basic needs. Hope the article benefitted you as well. If I missed out on some package, then do let me know.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>