<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Adsense on</title><link>/tags/adsense/</link><description>Recent content in Adsense on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2009 18:30:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/adsense/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Project: Shantz WordPress Prefix Suffix Updated to 1.1.2</title><link>/2009/02/19/project-shantz-wordpress-prefix-suffix-updated-to-112/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2009 18:30:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2009/02/19/project-shantz-wordpress-prefix-suffix-updated-to-112/</guid><description>My WordPress Plugin &amp;ldquo;Shantz Wordpress Prefix Suffix&amp;rdquo; has just been updated to version 1.1.2. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, this is a super-light and easy to use plugin that allows you to add any text or html/javascript/php code to your posts, be it the top of the posts, bottom of the posts or even in the middle. And you get a lot of options to control all this. I use it even on my site, to create links for my other blogs, adding copyright notices and even for advertisements (google adsense, chitika premium, etc).</description><content>&lt;p>My WordPress Plugin &amp;ldquo;Shantz Wordpress Prefix Suffix&amp;rdquo; has just been updated to version 1.1.2. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, this is a super-light and easy to use plugin that allows you to add any text or html/javascript/php code to your posts, be it the top of the posts, bottom of the posts or even in the middle. And you get a lot of options to control all this. I use it even on my site, to create links for my other blogs, adding copyright notices and even for advertisements (google adsense, chitika premium, etc).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This update brings in WordPress 2.7.1 compatibility and also another option to control the plugin order. If there are some other plugins that add content to your posts (e.g. sociable, simple tags, related posts, etc), you might notice that the text/code you append with this plugin may not occur in exactly the place you want (e.g. you might want to occur after all other plugins have posted their content). So, you can easily control this now by changing the priority value in the plugin settings. Make it higher to push the content down and lower it to add your content before anything else.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Call For Google Adsense Maths Class Charity Fund</title><link>/2008/11/23/call-for-google-adsense-maths-class-charity-fund/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2008 08:25:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/11/23/call-for-google-adsense-maths-class-charity-fund/</guid><description>I hereby call for setting up a charity fund so that we can donate some money to get the poor ol’ Google Adsense some Mathematics/Algebra 101 classes because apparantly it thinks that 0.63 + 0.07 = 0.69.</description><content>&lt;p>I hereby call for setting up a charity fund so that we can donate some money to get the poor ol’ Google Adsense some Mathematics/Algebra 101 classes because apparantly it thinks that 0.63 + 0.07 = 0.69.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/img/uploads/Google-AdSense-Reports-Miscalculation.png" alt="Google-AdSense-Reports-Miscalculation">&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Project: Shantz-WP-Prefix-Suffix Updated to 1.1.0</title><link>/2008/11/20/project-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-to-110/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 04:08:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/11/20/project-shantz-wp-prefix-suffix-updated-to-110/</guid><description>Well, its not just prefix suffix any more, because I added an option to add things in the middle of the posts as well. I got this idea because people told me that this was one of the most sought after option as advertisements (e.g. google adsense, adbrite, etc) give maximum click through rate when placed smack dab in the middle of the content. What’s more is that it is configurable and you can choose how many paragraphs and/or words should be skipped from the start of the post before you add whatever you want, be it text, css, html, php or javascript.</description><content>&lt;p>Well, its not just prefix suffix any more, because I added an option to add things in the middle of the posts as well. I got this idea because people told me that this was one of the most sought after option as advertisements (e.g. google adsense, adbrite, etc) give maximum click through rate when placed smack dab in the middle of the content. What’s more is that it is configurable and you can choose how many paragraphs and/or words should be skipped from the start of the post before you add whatever you want, be it text, css, html, php or javascript.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/img/uploads/screenshot_2D1.png">&lt;img src="/img/uploads/screenshot_2D1_thumb.jpg" alt="WordPress Plugin Shantz WP Prefix Suffic Configuration Screenshot">&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="/img/uploads/screenshot_2D2.png">&lt;img src="/img/uploads/screenshot_2D2_thumb.jpg" alt="Wordpress Plugin Shantz Wp Prefix Suffix In Action">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And don’t forget to let me know what you think about it or if you want any new features included.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Google Adsense : Conflict of Interests?</title><link>/2008/11/07/google-adsense-conflict-of-interests/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2008 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/11/07/google-adsense-conflict-of-interests/</guid><description>“Google Adsense” has been caught in a conflict of interests with its parent company “Google”. Google piad 140k to teh cause of “Say No to Prop 8” but on the other hand people reported that Google Adsense delivered a substantially huge amount of “Say Yes to Prop 8” advertisements all over the internet, even on sites which are completely out of context with this matter. Not only is this conflicting with the interests of the parent company but also with the “Terms of Use” put forward by Adsense that ads should not have any kind of intolerance or advocacy towards an individual or a group.</description><content>&lt;p>“Google Adsense” has been caught in a conflict of interests with its parent company “Google”. Google piad 140k to teh cause of “Say No to Prop 8” but on the other hand people reported that Google Adsense delivered a substantially huge amount of “Say Yes to Prop 8” advertisements all over the internet, even on sites which are completely out of context with this matter. Not only is this conflicting with the interests of the parent company but also with the “Terms of Use” put forward by Adsense that ads should not have any kind of intolerance or advocacy towards an individual or a group. Irate people took out their frustation on the &lt;a href="https://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=5576995&amp;amp;postID=8069138212199008176&amp;amp;isPopup=true">adsense blog&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, I just caught another conflict between google and adsense on my own blog. Basically, Google is against TLAs (text-link-ads) since they mess up the search engine rankings and even penalizes any site that sells or buys them. But look what I found in one of the ads displayed in google.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/img/2008/11/conflictofinterest.png">&lt;img src="/img/2008/11/conflictofinterest-thumb.png" alt="conflict-of-interest">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Looks like somebody needs to arrange a meeting between the google and adsense honchos to sort out what exactly is their stance on anything and everything.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Save Your Adsense Account: Put Up That Privacy Policy</title><link>/2008/11/04/save-your-adsense-account-put-up-that-privacy-policy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 17:35:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2008/11/04/save-your-adsense-account-put-up-that-privacy-policy/</guid><description>Google is known to be pretty strict with making sure that all Adsense publishers remain conformant to their policies. I’m not very old in this game but had read and heard enough (about google shutting down Adsense accounts without even warning) that I made sure to read their terms and conditions thoroughly. What got my attention was the very last line in the policy:
Now why I wrote this post was that though almost every site I visit has adsense ads, but only a very miniscule fraction of them is abiding with this condition.</description><content>&lt;p>Google is known to be pretty strict with making sure that all Adsense publishers remain conformant to their policies. I’m not very old in this game but had read and heard enough (about google shutting down Adsense accounts without even warning) that I made sure to read their terms and conditions thoroughly. What got my attention was the very last line in the &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/adsense/support/bin/answer.py?hl=en&amp;amp;answer=48182">policy&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Now why I wrote this post was that though almost every site I visit has adsense ads, but only a very miniscule fraction of them is abiding with this condition. Maybe they don’t know this because on my search, I came to know that this clause was added to google’s policy around March this year. I don’t know how much fuss is google is going to create over this but I’d rather be safe than sorry. Especially when it takes only a few minutes to create your privacy policy. To create yours with a few clicks, I came across a simple online template here: &lt;a href="http://www.serprank.com/privacy-policy-generator/index.php">Adsense Privacy Policy Generator&lt;/a>. I too used it (with a few modifications) to create my own &lt;a href="/privacy/">privacy policy&lt;/a>. You are free to use it to create your own.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>