<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Microsoft on</title><link>/tags/microsoft/</link><description>Recent content in Microsoft on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2010 19:48:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/microsoft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Real Threat Of Windows Phone 7</title><link>/posts/the-real-threat-of-windows-phone-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2010 19:48:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-real-threat-of-windows-phone-7/</guid><description>Many people say that Windows Phone 7 is a threat to iPhone because they are bringing in a super platform with a choice of multiple designs and multiple carriers with great Enterprise and gaming support and maintaining the lucrative integration that iPhone provides. Many also say that Windows Phone 7 is a threat to Android because it solves the problem of Apple&amp;rsquo;s draconian policies, gives choice to customers and all this without fragmenting the OS all over the place.</description></item><item><title>Boycott Novell Protestors Manhandled By National Free Software Conference 2008 Organizers</title><link>/posts/boycott-novell-protestors-manhandled-by-national-free-software-conference-2008-organizers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2008 09:38:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/boycott-novell-protestors-manhandled-by-national-free-software-conference-2008-organizers/</guid><description>This is a really sad day. Not only the organizers of National Conference On Free Software 2008 taking place at CUSAT seem to be utterly misguided when they decided to let Novell be on-board as their main sponsor, they even took the extreme step of bringing in police to silence the lone voices of the Boycott Novell protestors. They seem to be treading on the toes of not just free software but free speech as well, which is against the very ethics of the conference they are holding.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Has A Problem: Software Patents Go Up In Smoke</title><link>/posts/microsoft-has-a-problem-software-patents-go-up-in-smoke/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 18:35:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/microsoft-has-a-problem-software-patents-go-up-in-smoke/</guid><description>Just read over at groklaw about a ruling made last night by the US Appeals Court. According to it, the patents granted for business practices would have to undergo specific and stringent testing procedures to check the worthiness of granting a patent to it. Essentially, they are aiming to mandate a passing of &amp;ldquo;machine-or-transformation test&amp;rdquo; as a pre-requisite for granting a patent. This means that a mere &amp;ldquo;idea in my head&amp;rdquo; doesn&amp;rsquo;t qualify for a patent until it is put into practice on a machine or can transform the state of an object for a specific purpose.</description></item><item><title>TIP: Free Downloads For Windows Vista, XP Professional, Visual Studio 2008, MSDN And Much More</title><link>/posts/tip-free-downloads-for-windows-vista-xp-professional-visual-studio-2008-msdn-and-much-more/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2008 19:31:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/tip-free-downloads-for-windows-vista-xp-professional-visual-studio-2008-msdn-and-much-more/</guid><description>If you are a student (this works for non-students as well but I expect you to be honest ;) ), you can download a whole bunch of software for free. How? Well, all you need is to become an ACM student member, and join the MSDN AA (Microsoft Developer Network Academic Alliance) ACM Student Benefit Program.
Normally it takes around 19$ for you to become a student member but you can do it for free for a limited time by going to http://campus.</description></item><item><title>Firefox Incognito / Private Browsing Mode - Part II</title><link>/posts/firefox-incognito-private-browsing-mode-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2008 16:59:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/firefox-incognito-private-browsing-mode-part-ii/</guid><description>A few people (e.g. Varun) told me my previous post differed from the way how google chrome / Microsoft IE8 handle Incognito (Private Browsing) mode. The main consideration was that while chrome/IE8 don&amp;rsquo;t write anything to disk at all, the firefox method is an after-effect, i.e., writing to disk and then clearing it up while closing the window. Well, true but nothing is non-rectificable :). So this is a post about a method that one can use to go &amp;ldquo;really&amp;rdquo; undercover with firefox.</description></item><item><title>Firefox Incognito Mode Is Here: Move Over Chrome/IE8</title><link>/posts/firefox-incognito-mode-is-here-move-over-chromeie8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2008 17:49:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/firefox-incognito-mode-is-here-move-over-chromeie8/</guid><description>Update: Part 2 of this post is now up here to allay some of the drawbacks that were pointed out.
There has been so much hype over the “Incognito” (or Private Browsing) mode of Google Chrome / Microsoft IE8, with many internet users screeming Hallelujiah. But I don’t understand what the hoopla is all about. This mode has always been there in Mozilla firefox as well. You just need to devote less than one minute (yes, you read that right, less than one minute) to set it up.</description></item><item><title>Free Domain, Free Webhosting from Microsoft</title><link>/posts/free-domain-free-webhosting-from-microsoft/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2008 16:13:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/free-domain-free-webhosting-from-microsoft/</guid><description>Microsoft is doling out a lot of free stuff today. If you have a Live ID, or have the patience of 5 minutes to fill up a small form to create a new one, you can get free domain name as well as free webhosting from then for one complete year. Cool, huh? All you need to do is click here.
A word of caution: Unless you are creating a new website just for kicks, you might want to check out the terms and conditions properly because I&amp;rsquo;m not sure whether you can transfer the domain name to some other provider after the one year is over.</description></item><item><title>Nokia + Windows Mobile = Let's Kick Some &lt;InsertWMPhoneMakerName> Butt</title><link>/posts/nokia-windows-mobile-lets-kick-some-butt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2008 05:00:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/nokia-windows-mobile-lets-kick-some-butt/</guid><description>As everyone knows, I’m an out-and-out Windows Mobile worshipper. It’s like a girlfriend, who is very difficult to manage and understand at first, but is a great source of joy if you know how to manage her. I don’t like any other phones now; the extensibility given by WM will do that to you.
I also “admire” Nokia because of the quality and reliability they provide with their phones. Having worked for them in a project (Nokia Networks/Nokia Seimens Networks actually), I know how much testing they put in before releasing something.</description></item></channel></rss>